<paper id="1576962511"><title>SLIQ: A Fast Scalable Classifier for Data Mining</title><year>1996</year><authors><author org="IBM Almaden Research Center" id="2608244303">Manish Mehta</author><author org="IBM Almaden Research Center" id="2138427228">Rakesh Agrawal</author><author org="IBM Almaden Research Center" id="2279064906">Jorma Rissanen</author></authors><n_citation>640</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>85229681</reference><reference>1487801850</reference><reference>1533169541</reference><reference>1704669313</reference><reference>1864487875</reference><reference>1983661866</reference><reference>2100406636</reference><reference>2125055259</reference><reference>2142334564</reference></references><venue id="1132593990" type="C">Extending Database Technology</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0014141</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.51199">Decision tree</keyword><keyword weight="0.46968">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.44232">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47957">Categorical variable</keyword><keyword weight="0.51483">Tree (data structure)</keyword><keyword weight="0.56461">C4.5 algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.50278">Classifier (linguistics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.53584">Statistical classification</keyword><keyword weight="0.46847">Machine learning</keyword><keyword weight="0.56996">Decision tree learning</keyword><keyword weight="0.54263">Incremental decision tree</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><abstract>Classification is an important problem in the emerging field of data mining. Although classification has been studied extensively in the past, most of the classification algorithms are designed only for memory-resident data, thus limiting their suitability for data mining large data sets. This paper discusses issues in building a scalable classifier and presents the design of SLIQ, a new classifier. SLIQ is a decision tree classifier that can handle both numeric and categorical attributes. It uses a novel pre-sorting technique in the tree-growth phase. This sorting procedure is integrated with a breadth-first tree growing strategy to enable classification of disk-resident datasets. SLIQ also uses a new tree-pruning algorithm that is inexpensive, and results in compact and accurate trees. The combination of these techniques enables SLIQ to scale for large data sets and classify data sets irrespective of the number of classes, attributes, and examples (records), thus making it an attractive tool for data mining.</abstract></paper>