<paper id="1597650360"><title>The Financial Crimes Enforcement Network AI System (FAIS) Identifying Potential Money Laundering from Reports of Large Cash Transactions.</title><year>1995</year><authors><author org="" id="182233741">Ted E. Senator</author><author org="" id="2137686017">Henry G. Goldberg</author><author org="" id="2580896368">Jerry Wooton</author><author org="" id="2003360234">Matthew A. Cottini</author><author org="" id="2075483690">A. F. Umar Khan</author><author org="" id="2171791529">Christina D. Klinger</author><author org="" id="2009183241">Winston M. Llamas</author><author org="" id="2064887371">Michael P. Marrone</author><author org="" id="2167015915">Raphael W. H. Wong</author></authors><n_citation>72</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>85383827</reference><reference>201583589</reference><reference>1564733196</reference><reference>2914420373</reference></references><venue id="163019073" type="J">Ai Magazine</venue><doi>10.1609/aimag.v16i4.1169</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46224">Intelligent agent</keyword><keyword weight="0.44656">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.42737">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46847">Expert system</keyword><keyword weight="0.47019">Software agent</keyword><keyword weight="0.41665">Graphical user interface</keyword><keyword weight="0.46215">Enforcement</keyword><keyword weight="0.4097">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.4253">Finance</keyword><keyword weight="0.45518">User interface</keyword><keyword weight="0.53921">Money laundering</keyword><keyword weight="0.46968">Cash</keyword></keywords><publisher>American Association for Artificial Intelligence</publisher><abstract>The Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (FIN-CEN) AI system (FAIS) links and evaluates reports of large cash transactions to identify potential money laundering. The objective of FAIS is to discover previously unknown, potentially high-value leads for possible investigation. FAIS integrates intelligent human and software agents in a cooperative discovery task on a very large data space. It is a complex system incorporating several aspects of AI technology, including rule-based reasoning and a blackboard. FAIS consists of an underlying database (that functions as a black-board), a graphic user interface, and several preprocessing and analysis modules. FAIS has been in operation at FINCEN since March 1993; a dedicated group of analysts process approximately 200,000 transactions a week, during which time over 400 investigative support reports corresponding to over $1 billion in potential laundered funds were developed. FAISu0027s unique analytic power arises primarily from a change in view of the underlying data from a transaction-oriented perspective to a subject-oriented (that is, person or organization) perspective.</abstract></paper>