<paper id="1960052024"><title>On the controlled evolution of access rules in cooperative information systems</title><year>2005</year><authors><author org="Dept. Databases and Information Systems, University of Ulm, Germany#TAB#" id="2048013632">Stefanie Rinderle</author><author org="Information Systems Group, University of Twente, The Netherlands#TAB#" id="2124900482">Manfred Reichert</author></authors><n_citation>34</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>63980221</reference><reference>1503663442</reference><reference>1570265525</reference><reference>1592102665</reference><reference>1783266478</reference><reference>1841581133</reference><reference>1997868569</reference><reference>2013302775</reference><reference>2026913455</reference><reference>2038953226</reference><reference>2107271943</reference><reference>2147984485</reference><reference>2162168892</reference><reference>2167668272</reference></references><venue id="2754624328" type="C">International Conference on Move to Meaningful Internet Systems</venue><doi>10.1007/11575771_17</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.55004">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.58427">Organizational network analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.54742">Organizational unit</keyword><keyword weight="0.5456">Enterprise architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.53215">Organizational structure</keyword><keyword weight="0.4494">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.52976">Information access</keyword><keyword weight="0.4504">Operations research</keyword><keyword weight="0.64223">Organizational learning</keyword><keyword weight="0.62316">Organizational studies</keyword><keyword weight="0.43749">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.46683">Process management</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer Verlag</publisher><abstract>For several reasons enterprises are frequently subject to organizational change. Respective adaptations may concern business processes, but also other components of an enterprise architecture. In particular, changes of organizational structures often become :[32],"information about organizational entities and their relationships is maintained in organizational models. Therefore the quick and correct adaptation of these models is fundamental to adequately cope with changes. However, model changes alone are not sufficient to guarantee consistency. Since organizational models also provide the basis for defining access rules (e.g., actor assignments in workflow management systems or access rules in document–centered applications) this :[32],"information has to be adapted accordingly (e.g., to avoid non-resolvable actor assignments). Current approaches do not adequately address this problem, which often leads to security gaps and delayed change this :[125],"paper we present a comprehensive approach for the controlled evolution of organizational models in cooperative :[32],"information systems. First, we introduce a set of operators with well-defined semantics for defining and changing organizational models. Second, we present an advanced approach for the semi-automated adaptation of access rules when the underlying organizational model is changed. This includes a formal part concerning both the evolution of organizational models and the adaptation of related access rules.</abstract></paper>