<paper id="1559331297"><title>Distributed Implementation of SIGNAL: Scheduling &amp; Graph Clustering</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="GMD I5 - SKS" id="2973516409">Oliver Maffeïs</author><author org="IRISA" id="2974344388">Paul Le Guernic</author></authors><n_citation>32</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1480033811</reference><reference>1491178396</reference><reference>1998336350</reference><reference>2043331236</reference><reference>2084606150</reference><reference>2294861651</reference><reference>2478500381</reference></references><venue id="2759875671" type="C">International Symposium Organized Jointly with Working Group Provably Correct Systems on Formal Techniques in Real-Time and Fault-Tolerant Systems</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-58468-4_183</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46822">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.60497">Directed acyclic graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.47976">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.58166">Null graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.59469">Graph rewriting</keyword><keyword weight="0.59846">Wait-for graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.57698">Clustering coefficient</keyword><keyword weight="0.62308">Graph (abstract data type)</keyword><keyword weight="0.58659">Moral graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.56359">Voltage graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.46982">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>This paper introduces the scheduling strategy and some key tools which have been designed for the distributed implementation of SIGNAL, a real-time synchronous dataflow language. First, we motivate a scheduling strategy with respect to the reactivity and time-predictability requirements bound to real-time computing. Then, several key tools to implement this scheduling strategy are described. These tools are acting on the concept of Synchronous-Flow Dependence Graph (SFD Graph) which defines a generalization of Directed Acyclic Graph and constitutes the abstract representation of SIGNAL programs. The tools presented in this paper are: (a) the abstraction of SFD graphs which enables grain-size tuning according to the target architecture, (b) the notion of scheduling over SFD graphs and (c) qualitative clustering tools based on the notion of Compositional Deadlock Consistency.</abstract></paper>