<paper id="1982822209"><title>Fast K-dimensional tree algorithms for nearest neighbor search with application to vector quantization encoding</title><year>1992</year><authors><author org="Comput Syst. &amp; Common. Group, Tata Inst. of Fundamental Res., Bombay, India" id="2306235175">V. Ramasubramanian</author><author org="" id="2097766447">K.K. Paliwal</author></authors><n_citation>116</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1999199484</reference><reference>2024668293</reference><reference>2069797735</reference><reference>2098039338</reference><reference>2156097299</reference><reference>2165558283</reference></references><venue id="168680287" type="J">IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing</venue><doi>10.1109/78.120795</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.63123">Search algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.62873">Tree traversal</keyword><keyword weight="0.65137">Ball tree</keyword><keyword weight="0.62984">k-d tree</keyword><keyword weight="0.63526">Optimal binary search tree</keyword><keyword weight="0.45472">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.64341">Cover tree</keyword><keyword weight="0.66568">Nearest neighbor search</keyword><keyword weight="0.41652">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.64128">Interval tree</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>Fast search algorithms are proposed and studied for vector quantization encoding using the K-dimensional (K-d) tree structure. Here, the emphasis is on the optimal design of the K-d tree for efficient nearest neighbor search in multidimensional space under a bucket-Voronoi intersection search framework. Efficient optimization criteria and procedures are proposed for designing the K-d tree, for the case when the test data distribution is available (as in vector quantization application in the form of training data) as well as for the case when the test data distribution is not available and only the Voronoi intersection information is to be used. The criteria and bucket-Voronoi intersection search procedure are studied in the context of vector quantization encoding of speech waveform. They are empirically observed to achieve constant search complexity for O(log N) tree depths and are found to be more efficient in reducing the search complexity. A geometric interpretation is given for the maximum product criterion, explaining reasons for its inefficiency with respect to the optimization criteria. u003e</abstract></paper>