<paper id="1973113780"><title>Modeling hypergraphs by graphs with the same mincut properties</title><year>1993</year><authors><author org="Theoretische Informatik, Eidgenössische Technische Hochschule Zürich, CH-8092 Zürich, Switzerland" id="2650776867">Edmund Ihler</author><author org="Fachbereich Mathematik, Technische Universität Berlin, W-1000 Berlin 12, Germany" id="2140363637">Dorothea Wagner</author><author org="Institut für Informatik, Fachbereich Mathematik, Freie Universität Berlin, Arnimallee 2–6, W-1000 Berlin 33, Germany" id="2780958029">Frank Wagner</author></authors><n_citation>57</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>2029282358</reference><reference>2084528420</reference><reference>2158598102</reference></references><venue id="147953040" type="J">Information Processing Letters</venue><doi>10.1016/0020-0190(93)90115-P</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.59193">Cut</keyword><keyword weight="0.46088">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.46815">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.64502">Line graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.62963">Constraint graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.60575">Hypergraph</keyword><keyword weight="0.64802">Minimum cut</keyword><keyword weight="0.6001">Graph partition</keyword><keyword weight="0.40227">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.62425">Maximum cut</keyword><keyword weight="0.64966">Complement graph</keyword></keywords><publisher>Elsevier North-Holland, Inc.</publisher><abstract>An elegant and general way to apply graph partitioning algorithms to hypergraphs would be to model hypergraphs by graphs and apply the graph algorithms to these models. Of course such models have to simulate the given hypergraphs with respect to their cut :[42],"edge-weighted graph (V, E) is a cut-model for an :[42],"edge-weighted hypergraph (V, H) if the weight of the edges cut by any bipartition of V in the graph is the same as the weight of the hyperedges cut by the same bipartition in the hypergraph. We show that there is no cut-model in :[96],"we examine whether the addition of dummy vertices helps: An :[42],"edge-weighted graph (V ∪ D, E) is a mincut-model for an :[42],"edge-weighted hypergraph (V, H) if the weight of the hyperedges cut by a bipartition of the hypergraphs vertices is the same as the weight of a minimum cut separating the two parts in the graph. We construct such models using positive and negative weights. On the other hand, :[96],"we show that there is no mincut-model in general if only positive weights are allowed.</abstract></paper>