<paper id="1499561572"><title>Fundamental Principles of Deception in Genetic Search</title><year>1991</year><authors><author org="Department of Computer Science, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, Colorado#TAB#" id="1911861534">L. Darrell Whitley</author></authors><n_citation>213</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>64702643</reference><reference>141541527</reference><reference>1485961250</reference><reference>1496027058</reference><reference>1496327969</reference><reference>1568834902</reference><reference>1606791384</reference><reference>1639032689</reference><reference>1967093065</reference><reference>1979951029</reference><reference>2156728410</reference><reference>2726121458</reference></references><venue id="1159491267" type="C">Foundations of Genetic Algorithms</venue><doi>10.1016/B978-0-08-050684-5.50017-3</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.41997">Attractor</keyword><keyword weight="0.44638">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.54289">Deception</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Global optimum</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Function optimization</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Genetic search</keyword><keyword weight="0.45949">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.44216">Hyperplane</keyword><keyword weight="0.51952">Genetic algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.42689">Binary number</keyword></keywords><publisher>Elsevier</publisher><abstract>Abstract This paper presents several theorems concerning the nature of deception and the central role that deception plays in function optimization using genetic algorithms. A simple proof is offered which shows that the only problems which pose challenging optimization tasks are problems that involve some degree of deception and which result in conflicting k-arm bandit competitions between hyperplanes. The concept of a deceptive attractor is introduced and shown to be more general than the deceptive optimum found in the deceptive functions that have been constructed to date. Also introduced are the concepts of fully deceptive problems as well as less strict consistently deceptive problems. A proof is given showing that deceptive attractors must have a complementary bit pattern to that found in the binary representation of the global optimum if a function is to be either fully deceptive or consistently deceptive. Some empirical results are presented which demonstrate different methods of dealing with deception and poor linkage during genetic search.</abstract></paper>