<paper id="1577832266"><title>On the Feasibility of Informative Answers</title><year>1981</year><authors><author org="Hochschule der Bundeswehr München" id="2712488520">Jürgen M. Janas</author></authors><n_citation>18</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>88272009</reference><reference>1491698028</reference><reference>1519444349</reference><reference>1530765221</reference><reference>1532343648</reference><reference>1750334971</reference><reference>1849286993</reference><reference>2047499522</reference><reference>2085772207</reference><reference>2105486835</reference><reference>2137603007</reference><reference>2138709157</reference><reference>2165467455</reference><reference>2293634425</reference></references><venue id="" type="">Advances in Data Base Theory</venue><doi>10.1007/978-1-4615-8297-7_14</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.57373">Relational calculus</keyword><keyword weight="0.4575">Information retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.45545">Confidentiality</keyword><keyword weight="0.51476">Inference</keyword><keyword weight="0.45852">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.55084">Data integrity</keyword><keyword weight="0.49411">Formal methods</keyword><keyword weight="0.52737">Closed-world assumption</keyword><keyword weight="0.41562">Computation</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Boston, MA</publisher><abstract>In this chapter, we investigate the situation where a user’s request for data cannot be answered in the desired way because the data base does not contain the data requested. We argue that in such a situation it is not sufficient to report to the user the fact that the query failed, without providing the deeper reasons for the failure; an informative answer to a failing query, however, will adjust the user’s wrong assumptions about the contents of the data base and often will free him/her from the need of asking additional queries. We describe a formal method by means of which the reasons for the failure of a user’s query expressed in a relational calculus based language may be inferred and reported to the user as answer; special attention is paid to the amount of computation required for this answer generation procedure. We then show that a wide class of integrity constraints of a data base may be used to further improve the inference process and that any abuse of informative answers for the deduction of confidential information may be prevented easily.</abstract></paper>