<paper id="1980813849"><title>Out of scandinavia: alternative approaches to software design and system development</title><year>1989</year><authors><author org="Technische Universit채t Berlin, Berlin, Federal Republic of Germany" id="2138882956">Christiane Floyd</author><author org="Technische Universit채t Berlin, Berlin, Federal Republic of Germany" id="2054622882">Wolf-Michael Mehl</author><author org="Technische Universit채t Berlin, Berlin, Federal Republic of Germany" id="1985211160">Fanny-Michaela Reisin</author><author org="Technische Universit채t Berlin, Berlin, Federal Republic of Germany" id="2577261182">Gerhard Schmidt</author><author org="" id="2098416475">Gregor Wolf</author></authors><n_citation>211</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1557942541</reference><reference>1895273801</reference><reference>2016636471</reference><reference>2031542183</reference><reference>2044793135</reference><reference>2119490533</reference><reference>2166854582</reference><reference>2172227054</reference></references><venue id="2481449237" type="J">Human-Computer Interaction</venue><doi>10.1207/s15327051hci0404_1</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.52457">Software design</keyword><keyword weight="0.42862">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.60833">Design technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.48884">Democratization</keyword><keyword weight="0.47505">Sociocultural evolution</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">System development</keyword><keyword weight="0.50742">TRIPS architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.47183">Management science</keyword></keywords><publisher>L. Erlbaum Associates Inc.</publisher><abstract>This study set out to delineate the Scandinavian Approach to the development of computer-based systems. We aimed to help derive new ideas for human-oriented technology design in other countries. The study is based on the relevant literature, scientific contacts, and two field trips, and covers work in Denmark, Norway, and study :[50],"focuses on methodological questions and their theoretical foundations, on explicit strategies for social implementation, and on innovative design illustrated by reference to concrete projects. Though it makes no claim to present a sociopolitical analysis of Scandinavian technology design, the sociocultural background is given due is no :[96],"general agreement among Scandinavians as to whether or not there is a well-defined Scandinavian Approach. We have come to identify such an approach in certain common features shared by the different schools of thought. These include efforts toward humanization and democratization as overriding design goals, in keeping with the aim of building an egalitarian society.</abstract></paper>