<paper id="1543672175"><title>Electronic mail as a medium for rich communication: an empirical investigation using hermeneutic interpretation</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="Association for Information Systems" id="2158578300">Allen S. Lee</author></authors><n_citation>627</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1483988052</reference><reference>1586673878</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/249762</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.53207">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.4376">Corporation</keyword><keyword weight="0.51021">Appropriation</keyword><keyword weight="0.43217">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.54241">Media richness theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.58168">Organizational communication</keyword><keyword weight="0.46957">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.4821">Rational planning model</keyword><keyword weight="0.4582">Social constructionism</keyword><keyword weight="0.44915">Hermeneutics</keyword><keyword weight="0.44753">Management science</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>This study provides an account of how richness occurs in communication that uses electronic mail. In examining actual e-mail exchanged among managers in a corporation, the study interprets the managerial use of the communication medium of electronic mail as the users themselves understand and experience it. Employing the research approach of interpretivism in general and hermeneutics in particular, the study finds that richness or leanness is not an inherent property of the electronic-mail medium, but an emergent property of the interaction of the electronic-mail medium with its organizational context, where the interaction is described in terms of distanciation, autonomization, social construction, appropriation, and enactment.Conclusions and recommendations are that managers who receive e-mail are not passive recipients of data, but active producers of meaning; that the best or just an appropriate communication medium is not determined through an individual manageru0027s exercise of rational decision making, but emerges as best or appropriate over time, over the course of the mediumu0027s interactions with many users; that systems professionals need to treat the managerial user of an e-mail system not merely as a client of information services, but also as a processor or co-processor to be integrated into the system design; and that information systems researchers need to dedicate attention to the actual processes by which the users of communication medium come to understand themselves, their own use of the medium, and their organizational context.</abstract></paper>