<paper id="1981407462"><title>Applying participatory design and collaboration in digital public services for discovering and re-designing e-Government services</title><year>2007</year><authors><author org="Department of Informatics Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Greece" id="2083209772">Leo G. Anthopoulos</author><author org="Department of Informatics Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Greece" id="1991623872">Panagiotis Siozos</author><author org="Department of Informatics Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Greece" id="1026700288">Ioannis A. Tsoukalas</author></authors><n_citation>128</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1548983485</reference><reference>1981405649</reference><reference>1984200150</reference><reference>2026466478</reference><reference>2063697083</reference><reference>2091793080</reference><reference>2114498878</reference><reference>2145277440</reference><reference>2152328567</reference><reference>2153496902</reference><reference>2160196038</reference></references><venue id="201710173" type="J">Government Information Quarterly</venue><doi>10.1016/j.giq.2006.07.018</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.61055">Services computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.39571">Economics</keyword><keyword weight="0.52704">Participatory design</keyword><keyword weight="0.4892">Computer-supported cooperative work</keyword><keyword weight="0.47265">Public relations</keyword><keyword weight="0.46939">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.4609">Exploit</keyword><keyword weight="0.49087">Citizen journalism</keyword><keyword weight="0.48139">Web service</keyword><keyword weight="0.50426">Strategic planning</keyword><keyword weight="0.454">Politics</keyword></keywords><publisher>JAI</publisher><abstract>Abstract E-Government projects are currently service oriented, focusing on the implementation and diffusion of digital public services through one-stop points of access for citizens. E-Government strategic plans are political, directed at cost and time minimization during the execution of public services, and they do not take into account citizen needs or public administration operating procedures. Although these plans have led to the development of projects that have succeeded in cost and time savings for both citizens and public administration, surveys conducted around the world show that users evaluate digital public services and do not hesitate to return to traditional methods rather than using digital channels to transact with the public administration again; neither would they recommend the use of digital services to others. This article presents collaborative and participatory tools and methods designed to exploit the knowledge and experience of public servants in the improvement and execution of custom and non-automated public services. Collaborative tools can succeed in the development of real one-stop shops for e-Government, while on the other hand they can encourage both citizens and civil servants to participate in the e-Government era.</abstract></paper>