<paper id="1515365342"><title>MIS project teams: an investigation of cognitive style implications</title><year>1984</year><authors><author org="The University of North Carolina Greensboro, North Carolina" id="2136727569">Kathy Brittain White</author></authors><n_citation>89</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1531486736</reference><reference>1564930140</reference><reference>1565820044</reference><reference>1574834327</reference><reference>1734084043</reference><reference>1982272301</reference><reference>2096317043</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/249346</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.48937">Human resource management</keyword><keyword weight="0.47505">Human resources</keyword><keyword weight="0.62129">Project management 2.0</keyword><keyword weight="0.40852">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46433">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.62109">Project management triangle</keyword><keyword weight="0.70216">Project team</keyword><keyword weight="0.44747">Management science</keyword><keyword weight="0.44494">Scrutiny</keyword><keyword weight="0.52413">Cognitive style</keyword><keyword weight="0.47983">Personality</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>A profusion of technology is insufficient to implement effective computer systems without the full utilization of human resources to develop such systems. The issue of fully developing and utilizing available human resources is currently receiving careful scrutiny in the MIS :[40],"methodology for fully utilizing human resources has been maximizing productivity by stressing team effort. This research focuses on evaluating the systems development activities of two MIS project teams. Empirical evidence was gathered from interviews with MIS personnel and key users concerning strengths/weaknesses of the two project teams. Analysis was performed to determine the personality characteristics (as measured by the Myers-Briggs Type Indicator) of the MIS :[106],"results of this analysis indicated a void of certain personality styles in project team one. This void correlated with weaknesses ascertained from the interview data for project team one. Project team two, with all four personality types represented, was evaluated as very successful. Recommendations are made for assembling project teams based on these findings.</abstract></paper>