<paper id="1967977479"><title>Goal-oriented specification of adaptation requirements engineering in adaptive systems</title><year>2006</year><authors><author org="Michigan State University , East Lansing, Michigan" id="2492885994">Greg Brown</author><author org="Michigan State University , East Lansing, Michigan" id="2116990958">Betty H. C. Cheng</author><author org="Michigan State University , East Lansing, Michigan" id="211901146">Heather Goldsby</author><author org="Michigan State University , East Lansing, Michigan" id="2610681562">Ji Zhang</author></authors><n_citation>39</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1661159357</reference><reference>1988394140</reference><reference>2017739343</reference><reference>2045521911</reference><reference>2057807303</reference><reference>2062987034</reference><reference>2104493538</reference><reference>2117818414</reference><reference>2118926712</reference><reference>2138876988</reference><reference>2155386176</reference><reference>2157293983</reference><reference>2164527006</reference><reference>2166099324</reference><reference>2168029386</reference><reference>2177007941</reference></references><venue id="" type="">Proceedings of the 2006 international workshop on Self-adaptation and self-managing systems</venue><doi>10.1145/1137677.1137682</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.4789">Autonomic computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.47501">Software engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.58743">Adaptive system</keyword><keyword weight="0.46625">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.56822">Requirements engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.61985">Formal specification</keyword><keyword weight="0.63502">KAOS</keyword><keyword weight="0.46875">Software</keyword><keyword weight="0.46157">Adaptive behavior</keyword><keyword weight="0.5006">Semantics</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>Adaptive software is being used increasingly frequently by various users, such as the medical community, software industry, and in response to terror attacks. Therefore, understanding the requirements of an adaptive system is crucial to developing them correctly. Developers need to be able to reason about the requirements of a systemu0027s adaptive behavior. Adaptation semantics are intended to describe how systems behave during adaptation. Previously, Zhang and Cheng formally specified three commonly occurring adaptation semantics in terms of Adapt operator-extended LTL (A-LTL). This paper presents goal-oriented specifications of these three adaptation semantics. These specifications, specified with the KAOS methodology, provide a graphical wrapper to the formal A-LTL specifications of the semantics. The combination of the goal-oriented, graphical KAOS specifications and A-LTL specifications provides the benefits of formal specifications as well as the benefits of an easier to understand, graphical, and more intuitive presentation of adaptive systems requirements. This work also provides a means to incorporate the adaptation semantics into the goal-oriented requirements specifications of an adaptive system.</abstract></paper>