<paper id="1554384670"><title>Modeling Behavior of Geographic Objects: An Experience with the Object Modeling Technique</title><year>1997</year><authors><author org="University of Maine." id="306216343">Nectaria Tryfona</author><author org="University of Maine." id="2301663918">Dieter Pfoser</author><author org="Univ. of Patras#TAB#" id="2953935443">Thanasis Hadzilacos</author></authors><n_citation>24</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1583169995</reference><reference>1585704552</reference><reference>1849301553</reference><reference>1968945891</reference><reference>1996508268</reference><reference>1996759815</reference><reference>2060849841</reference><reference>2122534638</reference><reference>2131153442</reference></references><venue id="1134069326" type="C">Conference on Advanced Information Systems Engineering</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-63107-0_25</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.52112">Geographic information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.45396">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.48609">Conceptual design</keyword><keyword weight="0.48">Notation</keyword><keyword weight="0.57735">Object-modeling technique</keyword><keyword weight="0.45071">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.63788">Object model</keyword><keyword weight="0.53312">Semantic interoperability</keyword><keyword weight="0.6491">Object-based spatial database</keyword><keyword weight="0.49246">Semantics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Behavior of geographic objects holds a critical role in spatial databases. This, along with objectsu0027 position and space-varying attributes form a minimal set of concepts sufficient to capture spatial peculiarities in terms of the object-oriented rationale. We present the semantics and the graphical notation of a prototypical object-oriented model for the conceptual design of spatial databases: by extending the Object Model of the Object Modeling Technique to the Geographic Object Model, we show how the above three concepts fit naturally into any objectoriented tool. We augment this model with the constructs of spatial aggregation and spatial grouping to express the critical aspects of space-varying attributes, object boundary fuzziness and uncertainty, spatial relationships, and attribute generalization. Our proposal integrates the field- and object-based geographic views in one model. The principal idea behind this effort is the incorporation of a set of concepts into any semantic or object-oriented model in order to make them communicate at the conceptual level (semantic interoperability).</abstract></paper>