<paper id="1935088456"><title>Testing Probabilistic and Nondeterministic Processes</title><year>1992</year><authors><author org="Department of Computer Sciences, Chalmers University of Technology, 412 96, Göteborg, Sweden. Tel: 46-31-7721018" id="2124415778">Wang Yi</author><author org="Department of Mathematics and Computer Science, Aalborg University, 9220 Aalborg 0, Denmark. Tel 45-98158522" id="2146581609">Kim Guldstrand Larsen</author></authors><n_citation>120</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>2130773382</reference><reference>2137865376</reference><reference>2157144873</reference></references><venue id="" type="">Proceedings of the IFIP TC6/WG6.1 Twelth International Symposium on Protocol Specification, Testing and Verification XII</venue><doi>10.1016/B978-0-444-89874-6.50010-6</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46663">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.58013">Nondeterministic algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.47057">Operator (computer programming)</keyword><keyword weight="0.47868">Probabilistic logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.41779">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.44642">Binary number</keyword></keywords><publisher>North-Holland Publishing Co.</publisher><abstract>Abstract In this paper, we extend Milneru0027s CCS with a binary stochastic choice operator, ⊕p indexed with a probability p ∈]0, 1[to model probabilistic and nondeterministic processes. Intuitively, P ⊕p Q may move to P immediately with probability p, written P ⊗ p Q ⟶ e p P , , or to Q with probability 1 – p. Based on de Nicola and Hennessyu0027s testing [NH84], a theory of testing is proposed. Given a process P and a test T, we define a notion of P can pass T with a set of probabilities φ(P,T). For non-probabilistic processes and tests (e.g. written in CCS), it turns out that P must satisfy T when inf{φ(P,T)} = 1 and P may satisfy T when sup{φ(P,T)} = 1, where may satisfy and must satisfy are the two satisfaction relations between processes and tests due to de Nicola and Hennessy. In terms of φ(P,T), three testing preorders are defined, which in turn generalize Nicola-Hennessyu0027s may, must and test preorders to probabilistic and nondeterministic processes. Finally, as an example, a simple communication protocol is described and proved to behave like a one-place buffer.</abstract></paper>