<paper id="1880174920"><title>Why does a GSS fail to enhance group consensus and satisfaction? An investigation from an influence process perspective</title><year>1997</year><authors><author org="Department of Information Systems and Computer Science, National University of Singapore, Singapore," id="2937823502">W. Huang</author><author org="Department ofInformation Systems and Computer Science, National university of Singapore/2DePartment of Information S?stems, City University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong" id="2091071396">K.K. Wei</author><author org="Department ofInformation Systems and Computer Science, National university of Singapore" id="2403661337">C.Y. Tan</author><author org="Department ofInformation Systems and Computer Science, National university of Singapore" id="2152339489">K.S. Raman</author></authors><n_citation>7</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1489939810</reference><reference>1527944521</reference><reference>1549595874</reference><reference>1554753965</reference><reference>1578743203</reference><reference>1995864118</reference><reference>2047085612</reference><reference>2118612095</reference><reference>2159771480</reference><reference>2166484208</reference></references><venue id="1164519180" type="C">Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences</venue><doi>10.1109/HICSS.1997.665466</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Computer support</keyword><keyword weight="0.54492">Normative social influence</keyword><keyword weight="0.52798">Task analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Support system</keyword><keyword weight="0.37859">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.40986">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.47157">Variables</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Decision process</keyword><keyword weight="0.39186">Management science</keyword><keyword weight="0.43215">Offset (computer science)</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>Literature review shows that a group support system (GSS) generally fails to increase group consensus and satisfaction. The reasons for this failure are not fully known. This research investigates this issue from an influence process perspective. The independent variables were support (computer support versus non-computer support) and task type (intellective task versus preference task). The dependent variables were three influence process variables (informational influence, normative influence, and influence distribution) and three outcome variables (consensus, decision satisfaction, and decision process satisfaction). The findings suggest that the failure, from the influence process perspective, may be attributed to the offset effect of GSS. In the preference task, the increased part of group consensus and satisfaction, due to the GSS increased influence distribution balance, were offset at the same time by the decreased part, due to the GSS attenuated normative influence. Likewise, in the intellective task, the increased part of consensus and satisfaction, due to the GSS enhanced informational influence, were offset at the same time by the decreased part, due to the GSS decreased influence distribution balance. The implications for the offset effect is discussed.</abstract></paper>