<paper id="1524627302"><title>Collaborative activity and technological design: task coordination in London underground control rooms</title><year>1991</year><authors><author org="United Kingdom#TAB#" id="2122916519">Christian Heath</author><author org="United Kingdom#TAB#" id="2028577324">Paul Luff</author></authors><n_citation>304</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>117491099</reference><reference>1582925061</reference><reference>1895273801</reference><reference>1970110819</reference><reference>1971578604</reference><reference>1979618830</reference><reference>1991378280</reference><reference>2028945165</reference><reference>2079578564</reference><reference>2159397557</reference></references><venue id="1180389419" type="C">European Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work</venue><doi>10.1007/978-94-011-3506-1_5</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47649">Situated</keyword><keyword weight="0.46923">Interpersonal communication</keyword><keyword weight="0.55795">Computer-supported cooperative work</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Cooperative work</keyword><keyword weight="0.42157">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46577">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.44602">Human–computer interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.45698">Control room</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Work practice</keyword></keywords><publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher><abstract>Despite technical advances in CSCW over the past few years we still have relatively little understanding of the organisation of collaborative activity in real world, technologically supported, work environments. Indeed, it has been suggested that the failure of various technological applications may derive from its relative insensitivity to ordinary work practice and situated conduct. In this paper we discuss the possibility of utilising recent developments within social science, and in particular the naturalistic analysis of organisational conduct and interpersonal communication, as a basis for the design and development of tools and technologies to support collaborative work. Focussing on the Line Control Rooms on London Underground, a complex multimedia environment in transition, we begin to explicate the informal work practices and procedures whereby personnel systematically communicate information and coordinate a disparate collection of tasks and activities. These empirical investigations form the foundation to the design of new tools to support collaborative work in Line Control Rooms; technologies which will be sensitive to the ordinary conduct and practical skills of organisational personnel in the London Underground.</abstract></paper>