<paper id="1573918274"><title>Natural Language Assistant: A Dialog System for Online Product Recommendation</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="" id="2144944523">Joyce Yue Chai</author><author org="" id="2711407401">Veronika Horvath</author><author org="" id="1978991732">Nicolas Nicolov</author><author org="" id="2974847127">Margo Stys</author><author org="" id="264588417">Nanda Kambhatla</author><author org="" id="2047110219">Wlodek Zadrozny</author><author org="" id="2073846700">Prem Melville</author></authors><n_citation>39</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1546282236</reference><reference>1571763272</reference><reference>2005850841</reference><reference>2063443135</reference><reference>2069912724</reference><reference>2105256590</reference><reference>2141839844</reference><reference>2145618437</reference><reference>2153439141</reference><reference>2154267140</reference></references><venue id="163019073" type="J">Ai Magazine</venue><doi>10.1609/aimag.v23i2.1641</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.48825">IBM</keyword><keyword weight="0.48179">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.4556">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.53759">Information access</keyword><keyword weight="0.59865">Natural language user interface</keyword><keyword weight="0.5301">Natural language</keyword><keyword weight="0.56978">Information extraction</keyword><keyword weight="0.4314">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.51063">Business requirements</keyword><keyword weight="0.63161">Dialog system</keyword><keyword weight="0.49976">Statistical parsing</keyword></keywords><publisher /><abstract>With the emergence of electronic-commerce systems, successful information access on electroniccommerce web sites becomes essential. Menu-driven navigation and keyword search currently provided by most commercial sites have considerable limitations because they tend to overwhelm and frustrate users with lengthy, rigid, and ineffective interactions. To provide an efficient solution for information access, we have built the NATURAL language ASSISTANT (NLA), a web-based natural language dialog system to help users find relevant products on electronic-commerce sites. The system brings together technologies in natural language processing and human-computer interaction to create a faster and more intuitive way of interacting with web sites. By combining statistical parsing techniques with traditional AI rule-based technology, we have created a dialog system that accommodates both customer needs and business requirements. The system is currently embedded in an application for recommending laptops and was deployed as a pilot on IBMu0027s web site.</abstract></paper>