<paper id="1578152642"><title>Efficient System Modeling for Complex Real-Time Industrial Networks using the ACCORD/UML Methodology</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="LETI-DEIN - CEA/Saclay" id="2811282564">S. Gérard</author><author org="Intracom S.A.#TAB#" id="2973701847">Nikos S. Voros</author><author org="Intracom S.A.#TAB#" id="2675963964">Chris Koulamas</author><author org="LETI-DEIN - CEA/Saclay" id="1630443851">François Terrier</author></authors><n_citation>21</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1555104057</reference><reference>1560587131</reference><reference>1582068322</reference><reference>2130521512</reference></references><venue id="" type="">DIPES '00 Proceedings of the IFIP WG10.3/WG10.4/WG10.5 International Workshop on Distributed and Parallel Embedded Systems: Architecture and Design of Distributed Embedded Systems</venue><doi>10.1007/978-0-387-35409-5_2</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.53821">Active object</keyword><keyword weight="0.4751">Software engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.51757">Object-oriented programming</keyword><keyword weight="0.66801">UML tool</keyword><keyword weight="0.4546">Systems engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.52741">Unified Modeling Language</keyword><keyword weight="0.48577">Data sharing</keyword><keyword weight="0.73808">Applications of UML</keyword><keyword weight="0.39039">Engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.51372">Human multitasking</keyword><keyword weight="0.50465">Time to market</keyword></keywords><publisher>Kluwer, B.V.</publisher><abstract>Engineers are more and more often faced to the hard problem of developing more sophisticated real-time systems in a world where time to market constraints are constantly increasing. Object oriented modelling with UML brings significant answers to these issues. However, the real-time behavior specification of an application is not yet completely satisfying. Available methods provide a good support for parallelism modelling of an application but are often poor to express real-time features like deadlines, periods and priorities. In this paper, we present a specific UML use supporting qualitative (e.g. multitasking, data sharing, etc) and quantitative (e.g. deadline, period, etc) aspects of real-time behavioral specification. For that purpose, we introduce the concept of the UML active object and present a structured way to use UML Statecharts in order to describe the behavior of an active object without losing any object properties.</abstract></paper>