<paper id="1525935082"><title>Reasoning about Probabilistic Lossy Channel Systems</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org=", Uppsala University," id="1952177885">Parosh Aziz Abdulla</author><author org="&quot;University of Bonn&quot;" id="2163680003">Christel Baier</author><author org="North-Carolina State University" id="2156495138">S. Purushothaman Iyer</author><author org=", Uppsala University," id="2285498729">Bengt Jonsson</author></authors><n_citation>32</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1561838634</reference><reference>2017872109</reference><reference>2025970201</reference><reference>2035721896</reference><reference>2123160677</reference><reference>2166870727</reference></references><venue id="1145706541" type="C">International Conference on Concurrency Theory</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-44618-4_24</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44584">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.52954">Markov process</keyword><keyword weight="0.50962">Lossy compression</keyword><keyword weight="0.42819">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48708">Correctness</keyword><keyword weight="0.51529">Markov chain</keyword><keyword weight="0.44643">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.52133">Decidability</keyword><keyword weight="0.52072">Reachability problem</keyword><keyword weight="0.53526">Probabilistic logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.51666">Undecidable problem</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We consider the problem of deciding whether an infinite-state system (expressed as a Markov chain) satisfies a correctness property with probability 1. This problem is, of course, undecidable for general infinite-state systems. We focus our attention on the model of probabilistic lossy channel systems consisting of finite-state processes that communicating over unbounded lossy FIFO channels. Abdulla and Jonsson have shown that safety properties are decidable while progress properties are not for non-probabilistic lossy channel systems. Under assumptions of "sufficiently high" probability of loss, Baier and Engelen have shown how to check whether a property holds of probabilistic lossy channel system with probability :[102],"this paper we show that the problem of checking whether a progress property holds with probability 1 is undecidable, if the assumption about "sufficiently high" probability of loss is omitted. More surprisingly, we show that checking whether safety properties hold with probability 1 is undecidable too. Our proof depends upon simulating a perfect channel, with a high degree of confidence, using lossy channels.</abstract></paper>