<paper id="1493062108"><title>A Chosen-Plaintext Linear Attack on DES</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="University of Bergen" id="2035224540">Lars R. Knudsen</author><author org="University of Bergen" id="2034430715">John Erik Mathiassen</author></authors><n_citation>49</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>380217570</reference><reference>1537206908</reference><reference>1542500920</reference><reference>1553753418</reference><reference>1964723977</reference><reference>2027588622</reference><reference>2057524374</reference><reference>2099473571</reference></references><venue id="2758283624" type="C">Fast Software Encryption</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-44706-7_18</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.58094">Key space</keyword><keyword weight="0.58835">Watermarking attack</keyword><keyword weight="0.41221">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.41576">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.4">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.61761">Interpolation attack</keyword><keyword weight="0.42571">Arithmetic</keyword><keyword weight="0.60867">XSL attack</keyword><keyword weight="0.63574">Chosen-ciphertext attack</keyword><keyword weight="0.61964">Slide attack</keyword><keyword weight="0.6224">Ciphertext-only attack</keyword><keyword weight="0.57078">Key size</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In this paper we consider a chosen-plaintext variant of the linear attack on DES introduced by Matsui. By choosing plaintexts in a clever way one can reduce the number of plaintexts required in a successful linear attack. This reduces the amount of plaintexts to find key bits to a factor of more than four compared to Matsuiu0027s attack. To estimate the probabilities of success in the attack we did extensive experiments on DES reduced to 8 and 12 rounds. We believe that the results in this paper contain the fastest attack on the DES reported so far in the open literature. As an example, one attack needs about 242 chosen texts, finds 12 bits of key information and succeeds with a probability of about 86%. An additional 12 key bits can be found by similar methods. For comparison, Matsuiu0027s attack on the DES needs about 244 known texts, finds 13 bits of the key and succeeds with a probability of 78%. Of independent interest is a new approach searching for "pseudo-keys", which are secret key bits added an unknown but fixed value. These bits can be used to find the secret key bits at a later stage in the analysis.</abstract></paper>