<paper id="1504543534"><title>Off-Line Electronic Cash Based on Secret-Key Certificates</title><year>1995</year><authors><author org="CWI" id="2804674709">Stefan A. Brands</author></authors><n_citation>35</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>14282859</reference><reference>1482004896</reference><reference>1483083484</reference><reference>1484557542</reference><reference>1493020827</reference><reference>1511288679</reference><reference>1521562196</reference><reference>1535861450</reference><reference>1554259298</reference><reference>1555822216</reference><reference>1570307720</reference><reference>1571236476</reference><reference>1579851288</reference><reference>1586351688</reference><reference>1589034595</reference><reference>1594128832</reference><reference>1601001795</reference><reference>1608886058</reference><reference>1610603564</reference><reference>1882430379</reference><reference>1970606468</reference><reference>1979215153</reference><reference>2076158628</reference><reference>2095708839</reference><reference>2142968417</reference><reference>2153193245</reference></references><venue id="1133508372" type="C">Latin American Symposium on Theoretical Informatics</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-59175-3_86</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.43683">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.43584">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.52473">Electronic cash</keyword><keyword weight="0.47881">Smart card</keyword><keyword weight="0.44232">Probability distribution</keyword><keyword weight="0.44943">Payment</keyword><keyword weight="0.55776">Public-key cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.64791">Blind signature</keyword><keyword weight="0.44683">Cash</keyword><keyword weight="0.50503">Certificate</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>An off-line electronic coin system is presented that offers multi-party security and unconditional privacy of payments. The system improves significantly on the efficiency of the previously most efficient such system known in the literature, due to application of a recently proposed technique called secret-key certificates. By definition of secret-key certificates, pairs consisting of a public key and a matching certificate can be simulated with indistinguishable probability distribution. This allows a variety of polynomial-time reductions from a well-known signature scheme to the cash system. In particular, the withdrawal protocol can be proved to be restrictive blind with respect to one account holder, relying only on a standard intractability assumption; no such result has been proved before in the literature. Another consequence of the application of the secret-key certificate technique is that the withdrawal protocol is not a blind signature issuing protocol. This falsifies the popular belief that efficient privacy-protecting off-line electronic cash systems must be based on withdrawal protocols that are blind signature issuing protocols.</abstract></paper>