<paper id="1547665694"><title>Optimal reductions between oblivious transfers using interactive hashing</title><year>2006</year><authors><author org="McGill University, Montéral, QC, Canada#TAB#" id="2293660417">Claude Crépeau</author><author org="McGill University, Montéral, QC, Canada#TAB#" id="1207234522">George Savvides</author></authors><n_citation>31</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1577870632</reference><reference>1584785281</reference><reference>1958037614</reference><reference>1987667503</reference><reference>1997590300</reference><reference>2007661134</reference><reference>2016443801</reference><reference>2045234394</reference><reference>2049198367</reference><reference>2123789695</reference><reference>2134238617</reference><reference>2154300278</reference></references><venue id="1140213147" type="C">Theory and Application of Cryptographic Techniques</venue><doi>10.1007/11761679_13</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.51506">Cryptographic protocol</keyword><keyword weight="0.43898">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.44932">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.61025">K-independent hashing</keyword><keyword weight="0.59312">Hash function</keyword><keyword weight="0.59983">Consistent hashing</keyword><keyword weight="0.57288">2-choice hashing</keyword><keyword weight="0.62401">Dynamic perfect hashing</keyword><keyword weight="0.59287">Oblivious transfer</keyword><keyword weight="0.62514">Linear hashing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We present an asymptotically optimal reduction of one-out-of-two String Oblivious Transfer to one-out-of-two Bit Oblivious Transfer using Interactive Hashing in conjunction with Privacy Amplification. Interactive Hashing is used in an innovative way to test the receiveru0027s adherence to the protocol. We show that (1 + e)k uses of Bit OT suffice to implement String OT for k-bit strings. Our protocol represents a two-fold improvement over the best constructions in the literature and is asymptotically optimal. We then show that our construction can also accommodate weaker versions of Bit OT, thereby obtaining a significantly lower expansion factor compared to previous constructions. Besides increasing efficiency, our constructions allow the use of any 2-universal family of Hash Functions for performing Privacy Amplification. Of independent interest, our reduction illustrates the power of Interactive Hashing as an ingredient in the design of cryptographic protocols.</abstract></paper>