<paper id="1491461849"><title>On liveness preservation by composition of nets via a set of places</title><year>1990</year><authors><author org="Institut National des Télécommunications" id="2250290439">Younes Souissi</author></authors><n_citation>44</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1510345036</reference><reference>1513219382</reference><reference>1819916734</reference><reference>2106001218</reference><reference>2130638542</reference><reference>2179661259</reference></references><venue id="1204434967" type="C">Applications and Theory of Petri Nets</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0019979</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.40746">Monotonic function</keyword><keyword weight="0.41769">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.61914">Petri net</keyword><keyword weight="0.41764">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47413">Finite-state machine</keyword><keyword weight="0.41162">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.66661">Liveness</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In this article, we define classes of Petri nets for which the composition via a set of places preserves liveness. The new notion on which the definition of these classes is based is F-monotonicity. F-monotonicity is a property which refines liveness monotonicity. F-robust nets are defined as nets which are insensitive to some modification of a weighted amount of tokens (marking of places P). A net which can be composed with an F-robust net on P, and which respects the degree of non-sensitivity of the F-robust net is said to be a non-disturbing net with regard to the F-robust net. Nets for which Commoneru0027s property is a necessary and sufficient condition of liveness are shown to be F-robust. Nets with output places are also F-robust nets. The composition of an F-robust net with a non-disturbing net is shown to preserve liveness. F-strong nets constitute another class of nets that we can compose while preserving liveness. State machines are F-strong nets.</abstract></paper>