<paper id="1590482807"><title>Justifying electronic banking network expansion using real options analysis</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="Whitman School of Management" id="224258226">Michel Benaroch</author><author org="University of Minnesota" id="2186337131">Robert J. Kauffman</author></authors><n_citation>279</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>908949</reference><reference>1600826652</reference><reference>2099840395</reference><reference>2156284882</reference><reference>2163315205</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/3250936</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Electronic banking</keyword><keyword weight="0.46226">Actuarial science</keyword><keyword weight="0.44116">Software deployment</keyword><keyword weight="0.44184">Structured interview</keyword><keyword weight="0.44336">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.49614">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.46366">Operations research</keyword><keyword weight="0.45036">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.47683">Senior management</keyword><keyword weight="0.56455">Black–Scholes model</keyword><keyword weight="0.48718">Operationalization</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Network expansion</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>The application of real options analysis to information technology investment evaluation problems recently has been proposed in the IS literature (Chalasani et al. 1997; Dos Santos 1991; Kambil et al. 1993; Kumar 1996; Taudes 1998). The research reported on in this paper illustrates the value of applying real options analysis in the context of a case study involving the deployment of point-of-sale (POS) debit services by the Yankee 24 shared electronic banking network of New England. In the course of so doing, the paper also attempts to operationalize real options analysis concepts by examining claimed strengths of this analysis approach and balancing them against methodological difficulties that this approach is believed to involve. The research employs a version of the Black-Scholes option pricing model that is adjusted for risk-averse investors, showing how it is possible to obtain reliable values for Yankee 24u0027s "investment timing option," even in the absence of a market to price it. To gather evidence for the existence of the timing option, basic scenario assumptions, and the parameters of the adjusted Black-Scholes model, a structured interview format was developed. The results obtained using real options analysis enabled the networku0027s senior management to identify conditions for which entry into the POS debit market would be profitable. These results also indicated that, in the absence of formal evaluation of the timing option, traditional approaches for evaluating information technology investments would have produced the wrong recommendations.</abstract></paper>