<paper id="1972888601"><title>Toward a Theory of Intrinsically Motivating Instruction</title><year>1981</year><authors><author org="XEROX Palo Alto Research Center, Palo Alto, California#TAB#" id="2016338364">Thomas W. Malone</author></authors><n_citation>1502</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1998696323</reference><reference>2064430731</reference></references><venue id="78735424" type="J">Cognitive Science</venue><doi>10.1207/s15516709cog0504_2</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.49816">Computer-Assisted Instruction</keyword><keyword weight="0.44564">Social psychology</keyword><keyword weight="0.49709">Fantasy</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Intrinsic motivation</keyword><keyword weight="0.56476">Curiosity</keyword><keyword weight="0.47092">Cognitive psychology</keyword><keyword weight="0.44673">Psychology</keyword><keyword weight="0.47753">Teaching method</keyword><keyword weight="0.52211">Cognition</keyword><keyword weight="0.46715">Instrumental and intrinsic value</keyword><keyword weight="0.40339">Randomness</keyword></keywords><publisher>Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, Inc.</publisher><abstract>First, a number of previous theories of intrinsic motivation are reviewed. Then, several studies of highly motivating computer games are described. These studies focus on what makes the games fun, not on what makes them educational. Finally, with this background, a rudimentary theory of intrinsically motivating instruction is developed, based on three categories: challenge, fantasy, and is :[56],"hypothesized to depend on goals with uncertain outcomes. Several ways of making outcomes uncertain are discussed, including variable difficulty level, multiple level goals, hidden information, and randomness. Fantasy is claimed to have both cognitive and emotional advantages in designing instructional environments. A distinction is made between extrinsic fantasies that depend only weakly on the skill used in a game, and intrinsic fantasies that are intimately related to the use of the skill. Curiosity is separated into sensory and cognitive components, and it is suggested that cognitive curiosity can be aroused by making learners believe their knowledge structures are incomplete, inconsistent, or unparsimonious.</abstract></paper>