<paper id="1539444608"><title>Information resource management: a metadata perspective</title><year>1989</year><authors><author org="" id="2974618337">S. T. March</author><author org="" id="2973941007">Y.-G. Kim</author></authors><n_citation>12</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1986644012</reference><reference>2002949243</reference><reference>2038240823</reference><reference>2053495981</reference><reference>2055521902</reference><reference>2120958963</reference></references><venue id="9954729" type="J">Journal of Management Information Systems</venue><doi>10.1080/07421222.1988.11517829</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.68474">Resource management</keyword><keyword weight="0.71189">Metadata repository</keyword><keyword weight="0.67171">Metadata</keyword><keyword weight="0.44207">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.6496">Meta Data Services</keyword><keyword weight="0.46798">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.62145">Data dictionary</keyword><keyword weight="0.64714">Human resource management system</keyword><keyword weight="0.61874">Data management</keyword><keyword weight="0.65789">Metadata management</keyword></keywords><publisher>M. E. Sharpe, Inc.</publisher><abstract>Abstract:While information is recognized as an important corporate resource, its management has not been accomplished to the extent of other major resources. A major reason for this condition is that the information resource is not as well defined as other resources. To manage any resource effectively, the nature of that resource must be well defined. In this article, we first propose a model for corporate data. This model represents the data definition or “metadata” for Information Resource Management (irm). Through this metadata we define the “state” of the information resource. We characterize a set of dimensions for metadata and discuss its representation and management. Concepts from Information Resource Dictionary Systems (irds) are described as they support metadata management. We include irds contents, capabilities, and implementation issues. Finally, we assess the diverse impacts of metadata management on related Information System (is) issues such as end-user computing, corporate is planning, in...</abstract></paper>