<paper id="1540466136"><title>A Framework for Part-of Hierarchies in Terminological Logics</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="Department of Computer and Information science Linköping University, S-58183 Linköping, Sweden" id="1144865590">Lin Padgham</author><author org="Department of Computer and Information science Linköping University, S-58183 Linköping, Sweden" id="226242240">Patrick Lambrix</author></authors><n_citation>37</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>192407326</reference><reference>202363913</reference><reference>1887907765</reference><reference>1982452596</reference><reference>2025559026</reference><reference>2051476306</reference><reference>2078288474</reference></references><venue id="1155137614" type="C">Principles of Knowledge Representation and Reasoning</venue><doi>10.1016/B978-1-4832-1452-8.50140-8</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.61576">Knowledge representation and reasoning</keyword><keyword weight="0.53998">Inference</keyword><keyword weight="0.44091">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Stable states</keyword><keyword weight="0.63283">Commonsense reasoning</keyword><keyword weight="0.41183">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.45051">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.45207">Natural language processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.52306">Logic programming</keyword><keyword weight="0.51694">Hierarchy</keyword></keywords><publisher>Morgan Kaufmann Publishers</publisher><abstract>There is a growing recognition that part-whole hierarchies are a very general form of representation, widely used by humans in commonsense reasoning. This paper develops a terminological logic, and related inference mechanisms for representing and reasoning about composite concepts and individuals. A basic terminological logic language is extended with constructs for describing composite concepts in terms of their parts and the relationships between them. A part-of hierarchy is defined, based on the relationship of compositional inclusion. This part-of hierarchy is analogous to, but different from, the “is-a” hierarchy. Compositional inferencing is defined as a process which infers the existence of a whole, based on the existence of the required parts, where the parts are in the necessary relationship to each other. Three stable states are defined with respect to compositional inferencing - compositional extensions, credulous compositional extensions and skeptical compositional conclusions. This framework significantly enhances and is complementary to, knowledge representation and reasoning based on is-a hierarchies.</abstract></paper>