<paper id="1555229756"><title>An Optimal Automata Approach to LTL Model Checking of Probabilistic Systems</title><year>2003</year><authors><author org="ENS Cachan" id="2074486360">Jean-Michel Couvreur</author><author org="Universite de Bordeaux-I" id="2141321297">Nasser Saheb</author><author org="Universite de Bordeaux-I" id="2090879168">Grégoire Sutre</author></authors><n_citation>48</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>4285094</reference><reference>1491103651</reference><reference>1496256885</reference><reference>1972203711</reference><reference>1988808695</reference><reference>1990609140</reference><reference>2146706022</reference><reference>2165161585</reference></references><venue id="1201110412" type="C">International Conference on Logic Programming</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-39813-4_26</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.65412">Quantum finite automata</keyword><keyword weight="0.44505">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.66542">Automata theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.53105">Model checking</keyword><keyword weight="0.54143">EXPTIME</keyword><keyword weight="0.44089">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.49529">Automaton</keyword><keyword weight="0.45424">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.45889">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.49166">Almost surely</keyword><keyword weight="0.54019">Probabilistic logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.54655">Probabilistic automaton</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Most verification problems on finite systems may be formulated and solved optimally using automata based techniques. Nonetheless LTL verification of (finite) probabilistic systems, i.e. deciding whether a probabilistic system almost surely satisfies an LTL formula, remains one of the few exceptions to this rule. As a matter of fact, existing automata-based solutions to this problem lead to double EXPTIME algorithms, while Courcoubetis and Yannakakis provide an optimal one in single EXPTIME. In this study, we remedy this exception. Our optimal automata based method proceeds in two steps: we present a minimal translation from LTL to ω-automata and point out appropriate properties on these automata; we then show that checking whether a probabilistic system satisfies an ω-automaton with positive probability can be solved in linear time for this kind of automata. Moreover we extend our study to the evaluation of this probability. Finally, we discuss some experimentations with our implementation of these techniques: the ProbaTaf tool.</abstract></paper>