<paper id="1501674746"><title>Development of an Embedded Verifier for Java Card Byte Code Using Formal Methods</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="Gemplus Research Laboratory" id="2713101394">Ludovic Casset</author></authors><n_citation>33</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1489990994</reference><reference>1560655349</reference><reference>1633108902</reference><reference>2012470235</reference><reference>2028327857</reference><reference>2095851537</reference><reference>2096228713</reference><reference>2211336113</reference></references><venue id="1169806927" type="C">Formal Methods</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-45614-7_17</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47364">Programming language</keyword><keyword weight="0.4649">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.63442">Java annotation</keyword><keyword weight="0.62061">Real time Java</keyword><keyword weight="0.51801">Mathematical proof</keyword><keyword weight="0.53753">B-Method</keyword><keyword weight="0.66696">Java Card</keyword><keyword weight="0.63206">Java Modeling Language</keyword><keyword weight="0.6382">Formal methods</keyword><keyword weight="0.59083">Java</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The Java security policy is implemented using security components such as a Java Virtual Machine (JVM), API, verifier, and a loader. It is of prime importance to ensure that these components are implemented in accordance with their specifications. Formal methods can be used to bring the mathematical proof that their implementation corresponds to their specification. In this paper, we introduce the formal development of a complete byte code verifier for Java Card and its on-card integration. In particular, we aim to focus on the model and the proof of the complete type verifier for the Java Card language. The global architecture of the verification process implemented in this real industrial case study is described and the detailed specification of the type verifier is discusses as well as its proof. Moreover, this paper presents a comparison between formal and traditional development, summing up the pros and cons of using formal methods in industry.</abstract></paper>