<paper id="1594239811"><title>Self-Duality of Bounded Monotone Boolean Functions and Related Problems</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="Simon  Fraser University" id="2791047608">Daya Ram Gaur</author><author org="Simon  Fraser University" id="40940245">Ramesh Krishnamurti</author></authors><n_citation>19</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1541296345</reference><reference>1589962235</reference><reference>1594632484</reference><reference>1676134498</reference><reference>1971617887</reference><reference>1972004026</reference><reference>1996070840</reference><reference>2002660979</reference><reference>2023134879</reference><reference>2041324781</reference><reference>2052960791</reference><reference>2065895258</reference><reference>2080947358</reference><reference>2082478577</reference><reference>2086073919</reference><reference>2093776691</reference><reference>2108309071</reference><reference>2152689238</reference></references><venue id="1193108635" type="C">Algorithmic Learning Theory</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-40992-0_16</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.55656">Boolean function</keyword><keyword weight="0.50962">Monotonic function</keyword><keyword weight="0.47732">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.47843">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.5617">Boolean satisfiability problem</keyword><keyword weight="0.4668">Satisfiability</keyword><keyword weight="0.4984">Duality (optimization)</keyword><keyword weight="0.46408">Equivalence (measure theory)</keyword><keyword weight="0.53632">Time complexity</keyword><keyword weight="0.42545">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.58954">Bounded function</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In this paper we show the equivalence between the problem of determining self-duality of a boolean function in DNF and a special type of satisfiability problem called NAESPI. Eiter and Gottlob [8] use a result from [2] to show that self-duality of monotone boolean functions which have bounded clause sizes (by some constant) can be determined in polynomial time. We show that the self-duality of instances in the class studied by Eiter and Gottlob can be determined in time linear in the number of clauses in the input, thereby strengthening their result. Domingo [7] recently showed that self-duality of boolean functions where each clause is bounded by (√log n) can be solved in polynomial time. Our linear time algorithm for solving the clauses with bounded size infact solves the (√log n) bounded self-duality problem in O(n2 √log n) time, which is better bound then the algorithm of Domingo [7], class of :[149],"self-dual functions arising naturally in application domain has the property that every pair of terms in f intersect in at most constant number of variables. The equivalent subclass of NAESPI is the c-bounded NAESPI. We also show that c-bounded NAESPI can be solved in polynomial time when c is some constant. We also give an alternative characterization of almost :[149],"self-dual functions proposed by Bioch and Ibaraki [5] in terms of NAESPI instances which admit solutions of a u0027particularu0027 type.</abstract></paper>