<paper id="1495266644"><title>Self Protecting Pirates and Black-Box Traitor Tracing</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="CUNY." id="81359666">Aggelos Kiayias</author><author org="CertCo" id="2097786798">Moti Yung</author></authors><n_citation>1141</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1518164822</reference><reference>1560252361</reference><reference>1561762905</reference><reference>1583385494</reference><reference>1594802052</reference><reference>1596144702</reference><reference>1785500772</reference><reference>1971694152</reference><reference>2002087984</reference><reference>2091915899</reference><reference>2151066003</reference><reference>2295616646</reference><reference>2911546054</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-44647-8_4</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47417">Broadcast encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.4472">Black box (phreaking)</keyword><keyword weight="0.43939">Open problem</keyword><keyword weight="0.42628">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.41891">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.42716">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.40923">Software</keyword><keyword weight="0.48761">Ciphertext</keyword><keyword weight="0.6578">Traitor tracing</keyword><keyword weight="0.51698">Tracing</keyword><keyword weight="0.4179">Traceability</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We present a new generic black-box traitor tracing model in which the pirate-decoder employs a self-protection technique. This mechanism is simple, easy to implement in any (software or hardware) device and is a natural way by which a pirate (an adversary) which is black-box accessible, may try to evade detection. We present a necessary combinatorial condition for black-box traitor tracing of self-protecting devices. We constructively prove that any system that fails this condition, is incapable of tracing pirate-decoders that contain keys based on a superlogarithmic number of traitor keys. We then combine the above condition with specific properties of concrete systems. We show that the Boneh-Franklin (BF) scheme as well as the Kurosawa-Desmedt scheme have no black-box tracing capability in the self-protecting model when the number of traitors is superlogarithmic, unless the ciphertext size is as large as in a trivial system, namely linear in the number of users. This partially settles in the negative the open problem of Boneh and Franklin regarding the general black-box traceability of the BF scheme: at least for the case of superlogarithmic traitors. Our negative result does not apply to the Chor-Fiat-Naor (CFN) scheme (which, in fact, allows tracing in our self-protecting model); this separates CFN black-box traceability from that of BF. We also investigate a weaker form of black-box tracing called single-query "black-box confirmation." We show that, when suspicion is modeled as a confidence weight (which biases the uniform distribution of traitors), such single-query confirmation is essentially not possible against a self-protecting pirate-decoder that contains keys based on a superlogarithmic number of traitor keys.</abstract></paper>