<paper id="1972855212"><title>Reliable object storage to support atomic actions</title><year>1985</year><authors><author org="Laboratory for Computer Science, Massachusetts Institute of Technology Cambridge, MA" id="314402231">Brian M. Oki</author><author org="Laboratory for Computer Science, Massachusetts Institute of Technology Cambridge, MA" id="2084056563">Barbara H. Liskov</author><author org="Laboratory for Computer Science, Massachusetts Institute of Technology Cambridge, MA" id="1989816340">Robert W. Scheifler</author></authors><n_citation>43</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1557670639</reference><reference>1990247061</reference><reference>1991199257</reference><reference>2000018901</reference><reference>2106887953</reference><reference>2116436709</reference><reference>2145057157</reference><reference>2156529936</reference><reference>2914315669</reference></references><venue id="1171178643" type="C">Symposium on Operating Systems Principles</venue><doi>10.1145/323627.323642</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.52879">Atomicity</keyword><keyword weight="0.58544">Object storage</keyword><keyword weight="0.50145">File system</keyword><keyword weight="0.49253">Concurrency</keyword><keyword weight="0.45727">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45316">Real-time computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.58793">Information repository</keyword><keyword weight="0.44607">Argus</keyword><keyword weight="0.46404">Local area network</keyword><keyword weight="0.66345">Stable storage</keyword><keyword weight="0.46753">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>To preserve the consistency of on-line, long-lived, distributed data in the presence of concurrency and in the event of hardware failures, it is necessary to ensure atomicity and data resiliency in applications. The programming language Argus is designed to support such applications. This thesis investigates the mechanism needed to support the notion of data resiliency present in Argus. Data resiliency means that the probability is very high that the crash of a node or storage device in a distributed system does not cause the loss of vital data. Data resiliency requires the use of stable storage devices, memory devices that survive failure to a high probability. This thesis is not concerned with how to implement stable storage devices, but rather with how to organize the use of stable storage. The thesis presents a new organization of stable storage called the hybrid log that provides fast writing of information to stable storage and reasonably fast recovery of information from stable storage. In the context of this scheme, various algorithms are developed for writing objects to the log, recovering objects from the log, and housekeeping the log. {AD#A136484}</abstract></paper>