<paper id="1975861344"><title>Shortest prefix strings containing all subset permutations</title><year>1987</year><authors><author org="AT&amp;T Bell Lab, Murray Hill, NJ" id="2974275773">A. A. Schäffer</author></authors><n_citation>1</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1970804985</reference><reference>1982777258</reference><reference>2017207521</reference><reference>2073683173</reference><reference>2079303095</reference></references><venue id="18902827" type="J">Discrete Mathematics</venue><doi>10.1016/0012-365X(87)90193-2</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.467">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.47317">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.48627">Shortest path problem</keyword><keyword weight="0.53495">Upper and lower bounds</keyword><keyword weight="0.53831">Permutation</keyword><keyword weight="0.48983">Prefix</keyword><keyword weight="0.48483">Conjecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.40828">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.43582">Special case</keyword></keywords><publisher>North-Holland</publisher><abstract>Abstract What is the length of the shortest string consisting of elements of {1,…n} that contains as subsequences all permutations of any k-element subset? Many authors have considered the special case where k=n. We instead consider an incremental variation on this problem first proposed by Koutas and Hu. For a fixed value of n they ask for a string such that for all values of k⩽n, the prefix containing all permutations of any k-element subset as subsequences is as short as possible. The problem can also be viewed as follows: For k=1 one needs n distinct digits to find each of the n possible permutations. In going from k to k+1, one starts with a string containing all k-element permutations as subsequences, and one adds as few digits as possible to the end of the string so that the new string contains all (k+1)-element permutations. We give a new construction that gives shorter strings than the best previous construction. We then prove a weak form of lower bound for the number of digits added in successive suffixes. The lower bound proof leads to a construction that matches the bound exactly. The length of a shortest prefix string is k(n−2)+[ 1 3 (k+1)]+3 , for k u003e 2. The lengths for k=1, 2 are n and 2n−1. This proves the natural conjecture that requiring the strings to be prefixes strictly increases the length of the strings required for all but the smallest values of k.</abstract></paper>