<paper id="1654892695"><title>A confessional account of an ethnography about knowledge work</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="Southern#N#          Methodist University" id="2560365981">Ulrike Schultze</author></authors><n_citation>495</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1573335570</reference><reference>1587604579</reference><reference>2085740750</reference><reference>2117036312</reference><reference>2128992662</reference><reference>2170699450</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/3250978</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.50179">Competitive intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.49495">Reflexivity</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Information systems research</keyword><keyword weight="0.44324">Sociology</keyword><keyword weight="0.53344">Subjectivity</keyword><keyword weight="0.46479">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.47297">Confessional</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Knowledge creation</keyword><keyword weight="0.5066">Objectivity (philosophy)</keyword><keyword weight="0.4412">Ethnography</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>Information systems research has traditionally focused on information as an object that serves as input to decision making. Such a perspective attends mainly to the use of information. Increasingly, however, organizations are concerned about the production of information. This paper focuses on the work of producing informational objects, an activity central to knowledge work. Based on data collected during an eight-month ethnographic study of three groups of knowledge workers-computer system administrators, competitive intelligence analysts, and librarians-I explore the informing practices they relied upon. These are identified as ex-pressing, monitoring, and translating. Common to these informing practices is the knowledge workersu0027 endeavor to balance subjectivity and objectivity, where subjectivity is a necessary part of doing value adding work and objectivity promises workers authority and a sense of security.</abstract></paper>