<paper id="1587851807"><title>Categorical Approach to Horizontal Structuring and Refinement of High-Level Replacement Systems</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="Institute for Communication and Software Technology, Technical University of Berlin, Berlin, Germany" id="2154760523">Julia Padberg</author></authors><n_citation>19</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1512428151</reference><reference>1527747853</reference><reference>1574796876</reference><reference>1577316669</reference><reference>1600842815</reference><reference>1759712729</reference><reference>1856781494</reference><reference>1963498955</reference><reference>1986020155</reference><reference>1995768429</reference><reference>1995961297</reference><reference>2033983519</reference><reference>2093916942</reference><reference>2120995755</reference></references><venue id="148906134" type="J">Applied Categorical Structures</venue><doi>10.1023/A:1008695316594</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47349">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.51548">Limit (category theory)</keyword><keyword weight="0.47277">Rule-based machine translation</keyword><keyword weight="0.43999">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.54735">Petri net</keyword><keyword weight="0.5285">Categorical variable</keyword><keyword weight="0.46494">Requirements engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.45699">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.52467">Morphism</keyword><keyword weight="0.41071">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.4967">Special case</keyword></keywords><publisher /><abstract>Based on the well-known theory of high-level replacement systems – a categorical formulation of graph grammars – we present new results concerning refinement of high-level replacement systems. Motivated by Petri nets, where refinement is often given by morphisms, we give a categorical notion of refinement. This concept is called Q-transformations and is established within the framework of high-level replacement systems. The main idea is to supply rules with an additional morphism, which belongs to a specific class Q of morphisms. This leads to the new notions of Q-rules and Q-transformations. Moreover, several concepts and results of high-level replacement systems are extended to Q-transformations. These are sequential and parallel transformations, union, and fusion, based on different colimit constructions. The main results concern the compatibility of these constructions with Q-transformations that is the corresponding theorems for usual transformations are extended to Q-transformations. Finally, we demonstrate the application of these techniques for the special case of Petri nets to a case study concerning the requirements engineering of a medical information system.</abstract></paper>