<paper id="1514759812"><title>Local Scale Selection for Gaussian Based Description Techniques</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="INRIA-Rhône-Alpes" id="130614938">Olivier Chomat</author><author org="INRIA-Rhône-Alpes" id="2049605028">Vincent Colin de Verdière</author><author org="INRIA-Rhône-Alpes" id="2165726662">Daniela Hall</author><author org="INRIA-Rhône-Alpes" id="2420338556">James L. Crowley</author></authors><n_citation>37</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1495971627</reference><reference>1636936512</reference><reference>1991605728</reference><reference>1994297893</reference><reference>2055339315</reference><reference>2109200236</reference><reference>2123977795</reference><reference>2124087378</reference><reference>2135884851</reference><reference>2155919893</reference><reference>2157244669</reference><reference>2168766212</reference></references><venue id="1124077590" type="C">European Conference on Computer Vision</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-45054-8_8</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.5338">Scale invariance</keyword><keyword weight="0.57216">Edge detection</keyword><keyword weight="0.40102">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.63162">Scale space</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.45161">Computer vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.56864">Feature vector</keyword><keyword weight="0.62071">Scale-space axioms</keyword><keyword weight="0.45953">Pattern recognition</keyword><keyword weight="0.51492">Gaussian</keyword><keyword weight="0.48992">Pixel</keyword><keyword weight="0.42001">Machine learning</keyword><keyword weight="0.4917">Cognitive neuroscience of visual object recognition</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>This paper addresses the problem of the local scale parameter selection for recognition techniques based on Gaussian derivatives. Patterns are described in a feature space of which each dimension is a scale and orientation normalized receptive field (a unit composed of normalized Gaussian-based :[43],"invariance is obtained by automatic selection of an appropriate local scale [Lin98b] and followed by normalisation of the receptive field to the appropriate scale. Orientation :[43],"invariance is obtained by the determination of the dominant local orientation and by steering the receptive fields to this is :[88],"represented structurally in a feature space that is designed for the recognition of static object configurations. In this space an image is modeled by the vectorial representation of the receptive field responses at each pixel, forming a surface in the feature space. Recognition is achieved by measuring the distance between the vector of normalized receptive fields responses of an observed neighborhood and the surface point of the image :[158],"power of a scale equivariant feature space is validated by experimental results for point correspondences in images of different scales and the recognition of objects under different view points.</abstract></paper>