<paper id="1640973035"><title>Alternating automata, the weak monadic theory of the tree, and its complexity</title><year>1986</year><authors><author org="University of Illinois, University of Texas" id="2114238767">David E. Muller</author><author org="Université Paris#TAB#" id="2096994875">Ahmed Saoudi</author><author org="University of Illinois, Université Paris 7" id="2787184967">Paul E. Schnupp</author></authors><n_citation>166</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1492540572</reference><reference>1971416129</reference><reference>1996207810</reference></references><venue id="1141821850" type="C">International Colloquium on Automata, Languages and Programming</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-16761-7_77</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45806">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.45155">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.53855">Nondeterministic algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.40528">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.4764">Automaton</keyword><keyword weight="0.483">No free lunch in search and optimization</keyword><keyword weight="0.52539">Decidability</keyword><keyword weight="0.5135">Fundamental theorem</keyword><keyword weight="0.53583">Monadic predicate calculus</keyword><keyword weight="0.47087">Monad (functional programming)</keyword><keyword weight="0.46994">Alternation (linguistics)</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Beginning with the fundamental article of Chandra et al. [2], the notation of alternation has clarified several results concerning the complexity of logical theories. Muller and Schupp [9] extended the idea of alternation to automata working on trees. Although such automata are a generalization of Rabin’s model [12] of nondeterministic automata working on infinite trees, complementation and, thus, all Boolean operations, are easy for such automata. In particular, complementation costs no extra states. There is, of course, no free lunch and, in the alternating model, one must pay for projection. Thus, alternating automata do not give a simple proof of Rabin’s fundamental theorem [12] on the decidability of the full monadic theory of the tree. Indeed, one must appeal to the powerful “forgetful determinacy” theorem of Gurevitch and Harrington [3] to show that alternating automata can be simulated by nondeterministic Rabin automata.</abstract></paper>