<paper id="1522773110"><title>An Efficient MAC for Short Messages</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="Lucent Technologies'" id="2125066154">Sarvar Patel</author></authors><n_citation>16</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1656678770</reference><reference>1985623009</reference><reference>2107165730</reference><reference>2122984309</reference><reference>2131300413</reference><reference>2151413173</reference><reference>2916302273</reference></references><venue id="2758123139" type="C">Selected Areas in Cryptography</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-36492-7_23</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.67471">Hash-based message authentication code</keyword><keyword weight="0.50456">Authentication</keyword><keyword weight="0.58694">Message authentication code</keyword><keyword weight="0.51274">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.43029">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.60999">Cryptographic hash function</keyword><keyword weight="0.44689">Computer network</keyword><keyword weight="0.56687">Message broker</keyword><keyword weight="0.59912">Length extension attack</keyword><keyword weight="0.54517">Hash function</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer Berlin Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>HMAC is the internet standard for message authentication [BCK96, KBC97]. What distinguishes HMAC from other MAC algorithms is that it provides proofs of security assuming that the underlying cryptographic hash (e.g. SHA-1) has some reasonable properties. HMAC is efficient for long messages, however, for short messages the nested constructions results in a significant inefficiency. For example to MAC a message shorter than a block, HMAC requires at least two calls to the compression function rather than one.This inefficiency may be particularly high for some applications, like message authentication of signaling messages, where the individual messages may all fit within one or two blocks. Also for TCP/IP traffic it is well known that a large number of packets (e.g. acknowledgement) have sizes around 40 bytes which fit within a block of most cryptographic hashes. We propose an enhancement that allows both short and long messages to be message authenticated more efficiently than HMAC while also providing proofs of security. In particular, for a message smaller than a block our MAC only requires one call to the compression function.</abstract></paper>