<paper id="1868193499"><title>Decidability of Hybrid Systems with Rectangular Differential Inclusion</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="University of California" id="2895908682">Anuj Puri</author><author org="University of California" id="2214759960">Pravin Varaiya</author></authors><n_citation>132</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>59365162</reference><reference>1482233117</reference><reference>1499407607</reference><reference>1525512650</reference><reference>1572777470</reference><reference>1587275578</reference><reference>1823037702</reference><reference>1830600668</reference><reference>1885037678</reference><reference>1925408448</reference><reference>1995691455</reference><reference>2098228838</reference><reference>2167668895</reference></references><venue id="1162450063" type="C">Computer Aided Verification</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-58179-0_46</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.61917">Differential inclusion</keyword><keyword weight="0.57278">Differential equation</keyword><keyword weight="0.50738">Finite set</keyword><keyword weight="0.40135">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.44997">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.4694">Pure mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.50214">Decidability</keyword><keyword weight="0.50359">Regular language</keyword><keyword weight="0.58215">Hybrid system</keyword><keyword weight="0.54233">State space</keyword><keyword weight="0.59374">Hybrid automaton</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>A hybrid system is modeled with a finite set of locations and a differential inclusion associated with each location. We discuss a subclass of hybrid systems with constant rectangular differential inclusions. The continuous state of the system is x ∃ IRn with xi evolving with differential inclusion x i [L i , U i ] where L i , U i are integers (i.e., the slope of trajectory of xi could be changing, but is restricted to remain within [L i , U i ]). A transition from one location to another can be made provided the state satisfies the enabling condition for the transition. The state can also be initialized to a new value during the transition. The differential inclusion for x i can be changed when x i is an integer or when x i is initialized to a new value. We show that the verification problem for this class of hybrid systems is decidable. With this approach, systems with unsynchronized and drifting clocks can be modeled, a general differential equation can be abstracted by breaking the state space into regions with constant differential inclusions, and many previously presented hybrid system examples can be verified.</abstract></paper>