<paper id="1598468830"><title>Families of Consensus Algorithms</title><year>1988</year><authors><author org="Stanford, University" id="2278892267">Amotz Bar-Noy</author><author org="IBM Almaden Research Center and Hebrew University" id="1983290808">Danny Dolev</author></authors><n_citation>18</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>2026420798</reference><reference>2034791526</reference><reference>2091732787</reference><reference>2126924915</reference><reference>2294404229</reference></references><venue id="" type="">AWOC '88 Proceedings of the 3rd Aegean Workshop on Computing: VLSI Algorithms and Architectures</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0040405</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.48958">Integer</keyword><keyword weight="0.48148">Consensus</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Consensus algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.45051">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.50878">Upper and lower bounds</keyword><keyword weight="0.42084">SIMPLE algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.40342">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Message size</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><abstract>Three main parameters characterize the efficiency of algorithms that solve the Consensus Problem. The ratio between the total number of processors and the maximum number of faulty processors (n and t, respectively), the number of rounds, and the size of any single message. Lower bounds exist for each one of the three. In this paper we present two families of algorithms, each achieving the lower bound for one parameter and a trade-off between the other two. The first family includes algorithms where, given an integer k, the algorithm always requires the minimal possible number of rounds (t+1), with n=k(3t+1) processors and messages of size at most t O(t/k). To the second family belong algorithms in which all messages are of one bit size, the number of processors is t O((k+1)/k) and the number of rounds is t+t O ((k−1)/k). These two families are based on a very simple algorithm with (2t+1)(t+1) processors using the minimal number of rounds and the minimal message size (one bit).</abstract></paper>