<paper id="1970102673"><title>A new subsumption method in the connection graph proof procedure</title><year>1992</year><authors><author org="Computer Science Department, KAIST, P.O. Box 150, Cheongryang, Seoul, South Korea" id="2893111880">Byeong Man Kim</author><author org="Computer Science Department, KAIST, P.O. Box 150, Cheongryang, Seoul, South Korea" id="2894154508">Jung Wan Cho</author></authors><n_citation>6</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>90049463</reference><reference>122908603</reference><reference>134991542</reference><reference>152480905</reference><reference>1482767073</reference><reference>1514729613</reference><reference>1530670073</reference><reference>1963804765</reference><reference>1970045008</reference><reference>2010939537</reference><reference>2013192348</reference><reference>2018221833</reference><reference>2042066678</reference><reference>2100738443</reference><reference>2112827998</reference></references><venue id="90727058" type="J">Theoretical Computer Science</venue><doi>10.1016/0304-3975(92)90016-9</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.48276">Pairwise comparison</keyword><keyword weight="0.40309">Data processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.47149">Open problem</keyword><keyword weight="0.51813">Search algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.45576">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.51583">Graph rewriting</keyword><keyword weight="0.50669">Connectivity</keyword><keyword weight="0.54168">Time complexity</keyword><keyword weight="0.52721">Proof procedure</keyword><keyword weight="0.41407">Mathematics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Elsevier</publisher><abstract>Compared to most of the other resolution-based proof procedures, the connection graph proof procedure (CGPP) is superior due to its effective search space reduction rules. A test for subsumption in CGPP is sufficiently efficient in comparison with the standard test. But the subsumption with no restriction may cause logical inconsistency. The restriction on subsumption to maintain the consistency has been an open problem since it was first noticed in 1981. We define a newθ-subsumption which maintains the logical consistency and provides the graph transformation method which makes C subsume D with the new definition if C subsumes D with the original definition the subsumption test in :[102],"CGPP, it is essential to find a set of pairwise strongly compatible matching substitutions between literals in two clauses. This paper presents an algorithm which finds a set of pairwise strongly compatible matching substitutions efficiently, based on both the reduction of possible matching substitutions and bit operations. The worst-case time complexity of this algorithm is analyzed in terms of the estimated maximal number of string comparisons and it is shown that our complexity is lower than the other algorithms based on the s-link on the new definition of subsumption and the :[190],"improved algorithm for the pairwise strongly compatible test, an unrestricted subsumption algorithm and a restricted subsumption algorithm are suggested.</abstract></paper>