<paper id="1513538444"><title>Structuring modelling knowledge for CASE shells</title><year>1991</year><authors><author org="Delft University of Technology &gt;  &gt;  &gt;  &gt;" id="1246403823">T. F. Verhoef</author><author org="University of Nijmegen" id="2892040479">A. H. M. ter Hofstede</author><author org="Software Engineering Research Centre" id="2684690428">G. M. Wijers</author></authors><n_citation>27</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>139313190</reference><reference>166854877</reference><reference>1505294616</reference><reference>2031673060</reference><reference>2153856558</reference><reference>2163842000</reference><reference>2176296250</reference></references><venue id="1134069326" type="C">Conference on Advanced Information Systems Engineering</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-54059-8_101</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.51525">Workbench</keyword><keyword weight="0.4315">Architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.46072">Systems engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.45539">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.49649">Object type</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Support system</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Information modelling</keyword><keyword weight="0.57522">Computer-aided software engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.47535">Structuring</keyword><keyword weight="0.53778">Structured analysis</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In the SOCRATES project, it is claimed that improving automated support of information modelling processes should be realised by the development of a new architecture of CASE tools, which is method independent and as such should be implemented as a CASE shell. A CASE shell should include knowledge of both the tasks to be carried out in the information modelling process and the models resulting from that modelling process. By incorporating this knowledge in a CASE shell, the shell is transformed in a workbench or modelling support system for that specific modelling process. Crucial for the development of a CASE shell is the availability of a suitable technique for the uniform representation of information modelling knowledge. We will refer to such a technique as a meta-modelling technique. In this paper we present a meta-modelling technique in which modelling tasks and the resulting models can be integrated. The development of a CASE shell as such is beyond the scope of this paper. As to show the applicability of the meta-modelling technique presented, it has been used to represent Yourdonu0027s Modern Structured Analysis.</abstract></paper>