<paper id="1497058698"><title>Group-Oriented Undeniable Signature Schemes without the Assistance of a Mutually Trusted Party</title><year>1992</year><authors><author org="(University of Missouri, Kansas City)" id="724618227">Lein Harn</author><author org="Univ. of Sci. and Tech. of China" id="2435634824">Shoubao Yang</author></authors><n_citation>23</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1531764614</reference><reference>1541330898</reference><reference>1730634423</reference><reference>1981455414</reference><reference>1996360405</reference><reference>2229750252</reference><reference>2911424200</reference><reference>2911473785</reference><reference>2912577494</reference></references><venue id="1140213147" type="C">Theory and Application of Cryptographic Techniques</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-57220-1_57</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.67624">Undeniable signature</keyword><keyword weight="0.40835">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.4172">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.40883">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.66914">Group signature</keyword><keyword weight="0.63099">Blind signature</keyword><keyword weight="0.51086">T-group</keyword><keyword weight="0.51472">Public-key cryptography</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In a group-oriented (t, n) undeniable signature scheme, where t is the threshold value and n is the total number of group members, each group, instead of each individual member within the group, publishes a single group public key. During an initial “commitment phase”, at least t group members work together to sign a message. In a “verification phase”, all signers work together to prove the validity of the signature to an outsider. There is only a single group public key required for an outsider to verify the group signature. In case some group members disavow the signature, a judge can resolve the dispute between the group and a verifier. The group-oriented (t,n) undeniable signature scheme has the following four properties: (1) the group signature is mutually generated by at least t group members; (2) the signature verification process is simplified because there is only one group public key required; (3) the signature can only be verified with the consent of all signers; (4) the signers hold the responsibility to the signed messages. More specifically, we propose two schemes where the threshold value t can be either n or 1. In other words, it requires either all group members or a single member to sign a group signature. Moreover, these two schemes do not require the assistance of a mutually trusted party. Each member selects his own secret and the group public key is determined by all group members.</abstract></paper>