<paper id="1599345461"><title>Distinctions Among Different Types of Generalizing in Information Systems Research</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="Georgia State University" id="2288381087">Richard Baskerville</author><author org="Virginia Commonwealth University.." id="2158578300">Allen S. Lee</author></authors><n_citation>36</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1527353115</reference><reference>1598226182</reference><reference>1600390288</reference><reference>1603006768</reference><reference>1654892695</reference><reference>2051672709</reference><reference>2063917410</reference><reference>2079496287</reference><reference>2128816293</reference><reference>2140494533</reference><reference>2167126626</reference></references><venue id="" type="">Proceedings of the IFIP TC8 WG8.2 International Working Conference on New Information Technologies in Organizational Processes: Field Studies and Theoretical Reflections on the Future of Work</venue><doi>10.1007/978-0-387-35566-5_5</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47023">Generalizability theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.52465">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Information systems research</keyword><keyword weight="0.42438">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48114">Generalization</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Research methodology</keyword><keyword weight="0.46278">Action research</keyword><keyword weight="0.45047">Epistemology</keyword><keyword weight="0.53085">Generality</keyword></keywords><publisher>Kluwer, B.V.</publisher><abstract>It is incorrect and even harmful that many information systems researchers typically criticize their own intensive (qualitative, interpretive, critical, and case) research as lacking “generalizability.” We untangle and distinguish the numerous concepts now confounded in the single term “generalizability,” which are generality, generalization, generalize, general and generalizing. These clarified terms allow us to identify four distinct forms of generalizing (everyday inductive generalizing, everyday deductive generalizing, academic inductive generalizing, and academic deductive generalizing), each of which we illustrate with an information systems-related example. The clarified terms provide the basis for an explanation of how information systems researchers who perform intensive research may properly lay claim to generality for their research.</abstract></paper>