<paper id="1793284863"><title>A Storage and Access Architecture for Efficient Query Processing in Spatial Database Systems</title><year>1993</year><authors><author org="Univ. of Munich" id="658694092">Thomas Brinkhoff</author><author org="Univ. of Munich" id="1999884152">Holger Horn</author><author org="Univ. of Munich" id="1919135125">Hans-Peter Kriegel</author><author org="Univ. of Munich" id="2949107815">Ralf Schneider</author></authors><n_citation>50</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1508355855</reference><reference>1555915743</reference><reference>1557835717</reference><reference>1560538750</reference><reference>1581321178</reference><reference>1721498786</reference><reference>2062184932</reference><reference>2072627547</reference><reference>2074429597</reference><reference>2086797095</reference><reference>2111380344</reference><reference>2118269922</reference><reference>2127196484</reference><reference>2135658482</reference><reference>2144777244</reference><reference>2151135734</reference></references><venue id="" type="">SSD '93 Proceedings of the Third International Symposium on Advances in Spatial Databases</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-56869-7_20</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.61118">Query optimization</keyword><keyword weight="0.60055">Query language</keyword><keyword weight="0.46359">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.57272">Range query (data structures)</keyword><keyword weight="0.59477">View</keyword><keyword weight="0.63609">Spatial query</keyword><keyword weight="0.60573">Online aggregation</keyword><keyword weight="0.48346">Modular design</keyword><keyword weight="0.46544">Database</keyword><keyword weight="0.57555">Spatial database</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Due to the high complexity of objects and queries and also due to extremely large data volumes, geographic database systems impose stringent requirements on their storage and access architecture with respect to efficient query processing. Performance improving concepts such as spatial storage and access structures, approximations, object decompositions and multi-phase query processing have been suggested and analyzed as single building blocks. In this paper, we describe a storage and access architecture which is composed from the above building blocks in a modular fashion. Additionally, we incorporate into our architecture a new ingredient, the scene organization, for efficiently supporting set-oriented access of large-area region queries. An experimental performance comparison demonstrates that the concept of scene organization leads to considerable performance improvements for large-area region queries by a factor of up to 150.</abstract></paper>