<paper id="1527005907"><title>A New Identification Scheme Based on Syndrome Decoding</title><year>1993</year><authors><author org="E´cole Normale Supe´rieure#TAB#" id="2097349350">Jacques Stern</author></authors><n_citation>207</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>90698540</reference><reference>1518383700</reference><reference>1536493828</reference><reference>1589034595</reference><reference>1968182591</reference><reference>1979215153</reference><reference>2035929826</reference><reference>2093465763</reference><reference>2150780437</reference><reference>2152005134</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-48329-2_2</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46674">Kernel (linear algebra)</keyword><keyword weight="0.58337">Identification scheme</keyword><keyword weight="0.50155">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.44671">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48201">Cryptographic hash function</keyword><keyword weight="0.45049">Arithmetic</keyword><keyword weight="0.44758">Quadratic equation</keyword><keyword weight="0.45501">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47239">Mathematical proof</keyword><keyword weight="0.49911">Decoding methods</keyword><keyword weight="0.45914">Binary number</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Zero-knowledge proofs were introduced in 1985, in a paper by Goldwasser, Micali and Rackoff ([6]). Their practical significance was soon demonstrated in the work of Fiat and Shamir ([4]), who turned zero-knowledge proofs of quadratic residuosity into efficient means of establishing user identities. Still, as is almost always the case in public-key cryptography, the Fiat-Shamir scheme relied on arithmetic operations on large numbers. In 1989, there were two attempts to build identification protocols that only use simple operations (see [11, 10]). One appeared in the EUROCRYPT proceedings and relies on the intractability of some coding problems, the other waa presented at the CRYPTO rump session and depends on the so-called Permuted Kernel problem (PKP). Unfortunately, the first of the schemes was not really practical. In the present paper, we propose a new identification scheme, based on error-correcting codes, which is zero-knowledge and is of practical value. Furthermore, we describe several variants, including one which has an identity based character. The security of our scheme depends on the hardness of decoding a word of given syndrome w.r.t. some binary linear error-correcting code.</abstract></paper>