<paper id="1569070677"><title>Modeling and Managing Interactions among Business Processes</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="Software Technology Lab, Hewlett-Packard Laboratories, Palo Alto," id="2145207705">Fabio Casati</author><author org="Etnoteam, Milan, Italy" id="2078253689">Angela Discenza</author></authors><n_citation>54</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>8667049</reference><reference>1579145134</reference><reference>1600899372</reference><reference>1984192117</reference><reference>2004034641</reference><reference>2019125550</reference><reference>2034873286</reference><reference>2075671196</reference><reference>2118305052</reference><reference>2120484103</reference><reference>2125294767</reference><reference>2153933075</reference></references><venue id="180847057" type="J">Journal of Systems Integration</venue><doi>10.1023/A:1011232926591</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.6264">Artifact-centric business process model</keyword><keyword weight="0.6349">Business process management</keyword><keyword weight="0.61802">Business process</keyword><keyword weight="0.43573">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.6379">Business process modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.62337">Workflow engine</keyword><keyword weight="0.59464">Workflow management system</keyword><keyword weight="0.59443">Workflow</keyword><keyword weight="0.62242">Business Process Model and Notation</keyword><keyword weight="0.46902">Process management</keyword></keywords><publisher>Kluwer</publisher><abstract>Most workflow management systems (WfMSs) only support the separate andindependent execution of business processes. However, processes often needto interact with each other, in order to synchronize the execution of theiractivities, to exchange process data, to request execution of services, orto notify progresses in process execution. Recent market trends also raisethe need for cooperation and interaction between processes executed in differentorganizations, posing additional challenges. In fact, in order to reduce costsand provide better services, companies are pushed to increase cooperation and toform virtual enterprises, where business processes span across organizationalboundaries and are composed of cooperating workflows executed in differentorganizations. Workflow interaction in a cross-organizational environment iscomplicated by the heterogeneity of workflow management platforms on top ofwhich workflows are defined and executed and by the different and possiblycompeting business policies and business goals that drive process executionin each organization.</abstract></paper>