<paper id="1539624384"><title>Computerized loan origination systems: an industry case study of the electronic markets hypothesis</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="" id="2322975921">Christopher M. Hess</author><author org="" id="2304793874">Chris F. Kemerer</author></authors><n_citation>170</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1862276743</reference><reference>1962360624</reference><reference>1963608591</reference><reference>1991358063</reference><reference>2118936359</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/249618</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.51117">Financial intermediary</keyword><keyword weight="0.4508">Incomplete contracts</keyword><keyword weight="0.53756">Loan</keyword><keyword weight="0.43121">Economics</keyword><keyword weight="0.44177">Actuarial science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47172">Clos network</keyword><keyword weight="0.40888">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.45825">Financial system</keyword><keyword weight="0.42518">Hierarchy</keyword><keyword weight="0.40749">Opposition (planets)</keyword><keyword weight="0.62074">Loan origination</keyword><keyword weight="0.48123">Liberian dollar</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>Much has been written in recent years about the changes in corporate strategies and industry structures associated with electronic coordination of market activities. This paper considers the advent of electronic market coordination in the home mortgage industry, focusing on Computerized Loan Origination (CLO) systems. Case studies of five CLOs (First Bostonu0027s Shelternet, PRCu0027s Loan Express, American Financial Networku0027s Rennie Mae, Prudentialu0027s CLOS, and Citicorpu0027s Mortgage Power Plus) reveal a range of system functionalities. Predictions from the Electronic Markets Hypothesis (EMH) are tested against the empirical results of the five case studies. As suggested by the EMH, financial intermediaries have been threatened by the introduction of CLOs, and in some cases, opposition has been mounted against the systems. On the other hand, despite the availability of the technology and mortgagesu0027 seemingly favorable characteristics as an electronically mediated market product, the industry has not been fundamentally changed by the introduction of these systems, despite more than a decade of experience with them. Of the two case studies that could be characterized as electronic markets, neither continues to exist in that form today. And the system with the largest dollar volume of mortgages of the five is best characterized as an electronic hierarchy. These results suggest that either the full results predicted by the EMH require a longer gestation period or that the underlying hypothesis will require augmentation in order to fully explain the results in the home mortgage market.</abstract></paper>