<paper id="1678418905"><title>Modelling inter-organizational trade using Documentary Petri Nets</title><year>1995</year><authors><author org="EURIDIS, Erasmus Univ. Rotterdam, Netherlands" id="2974368532">R.W.H. Bons</author><author org="EURIDIS, Erasmus Univ. Rotterdam, Netherlands" id="2114236770">R.M. Lee</author><author org="EURIDIS, Erasmus Univ. Rotterdam, Netherlands" id="2941045449">R.W. Wagenaar</author><author org="" id="2004787119">C.D. Wrigley</author></authors><n_citation>22</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>563347754</reference><reference>1515565939</reference><reference>1572660965</reference><reference>1573192249</reference><reference>1982451001</reference><reference>1997422892</reference><reference>2052404792</reference><reference>2166766059</reference></references><venue id="1164519180" type="C">Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences</venue><doi>10.1109/HICSS.1995.375561</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.50217">Knowledge representation and reasoning</keyword><keyword weight="0.4428">Linkage (mechanical)</keyword><keyword weight="0.62188">Petri net</keyword><keyword weight="0.4927">Electronic data interchange</keyword><keyword weight="0.45272">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45123">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.47095">High-level programming language</keyword><keyword weight="0.46998">Electronic trading</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Representation language</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><abstract>Organizations engaging in electronic commerce typically are faced with defining detailed bilateral agreements between business partners. This implies that set-up costs for new electronic linkages can be quite high. There is a growing need to model and simulate this form of interorganizational interaction to lower these costs. The research presented contributes to this problem in two ways by: stipulating requirements on representation languages to be used for modelling trade procedures; and presenting a common graph-based representation language, Documentary Petri Nets, which satisfies these requirements. The practical implementation of Documentary Petri Net models is illustrated using a modelling environment, Case/Open-edi, a tool that may be used for the design and analysis of trade procedures. A simplified documentary credit procedure is used to give an example of such a Documentary Petri Net model. Finally, conclusions and directions for research are given. u003e</abstract></paper>