<paper id="1590655251"><title>CARTECH: A Prototype of Geographical Information System</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="Algotech s.r.l" id="2012485731">Franco Arcieri</author><author org="C.N.R." id="1998351617">Enrico Nardelli</author><author org="Univ. di Roma &quot;La Sapienza&quot;" id="2949811704">Maurizio Talamo</author></authors><n_citation>1</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>189903331</reference><reference>204302661</reference><reference>1539415901</reference><reference>1560538750</reference><reference>1576894213</reference><reference>1603334326</reference><reference>1603727901</reference><reference>1985223393</reference><reference>1998004763</reference><reference>2000654499</reference><reference>2063853463</reference><reference>2072831861</reference><reference>2089871642</reference><reference>2111112637</reference><reference>2120450053</reference><reference>2169247002</reference></references><venue id="" type="">Proceedings of the International Workshop on Advanced Information Systems: Geographic Information Systems</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-58795-0_46</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.57249">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.56065">Geospatial analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.5569">Geographic information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.52262">End user</keyword><keyword weight="0.46886">Information retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.47377">Software engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.56859">Logical data model</keyword><keyword weight="0.53276">Local information systems</keyword><keyword weight="0.50815">GIS and public health</keyword><keyword weight="0.53823">System integration</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In this paper all major issues related to definition, design and implementation of a prototype of the geographical information system CARTECH are presented and discussed. The prototype proposes solutions for the most important requirements for geographical information systems (GIS). Namely, the double nature (spatial and descriptive) of geographical data, the fact that querying geographical information usually involves the specification of conditions which regards both the descriptive component of the data and the spatial one, the need of efficient spatial access methods to provide efficient and reliable management of large quantities of data. Moreover it also considers the important issue that user interaction with systems dealing with complex application realities, like geography, is typically incremental and iterative and proceed trough a process of view definition, updating and refinement. System highlights are: a system integration methodology to reuse existing modules so to deal in an efficient way with specialized aspects of the data and to build an overall system without re-inventing the wheel; a unifying logical data model to provide the end user with a uniform view of geographical entities, and to the designer a formal tool for the correct specification of data schemes and operations; support for the maintenance of consistency during the view building operations which are the result of the user-system interaction activities.</abstract></paper>