<paper id="1966904164"><title>Computer conferencing and task-oriented decisions: implications for group decision support</title><year>1988</year><authors><author org="University of Denver, Denver CO#TAB#" id="2119008449">Jill Y. Smith</author><author org="University of North Texas (Denton)" id="1860730808">Michael T. Vanecek</author></authors><n_citation>25</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>108549163</reference><reference>1527944521</reference><reference>1590859763</reference><reference>2122418187</reference><reference>2137186082</reference><reference>2145727840</reference><reference>2161662174</reference><reference>2166082726</reference></references><venue id="38883057" type="J">Information &amp; Management</venue><doi>10.1016/0378-7206(88)90003-1</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Computer conferencing</keyword><keyword weight="0.47782">Data collection</keyword><keyword weight="0.50929">Interpersonal communication</keyword><keyword weight="0.41885">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.568">Decision support system</keyword><keyword weight="0.42818">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.45334">Variables</keyword><keyword weight="0.58682">R-CAST</keyword><keyword weight="0.45629">Perception</keyword><keyword weight="0.55164">Group decision-making</keyword></keywords><publisher>North-Holland</publisher><abstract>Abstract An experiment was used to compare the impact of two very different communication modes during task-oriented group decision making activities. Subjects completed a task-oriented decision making activity using either face-to-face (simultaneous) or computer conferencing (nonsimultaneous) communication modes. Each subject had insufficient task information. Hence, subjects had to share task information for the group to reach a decision. The study used a temporal theoretical framework. The independent variable was communications mode. The temporal dependent and intervening variables consisted of the amount of information shared; the significance and comprehensiveness of the shared information; and, perception of progress made towards goal and freedom to participate. Communication quality was the outcome dependent variable. Data collection consisted of tape recorded sessions, computer generated transcripts, task questionnaires, and interviews.</abstract></paper>