<paper id="1599490814"><title>A restrictive blind signature scheme with applications to electronic cash</title><year>1997</year><authors><author org="Katholieke Universiteit Leuven Laboratorium ESAT-COSIC" id="2076607090">C. Radu</author><author org="Katholieke Universiteit Leuven Laboratorium ESAT-COSIC" id="2037293133">R. Govaerts</author><author org="Katholieke Universiteit Leuven Laboratorium ESAT-COSIC" id="1964643177">J. Vandewalle</author></authors><n_citation>5</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1483083484</reference><reference>1493020827</reference><reference>1503054601</reference><reference>1511288679</reference><reference>1554259298</reference><reference>1589034595</reference><reference>1979215153</reference><reference>2095708839</reference><reference>2151413173</reference><reference>2153193245</reference></references><venue id="1130451194" type="C">International Conference on Communications</venue><doi>10.1007/978-0-387-35083-7_18</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.56684">Identification scheme</keyword><keyword weight="0.44543">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.44048">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.50733">Electronic cash</keyword><keyword weight="0.43833">Computer network</keyword><keyword weight="0.5723">Cryptographic primitive</keyword><keyword weight="0.50189">Anonymity</keyword><keyword weight="0.43856">Payment</keyword><keyword weight="0.71935">Blind signature</keyword></keywords><publisher>Chapman &amp; Hall, Ltd.</publisher><abstract>A restrictive blind signature scheme is a cryptographic primitive involved in the design of untraceable off-line electronic payment systems. The security of this primitive determines both the integrity of the bank and the anonymity of the payers. Brands proved that a restrictive blind issuing protocol for secret-key certificates can be derived from any signature scheme of Fiat-Shamir type, if the latter can be ordinary blinded. There is not a similar result for the restrictive blind issuing of public-key certificates. Only one such primitive is known. It is derived from Schnorr’s identification protocol. Our paper presents another restrictive blind signature scheme, that can be used for public-key certificates. This solution is developed from the Identification Scheme type 1 and the corresponding signature scheme introduced by Okamoto. Using this blind signature protocol, we design an efficient untraceable electronic cash system.</abstract></paper>