<paper id="1607921603"><title>An Integrity Check Value Algorithm for Stream Ciphers</title><year>1993</year><authors><author org="Telecom Australia Research Laboratories#TAB#" id="2431710816">Richard Taylor</author></authors><n_citation>45</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1482660480</reference><reference>1488442350</reference><reference>1523854767</reference><reference>1549228503</reference><reference>1600432225</reference><reference>1813564308</reference><reference>1985623009</reference><reference>2007585625</reference><reference>2052207834</reference><reference>2098801947</reference><reference>2134518741</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-48329-2_4</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.42215">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.42427">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.60153">CBC-MAC</keyword><keyword weight="0.59084">Block cipher mode of operation</keyword><keyword weight="0.62903">Fluhrer, Mantin and Shamir attack</keyword><keyword weight="0.46889">Communication channel</keyword><keyword weight="0.62449">Running key cipher</keyword><keyword weight="0.41538">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.55216">Encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.64027">Stream cipher</keyword><keyword weight="0.66208">Stream cipher attack</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>A method of calculating an integrity check value (icv) with the use of a stream cipher is presented. The strength of the message integrity this provides is analysed and proven to be dependent on the unpredictability of the stream cipher used. A way of efficiently providing both integrity and encryption with the use of a single stream cipher is also explained. Note that the method of providing message integrity, used with or without encryption, is not subject to a number of attacks that succeed against many conventional integrity schemes. Specifically any legitimate message-icv pair that is copied or removed and subsequently replayed will have an appropriately small small chance of deceiving the receiver. Furthermore, any message-icv pair generated by an attacker and injected into the communication channel will have an appropriately small chance of escaping detection unless the attacker has actually broken the stream cipher. This is the case even if the attacker has any amount of chosen messages and corresponding icvs or performs any number of calculations.</abstract></paper>