<paper id="1838866020"><title>Triadic Concept Graphs</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="Technische Universität Darmstadt," id="2151365529">Rudolf Wille</author></authors><n_citation>20</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1481721063</reference><reference>1486545284</reference><reference>1493596129</reference><reference>1499449884</reference><reference>1516346799</reference><reference>1572977915</reference><reference>1790062403</reference><reference>1865672346</reference><reference>1880174554</reference><reference>2405001542</reference></references><venue id="1137878512" type="C">International Conference on Conceptual Structures</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0054915</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.41654">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.50369">Knowledge representation and reasoning</keyword><keyword weight="0.50582">Mathematical structure</keyword><keyword weight="0.43673">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.53136">Concept learning</keyword><keyword weight="0.65487">Conceptual graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.46915">Knowledge-based systems</keyword><keyword weight="0.56636">Semantic network</keyword><keyword weight="0.44939">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.43798">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.56643">Representation (mathematics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.56484">Formal concept analysis</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In the paper “Conceptual Graphs and Formal Concept Analysis”, the author has presented a first attempt in unifying the Theory of Conceptual Graphs and Formal Concept Analysis. This context-based approach, which is philosophically supported by Peirceu0027s pragmatic epistemology, is grounded on families of related formal contexts whose formal concepts allow a mathematical representation of the concepts and relations of conceptual graphs. Such representation of a conceptual graph is called a “concept graph” of the context family from which it is derived. In this paper the theory of concept graphs is extended to allow a mathematical representation of nested conceptual graphs by “triadic concept graphs”. As in the preceding paper, our focuss lies on the mathematical structure theory, which later could be used for extending the already developed logical theory of simple concept graphs. The overall aim of this research is to contribute to the development of a contextual logic as basis of Conceptual Knowledge Processing.</abstract></paper>