<paper id="1570522464"><title>eXpert-BSM: a host-based intrusion detection solution for Sun Solaris</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="Syst. Design Lab., SRI Int., Menlo Park, CA, USA" id="2192407609">U. Lindqvist</author><author org="Syst. Design Lab., SRI Int., Menlo Park, CA, USA" id="2389047378">P.A. Porras</author></authors><n_citation>57</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1484589875</reference><reference>1506072753</reference><reference>1570845098</reference><reference>1868467482</reference><reference>1990166243</reference><reference>2095979141</reference><reference>2117002131</reference><reference>2121886199</reference><reference>2132111557</reference><reference>2132625653</reference><reference>2155547871</reference><reference>2162038855</reference><reference>2166332868</reference></references><venue id="1195398546" type="C">Annual Computer Security Applications Conference</venue><doi>10.1109/ACSAC.2001.991540</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.64172">Host-based intrusion detection system</keyword><keyword weight="0.45539">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.42961">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.49372">Expert system</keyword><keyword weight="0.48889">Audit trail</keyword><keyword weight="0.48932">System monitoring</keyword><keyword weight="0.48208">Knowledge base</keyword><keyword weight="0.48145">Daemon</keyword><keyword weight="0.60437">Intrusion detection system</keyword><keyword weight="0.44523">Operating system</keyword><keyword weight="0.48719">The Internet</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>eXpert-BSM is a real time forward-reasoning expert system that analyzes Sun Solaris audit trails. Based on many years of intrusion detection research, eXpert-BSMu0027s knowledge base detects a wide range of specific and general forms of misuse, provides detailed reports and recommendations to the system operator, and has a low false-alarm rate. Host-based intrusion detection offers the ability to detect misuse and subversion through the direct monitoring of processes inside the host, providing an important complement to network-based surveillance. Suites of eXpert-BSMs may be deployed throughout a network, and their alarms managed, correlated, and acted on by remote or local subscribing security services, thus helping to address issues of decentralized management. Inside the host, eXpert-BSM is intended to operate as a true security daemon for host systems, consuming few CPU cycles and very little memory and secondary storage. eXpert-BSM has been available for download on the Internet since April 2000, and has been successfully deployed in several production environments.</abstract></paper>