<paper id="1982683160"><title>Does the medium make a difference? two studies of writing with pen and paper and with computers</title><year>1989</year><authors><author org="Information Technology Center, Carnegie-Mellon University, Pittsburgh, Pa" id="2671398719">Christina Haas</author></authors><n_citation>48</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>2001438822</reference><reference>2053665053</reference><reference>2070458494</reference></references><venue id="2481449237" type="J">Human-Computer Interaction</venue><doi>10.1207/s15327051hci0402_3</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.41166">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.60013">Personal computer</keyword><keyword weight="0.44033">Workstation</keyword><keyword weight="0.43151">Total quality management</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Partial replication</keyword><keyword weight="0.4304">Multimedia</keyword><keyword weight="0.56492">Computer technology</keyword></keywords><publisher>L. Erlbaum Associates Inc.</publisher><abstract>This article reports two studies examining how the use of computer technology affects writersu0027 processes and resulting written products. The first experiment, a partial replication of Gouldu0027s (1981) study, compared the efficiency and quality of 15 experienced writersu0027 persuasive letters written in three counterbalanced conditions: pen and paper, standard personal computer, and advanced workstation. Analyses of time to compose and length of the resulting letters showed that when composing with the advanced workstations, writers wrote for longer periods of time and composed longer letters than when composing with pen and paper. Rate of composition (words per min) was similar in all three conditions. Scores for content quality, mechanics quality, and total quality were also collected and analyzed. Letters composed with the personal computer were poorer in content quality and total quality. There were no differences in mechanics quality. In the second experiment, 8 of the original 15 writers revised two of their letters in the medium with which they were composed. Think-aloud protocols collected while the writers revised their letters were collected and analyzed. When revising with pen and paper, writers planned more than when revising on-line; they also planned more before beginning their revisions. However, when revising in the computer conditions, writers reread their texts more and paid more attention to the medium than when revising on paper.</abstract></paper>