<paper id="1527971240"><title>Computational Methods for Physically-based FE Mesh Generation</title><year>1992</year><authors><author org="Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Department of Mechanical Engineering, Computer Aided Design Laboratory, 77 Massachusetts Ave., Cambridge, MA 02139" id="2113706013">Kenji Shimada</author><author org="Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Department of Mechanical Engineering, Computer Aided Design Laboratory, 77 Massachusetts Ave., Cambridge, MA 02139" id="2274962678">David C. Gossard</author></authors><n_citation>18</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1977272035</reference><reference>2162703509</reference></references><venue id="2756173985" type="C">International PROLAMAT Conference on Human Aspects in Computer Integrated Manufacturing</venue><doi>10.1016/B978-0-444-89465-6.50038-7</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45343">Topology</keyword><keyword weight="0.42377">Mathematical optimization</keyword><keyword weight="0.49692">Equilateral triangle</keyword><keyword weight="0.55334">Polygon mesh</keyword><keyword weight="0.54546">Soap bubble</keyword><keyword weight="0.38969">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Hexagonal crystal system</keyword><keyword weight="0.47239">Point particle</keyword><keyword weight="0.60769">Mesh generation</keyword><keyword weight="0.56519">Delaunay triangulation</keyword><keyword weight="0.47876">Bubble</keyword></keywords><publisher>North-Holland Publishing Co.</publisher><abstract>Abstract This paper describes a new computational method for fully automated 2D/3D FE mesh generation that satisfies the basic requirements of element shape regularity, node constraint capability, and density control. We propose a physically-based approach inspired by natureu0027s shape finding process which gives topology and geometry similar to ideal FE meshes. A good 2D example is the pattern assumed by soap bubbles floating in liquid, a repeating hexagonal pattern. Connecting the bubbleu0027s center points produces a mesh of equilateral triangles. In the proposed approach, each mesh node is modeled as a bubble with a point mass and viscous damping, and bubbles attract or repel each other depending on proximity. After the final force-balancing bubble configuration is obtained by solving the governing equation of motion numerically, a complete mesh is generated by Delaunay triangulation.</abstract></paper>