<paper id="1974168649"><title>Theoretical foundations for compensations in flow composition languages</title><year>2005</year><authors><author org="Università di Pisa, Italia#TAB#" id="2147391338">Roberto Bruni</author><author org="Università di Pisa, Italia#TAB#" id="2633217000">Hernán Melgratti</author><author org="Università di Pisa, Italia#TAB#" id="1970207042">Ugo Montanari</author></authors><n_citation>192</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1521925456</reference><reference>1587877137</reference><reference>1602569358</reference><reference>1608333380</reference><reference>1962632332</reference><reference>1995406252</reference><reference>2015234709</reference><reference>2058769589</reference><reference>2123197446</reference><reference>2150864072</reference><reference>2154606502</reference><reference>2161062963</reference><reference>2163012804</reference><reference>2164091052</reference></references><venue id="1160032607" type="C">Symposium on Principles of Programming Languages</venue><doi>10.1145/1040305.1040323</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.55554">Atomicity</keyword><keyword weight="0.49222">Operational semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.44732">Programming language</keyword><keyword weight="0.49188">Undo</keyword><keyword weight="0.48931">Business process</keyword><keyword weight="0.45219">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.50136">Exception handling</keyword><keyword weight="0.5023">Hierarchy</keyword><keyword weight="0.50684">Process calculus</keyword><keyword weight="0.48892">Transactional leadership</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>A key aspect when aggregating business processes and web services is to assure transactional properties of process executions. Since transactions in this context may require long periods of time to complete, traditional mechanisms for guaranteeing atomicity are not always appropriate. Generally the concept of long running transactions relies on a weaker notion of atomicity based on compensations. For this reason, programming languages for service composition cannot leave out two key aspects: compensations, i.e. ad hoc activities that can undo the effects of a process that fails to complete, and transactional boundaries to delimit the scope of a transactional flow. This paper presents a hierarchy of transactional calculi with increasing expressiveness. We start from a very small language in which activities can only be composed sequentially. Then, we progressively introduce parallel composition, nesting, programmable compensations and exception handling. A running example illustrates the main features of each calculus in the hierarchy.</abstract></paper>