<paper id="1908162016"><title>RelExt : a tool for relation extraction from text in ontology extension</title><year>2005</year><authors><author org="Language Technology Lab, German Research Center for Artificial Intelligence (DFKI GmbH), Saarbrücken, Germany#TAB#" id="2496980821">Alexander Schutz</author><author org="Language Technology Lab, German Research Center for Artificial Intelligence (DFKI GmbH), Saarbrücken, Germany#TAB#" id="1985997350">Paul Buitelaar</author></authors><n_citation>149</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>103785035</reference><reference>144386144</reference><reference>1480596212</reference><reference>1528859321</reference><reference>1573981182</reference><reference>1846742003</reference><reference>1940888119</reference><reference>1978799369</reference><reference>2004620268</reference><reference>2075123415</reference><reference>2099808592</reference><reference>2149654329</reference><reference>2153804780</reference></references><venue id="1155608529" type="C">International Semantic Web Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/11574620_43</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.61022">Ontology (information science)</keyword><keyword weight="0.56222">Ontology</keyword><keyword weight="0.51217">Verb</keyword><keyword weight="0.65158">Ontology engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.51424">Question answering</keyword><keyword weight="0.45634">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.58751">Modal verb</keyword><keyword weight="0.49797">Semantic Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.4385">Database</keyword><keyword weight="0.54015">Relationship extraction</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Domain ontologies very rarely model verbs as relations holding between concepts. However, the role of the verb as a central connecting element between concepts is undeniable. Verbs specify the interaction between the participants of some action or event by expressing relations between them. In parallel, it can be argued from an ontology engineering point of view that verbs express a relation between two classes that specify domain and range. The work described here is concerned with relation extraction for ontology extension along these lines. We describe a system (RelExt) that is capable of automatically identifying highly relevant triples (pairs of concepts connected by a relation) over concepts from an existing ontology. RelExt works by extracting relevant verbs and their grammatical arguments (i.e. terms) from a domain-specific text collection and computing corresponding relations through a combination of linguistic and statistical processing. The paper includes a detailed description of the system architecture and evaluation results on a constructed benchmark. RelExt has been developed in the context of the SmartWeb project, which aims at providing intelligent information services via mobile broadband devices on the FIFA World Cup that will be hosted in Germany in 2006. Such services include location based navigational information as well as question answering in the football domain.</abstract></paper>