<paper id="1979472512"><title>A spectrum of logical definitions of model-based diagnosis</title><year>1991</year><authors><author org="Dipartimento di Informatica, Universita di Torino, Corso Svizzera 185, 10149 Torino, Italy" id="682889704">Luca Console</author><author org="Dipartimento di Informatica, Universita di Torino, Corso Svizzera 185, 10149 Torino, Italy" id="435749394">Pietro Torasso</author></authors><n_citation>220</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>100105580</reference><reference>102163706</reference><reference>163500809</reference><reference>1484786551</reference><reference>1567176099</reference><reference>1575798436</reference><reference>1766332311</reference><reference>1797873548</reference><reference>1983382292</reference><reference>2032511848</reference><reference>2092911568</reference><reference>2108309071</reference><reference>2116938596</reference><reference>2140627345</reference><reference>2144386448</reference><reference>2912324937</reference></references><venue id="1120693805" type="C">Computational Intelligence</venue><doi>10.1111/j.1467-8640.1991.tb00388.x</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45079">Knowledge representation and reasoning</keyword><keyword weight="0.40612">Restrictiveness</keyword><keyword weight="0.37502">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48176">Model-based reasoning</keyword><keyword weight="0.49611">Abductive reasoning</keyword><keyword weight="0.38203">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.40217">Epistemology</keyword><keyword weight="0.41543">Completeness (statistics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.37114">Machine learning</keyword></keywords><publisher>Blackwell Publishers, Inc.</publisher><abstract>In this paper, we analyze the logical definitions of model-based diagnosis recently presented in the literature, and we propose a unified framework (based on the integration of abductive and consistency-based reasoning) in which most of such definitions can be captured. This allows us to single out the existence of a spectrum of alternatives in the logical definition of diagnosis. A lot of attention in the paper is devoted to analyzing the differences among the definitions in the spectrum. In particular, we show that the definitions can be compared on the basis of their restrictive-ness and we relate such a restrictiveness with the completeness of the model of the system to be :[111],"cet article, les auteurs analysent les definitions logiques de diagnostics bases sur un modele dont il a ete question recemment dans certains ouvrages. Ils proposent un cadre unifie (base sur lu0027integration du raisonnement abductif et du raisonnement base sur la consistance) a lu0027interieur duquel la plupart de ces definitions peuvent ětre regroupees. Cette particularite permet de mettre en lumiere lu0027existence du0027un spectre du0027alternatives dans la definition logique du diagnostic. Cet article accorde une attention toute particuliere a lu0027analyse des differences entre les definitions du spectre. En outre, les auteurs demontrent que les definitions peuvent ětre compareees en fonction de leur caractere restrictif, qui est ensuite mis en relation avec la completude du modele du systeme faisant lu0027objet du0027un diagnostic.</abstract></paper>