<paper id="1598226182"><title>CASE tools as organizational change: investigating incremental and radical changes in systems development</title><year>1993</year><authors><author org="Sloan School of Management Massachusetts Institute of Technology Cambridge, Massachusetts" id="343986580">Wanda J. Orlikowski</author></authors><n_citation>1273</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>789477022</reference><reference>1569587475</reference><reference>1965001338</reference><reference>1993134101</reference><reference>2049546814</reference><reference>2055800832</reference><reference>2128992662</reference><reference>2138672502</reference><reference>2162213353</reference><reference>2166624200</reference><reference>2913217271</reference><reference>2948869544</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/249774</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44057">Social environment</keyword><keyword weight="0.56913">Grounded theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.54169">Management information systems</keyword><keyword weight="0.43071">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48113">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.49575">Implementation</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">System development</keyword><keyword weight="0.56238">Computer-aided software engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.54033">Empirical research</keyword><keyword weight="0.47548">Management science</keyword></keywords><publisher>Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT), Sloan School of Management</publisher><abstract>This paper presents the findings of an empirical study into two organizationsu0027 experiences with the adoption and use of CASE tools over time. Using a grounded theory research approach, the study characterizes the organizationsu0027 experiences in terms of processes of incremental or radical organizational change. These findings are used to develop a theoretical framework for conceptualizing the organizational issues around the adoption and use of these tools-issues that have been largely missing from contemporary discussions of CASE tools. The paper thus has important implications for research and practice. Specifically, the framework and findings suggest that in order to account for the experiences and outcomes associated with CASE tools, researchers should consider the social context of systems development, the intentions and actions of key players, and the implementation process followed by the organization. Similarly, the paper suggests that practitioners will be better able to manage their organizationsu0027 experiences with CASE tools if they understand that such implementations involve a process of organizational change over time and not merely the installation of a new technology.</abstract></paper>