<paper id="1985815525"><title>Locating application data across service discovery domains</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="University of California Los Angeles; Los Angeles CA" id="2105267340">Paul Castro</author><author org="University of California Los Angeles; Los Angeles CA" id="2974747616">Benjamin Greenstein</author><author org="University of California Los Angeles; Los Angeles CA" id="2033368653">Richard Muntz</author><author org="IBM T.J. Watson Research Center, 30 Saw Mill River Road, Hawthorne, NY" id="2082166982">Chatschik Bisdikian</author><author org="IBM T.J. Watson Research Center, 30 Saw Mill River Road, Hawthorne, NY" id="1277508527">Parviz Kermani</author><author org="Columbia University, 1214 Amsterdam Ave., Mail Code: 0401, New York, NY" id="702461222">Maria Papadopouli</author></authors><n_citation>47</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1513710402</reference><reference>1735967030</reference><reference>1989163006</reference><reference>2122269925</reference><reference>2125855750</reference><reference>2137899328</reference><reference>2148251644</reference><reference>2156384678</reference></references><venue id="1123349196" type="C">ACM/IEEE International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking</venue><doi>10.1145/381677.381681</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.4465">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.5441">Directory</keyword><keyword weight="0.53359">Data cluster</keyword><keyword weight="0.51871">Data sharing</keyword><keyword weight="0.46795">Computer network</keyword><keyword weight="0.55553">Protocol overhead</keyword><keyword weight="0.49317">Ubiquitous computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.43443">Hierarchy</keyword><keyword weight="0.61493">Service discovery</keyword><keyword weight="0.62563">Directory service</keyword><keyword weight="0.46092">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>The bulk of proposed pervasive computing devices such as PDAs and cellular telephones operate as thin clients within a larger infrastructure. To access services within their local environment, these devices participate in a service discovery protocol which involves a master directory that registers all services available in the local environment. These directories typically are isolated from each other. Devices that move across service discovery domains have no access to information outside their current local domain. In this paper we propose an application-level protocol called VIA that enables data sharing among discovery domains. Each directory maintains a table of active links to other directories that share related information. A set of linked directories forms a data cluster that can be queried by devices for information. The data cluster is distributed, self-organizing, responsive to data mobility, and robust to failures. Using application-defined data schemas, clusters organize themselves into a hierarchy for efficient querying and network resource usage. Through analysis and simulation we describe the behavior of VIA under different workloads and show that the protocol overhead for both maintaining a cluster and handling failures grows slowly with the number of gateways.</abstract></paper>