<paper id="1543585825"><title>A practical and provably secure scheme for publicly verifiable secret sharing and its applications</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="NTT Laboratories" id="97468126">Eiichiro Fujisaki</author><author org="NTT Laboratories" id="2142935726">Tatsuaki Okamoto</author></authors><n_citation>115</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1497619716</reference><reference>1559728000</reference><reference>1603031068</reference><reference>1837145606</reference><reference>1850675439</reference><reference>1885156594</reference><reference>1979215153</reference><reference>2043210833</reference><reference>2142968417</reference><reference>2168970529</reference></references><venue id="1140213147" type="C">Theory and Application of Cryptographic Techniques</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0054115</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.57163">Secret sharing</keyword><keyword weight="0.43318">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.52136">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.57625">Commitment scheme</keyword><keyword weight="0.51278">Cryptosystem</keyword><keyword weight="0.43216">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.63323">Verifiable secret sharing</keyword><keyword weight="0.53172">Public-key cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.57658">Key escrow</keyword><keyword weight="0.42253">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.50159">Discrete logarithm</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>A publicly verifiable secret sharing (PVSS) scheme, named by Stadler in [Sta96], is a special VSS scheme in which anyone, not only the shareholders, can verify that the secret shares are correctly distributed. The property of public verifiability is what the first proposed VSS scheme [CGMA85] incorporated but later protocols [GMW87, Fel87, Ped91] failed to include. PVSS can provide some interesting properties in the systems using VSS. For instance, it gives a practical solution to (k, l)-threshold VSS assuming no broadcast channel. Stadler proposed two PVSS protocols: one is as secure as the Decision-Diffie-Hellman problem and the other is not formally discussed about security. This paper presents a practical and provably secure PVSS scheme which is O(¦v¦) times more efficient than Stadleru0027s PVSS schemes where ¦v¦ denotes the size of the secret. It can be incorporated into various cryptosystems based on the factoring and the discrete logarithm to transform them into publicly verifiable key escrow (PVKE) systems. In addition, those key escrow cryptosystems can be easily modified into the verifiable partial key escrow (VPKE) ones with the property of delayed recovery [BG97]. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first realization of a VPKE cryptosystem based on the factoring with the delayed recovery.</abstract></paper>