<paper id="1977121595"><title>Complexity of query processing in databases with OR-objects</title><year>1989</year><authors><author org="Department of Computer Science, Rutgers University, New Brunswick NJ" id="152915441">T. Imielinski</author><author org="Department of Computer Science, Rutgers University, New Brunswick NJ" id="2478357153">K. Vadaparty</author></authors><n_citation>39</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1979514837</reference><reference>1989783863</reference><reference>1990391007</reference><reference>2065251436</reference><reference>2066406253</reference><reference>2077202644</reference><reference>2088094394</reference></references><venue id="1184151122" type="C">Symposium on Principles of Database Systems</venue><doi>10.1145/73721.73726</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.68649">Conjunctive query</keyword><keyword weight="0.45479">Open problem</keyword><keyword weight="0.44719">Negation</keyword><keyword weight="0.51532">Graph isomorphism</keyword><keyword weight="0.44135">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.53213">P</keyword><keyword weight="0.45729">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.43372">Predicate (grammar)</keyword><keyword weight="0.44919">Syntax</keyword><keyword weight="0.57027">Boolean conjunctive query</keyword><keyword weight="0.42056">Database</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>If ground disjunctive facts are admitted into a database the data complexity of conjunctive queries grows from PTIME into CoNP with some simple examples of CoNP-Complete conjunctive queries. A natural question which arises in this context is whether it is possible to syntactically characterize those queries which are “bad” (i.e. CoNP-Complete) from those that are “good” (i.e. with PTIME data complexity) given a predefined u0027pattern” of disjunctions in the database. In this paper, we study the data complexity of conjunctive queries. We give a complete syntactic characterization of CoNP-Complete conjunctive queries for a class of disjunctive databases called OR-Databases. Our results can be used in complexity tailored design where design decisions are motivated by complexity of query processing. Also, we establish that a similar complete syntactic characterization for disjunctive queries, with negation allowed only on base predicates, would answer the open problem “Does Graph Isomorphism belong to PTIME or is it NP-Complete?”.</abstract></paper>