<paper id="1982227476"><title>A Designer’s Guide to KEMs</title><year>2003</year><authors><author org="Univ. of London#TAB#" id="2164332690">Alexander W. Dent</author></authors><n_citation>55</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1506470410</reference><reference>1516512945</reference><reference>1525812338</reference><reference>1529862094</reference><reference>1589586740</reference><reference>1660562555</reference><reference>1706109527</reference><reference>1871739018</reference><reference>2052267638</reference><reference>2156186849</reference><reference>2157679418</reference><reference>2161195863</reference></references><venue id="106296714" type="J">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-40974-8_12</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.54155">Symmetric-key algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.5433">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.44415">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.437">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.51415">Random oracle</keyword><keyword weight="0.64005">Key encapsulation</keyword><keyword weight="0.58643">Encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.44945">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.54606">Trapdoor function</keyword><keyword weight="0.63529">Probabilistic encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.55048">Public-key cryptography</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>A generic or KEM-DEM hybrid construction is a formal method for combining asymmetric and symmetric encryption techniques to give an efficient, provably secure public-key encryption scheme. This method combines an asymmetric key encapsulation mechanism (KEM) with a symmetric data encapsulation mechanism (DEM). A KEM is a probabilistic algorithm that produces a random symmetric key and an asymmetric encryption of that key. A DEM is a deterministic algorithm that takes a message and a symmetric key and encrypts the message under that key. Each of these components must satisfy its own security conditions if the overall scheme is to be secure. In this paper we describe generic constructions for provably secure KEMs based on weak encryption algorithms. We analyse the two most popular techniques for constructing a KEM and note that they are either overly complex or based on needlessly strong assumptions about the security of the underlying trapdoor function. Hence we propose two new, simple methods for constructing a KEM where the security of the KEM is based on weak assumptions about the underlying function. Lastly we propose a new KEM based on the Rabin function that is both efficient and secure, and is the first KEM to be proposed whose security depends upon the intractability of factoring.</abstract></paper>