<paper id="1974396457"><title>A Sequent Calculus for Type Assignment</title><year>1977</year><authors><author org="" id="1462771379">Jonathan P. Seldin</author></authors><n_citation>8</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>2075824323</reference><reference>2115610240</reference><reference>2149837936</reference></references><venue id="177675236" type="J">Journal of Symbolic Logic</venue><doi>10.2307/2272314</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.43994">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.61989">Natural deduction</keyword><keyword weight="0.59328">Sequent calculus</keyword><keyword weight="0.59905">Noncommutative logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.56641">Mathematical proof</keyword><keyword weight="0.61384">Sequent</keyword><keyword weight="0.53652">Counterexample</keyword><keyword weight="0.67568">Cut-elimination theorem</keyword><keyword weight="0.40562">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.58875">Curry–Howard correspondence</keyword></keywords><publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher><abstract>u0027 The first version of this paper was written in March, 1973. The subsequent revisions concern the exposition and not the mathematical results. An abstract of this paper appeared in Notices of the American Mathematical Society, vol. 20 (1973), p. A-502, no. 73T-E85. This research was supported by Illinois State appropriated funds administered by the Mathematics Department of Southern Illinois University at Carbondale. 2 The system also appears in [7, ?9C], and was originally proposed in [14, ?3E6]. 3 Thus, the equivalence with the natural deduction formulation (T-formulation) also fails unless Rule Cut is postulated for the system. Furthermore, [7, Theorems 9.19 and 9.20 and Corollary 9.20.1] are false and the proof of [7, Theorem 9.21] is invalid although the theorem can be proved another way. A correction to this part of [7, ?9C] has been indicated (without the details of the proofs, as is the basic policy of this work) in the recently published Italian edition, and will appear in any future printings of the English edition. [14, ?3E6] and [3, ?14E6] should be deleted. 4 It is true in A-calculus that the corresponding property holds; however, the possibility of using A-calculus for this system was already excluded for the reason stated in [3, ?14E6]. This defect in the proof was pointed out to me by Roger Hindley in a letter dated October 27, 1972; I found the counterexample in the process of trying to patch up the proof. 5 This is essentially the same as the system of Girard in [5, Chapter 1, ?2]; Girardu0027s system is an extension of ordinary functionality in that it has additional primitive formation rules for types, but the sequent calculus formulation for it is constructed on the same principles as the system of [2].</abstract></paper>