<paper id="1779750950"><title>The Semantic Clause Graph Procedure - A First Overview</title><year>1986</year><authors><author org="University, FB Informatik" id="2641069129">Hans Jürgen Ohlbach</author></authors><n_citation>4</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>134991542</reference><reference>1480491343</reference><reference>1970045008</reference><reference>1988225490</reference><reference>1993517298</reference><reference>2002861469</reference><reference>2047669821</reference><reference>2058156127</reference><reference>2100738443</reference><reference>2152037678</reference><reference>2153131284</reference><reference>2740900434</reference><reference>2913631015</reference><reference>2914936697</reference></references><venue id="" type="">GWAI-86 und 2. Österreichische Artificial-Intelligence-Tagung</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-642-71385-9_23</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.44581">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.45469">Natural language processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.59773">Soundness</keyword><keyword weight="0.55121">Rule of inference</keyword><keyword weight="0.50549">Completeness (statistics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.51471">Semantics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The classic resolution principle is extended such that knowledge about the underlying semantics can be incorporated and control information can be represented explicitely. This new inference rule, called “conditioned theory resolution“ is a combination of M. Stickel’s theory resolution and G.P. Huet’s constrained resolution. It is the basis for the semantic clause graph procedure, a modification of Kowalski’s connection graph procedure. The nodes of a semantic clause graph are still labelled with literals, but the links connect sets of literals which are, under certain conditions, contradictory relative to some special theory. The theoretical description of this method provides a general framework to define combinations of special purpose inference rules and to prove their completeness and soundness. Semantic clause graphs based on conditioned theory resolution are the kemel datastructure for a redesigned version of the Markgraph Karl Refutation Procedure.</abstract></paper>