<paper id="83160502"><title>A KNOWLEDGE INTENSIVE APPROACH TO CONCEPT INDUCTION</title><year>1988</year><authors><author org="Dipartimento di Informatica, Universita' di Torino, C.so Svizzera 185, 10149 - Torino, Italy" id="2789751053">Francesco Bergadano</author><author org="Dipartimento di Informatica, Universita' di Torino, C.so Svizzera 185, 10149 - Torino, Italy" id="2039763176">Attilio Giordana</author></authors><n_citation>79</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>92063309</reference><reference>96818074</reference><reference>1523646877</reference><reference>1535993640</reference><reference>1552124635</reference><reference>1553997986</reference><reference>1975420837</reference><reference>1999038366</reference><reference>2024868117</reference><reference>2027276583</reference><reference>2067642555</reference><reference>2101602574</reference><reference>2159965310</reference><reference>2180885055</reference><reference>2974365732</reference></references><venue id="1180662882" type="C">International Conference on Machine Learning</venue><doi>10.1016/B978-0-934613-64-4.50037-2</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Learning set</keyword><keyword weight="0.5971">Domain knowledge</keyword><keyword weight="0.64441">Concept class</keyword><keyword weight="0.44751">Discriminant</keyword><keyword weight="0.46396">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.54227">Domain theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.47124">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.51199">Operationalization</keyword><keyword weight="0.46522">Counterexample</keyword><keyword weight="0.46641">Machine learning</keyword></keywords><publisher>Morgan Kaufmann</publisher><abstract>In this paper we present a concept acquisition methodology that uses data (concept examples and counterexamples), domain knowledge and tentative concept descriptions in an integrated way. Domain knowledge can be incomplete and/or incorrect with respect to the given data; moreover, the tentative concept descriptions can be expressed in a form which is not operational. The methodology is aimed at producing discriminant and operational concept descriptions, by integrating inductive and deductive learning. In fact, the domain theory is used in a deductive process, that tries to operationalize the tentative concept descriptions, but the obtained results are tested on the whole learning set rather than on a single example. Moreover, deduction is interleaved with the application of data-driven inductive steps. In this way, a search in a constrained space of possible descriptions can help overcome some limitations of the domain theory (e.g. inconsistency). The method has been tested in the framework of the inductive learning system, “ML-SMART,”, previously developed by the authors, and a simple example is also given.</abstract></paper>