<paper id="1522706628"><title>Non-interactive zaps and new techniques for NIZK</title><year>2006</year><authors><author org="Computer Science Department, UCLA, Los Angeles, CA#TAB#" id="2138263338">Jens Groth</author><author org="Computer Science Department, UCLA, Los Angeles, CA#TAB#" id="1482108584">Rafail Ostrovsky</author><author org="Computer Science Department, UCLA, Los Angeles, CA#TAB#" id="2159933393">Amit Sahai</author></authors><n_citation>112</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1548963432</reference><reference>1577653766</reference><reference>1590713339</reference><reference>1626447266</reference><reference>1970606468</reference><reference>1995926987</reference><reference>2086042811</reference><reference>2132951912</reference><reference>2142968417</reference><reference>2614003720</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/11818175_6</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44039">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.42092">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.51415">Proof theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.43415">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.50992">Mathematical proof</keyword><keyword weight="0.57512">Witness-indistinguishable proof</keyword><keyword weight="0.49505">Security parameter</keyword><keyword weight="0.47048">String (computer science)</keyword><keyword weight="0.48942">Gas meter prover</keyword><keyword weight="0.55731">Zero-knowledge proof</keyword><keyword weight="0.47177">Diffie–Hellman problem</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In 2000, Dwork and Naor proved a very surprising result: that there exist “Zaps”, two-round witness-indistinguishable proofs in the plain model without a common reference string, where the Verifier asks a single question and the Prover sends back a single answer. This left open the following tantalizing question: does there exist a non-interactive witness indistinguishable proof, where the Prover sends a single message to the Verifier for some non-trivial NP-language? In 2003, Barak, Ong and Vadhan answered this question affirmatively by derandomizing Dwork and Naoru0027s construction under a complexity theoretic assumption, namely that Hitting Set Generators against co-nondeterministic circuits this :[99],"paper, we construct non-interactive Zaps for all NP-languages. We accomplish this by introducing new techniques for building Non-Interactive Zero Knowledge (NIZK) Proof and Argument systems, which we believe to be of independent interest, and then modifying these to yield our main result. Our construction is based on the Decisional Linear Assumption, which can be seen as a bilinear group variant of the Decisional Diffie-Hellman our single message witness-indistinguishable :[165],"proof for Circuit Satisfiability is of size O(k|C|) bits, where k is a security parameter, and |C| is the size of the circuit. This is much more efficient than previous constructions of 1- or 2-move Zaps.</abstract></paper>