<paper id="1580920982"><title>On the Security Properties of OAEP as an All-or-Nothing Transform</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="MIT — Laboratory for Computer Science" id="2145438289">Victor Boyko</author></authors><n_citation>76</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1519969013</reference><reference>1552695147</reference><reference>1575126375</reference><reference>1809369763</reference><reference>1987667503</reference><reference>1996360405</reference><reference>2047925852</reference><reference>2052267638</reference><reference>2055993618</reference><reference>2103221883</reference><reference>2108834246</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-48405-1_32</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.51316">Semantic security</keyword><keyword weight="0.50835">Block cipher</keyword><keyword weight="0.60164">Optimal asymmetric encryption padding</keyword><keyword weight="0.43155">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.51483">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.56543">Concrete security</keyword><keyword weight="0.67036">All-or-nothing transform</keyword><keyword weight="0.52872">Random oracle</keyword><keyword weight="0.52487">Encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.43436">Theoretical computer science</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><abstract>This paper studies All-or-Nothing Transforms (AONTs), which have been proposed by Rivest as a mode of operation for block ciphers. An AONT is an unkeyed, invertible, randomized transformation, with the property that it is hard to invert unless all of the output is known. Applications of AONTs include improving the security and speed of encryption. We give several formal definitions of security for AONTs that are stronger and more suited to practical applications than the original definitions. We then prove that Optimal Asymmetric Encryption Padding (OAEP) satisfies these definitions (in the random oracle model). This is the first construction of an AONT that has been proven secure in the strong sense. Our bound on the adversaryu0027s advantage is nearly optimal, in the sense that no adversary can do substantially better against the OAEP than by exhaustive search. We also show that no AONT can achieve substantially better security than OAEP.</abstract></paper>