<paper id="1515104861"><title>Citizen Participation in Public Affairs</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="University of Napier" id="2090530440">Ann Macintosh</author><author org="University of Napier" id="2108510001">Ella Smith</author></authors><n_citation>31</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2138504130</reference></references><venue id="1132800348" type="C">Electronic Government</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-46138-8_41</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.5374">Civil society</keyword><keyword weight="0.4895">Best practice</keyword><keyword weight="0.37797">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48012">Public relations</keyword><keyword weight="0.52622">Direct democracy</keyword><keyword weight="0.51274">Social engagement</keyword><keyword weight="0.52046">Democracy</keyword><keyword weight="0.46382">Sustainable development</keyword><keyword weight="0.53023">Government</keyword><keyword weight="0.46245">Virtual community</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Reflecting on the European Commissions stated aim to broaden democracy this paper examines the nature of e-participation and considers concepts of democracy and issues surrounding citizen participation in pubic affairs. The paper describes how citizens are engaging with government and with each other about policy related issues that concern them, using technology specially designed for the purpose. The paper describes a case study of electronic participation developed for the Environment Group of the Scottish Executive in Summer 2001. Using the empirical data from this study the paper explores best practice guidelines for governments who wish to engage citizens in policymaking. The difficult task of addressing the requirements of all stakeholders, i.e. government, civil society organizations (CSOs) and citizens in designing the technology is discussed. The use and moderation of the electronic tools over the engagement period is assessed. Finally, the paper considers how the use of electronic tools can be monitored and their impact on citizen participation and the decision-making of government be assessed.</abstract></paper>