<paper id="1979631724"><title>A methodology for supporting existing CODASYL databases with new database machines</title><year>1978</year><authors><author org="" id="2251854863">Jayanta Banerjee</author><author org="" id="1098898639">David K. Hsiao</author></authors><n_citation>10</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1982405273</reference><reference>1983959468</reference><reference>2041415271</reference><reference>2074302481</reference><reference>2138398171</reference><reference>2159931520</reference></references><venue id="" type="">Proceedings of the 1978 annual conference on </venue><doi>10.1145/800178.810163</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.63677">Database tuning</keyword><keyword weight="0.64125">Database model</keyword><keyword weight="0.46121">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.6785">CODASYL</keyword><keyword weight="0.63621">View</keyword><keyword weight="0.64767">Database design</keyword><keyword weight="0.63796">Database schema</keyword><keyword weight="0.63073">Database testing</keyword><keyword weight="0.66872">Database machine</keyword><keyword weight="0.46504">Database</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>In this paper, an attempt is made to show that conventional database management system software, in particular those of CODASYL type, can be effectively replaced by database machines with good performance. The replacement of CODASYL system software involves two main steps: (i) In order to preserve the notions of CODASYL records, sets,-areas, and others, we need a methodology for database transformation so that an existing CODASYL database may be transformed into suitable formats for storing and retrieving in the database machine. (2) For the purpose of allowing existing application programs written in a CODASYL data sublanguage to store, retrieve and manipulate CODASYL data in the new environment without reprogramming, we need to be able to translate the data sublanguage calls dynamically into the commands of the database machine. Such process is termed query translation . In this paper, a database transformation methodology and a query translation process are presented which ensure that the content-addressability and parallel read-out capability of the database machine are used to advantage. The machine in consideration is known as the database computer (DBC) and is also briefly reviewed. DBC is one of the u0027typicalu0027 new back-end machines for database management which utilize the emerging hardware and the modification of existing hardware for performance gain and capacity increase.</abstract></paper>