<paper id="1531197527"><title>Web assessment-measuring the effectiveness of electronic commerce sites going beyond traditional marketing paradigms</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="Inst. for Media &amp; Commun. Manage., St. Gallen Univ., Switzerland" id="2210204088">P. Schubert</author><author org="" id="676298605">D. Selz</author></authors><n_citation>112</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>63153948</reference><reference>97221455</reference><reference>1604380167</reference><reference>1921373204</reference><reference>2022546092</reference><reference>2037717074</reference><reference>2102711197</reference><reference>2145903312</reference><reference>2158182745</reference></references><venue id="1164519180" type="C">Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences</venue><doi>10.1109/HICSS.1999.772941</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.66388">Web development</keyword><keyword weight="0.59369">Marketing management</keyword><keyword weight="0.61742">Marketing research</keyword><keyword weight="0.47765">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.59808">Business marketing</keyword><keyword weight="0.44129">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.60644">Digital marketing</keyword><keyword weight="0.67122">Internet presence management</keyword><keyword weight="0.62247">E-commerce</keyword><keyword weight="0.45193">Marketing</keyword><keyword weight="0.63975">The Internet</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><abstract>Successfully conducting business on the Internet calls for new marketing paradigms that meet the requirements of the unique combination of its inherent characteristics: electronic markets, technological platform, and marketing issues. In this context, electronic markets are the framework in which market transactions are performed on the Internet. Underlying Internet technology forces marketing activities to be different from the ones applied to traditional sales channels and performance marketing is the essential ingredient for creating the best offering for the customer. The Web Assessment model unites these constituting characteristics into one approach for the evaluation of commercial Web sites. Based upon the Web Assessment methodology a software tool was created in order to enable Web users to make an online evaluation of their favorite Web sites. The paper describes the underlying model and presents the first observations which could be made when using the tool. The findings outlined in this paper were collected from participating Internet users who completed the online questionnaire. The data is a collection of subjective user assessments of various Internet commerce applications. There are various kinds of observations which can be made with the Web Assessment tool.</abstract></paper>