<paper id="24658438"><title>An evaluation of research productivity in academic IT</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="Colorado State University" id="1983295026">Susan Athey</author><author org="Colorado State University" id="2013438652">John Plotnicki</author></authors><n_citation>62</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>2004470428</reference><reference>2038907453</reference></references><venue id="7020383" type="J">Communications of The Ais</venue><doi>10.17705/1cais.00307</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46859">Publication</keyword><keyword weight="0.43096">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.49604">Portfolio</keyword><keyword weight="0.50911">Publishing</keyword><keyword weight="0.39526">Engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.46176">Library science</keyword></keywords><publisher>Association for Information Systems</publisher><abstract>Scholarly research continues to be a significant component of a faculty member’s portfolio. The evaluation of the quality and quantity of that research is becoming increasingly important for tenure and promotion decisions and post-tenure reviews. Using surveys, several recent articles attempted to rank or group IT journals by quality perceptions. This study extends these previous studies by considering the quantity dimension of scholarly research by investigating the number of publications that appear in a set of top-tier IT journals by both individual author and institution. Data is presented on the most prolific publishers and the most productive IS departments in publishing in these "premier" journals. 1223 authors from 389 different universities were published with an average of 1.41 authors per IS article. Only three non-U.S. universities (National University of Singapore, Queenu0027s University, and University of British Columbia) are in the top 24 publishing universities. 73% of researchers who published in these "premier" journals publish less than one adjusted count article in a top-tier journal in 5 years using the adjusted count. Only 49 authors had their names on 5 or more top-tier IS articles in 5 years leading to the conclusion that achieving tenure</abstract></paper>