<paper id="1965187559"><title>The effects of relational and entity-relationship data models on query performance of end users</title><year>1989</year><authors><author org="University of Tennessee at Chattanooga,USA" id="2257133698">W. J. K. Jih</author><author org="Winthrop College , USA" id="2974545690">D. A. Bradbard</author><author org="Auburn University, USA." id="2974334232">C. A. Snyder</author><author org="Texas Instrum., USA#TAB#" id="2649755936">N. G. A. Thompson</author></authors><n_citation>50</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>63493895</reference><reference>2049650335</reference><reference>2059311901</reference><reference>2088873887</reference><reference>2090253867</reference><reference>2130332717</reference></references><venue id="129573059" type="J">International Journal of Human-computer Studies / International Journal of Man-machine Studies</venue><doi>10.1016/0020-7373(89)90007-2</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45707">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.62091">Database model</keyword><keyword weight="0.45678">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.65019">View</keyword><keyword weight="0.45192">Human–computer interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.47008">Natural language processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.65078">Query optimization</keyword><keyword weight="0.62109">Semi-structured model</keyword><keyword weight="0.62211">Database design</keyword><keyword weight="0.61648">Query by Example</keyword><keyword weight="0.6162">Online aggregation</keyword><keyword weight="0.61703">Relational model</keyword></keywords><publisher>Academic Press Ltd.</publisher><abstract>Abstract In database systems the end user interacts with the database at the external schema level. At this level the user sees only the logical structure of the database that is relevant to his/her work. Both the relational and the entity-relationship model have proponents arguing that one data model is superior to the other when used in the end user environment. However, a literature review indicated that these arguments have not been based on empirical results from a systematic inquiry. The study reported here examined this issue through a controlled experiment using query writing as the task. Our basic assumption was that if one data model was superior to the other, then the superiority of the model would be reflected in the useru0027s query writing performance. In addition, this superiority would be demonstrated on both simple and complex tasks. Query writing performance was measured by three variables: number of syntax errors, number of semantic errors, and amount of time to complete queries. The results indicated that subjects using the relational model made fewer syntax errors, but required more time to complete a query. No significant differences in the number of semantic errors were found between the two data models. Based on these results, neither the relational nor the entity-relational data model was clearly superior when used as the interface between a database system and the end user. As expected, the more complex tasks caused more syntax and semantic errors, and required more time to complete.</abstract></paper>