<paper id="1597431254"><title>Piggy bank: experience the semantic web inside your web browser</title><year>2005</year><authors><author org="MIT Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory, The Stata Center, Cambridge, MA" id="2156123617">David Huynh</author><author org="MIT Digital Libraries Research Group, Cambridge, MA#TAB#" id="2033054710">Stefano Mazzocchi</author><author org="MIT Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory, The Stata Center, Cambridge, MA" id="2305153757">David Karger</author></authors><n_citation>174</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1989113549</reference><reference>2042616792</reference><reference>2090656662</reference><reference>2118322263</reference><reference>2129714799</reference><reference>2132805951</reference><reference>2137891816</reference><reference>2138405339</reference><reference>2156492599</reference></references><venue id="1155608529" type="C">International Semantic Web Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/11574620_31</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.70281">Static web page</keyword><keyword weight="0.72903">Web API</keyword><keyword weight="0.47762">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.7076">Web page</keyword><keyword weight="0.82087">Semantic Web Stack</keyword><keyword weight="0.43111">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.7142">Web standards</keyword><keyword weight="0.7351">Data Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.71553">Semantic Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.76399">Social Semantic Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.44566">Database</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The Semantic Web Initiative envisions a Web wherein information is offered free of presentation, allowing more effective exchange and mixing across web sites and across web pages. But without substantial Semantic Web content, few tools will be written to consume it; without many such tools, there is little appeal to publish Semantic Web :[53],"break this chicken-and-egg problem, thus enabling more flexible informa-tion access, we have created a web browser extension called Piggy Bankthat lets users make use of Semantic Web content within Web content as users browse the Web. Wherever Semantic Web content is not available, Piggy Bank can invoke screenscrapers to re-structure information within web pages into Semantic Web format. Through the use of Semantic Web technologies, Piggy Bank provides direct, immediate benefits to users in their use of the existing Web. Thus, the ex-istence of even just a few Semantic Web-enabled sites or a few scrapers already benefits users. Piggy Bank thereby offers an easy, incremental upgrade path to users without requiring a wholesale adoption of the Semantic Webu0027s :[172],"further improve this Semantic Web experience, we have created Semantic Bank, a web server application that lets Piggy Bank users share the Semantic Web information they have collected, enabling collaborative efforts to build so-phisticated Semantic Web information repositories through simple, everydayu0027s use of Piggy Bank.</abstract></paper>