<paper id="1524343817"><title>Process tracing methods in decision support systems research: exploring the black box</title><year>1987</year><authors><author org="Univ. of Houston, Houston,TX#TAB#" id="2668343273">Peter Todd</author><author org="UNIVERSITY OF BRITISH COLUMBIA Vancouver, Canada" id="37162533">Izak Benbasat</author></authors><n_citation>190</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>89327545</reference><reference>2008710914</reference><reference>2023495440</reference><reference>2029320526</reference><reference>2036113824</reference><reference>2047615504</reference><reference>2122418187</reference><reference>2164832405</reference><reference>2177554891</reference><reference>2192243333</reference><reference>2795596704</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/248979</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.51169">Black box (phreaking)</keyword><keyword weight="0.56904">Protocol analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.44156">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.55792">Decision support system</keyword><keyword weight="0.51152">Black box</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Decision process</keyword><keyword weight="0.63177">Process tracing</keyword><keyword weight="0.51349">Strengths and weaknesses</keyword><keyword weight="0.46136">Management science</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>An overview is provided of the appficability to DSS research of process tracing methodologies in general and verbal protocol analysis in particular. Rationale is developed for why process tracing methods are an important addition to the inventory of methodologies available to researchers, stressing the need to explore the "black box" of decision processes. A variety of process tracing methods are presented, along with their relative strengths and weaknesses. Verbal protocol analysis is discussed as a particularly promising method for use in DSS research. The nature of verbal protocols is outlined and methods for analysis are reviewed. The criticisms of this method and the controversy surrounding its use are discussed, and an assessment of the validity of these criticisms is provided. Finally, areas of DSS research in which protocols may prove valuable are identified and relevant studies are examined.</abstract></paper>