<paper id="1975078815"><title>Calibration of hand-held camera sequences for plenoptic modeling</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="Inst. for Comput. Sci., Kiel Univ., Germany" id="2128502969">R. Koch</author><author org="" id="2198039525">M. Pollefeys</author><author org="" id="2176767162">B. Heigl</author><author org="" id="2107867962">L. Van Gool</author><author org="" id="2129074962">H. Niemann</author></authors><n_citation>75</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1482517735</reference><reference>1488812736</reference><reference>1528329704</reference><reference>1543549646</reference><reference>1548828277</reference><reference>1549739843</reference><reference>1551246377</reference><reference>1573617947</reference><reference>1943823759</reference><reference>2063366997</reference><reference>2063599328</reference><reference>2111169574</reference><reference>2124535811</reference><reference>2134211982</reference><reference>2151285962</reference><reference>2294985758</reference></references><venue id="1164975091" type="C">International Conference on Computer Vision</venue><doi>10.1109/ICCV.1999.791277</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47386">Iterative reconstruction</keyword><keyword weight="0.4738">Computer vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.45835">Computer graphics (images)</keyword><keyword weight="0.41315">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47271">Computational geometry</keyword><keyword weight="0.66609">Camera auto-calibration</keyword><keyword weight="0.46634">Ground truth</keyword><keyword weight="0.48843">Solid modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.6298">Depth map</keyword><keyword weight="0.59833">Rendering (computer graphics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.6669">Image-based modeling and rendering</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>We focus on the calibration of very long image sequences from a hand-held camera that samples the viewing sphere of a scene. View sphere sampling is important for plenoptic (image-based) modeling that captures the appearance of a scene by storing images from all possible directions. The plenoptic approach is appealing since it allows, in principle, fast scene rendering of scenes with complex geometry and surface reflections, without the need for an explicit geometrical scene model. However the acquired images have to be calibrated, and current approaches mostly use pre-calibrated acquisition systems. This limits the generality of the approach. We propose using an uncalibrated hand-held camera only. The image sequence is acquired by simply waving the camera around the scene objects, creating a zigzag scan path over the viewing sphere. We extend the sequential camera tracking of an existing structure-from-motion approach to the calibration of a mesh of viewpoints. Novel views are generated by piecewise mapping and interpolating the new image from the nearest viewpoints according to the viewpoint mesh. Local depth map estimates enhance the rendering process. Extensive experiments with ground truth data and hand-held sequences confirm the performance of our approach.</abstract></paper>