<paper id="1826290430"><title>StatStream: statistical monitoring of thousands of data streams in real time</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, Department of Computer Science, New York University#TAB#" id="2148474985">Yunyue Zhu</author><author org="Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, Department of Computer Science, New York University#TAB#" id="2082974086">Dennis Shasha</author></authors><n_citation>560</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1499049447</reference><reference>1562291184</reference><reference>1991962718</reference><reference>2001103857</reference><reference>2004110412</reference><reference>2004154913</reference><reference>2024766881</reference><reference>2036557187</reference><reference>2042591571</reference><reference>2053062040</reference><reference>2068714596</reference><reference>2081189989</reference><reference>2097983034</reference><reference>2100369465</reference><reference>2106163100</reference><reference>2110825163</reference><reference>2112452856</reference><reference>2114944618</reference><reference>2128061541</reference><reference>2138087993</reference><reference>2148039410</reference><reference>2163150150</reference><reference>2952622241</reference></references><venue id="1133523790" type="C">Very Large Data Bases</venue><doi>10.1016/B978-155860869-6/50039-1</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.52036">Data structure</keyword><keyword weight="0.50538">Time series</keyword><keyword weight="0.4631">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.56692">Data stream mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.52969">Sliding window protocol</keyword><keyword weight="0.44608">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48938">Response time</keyword><keyword weight="0.51355">Synthetic data</keyword><keyword weight="0.5113">Discrete Fourier transform</keyword><keyword weight="0.48851">Computation</keyword></keywords><publisher>VLDB Endowment</publisher><abstract>Consider the problem of monitoring tens of thousands of time series data streams in an online fashion and making decisions based on them. In addition to single stream statistics such as average and standard deviation, we also want to find high correlations among all pairs of streams. A stock market trader might use such a tool to spot arbitrage opportunities. This paper proposes efficient methods for solving this problem based on Discrete Fourier Transforms and a three level time interval hierarchy. Extensive experiments on synthetic data and real world financial trading data show that our algorithm beats the direct computation approach by several orders of magnitude. It also improves on previous Fourier Transform approaches by allowing the efficient computation of time-delayed correlation over any size sliding window and any time delay. Correlation also lends itself to an efficient grid-based data structure. The result is the first algorithm that we know of to compute correlations over thousands of data streams in real time. The algorithm is incremental, has fixed response time, and can monitor the pairwise correlations of 10,000 streams on a single PC. The algorithm is embarrassingly parallelizable.</abstract></paper>