<paper id="1851462883"><title>Moving document collections online: the evolution of a shared repository</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="Xerox Palo Alto Research Center#TAB#" id="2073339349">Randall H. Trigg</author><author org="Xerox Palo Alto Research Center#TAB#" id="2018895726">Jeanette Blomberg</author><author org="Xerox Palo Alto Research Center#TAB#" id="2011668444">Lucy Suchman</author></authors><n_citation>66</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1589011413</reference><reference>1972252515</reference><reference>1976482843</reference><reference>1995644500</reference><reference>1999595135</reference><reference>2027240204</reference><reference>2027261940</reference><reference>2041513874</reference><reference>2084595050</reference><reference>2102475035</reference><reference>2119496217</reference><reference>2156492599</reference></references><venue id="1180389419" type="C">European Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work</venue><doi>10.1007/0-306-47316-X_18</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47162">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.52863">Workgroup</keyword><keyword weight="0.44019">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Classification scheme</keyword><keyword weight="0.41963">Coding (social sciences)</keyword><keyword weight="0.44375">Human–computer interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.445">Software</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Online document</keyword><keyword weight="0.49491">Digital media</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Design Document Listing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher><abstract>This paper reports on a work-oriented design project concerned with the question of how to migrate shared, workgroup document collections currently kept on paper online. Based in a civil engineering work group, the focus of our project is a document collection called the "project files," a heterogeneous mix of documents that serve as an ongoing resource for the group during a projectu0027s course as well as an archival record at its completion. We describe the dynamics of the standardized classification scheme in use for the project files, existing practices of document filing including routine troubles, and the prototype developed to move the project files online. The latter includes a configuration of hardware and software along with associated practices of document scanning, coding and search. We conclude with some reflections on the difficulties of maintaining alignment across paper and digital media in the migration to online document collections, and with a summary of the questions posed and answers provided by our project.</abstract></paper>