<paper id="1539207281"><title>Hidden-Vector Encryption with Groups of Prime Order</title><year>2008</year><authors><author org="Dipartimento di Informatica ed Applicazioni, Università di Salerno, Fisciano, (SA), Italy#TAB#" id="1982007364">Vincenzo Iovino</author><author org="Dipartimento di Informatica ed Applicazioni, Università di Salerno, Fisciano, (SA), Italy#TAB#" id="2291003365">Giuseppe Persiano</author></authors><n_citation>77</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1589843374</reference><reference>1596208550</reference><reference>2138001464</reference><reference>2151471396</reference><reference>2154448764</reference><reference>2161214567</reference><reference>2614003720</reference></references><venue id="2756132311" type="C">International Conference on Pairing-based Cryptography</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-85538-5_5</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.68419">Multiple encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.6874">Deterministic encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.73144">Attribute-based encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.67394">Plaintext-aware encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.68383">Encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.44474">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.66042">40-bit encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.68346">Probabilistic encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.65802">Filesystem-level encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.39468">Mathematics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Predicate encryption schemes are encryption schemes in which each ciphertext Ct is associated with a binary attribute vector and keys Kare associated with predicates. A key Kcan decrypt a ciphertext if and only if the attribute vector of the ciphertext satisfies the predicate of the key. Predicate encryption schemes can be used to implement fine-grained access control on encrypted data and to perform search on encrypted vector encryption schemes :[77],"[Boneh and Waters --- TCC 2007] are encryption schemes in which each ciphertext is associated with a binary vector and each key Kis associated with binary vector with "donu0027t care" entries (denoted with i¾?). Key Kcan decrypt ciphertext if and only if and agree for all ifor which $y_i\ne vector encryption schemes are :[160],"an important type of predicate encryption schemes as they can be used to construct more sophisticated predicate encryption schemes (supporting for example range and subset :[190],"give a construction for hidden-vector encryption from standard complexity assumptions on bilinear groups of prime order. Previous constructions were in bilinear groups of composite orderand thus resulted in less efficient schemes. Our construction is both payload-hiding and attribute-hiding meaning that also the privacy of the attribute vector, besides privacy of the cleartext, is guaranteed.</abstract></paper>