<paper id="1974265510"><title>BI as an assertion language for mutable data structures</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="Queen Mary and Westfield College, London. UK" id="2026582897">Samin S. Ishtiaq</author><author org="Queen Mary and Westfield College, London. UK" id="188470835">Peter W. O'Hearn</author></authors><n_citation>477</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>53688630</reference><reference>1507902915</reference><reference>1548258731</reference><reference>1563480347</reference><reference>1986057687</reference><reference>2008132476</reference><reference>2021081188</reference><reference>2026928233</reference><reference>2032767692</reference><reference>2067780727</reference><reference>2074070820</reference><reference>2075350371</reference><reference>2095224573</reference><reference>2097185397</reference><reference>2107905351</reference><reference>2120897738</reference><reference>2146724103</reference><reference>2158376721</reference><reference>2160255280</reference><reference>2167998587</reference><reference>2169907127</reference><reference>2170577595</reference><reference>2911227993</reference><reference>2911865844</reference></references><venue id="1160032607" type="C">Symposium on Principles of Programming Languages</venue><doi>10.1145/1988042.1988050</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.66613">Intuitionistic logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.45215">Programming language</keyword><keyword weight="0.43971">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.66836">Minimal logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.647">Multimodal logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.45114">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.67128">Bunched logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.66919">Many-valued logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.64143">Predicate logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.64689">Higher-order logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.66847">Intermediate logic</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>Reynolds has developed a logic for reasoning about mutable data structures in which the pre- and postconditions are written in an intuitionistic logic enriched with a spatial form of conjunction. We investigate the approach from the point of view of the logic BI of bunched implications of Ou0027Hearnand Pym. We begin by giving a model in which the law of the excluded middleholds, thus showing that the approach is compatible with classical logic. The relationship between the intuitionistic and classical versions of the system is established by a translation, analogous to a translation from intuitionistic logic into the modal logic S4. We also consider the question of completeness of the axioms. BIu0027s spatial implication is used to express weakest preconditions for object-component assignments, and an axiom for allocating a cons cell is shown to be complete under an interpretation of triplesthat allows a command to be applied to states with dangling pointers. We make this latter a feature, by incorporating an operation, and axiom, for disposing of memory. Finally, we describe a local character enjoyed by specifications in the logic, and show how this enables a class of frame axioms, which say what parts of the heap donu0027t change, to be inferred automatically.</abstract></paper>