<paper id="1507772788"><title>Designing pervasive brain-computer interfaces</title><year>2007</year><authors><author org="College of Computing, Georgia Inst. of Tech., Atlanta, GA#TAB#" id="73827769">Nithya Sambasivan</author><author org="College of Computing, Georgia Inst. of Tech., Atlanta, GA#TAB#" id="2139964193">Melody Moore Jackson</author></authors><n_citation>7</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>2035756599</reference><reference>2036120747</reference><reference>2041006415</reference><reference>2106006415</reference></references><venue id="" type="">USAB'07 Proceedings of the 3rd Human-computer interaction and usability engineering of the Austrian computer society conference on HCI and usability for medicine and health care</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-76805-0_22</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.51667">Value sensitive design</keyword><keyword weight="0.46174">Imaging technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.42264">Activities of daily living</keyword><keyword weight="0.42657">Brain–computer interface</keyword><keyword weight="0.45231">Recreation</keyword><keyword weight="0.47485">Human–computer interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.51443">Ubiquitous computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.38306">Engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.46479">Multimedia</keyword><keyword weight="0.45538">restrict</keyword><keyword weight="0.55166">User-centered design</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The following paper reports on a prototype Brain-computer Interface designed for pervasive control by paralyzed users. Our study indicates that current control and communication devices for users with severe physical disabilities restrict control and independence, offer little articulation and communication capabilities. Integrating multiple devices and services, our application is based on the functional Near-Infrared Imaging technology. Based on the overarching Value-sensitive design framework, our solution is informed by the usage patterns of technology, living habits and daily activities of the disabled users. By designing the context-aware pervasive control solution, we create a venue for communication, environmental control, recreation, assistance and expression among physically disabled patients. The evaluations results of the prototype are also discussed.</abstract></paper>