<paper id="1482463223"><title>Control of problem solving: principles and architecture</title><year>1990</year><authors><author org="Rockwell International Science Center, Palo Alto Laboratory, 444 High Street, Palo Alto, CA 94301" id="2785979041">Jack S. Breese</author><author org="Rockwell International Science Center, Palo Alto Laboratory, 444 High Street, Palo Alto, CA 94301" id="2788541702">Michael R. Fehling</author></authors><n_citation>14</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>36924071</reference><reference>1967361629</reference><reference>1968431527</reference><reference>1968432373</reference><reference>1997595419</reference><reference>2018220283</reference><reference>2034700025</reference><reference>2051768896</reference><reference>2054591792</reference><reference>2080637705</reference><reference>2088685985</reference><reference>2122333694</reference></references><venue id="1204606053" type="C">Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence</venue><doi>10.1016/B978-0-444-88650-7.50010-X</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.51381">Architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.49629">Scheduling (computing)</keyword><keyword weight="0.48301">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47373">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.42107">Cost–benefit analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.51256">Value of information</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.68649">Reference architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Computational architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.46879">Machine learning</keyword><keyword weight="0.48686">Interleaving</keyword></keywords><publisher>North-Holland Publishing Co.</publisher><abstract>This paper presents an approach to the design of autonomous, real-time systems operating in uncertain environments. We address issues of problem solving and reflective control of reasoning under uncertainty in terms of two fundamental elements: 1) a set of decision-theoretic models for selecting among alternative problem-solving methods and 2) a general computational architecture for resource-bounded problem solving. The decision-theoretic models provide a set of principles for choosing among alternative problem-solving methods based on their relative costs and benefits, where benefits are characterized in terms of the value of information provided by the output of a reasoning activity. The output may be an estimate of some uncertain quantity or a recommendation for action. The computational architecture, called Schemer-II, provides for interleaving of and communication among various problem-solving subsystems. These subsystems provide alternative approaches to information gathering, belief refinement, solution construction, and solution execution. In particular, the architecture provides a mechanism for interrupting the subsystems in response to critical events. We provide a decision theoretic account for scheduling problem-solving elements and for critical-event-driven interruption of activities in an architecture such as Schemer-II.</abstract></paper>