<paper id="1972665620"><title>A method for automatic rule derivation to support semantic query optimization</title><year>1992</year><authors><author org="" id="2145338918">Michael Siegel</author><author org="" id="2193485399">Edward Sciore</author><author org="" id="2673347819">Sharon Salveter</author></authors><n_citation>68</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>16144991</reference><reference>16887288</reference><reference>30253544</reference><reference>86497608</reference><reference>99733817</reference><reference>1500442713</reference><reference>1514871965</reference><reference>1523083798</reference><reference>1580108468</reference><reference>1585544964</reference><reference>1971828701</reference><reference>1989625540</reference><reference>2005132320</reference><reference>2035382654</reference><reference>2046269252</reference><reference>2048001632</reference><reference>2053253502</reference><reference>2054819113</reference><reference>2058978608</reference><reference>2072627547</reference><reference>2073987830</reference><reference>2088627600</reference><reference>2107783730</reference><reference>2132174753</reference><reference>2152149667</reference><reference>2158141386</reference><reference>2175812749</reference><reference>2568108772</reference></references><venue id="90119964" type="J">ACM Transactions on Database Systems</venue><doi>10.1145/146931.146932</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Semantic query optimization</keyword><keyword weight="0.4768">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.46052">Data processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.47393">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.63396">View</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.635">Semantic query</keyword><keyword weight="0.68314">Query optimization</keyword><keyword weight="0.50681">Data integrity</keyword><keyword weight="0.52825">Rule of inference</keyword><keyword weight="0.48486">Semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.46073">Database</keyword><keyword weight="0.47322">Machine learning</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>The use of inference rules to support intelligent data processing is an increasingly important tool in many areas of computer science. In database systems, rules are used in semantic query optimization as a method for reducing query processing costs. The savings is dependent on the ability of experts to supply a set of useful rules and the ability of the optimizer to quickly find the appropriate transformations generated by these rules. Unfortunately, the most useful rules are not always those that would or could be specified by an expert. This paper describes the architecture of a system having two interrelated components: a combined conventional/semantic query optimizer, and an automatic rule deriver. Our automatic rule derivation method uses intermediate results from the optimization process to direct the search for learning new rules. Unlike a system employing only user-specified rules, a system with an automatic capability can derive rules that may be true only in the current state of the database and can modify the rule set to reflect changes in the database and its usage pattern. This system has been implemented as an extension of the EXODUS conventional query optimizer generator. We describe the implementation, and show how semantic query optimization is an extension of conventional optimization in this context.</abstract></paper>