<paper id="1517362503"><title>Trading one-wayness against chosen-ciphertext security in factoring-based encryption</title><year>2006</year><authors><author org="Cryptography Group, Security Labs, Gemalto," id="2117657652">Pascal Paillier</author><author org="Departament de Matemàtica Aplicada, Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya#TAB#" id="2137851336">Jorge L. Villar</author></authors><n_citation>27</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1515644111</reference><reference>1516512945</reference><reference>1540889651</reference><reference>1552695147</reference><reference>1557014463</reference><reference>1569930334</reference><reference>1603331866</reference><reference>1606412873</reference><reference>1880955573</reference><reference>2052267638</reference><reference>2073210531</reference><reference>2132172731</reference><reference>2151413173</reference><reference>2161195863</reference><reference>2167989228</reference><reference>2593949227</reference></references><venue id="2535638237" type="C">International Conference on the Theory and Application of Cryptology and Information Security</venue><doi>10.1007/11935230_17</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.43077">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.56691">Optimal asymmetric encryption padding</keyword><keyword weight="0.5231">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.42778">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.55247">Random oracle</keyword><keyword weight="0.54838">Encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.43414">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.50217">Cryptosystem</keyword><keyword weight="0.52542">Ciphertext</keyword><keyword weight="0.55096">Public-key cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.55747">Factoring</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We revisit a long-lived folklore impossibility result for factoring-based encryption and properly establish that reaching maximally secure one-wayness (i.e. equivalent to factoring) and resisting chosen-ciphertext attacks (CCA) are incompatible goals for single-key cryptosystems. We pinpoint two tradeoffs between security notions in the standard model that have always remained unnoticed in the Random Oracle (RO) model. These imply that simple RO-model schemes such as Rabin/RW-SAEP[+]/OAEP[+][+], EPOC-2, etc. admit no instantiation in the standard model which CCA security is equivalent to factoring via a key-preserving reduction. We extend this impossibility to arbitrary reductions assuming non-malleable key generation, a property capturing the intuition that factoring a modulus n should not be any easier when given a factoring oracle for moduli n′≠n. The only known countermeasures against our impossibility results, besides malleable key generation, are the inclusion of an additional random string in the public key, or encryption twinning as in Naor-Yung or Dolev-Dwork-Naor constructions.</abstract></paper>