<paper id="1527008463"><title>A Classification of Symbolic Transition Systems</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="University of California" id="2707196735">Thomas A. Henzinger</author><author org="University of California" id="2156286033">Rupak Majumdar</author></authors><n_citation>10</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1490569620</reference><reference>1515514400</reference><reference>1517157359</reference><reference>1525028586</reference><reference>1596365597</reference><reference>1967174286</reference><reference>2004463571</reference><reference>2017759899</reference><reference>2021473546</reference><reference>2085838366</reference><reference>2098817244</reference><reference>2101508170</reference><reference>2112535338</reference><reference>2117087357</reference><reference>2123910665</reference><reference>2124778357</reference><reference>2137951255</reference><reference>2147340401</reference></references><venue id="1178070762" type="C">Symposium on Theoretical Aspects of Computer Science</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-46541-3_2</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.54046">Transition system</keyword><keyword weight="0.46456">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.45764">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.47082">Observable</keyword><keyword weight="0.56623">Model checking</keyword><keyword weight="0.50418">Finite set</keyword><keyword weight="0.43136">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48996">Linear temporal logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.485">Reachability</keyword><keyword weight="0.53411">Finitary</keyword><keyword weight="0.48014">Formal verification</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We define five increasingly comprehensive classes of infinite-state systems, called STS1-5, whose state spaces have finitary structure. For four of these classes, we provide examples from hybrid :[27],"These are the systems with finite bisimilarity quotients. They can be analyzed symbolically by (1) iterating the predecessor and boolean operations starting from a finite set of observable state sets, and (2) terminating when no new state sets are generated. This enables model checking of the :[27],"These are the systems with finite :[74],"similarity quotients. They can be analyzed symbolically by iterating the predecessor and positive boolean operations. This enables model checking of the existential and universal fragments of the :[27],"These are the systems with finite :[108],"trace-equivalence quotients. They can be analyzed symbolically by iterating the predecessor operation and a restricted form of positive boolean operations (intersection is restricted to intersection with observables). This enables model checking of linear temporal :[27],"These are the systems with finite :[149],"distance-equivalence quotients (two states are equivalent if for every distance d, the same observables can be reached in d transitions). The systems in this class can be analyzed symbolically by iterating the predecessor operation and terminating when no new state sets are generated. This enables model checking of the existential conjunction-free and universal disjunction-free fragments of the :[27],"These are the systems with finite :[213],"bounded-reachability quotients (two states are equivalent if for every distance d, the same observables can be reached in d or fewer transitions). The systems in this class can be analyzed symbolically by iterating the predecessor operation and terminating when no new states are encountered. This enables model checking of reachability properties.</abstract></paper>