<paper id="1572880398"><title>Applying a holistic approach to develop user-friendly, customer-oriented E-government portal interfaces</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="Institute of Applied Computer Science, Division: Business, Administration and Society, University of Linz, Austria#TAB#" id="2125281065">Maria A. Wimmer</author><author org="Institute of Applied Computer Science, Division: Business, Administration and Society, University of Linz, Austria#TAB#" id="2550916071">Ute Holler</author></authors><n_citation>22</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1573638087</reference><reference>2087795270</reference><reference>2092498789</reference><reference>2342091124</reference><reference>2400441912</reference></references><venue id="106296714" type="J">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-36572-9_13</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46516">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.56992">Public service</keyword><keyword weight="0.43811">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.53093">Usability</keyword><keyword weight="0.52541">User Friendly</keyword><keyword weight="0.53807">Electronic media</keyword><keyword weight="0.57938">Public sector</keyword><keyword weight="0.60212">User interface</keyword><keyword weight="0.57315">User requirements document</keyword><keyword weight="0.51787">The Internet</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>e-Government is an important field of application for providing electronic public services to a wide range of users. Especially in the public sector, the customers are very heterogeneous with different expertise and know-how on using electronic media such as the Internet. Moreover, the public sector is characterised by providing a wide range of different kinds of public services varying for the distinct user groups. Developing appropriate, user-friendly portal interfaces for virtual administrations, which offer a broad range of public services to the distinct user groups, requires a careful investigation of the user needs and service requirements. In this contribution, we provide a first examination of usability and easy-to-use requirements in relation to target user groups and process models for electronic public service delivery. We define an overall interface architecture and discuss the required front-office functionality for a user-friendly and intuitive e-Government portal serving distinct target groups.</abstract></paper>