<paper id="1830600668"><title>Timing Verification by Successive Approximation</title><year>1992</year><authors><author org="AT&amp;T Bell Lab.#TAB#" id="689646243">Rajeev Alur</author><author org="AT&amp;T Bell Lab.#TAB#" id="2306579703">Alon Itai</author><author org="AT&amp;T Bell Lab.#TAB#" id="2468610965">Robert P. Kurshan</author><author org="AT&amp;T Bell Lab.#TAB#" id="294360276">Mihalis Yannakakis</author></authors><n_citation>79</n_citation><doc_type>Patent</doc_type><references><reference>59365162</reference><reference>1482233117</reference><reference>1583165871</reference><reference>2030166143</reference></references><venue id="1162450063" type="C">Computer Aided Verification</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-56496-9_12</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Language inclusion</keyword><keyword weight="0.45628">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.50083">Automaton</keyword><keyword weight="0.45446">Shaping</keyword><keyword weight="0.47209">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.46989">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.53392">Time complexity</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Apparatus for developing and verifying systems. The disclosed apparatus employs a computationally-tractable technique for verifying whether a system made up of a set of processes, each of which has at least one delay constraint associated with it, satisfies a given temporal property. The technique deals with the verification as a language inclusion problem, i.e., it represents both the set of processes and the temporal property as automata and determines whether there is a restriction of the set of processes such that the language of the automaton representing the restricted set of processes is included in the language of the automaton representing the temporal property. The technique is computationally tractable because it deals with the problem iteratively: it tests whether a current restriction of the set of processes is included, and if not, it employs a counter-example for the inclusion to either determine that the delay constraints render satisfaction of the given temporal property or to derive a new restriction of the set of processes. Further included in the disclosure are techniques for checking the timing consistency of the counter-example with respect to a delay constraint and techniques for finding the optimal delay constraint.</abstract></paper>