<paper id="1535972735"><title>On Perfect and Adaptive Security in Exposure-Resilient Cryptography</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="New-York University &gt;  &gt;  &gt;  &gt;" id="1259442811">Yevgeniy Dodis</author><author org="Princeton University *" id="2159933393">Amit Sahai</author><author org="massachusetts institute of technology" id="2132461468">Adam Smith</author></authors><n_citation>78</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>18949936</reference><reference>1492657530</reference><reference>1495104849</reference><reference>1515957510</reference><reference>1516739635</reference><reference>1519969013</reference><reference>1534695542</reference><reference>1541483074</reference><reference>1549438532</reference><reference>1575126375</reference><reference>1580181578</reference><reference>1580920982</reference><reference>1809369763</reference><reference>2007661134</reference><reference>2026474140</reference><reference>2052207834</reference><reference>2110218640</reference><reference>2114673105</reference><reference>2114924587</reference><reference>2127572279</reference><reference>2752444925</reference></references><venue id="1140213147" type="C">Theory and Application of Cryptographic Techniques</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-44987-6_19</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45858">Binary logarithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.47673">Block cipher</keyword><keyword weight="0.50989">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.44536">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47683">Upper and lower bounds</keyword><keyword weight="0.44635">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.45451">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.53233">Cryptographic primitive</keyword><keyword weight="0.46867">Probabilistic logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.52204">Pseudorandom generator</keyword><keyword weight="0.46325">Hypercube</keyword><keyword weight="0.43317">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><abstract>We consider the question of adaptive security for two related cryptographic primitives: all-or-nothing transforms and exposure-resilient functions. Both are concerned with retaining security when an intruder learns some bits of a string which is supposed to be secret: all-or-nothing transforms (AONT) protect their input even given partial knowledge of the output; exposure-resilient functions (ERF) hide their output even given partial exposure of their input. Both of these primitives can be defined in the perfect, statistical and computational settings and have a variety of applications in cryptography. In this paper, we study how these notions fare against adaptive adversaries, who may choose which positions of a secret string to observe on the the :[111],"perfect setting, we prove a new, strong lower bound on the constructibility of (perfect) AONT. This applies to both standard and adaptively secure AONT. In particular, to hide an input as short as log n bits, the adversary must see no more than half of the n-bit output. This bound also provides a new impossibility result on the existence of (ramp) secret-sharing schemes [6] and relates to a combinatorial problem of independent interest: finding "balanced" colorings of the the statistical setting, we :[191],"show that adaptivity adds strictly more power to the adversary. We relate and reduce the construction of adaptive ERFu0027s to that of almost-perfect resilient functions [19], for which the adversary can actually set some of the input positions and still learn nothing about the output. We give a probabilistic construction of these functions which is essentially optimal and substantially improves on previous constructions of [19, 5]. As a result, we get nearly optimal adaptively secure ERFu0027s and AONTu0027s. Finally, extending the statistical construction we obtain optimal computational adaptive ERFu0027s, "public-value" AONTu0027s and resilient functions.</abstract></paper>