<paper id="1505994399"><title>Linear cryptanalysis of stream ciphers</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="Queensland Univ. of Technology#TAB#" id="2973538862">Jovan Dj. Golić</author></authors><n_citation>34</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>118210125</reference><reference>1497892245</reference><reference>1519262055</reference><reference>1531434127</reference><reference>1540135241</reference><reference>1549665762</reference><reference>1551013114</reference><reference>1571317543</reference><reference>1584896380</reference><reference>1589410660</reference><reference>1590855138</reference><reference>1600145187</reference><reference>1629301835</reference><reference>1661175875</reference><reference>1964723977</reference><reference>1979198062</reference><reference>1981205339</reference><reference>2061168187</reference><reference>2064301354</reference><reference>2080017147</reference><reference>2087189997</reference><reference>2104482156</reference><reference>2107271959</reference><reference>2161517294</reference><reference>2162442687</reference><reference>2171646842</reference></references><venue id="2758283624" type="C">Fast Software Encryption</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-60590-8_13</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.74616">Keystream</keyword><keyword weight="0.63344">Higher-order differential cryptanalysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.60418">Block cipher</keyword><keyword weight="0.64714">Piling-up lemma</keyword><keyword weight="0.41036">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.43974">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.42389">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.6486">Stream cipher</keyword><keyword weight="0.67874">Correlation attack</keyword><keyword weight="0.7084">Linear cryptanalysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.65238">Differential cryptanalysis</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer Berlin Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Starting from recent results on a linear statistical weakness of keystream generators and on linear correlation properties of combiners with memory, linear cryptanalysis of stream ciphers based on the linear sequential circuit approximation of finite-state machines is introduced as a general method for assessing the strength of stream ciphers. The statistical weakness can be used to reduce the uncertainty of unknown plaintext and also to reconstruct the unknown structure of a keystream generator, regardless of the initial state. The linear correlations in arbitrary keystream generators can be used for divide and conquer correlation attacks on the initial state based on known plaintext or ciphertext only. Linear cryptanalysis of irregularly clocked shift registers as well as of arbitrary shift register based binary keystream generators proves to be feasible. In particular, the direct stream cipher mode of block ciphers, the basic summation generator, the shrinking generator, the clock-controlled cascade generator, and the modified linear congruential generators are analyzed. It generally appears that simple shift register based keystream generators are potentially vulnerable to linear cryptanalysis. A proposal of a novel, simple and secure keystream generator is also presented.</abstract></paper>