<paper id="1967400027"><title>Zero-Safe Nets, or Transition Synchronization Made Simple</title><year>1997</year><authors><author org="Computer Science Department University of Pisa Corso Italia 40, 56125 Pisa, Italy" id="2147391338">Roberto Bruni</author><author org="Computer Science Laboratory SRI International 333 Ravenswood Ave., Menlo Park, CA, 94025 USA" id="2925215115">Ugo Montanari</author></authors><n_citation>36</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1585042602</reference><reference>1602232868</reference><reference>1604240241</reference><reference>1909063750</reference><reference>1988204590</reference><reference>2022120297</reference><reference>2022479543</reference><reference>2035959929</reference><reference>2036271734</reference><reference>2052906135</reference><reference>2061288205</reference><reference>2117243261</reference><reference>2132179319</reference><reference>2296604987</reference></references><venue id="50368787" type="J">Electronic Notes in Theoretical Computer Science</venue><doi>10.1016/S1571-0661(05)80466-9</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.43791">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.45219">Synchronization</keyword><keyword weight="0.4802">Operational semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.56745">Petri net</keyword><keyword weight="0.41959">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.5078">Process architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.47343">Monoid</keyword><keyword weight="0.44082">Database transaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.45226">Security token</keyword><keyword weight="0.47319">Adjunction</keyword></keywords><publisher>Elsevier</publisher><abstract>Abstract In addition to ordinary places, called stable, zero-safe nets are equipped with zero places, which in a stable marking cannot contain any token. An evolution between two stable markings, instead, can be a complex computation called stable transaction, which may use zero places, but which is atomic when seen from stable places: no stable token generated in a transaction can be reused in the same transaction. Every zero-safe net has an ordinary Place-Transition net as its abstract counterpart, where only stable places are maintained, and where every transaction becomes a transition. The two nets allow us to look at the same system from both an abstract and a refined viewpoint. To achieve this result no new interaction mechanism is used, besides the ordinary token-pushing rules of nets. The refined zero-safe nets can be much smaller than their corresponding abstract P/T nets, since they take advantage of a transition synchronization mechanism. For instance, when transactions of unlimited length are possible in a zero safe net, the abstract net becomes infinite, even if the refined net is finite. In the second part of the paper two universal constructions - both following the Petri nets are monoids approach and the collective token philosophy - are used to give evidence of the naturality of our definitions. More precisely, the operational semantics of zero-safe nets is characterized as an adjunction, and the derivation of abstract P/T nets as a coreflection.</abstract></paper>