<paper id="1978711911"><title>Artificial fishes: physics, locomotion, perception, behavior</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="Dept. of Computer Science, University of Toronto#TAB#" id="2168435742">Xiaoyuan Tu</author><author org="Dept. of Computer Science, University of Toronto#TAB#" id="668754370">Demetri Terzopoulos</author></authors><n_citation>588</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1991022228</reference><reference>2037184437</reference><reference>2043878167</reference><reference>2070545326</reference><reference>2091051792</reference><reference>2122850838</reference><reference>2128597598</reference><reference>2150312211</reference></references><venue id="1164321581" type="C">International Conference on Computer Graphics and Interactive Techniques</venue><doi>10.1145/192161.192170</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.50207">Artificial life</keyword><keyword weight="0.47059">Situated</keyword><keyword weight="0.38584">Computer vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.40624">Fin</keyword><keyword weight="0.48598">Autonomous agent</keyword><keyword weight="0.38918">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.43837">Motor control</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.45456">Animation</keyword><keyword weight="0.43815">Perception</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>This paper proposes a framework for animation that can achieve the intricacy of motion evident in certain natural ecosystems with minimal input from the animator. The realistic appearance, movement, and behavior of individual animals, as well as the patterns of behavior evident in groups of animals fall within the scope of the framework. Our approach to emulating this level of natural complexity is to model each animal holistically as an autonomous agent situated in its physical world. To demonstrate the approach, we develop a physics-based, virtual marine world. The world is inhabited by artificial fishes that can swim hydrodynamically in simulated water through the motor control of internal muscles that motivates fins. Their repertoire of behaviors relies on their perception of the dynamic environment. As in nature, the detailed motions of artificial fishes in their virtual habitat are not entirely predictable because they are not scripted.</abstract></paper>