<paper id="1593505641"><title>Software in the Soviet Union: Progress and Problems</title><year>1979</year><authors><author org="Woodrow Wilson School of Public, Princeton University, and International Affairs" id="2153917251">Seymour E. Goodman</author></authors><n_citation>14</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1581626839</reference><reference>1990876403</reference><reference>1997931117</reference><reference>1998595415</reference><reference>2155970780</reference></references><venue id="183285281" type="J">Advances in Computers</venue><doi>10.1016/S0065-2458(08)60585-9</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.40016">Data processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.43367">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.50784">Software</keyword><keyword weight="0.50461">Systemic problem</keyword><keyword weight="0.41309">Law</keyword><keyword weight="0.60542">Software development</keyword></keywords><publisher>Elsevier</publisher><abstract>Publisher Summary This chapter presents a broad perspective on software development in the USSR. It is convenient to classify loosely the factors that affect the production and use of software in the Soviet Union in terms of four categories: (1) those that depend on hardware availability (2) those that are related to priorities in the allocation of effort and other resources; (3) those that are dependent on the nature of Soviet institutions— that is, systemic factors; and (4) those that involve technology transfers from foreign sources. Soviets have made substantial progress in removing limitations because of hardware availability, some progress because of changes in priorities, and as yet relatively little progress in overcoming an assortment of complex systemic problems that affect the development of software. Soviet software progress and problems cannot be understood on a technical basis alone. Any serious study of the Soviet software industry must involve some implicit and explicit comparisons with its US counterpart. The development of Soviet computing has tended to follow closely the US technical pattern, but it has differed considerably in terms of timescale, philosophy, institutional arrangements, capital decisions, and applications. In particular, the USSR was slow to appreciate data processing and to develop the technology to support the widespread use of digital computers for such applications.</abstract></paper>