<paper id="1545694218"><title>QoS aggregation in Web service compositions</title><year>2005</year><authors><author org="Inst. of Telecommun. Syst., Technische Univ. Berlin, Germany" id="2163863025">M.C. Jaeger</author><author org="Inst. of Telecommun. Syst., Technische Univ. Berlin, Germany" id="2375004">G. Rojec-Goldmann</author><author org="Inst. of Telecommun. Syst., Technische Univ. Berlin, Germany" id="2139526993">G. Muhl</author></authors><n_citation>111</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2006053872</reference><reference>2021538441</reference><reference>2087258511</reference><reference>2126728257</reference><reference>2140744542</reference><reference>2141880113</reference><reference>2157699834</reference><reference>2911625174</reference></references><venue id="2754955730" type="C">IEEE International Conference on e-Technology, e-Commerce and e-Service</venue><doi>10.1109/EEE.2005.110</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.68484">Mobile QoS</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Internet quality of service</keyword><keyword weight="0.44743">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46154">Computer network</keyword><keyword weight="0.56026">Quality of service</keyword><keyword weight="0.59477">Web service</keyword><keyword weight="0.54378">The Internet</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>For the composition of Web services non-functional characteristics are commonly considered criteria for finding and selecting available services. Our work focuses on a mechanism that determines the overall quality-of-service (QoS) of a composition by aggregating the QoS of the individual services. With aggregated QoS it can be verified whether a set of services satisfies the QoS requirements for the whole composition or not. The aggregation performed builds upon abstract composition patterns, which model basic structural elements of a composition like parallel paths, a sequence, or a looped execution. In this work we extend existing composition patterns with the abilities to consider dependencies between services. Furthermore we introduce, how to use the pattern-based aggregation in the monitoring process during run-time. We explain how the data derived from the monitoring process can be used to calculate a more accurate aggregation of QoS for the composition.</abstract></paper>