<paper id="1582340466"><title>User Modeling for Adaptive News Access</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="Dept. of Information and Computer Science, University of California, Irvine, CA, USA. E-mail: dbillsus@ics.uci.edu" id="2186721938">Daniel Billsus</author><author org="Department of Information &amp; Computer Science, University of California, Irvine, CA, USA." id="1996789426">Michael J. Pazzani</author></authors><n_citation>400</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1493526108</reference><reference>1550363981</reference><reference>1968397045</reference><reference>2022775778</reference><reference>2051296598</reference><reference>2063409629</reference><reference>2085989833</reference><reference>2114535528</reference><reference>2124591829</reference><reference>2124756613</reference><reference>2126850915</reference><reference>2147654806</reference><reference>2149706766</reference><reference>2162077280</reference><reference>2167277498</reference></references><venue id="160628929" type="J">User Modeling and User-adapted Interaction</venue><doi>10.1023/A:1026501525781</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.4642">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.64275">User experience design</keyword><keyword weight="0.47394">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48611">Human–computer interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.69256">User modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.56653">Information retrieval applications</keyword><keyword weight="0.55772">Systems architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.62593">Computer user satisfaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.66818">User interface</keyword><keyword weight="0.67205">User interface design</keyword><keyword weight="0.62682">User requirements document</keyword><keyword weight="0.46943">Machine learning</keyword></keywords><publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher><abstract>We present a framework for adaptive news access, based on machine learning techniques specifically designed for this task. First, we focus on the systemu0027s general functionality and system architecture. We then describe the interface and design of two deployed news agents that are part of the described architecture. While the first agent provides personalized news through a web-based interface, the second system is geared towards wireless information devices such as PDAs (personal digital assistants) and cell phones. Based on implicit and explicit user feedback, our agents use a machine learning algorithm to induce individual user models. Motivated by general shortcomings of other user modeling systems for Information Retrieval applications, as well as the specific requirements of news classification, we propose the induction of hybrid user models that consist of separate models for short-term and long-term interests. Furthermore, we illustrate how the described algorithm can be used to address an important issue that has thus far received little attention in the Information Retrieval community: a useru0027s information need changes as a direct result of interaction with information. We empirically evaluate the systemu0027s performance based on data collected from regular system users. The goal of the evaluation is not only to understand the performance contributions of the algorithmu0027s individual components, but also to assess the overall utility of the proposed user modeling techniques from a user perspective. Our results provide empirical evidence for the utility of the hybrid user model, and suggest that effective personalization can be achieved without requiring any extra effort from the user.</abstract></paper>