<paper id="1968597711"><title>Inner-core and outer-core functions of partially defined Boolean functions</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="Department of Systems and Human Science, Graduate School of Engineering Science, Osaka University, Toyonaka, Osaka 560-0043, Japan" id="2343481990">Kazuhisa Makino</author><author org="Department of Applied Mathematics and Physics, Graduate School of Informatics, Kyoto University, Kyoto 606-8501, Japan" id="2110223873">Toshihide Ibaraki</author></authors><n_citation>11</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1484529399</reference><reference>1594632484</reference><reference>1972004026</reference><reference>2002660979</reference><reference>2007940874</reference><reference>2026480866</reference><reference>2059413692</reference><reference>2065895258</reference><reference>2080947358</reference><reference>2085518646</reference><reference>2093776691</reference><reference>2149706766</reference><reference>2152689238</reference></references><venue id="171741597" type="J">Discrete Applied Mathematics</venue><doi>10.1016/S0166-218X(99)00101-8</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.55625">Boolean network</keyword><keyword weight="0.57685">Boolean function</keyword><keyword weight="0.59603">Karp–Lipton theorem</keyword><keyword weight="0.47319">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.40387">Inner core</keyword><keyword weight="0.47483">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.59326">Polynomial</keyword><keyword weight="0.60494">Parity function</keyword><keyword weight="0.56404">Time complexity</keyword><keyword weight="0.58839">Boolean expression</keyword><keyword weight="0.41698">Mathematics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Elsevier Science Publishers B. V.</publisher><abstract>Abstract Given a class of functions C , we introduce the k-inner-core and k-outer-core functions of a partially defined Boolean function (T,F), in order to identify the set of vectors which are immune up to k classification errors in T∪F, where T denotes a set of true vectors (or positive examples) and F denotes a set of false vectors (or negative examples). We restrict C to classes C + and C ⊨ of positive and regular functions, respectively, and investigate various problems associated with inner-core and outer-core functions. In particular, we show that there is no polynomial total time algorithm for computing the k-inner-core function for class C + and general k, unless P=NP; but there is an input polynomial time algorithm if k is fixed. The situation for the outer-core function is different. It is shown that, for class C + and a fixed k, there is a polynomial total time algorithm for computing the k-outer-core function if and only if there is a polynomial total time algorithm for dualizing a positive Boolean function (the complexity of this problem is not known yet). For class C ⊨ , there are incrementally polynomial time algorithms for computing both the k-inner-core and k-outer-core functions.</abstract></paper>