<paper id="1580124140"><title>A Method Engineering Approach to Information Systems Development</title><year>1993</year><authors><author org="University of Twente, School of Management Studies, P.O. Box 217, 7500 AE Enschede, The Netherlands" id="2072764079">Kees van Slooten</author><author org="University of Twente, Dept. of Computer Science, P.O. Box 217, 7500 AE Enschede, The Netherlands" id="2776348112">Sjaak Brinkkemper</author></authors><n_citation>69</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1516470828</reference><reference>1533447818</reference><reference>1985322517</reference><reference>1994932859</reference><reference>2031096619</reference><reference>2031542183</reference><reference>2066900729</reference><reference>2069752849</reference><reference>2079383480</reference><reference>2114880097</reference><reference>2621040763</reference></references><venue id="" type="">Proceedings of the IFIP WG8.1 Working Conference on Information System Development Process</venue><doi>10.1016/B978-0-444-81594-1.50016-7</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.64403">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.4726">Systems engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.4692">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.65359">Method engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.5155">Road map</keyword><keyword weight="0.52632">Domain of discourse</keyword><keyword weight="0.6851">Systems development life cycle</keyword><keyword weight="0.65605">Information engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.5271">Design process</keyword><keyword weight="0.44898">Contingency</keyword></keywords><publisher>School of Management Studies</publisher><abstract>Abstract Method Engineering is introduced as an approach to configure project specific methods for the development of information systems. We propose to support method engineering with a formal procedure to configure development scenarios from project characterizations. The project characterization is defined by a number of project contingency factors and determines the interest of aspects considered during the development of information systems. Process-, information-, behaviour-, organization-, and problem-oriented aspects constitute one dimension of a framework facilitating the selection of fragments of methods as components of the required scenario. The other dimension of the framework consists of two levels for the analysis and design process related to the levels of decomposition of the object system, or universe of discourse. Also, a development strategy is derived from the project characterization which means selecting a route map for information systems development. The available fragments of methods, and the route maps, will be stored in what we call a method base.</abstract></paper>