<paper id="1488996954"><title>Distributed Global Transaction Support for Workflow Management Applications</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="UNIVERSITY OF TWENTE" id="2427435393">Jochem Vonk</author><author org="UNIVERSITY OF TWENTE" id="330448013">Paul W. P. J. Grefen</author><author org="UNIVERSITY OF TWENTE" id="2461735937">Erik Boertjes</author><author org="UNIVERSITY OF TWENTE" id="2092532607">Peter M. G. Apers</author></authors><n_citation>11</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1491743220</reference><reference>1522974305</reference><reference>1855065956</reference><reference>1892663663</reference><reference>2129338772</reference><reference>2129674434</reference><reference>2139576103</reference><reference>2153938134</reference><reference>2296513999</reference></references><venue id="1192664773" type="C">Database and Expert Systems Applications</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-48309-8_89</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.68009">Transaction processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.44943">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.71287">Workflow technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.46482">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.64894">Online transaction processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.64948">Windows Workflow Foundation</keyword><keyword weight="0.73087">Workflow engine</keyword><keyword weight="0.73469">Workflow management system</keyword><keyword weight="0.68857">Distributed transaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.65476">Transaction processing system</keyword><keyword weight="0.464">Database</keyword><keyword weight="0.47619">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><abstract>Workflow management systems require advanced transaction support to cope with their inherently long-running processes. The recent trend to distribute workflow executions requires an even more advanced transaction support system that is able to handle distribution. This paper presents a model as well as an architecture to provide distributed advanced transaction support. Characteristic of the transaction support system is the ability to deal with arbitrary distribution of business processes over multiple workflow management systems and the support for flexible rollbacks. The modularity of the architecture and the orthogonality with respect to the workflow management system allows the transaction system to be applied in other application areas as well. The high scalability of the architecture allows an arbitrary combination of transaction support systems and workflow management systems of which the locations are irrelevant. In the WIDE project, the developed technology is applied to the commercial FORO workflow management system.</abstract></paper>