<paper id="1526337814"><title>A Small Set of Formal Topological Relationships Suitable for End-User Interaction</title><year>1993</year><authors><author org="Università di L'Aquila#TAB#" id="180789617">Eliseo Clementini</author><author org="Università di L'Aquila#TAB#" id="2140711207">Paolino Di Felice</author><author org="TNO Physics and Electronics Laboratory" id="2558014341">Peter van Oosterom</author></authors><n_citation>370</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1849301553</reference><reference>1907279173</reference><reference>2032357318</reference><reference>2050365841</reference><reference>2072627547</reference><reference>2085827136</reference><reference>2162064942</reference></references><venue id="" type="">SSD '93 Proceedings of the Third International Symposium on Advances in Spatial Databases</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-56869-7_16</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.43343">Topology</keyword><keyword weight="0.4749">Geographic information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.47771">Query language</keyword><keyword weight="0.46744">End user</keyword><keyword weight="0.45649">Information retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.46522">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.53433">Spatial query</keyword><keyword weight="0.45906">Small set</keyword><keyword weight="0.48062">Completeness (statistics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.47511">Semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.55807">Spatial database</keyword><keyword weight="0.39899">Mathematics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><abstract>Topological relationships between spatial objects represent important knowledge that users of geographic information systems expect to retrieve from a spatial database. A difficult task is to assign precise semantics to user queries involving concepts such as “crosses”, “is inside”, “is adjacent”. In this paper, we present two methods for describing topological relationships. The first method is an extension of the geometric point-set approach by taking the dimension of the intersections into account. This results in a very large number of different topological relationships for point, line, and area features. In the second method, which aims to be more suitable for humans, we propose to group all possible cases into a few meaningful topological relationships and we discuss their exclusiveness and completeness with respect to the point-set approach.</abstract></paper>