<paper id="1493969756"><title>Collision free hash functions and public key signature schemes</title><year>1987</year><authors><author org="Aarhus University, Inst. of Math., Ny Munkegade, Aarhus C, Denmark#TAB#" id="2682364181">Ivan Bjerre Damgård</author></authors><n_citation>277</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1512372863</reference><reference>1541421768</reference><reference>1543503103</reference><reference>1985623009</reference><reference>2099188893</reference><reference>2151413173</reference><reference>2166457424</reference></references><venue id="1140213147" type="C">Theory and Application of Cryptographic Techniques</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-39118-5_19</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.67284">SHA-2</keyword><keyword weight="0.44607">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.42863">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.65587">Merkle signature scheme</keyword><keyword weight="0.71927">Collision resistance</keyword><keyword weight="0.44415">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.67623">SWIFFT</keyword><keyword weight="0.67198">Hash function</keyword><keyword weight="0.66828">Security of cryptographic hash functions</keyword><keyword weight="0.65562">Hash chain</keyword><keyword weight="0.68639">Collision attack</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In this paper, we present a construction of hash functions. These functions are collision free in the sense that under some cryptographic assumption, it is provably hard for an enemy to find collisions. Assumptions that would be sufficient are the hardness of factoring, of discrete log, or the (possibly) more general assumption about the existence of claw free sets of :[60],"ability of a hash function to improve security and speed of a signature scheme is discussed: for example, we can combine the RSA-system with a collision free hash function based on factoring to get a scheme which is more efficient and much more the :[104],"effect of combining the Goldwasser-Micali-Rest signature scheme with one of our functions is studied. In the factoring based implementation of the scheme using a k-bit modulus, the signing process can be speeded up by a factor roughly equal to kċO (log2(k)), while the signature checking process will be faster by a factor of O (log2(k)).</abstract></paper>