<paper id="1966340945"><title>E-government research: Reviewing the literature, limitations, and ways forward</title><year>2007</year><authors><author org="Department of Political Science and Public Administration, Hacettepe University, Turkey" id="2161359622">Mete Yildiz</author></authors><n_citation>624</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1972204240</reference><reference>1973857370</reference><reference>1974245498</reference><reference>1974716766</reference><reference>1976431997</reference><reference>1985730694</reference><reference>1989198285</reference><reference>2007185530</reference><reference>2012016639</reference><reference>2020050623</reference><reference>2026593392</reference><reference>2027953958</reference><reference>2035224826</reference><reference>2037779348</reference><reference>2044901030</reference><reference>2050523348</reference><reference>2053830848</reference><reference>2054030698</reference><reference>2056272736</reference><reference>2057779782</reference><reference>2061875897</reference><reference>2074533043</reference><reference>2084419793</reference><reference>2084937952</reference><reference>2087794779</reference><reference>2160196038</reference></references><venue id="201710173" type="J">Government Information Quarterly</venue><doi>10.1016/j.giq.2007.01.002</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.51868">Vagueness</keyword><keyword weight="0.46593">Positive economics</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">E-Government</keyword><keyword weight="0.44537">Sociology</keyword><keyword weight="0.4605">Public relations</keyword><keyword weight="0.49255">Tying</keyword><keyword weight="0.49562">Politics</keyword><keyword weight="0.48702">Mainstream</keyword><keyword weight="0.45615">Management science</keyword><keyword weight="0.52752">Empirical research</keyword></keywords><publisher>JAI</publisher><abstract>This article claims to be both a review and an agenda-setting piece. It is argued that e-government research suffers from definitional vagueness of the e-government concept, oversimplification of the e-government development processes within complex political and institutional environments, and various methodological limitations. In order to address these issues, the article reviews the limitations in the e-government literature, and it suggests ways forward. To do so, the study critically analyzes the development and various definitions of the e-government concept. After discussing the limitations of the concept, methodological and conceptual remedies such as (i) better examining and explaining the processes of – and participation patterns in – e-government projects within complex political environments, (ii) addressing the problem of under-specification in the e-government literature by the production of more grounded, empirical studies that would create new theoretical arguments and provide new concepts and categories so as to enhance our understanding of e-government policy processes and actors, and (iii) tying the subject of e-government strongly to mainstream public administration research are suggested in the final part of the analysis.</abstract></paper>