<paper id="1719766253"><title>Efficient Implementation of Rijndael Encryption in Reconfigurable Hardware: Improvements and Design Tradeoffs</title><year>2003</year><authors><author org="Université catholique de Louvain &gt;  &gt;  &gt;  &gt;" id="2085610964">Francois-Xavier Standaert</author><author org="Université catholique de Louvain &gt;  &gt;  &gt;  &gt;" id="296332964">Gael Rouvroy</author><author org="Université catholique de Louvain &gt;  &gt;  &gt;  &gt;" id="2195205560">Jean-Jacques Quisquater</author><author org="Université catholique de Louvain &gt;  &gt;  &gt;  &gt;" id="2077657242">Jean-Didier Legat</author></authors><n_citation>154</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>62567376</reference><reference>170872169</reference><reference>1487268209</reference><reference>1607684240</reference><reference>1964872674</reference><reference>2099179520</reference><reference>2109970735</reference><reference>2112244944</reference><reference>2117013296</reference><reference>2127752881</reference><reference>2130407297</reference><reference>2145881907</reference></references><venue id="1127098075" type="C">Cryptographic Hardware and Embedded Systems</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-45238-6_27</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45686">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.56779">Advanced Encryption Standard</keyword><keyword weight="0.46172">Parallel computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.53048">Field-programmable gate array</keyword><keyword weight="0.53804">Place and route</keyword><keyword weight="0.576">Encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.53099">Virtex</keyword><keyword weight="0.51517">Design process</keyword><keyword weight="0.65375">AES implementations</keyword><keyword weight="0.4627">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.56846">Reconfigurable computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.47097">Embedded system</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Performance evaluation of the Advanced Encryption Standard candidates has led to intensive study of both hardware and software implementations. However, although plentiful papers present various implementation results, it seems that efficiency could still be greatly improved by applying good design rules adapted to devices and algorithms. This paper addresses various approaches for efficient FPGA implementations of the Advanced Encryption Standard algorithm. As different applications of the AES algorithm may require different speed/area tradeoffs, we propose a rigorous study of the possible implementation schemes, but also discuss design methodology and algorithmic optimization in order to improve previously reported results. We propose heuristics to evaluate hardware efficiency at different steps of the design process. We also define an optimal pipeline that takes the place and route constraints into account. Resulting circuits significantly improve previously reported results: throughput is up to 18.5 Gbits/sec and area requirements can be limited to 542 slices and 10 RAM blocks with a ratio throughput/area improved by at least 25% of the best-known designs in the Xilinx Virtex-E technology.</abstract></paper>