<paper id="1530127443"><title>AN AIRTRAVEL EXPERT DATABASE</title><year>1988</year><authors><author org="Technische Universität München, Lehrstuhl Prof. Bayer, Postfach 20 24 20, D-8000 München 2" id="2574434342">Burkhard Freitag</author><author org="Technische Universität München, Lehrstuhl Prof. Bayer, Postfach 20 24 20, D-8000 München 2" id="2399577511">Olaf Biernath</author></authors><n_citation>8</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>97364269</reference><reference>146663255</reference><reference>1570025952</reference><reference>1855541034</reference><reference>2027276583</reference><reference>2070553391</reference><reference>2092842298</reference><reference>2132063146</reference><reference>2143526228</reference><reference>2163810897</reference><reference>2167527087</reference></references><venue id="" type="">Proceedings of the Third International Conference on Data and Knowledge Bases#R##N#Improving Usability and Responsiveness</venue><doi>10.1016/B978-1-4832-1313-2.50009-3</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47342">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.64333">Database tuning</keyword><keyword weight="0.52195">Heuristic</keyword><keyword weight="0.61163">Deductive database</keyword><keyword weight="0.47441">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.64204">View</keyword><keyword weight="0.63405">Database design</keyword><keyword weight="0.63194">Database schema</keyword><keyword weight="0.5048">Heuristics</keyword><keyword weight="0.6332">Database theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.4649">Database</keyword></keywords><publisher>Morgan Kaufmann</publisher><abstract>In this paper an Airtravel Expert Database built on top of a deductive database system is presented. The system makes extensive use of domain dependent heuristics and is able to find optimal time flight connections between any two airports under a number of user specified restrictions such as day and time of departure/arrival or preferred airlines. Basic data is taken from the official airline timetables and stored as base relations of the deductive database. Essentially the system performs a bidirectional heuristic search in the (weighted) graph given by the direct flight network. The basic query evaluation method is sloppy delta iteration. The query evaluation strategy can be viewed as informed because sloppy iteration provides a means to incorporate problem dependent heuristic knowledge. The Airtravel Expert Database serves as both a means for the investigation of the sloppy iteration scheme and as the kernel of an operational large scale airtravel information system with the potential to handle a large database and with the extensibility to access an external database.</abstract></paper>