<paper id="1592962610"><title>The effects of information system user expectations on their performance and perceptions</title><year>1993</year><authors><author org="M.J. Neeley School of Business, Texas Christian University, Fort Worth, Texas#TAB#" id="1273249561">Bernadette Szajna</author><author org="College of Business Administration, University of Houston, Houston, Texas" id="2303779361">Richard W. Scamell</author></authors><n_citation>249</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1574807592</reference><reference>1954663826</reference><reference>1987333162</reference><reference>1988410705</reference><reference>1990810281</reference><reference>1998970014</reference><reference>2011976980</reference><reference>2027462003</reference><reference>2036113824</reference><reference>2127455238</reference><reference>2157311082</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/249589</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.53832">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.65371">User expectations</keyword><keyword weight="0.50693">Cognitive dissonance</keyword><keyword weight="0.55983">End user</keyword><keyword weight="0.50209">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.41695">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45027">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.46647">Perception</keyword><keyword weight="0.43694">Realism</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>The consequences of information system failure become more acute as organizations continue to invest in information technology and application development. Being able to better predict IS failure before implementation of a system could facilitate changes in the information system that can lead to implementation success. The realism of user expectations has been suggested as one possible means of assessing the eventual success or failure of an IS. Cognitive dissonance theory was used to hypothesize the behavior and attitudes of end users having certain expectations of a system. This experiment investigates the association between unrealistic expectations with both usersu0027 perceptions (i.e., user satisfaction) and their performance with the IS (i.e., decision performance). A longitudinal experiment was performed in which the expectations of the subjects were manipulated to be unrealistically high, realistically moderate, or unrealistically low. The results suggest an association between realism of usersu0027 expectations and their perceptions but not their actual performance. Future research should be directed toward the development of an instrument to measure user expectations, as well as toward understanding the causes of unrealistic user expectations.</abstract></paper>