<paper id="1849252796"><title>A Formal Definition of Binary Topological Relationships</title><year>1989</year><authors><author org="University of Maine." id="66103918">Max J. Egenhofer</author></authors><n_citation>269</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1562735428</reference><reference>1603382969</reference><reference>1945128294</reference><reference>2050365841</reference></references><venue id="" type="">FOFO '89 Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Foundations of Data Organization and Algorithms</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-51295-0_148</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.40466">Integer</keyword><keyword weight="0.42219">Data processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.58834">Spatial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.44861">Information retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.48875">Inference</keyword><keyword weight="0.44013">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.58758">Spatial query</keyword><keyword weight="0.48526">Rotation formalisms in three dimensions</keyword><keyword weight="0.43614">Management system</keyword><keyword weight="0.59973">Spatial database</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The exploration of spatial relationships is a multi-disciplinary effort involving researchers from linguistics, cognitive science, psychology, geography, cartography, semiology, computer science, surveying engineering, and mathematics. Terms like close and far or North and South are not as clearly understood as the standard relationships between integer numbers. The treatment of relationships among spatial objects is an essential task in geographic data processing and CAD/CAM. Spatial query languages, for example, must offer terms for spatial relationships; spatial database management systems need algorithms to determine relationships. Hence, a formal definition of spatial relationships is necessary to clarify the usersu0027 diverse understanding of spatial relationships and to actually deduce relationships among spatial objects. Based upon such formalisms, spatial reasoning and inference will be possible.</abstract></paper>