<paper id="1980521624"><title>Information systems management and strategy formulation: the ‘stages of growth’ model revisited</title><year>1991</year><authors><author org="Warwick Business School, University of Warwick, England, and Corporate Systems Planning Pty Ltd, Perth, Australia" id="162332485">Robert D. Galliers</author><author org="Warwick Business School, University of Warwick, England, and Corporate Systems Planning Pty Ltd, Perth, Australia" id="2465061769">A. R. Sutherland</author></authors><n_citation>259</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>2037027277</reference><reference>2044790070</reference><reference>2046080825</reference></references><venue id="92260147" type="J">Information Systems Journal</venue><doi>10.1111/j.1365-2575.1991.tb00030.x</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.50557">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.50311">Management information systems</keyword><keyword weight="0.43007">Mathematical economics</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Growth model</keyword><keyword weight="0.44575">Empirical evidence</keyword><keyword weight="0.41364">Human resources</keyword><keyword weight="0.41008">Sociology</keyword><keyword weight="0.41914">Operations research</keyword><keyword weight="0.41136">Data processing system</keyword><keyword weight="0.49916">Strategic information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.42382">Management science</keyword></keywords><publisher>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher><abstract>Abstract. The original ‘stages of growth’ model, as applied to the field of Information Systems (Gibson u0026 Nolan, 1974), may be viewed as seminal, given the influence it has had on both theory and practice (Nolan, 1984; Sullivan, 1985; Ward, et al., 1990). This is so, despite the modelu0027s lack of substantiation based on empirical evidence, the overly simplistic assumptions on which it is based, and the limited focus of the original concept (Benbasat, et al., 1984; King u0026 Kraemer, :[80],"its first appearance, the model has been refined following many applications (Nolan, 1979, 1984). In addition, others have developed ‘stages of growth’ models of their own. For example, Somogyi u0026 Galliers, (1987a, b)provide a model depicting the move from basic data processing systems to strategic information systems, tracing the early days of commercial applications of computing through to the present day (Ward et al. 1990). Earl (1983, 1986, 1988, 1989) proposes a stages-model for information systems planning, as does Bhabuta (1988), while Hirschheim, et al. (1988) have developed a more broadly focused model associated with the development of the information-systems management a :[182],"result of a review of the above and of a case study research undertaken in Perth, Western Australia, a revised model was developed, which takes account of current thinking and past experience in the application of the various ‘stages of growth’ models (Sutherland u0026 Galliers, :[229],"paper sets out to review some of these models and proceeds to describe the process of developing, testing and applying the revised ‘stages of growth’ model. The model is more broadly focused than the original concept, incorporating strategic, organizational, human resource and management considerations. As a result, it is argued that this model has greater utility than :[80],"its predecessors.</abstract></paper>