<paper id="1709117811"><title>A Low-Complexity and High-Performance Algorithm for the Fast Correlation Attack</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="Serbian Academy of Science and Arts" id="222837960">Miodrag J. Mihaljevic</author><author org="University of Hawaii," id="2511994844">Marc P. C. Fossorier</author><author org="University of Tokyo" id="2101807108">Hideki Imai</author></authors><n_citation>50</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1506732303</reference><reference>1526649776</reference><reference>1539946152</reference><reference>1545049011</reference><reference>1587856445</reference><reference>1605174360</reference><reference>1660562555</reference><reference>1661175875</reference><reference>1748141888</reference><reference>1836967236</reference><reference>1868012152</reference><reference>1979198062</reference><reference>1985029805</reference><reference>2045407304</reference><reference>2123530431</reference><reference>2127909992</reference><reference>2161517294</reference></references><venue id="2758283624" type="C">Fast Software Encryption</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-44706-7_14</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.69971">Sequential decoding</keyword><keyword weight="0.6047">Berlekamp–Welch algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.59344">Convolutional code</keyword><keyword weight="0.4366">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.51897">Block code</keyword><keyword weight="0.46922">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.56226">Correlation attack</keyword><keyword weight="0.58371">Decoding methods</keyword><keyword weight="0.65399">List decoding</keyword><keyword weight="0.55623">Belief propagation</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>An algorithm for cryptanalysis of certain keystream generators is proposed. The developed algorithm has the following two advantages over other reported ones: (i) it is more powerful and (ii) it provides a high-speed software implementation, as well as a simple hard-ware one, suitable for high parallel architectures. The novel algorithm is a method for the fast correlation attack with significantly better performance than other reported methods, assuming a lower complexity and the same inputs. The algorithm is based on decoding procedures of the corresponding binary block code with novel constructions of the parity-checks, and the following two decoding approaches are employed: the a posterior probability based threshold decoding and the belief propagation based bit-flipping iterative decoding. These decoding procedures offer good trade-offs between the required sample length, overall complexity and performance. The novel algorithm is compared with recently proposed improved fast correlation attacks based on convolutional codes and turbo decoding. The underlying principles, performance and complexity are compared, and the gain obtained with the novel approach is pointed out.</abstract></paper>