<paper id="1840655788"><title>The Consistency of Task-Based Authorization Constraints in Workflow Systems</title><year>2004</year><authors><author org="University of Pennsylvania" id="2021204492">Kaijun Tan</author><author org="Univ. of London#TAB#" id="2145819526">Jason Crampton</author><author org="University of Pennsylvania" id="1683457605">Carl A. Gunter</author></authors><n_citation>82</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1503568870</reference><reference>1538129883</reference><reference>1639227833</reference><reference>1979711649</reference><reference>1996983098</reference><reference>2015234709</reference><reference>2021079739</reference><reference>2024211312</reference><reference>2026913455</reference><reference>2038953226</reference><reference>2054245586</reference><reference>2100245805</reference><reference>2134167896</reference><reference>2145857528</reference><reference>2162171351</reference><reference>2163283609</reference><reference>2166602595</reference></references><venue id="2615919549" type="C">IEEE Computer Security Foundations Symposium</venue><doi>10.1109/CSFW.2004.22</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.71164">Workflow technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.56203">Business process</keyword><keyword weight="0.4576">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.54007">Role-based access control</keyword><keyword weight="0.64119">XPDL</keyword><keyword weight="0.57375">Security policy</keyword><keyword weight="0.72789">Workflow engine</keyword><keyword weight="0.71736">Workflow management system</keyword><keyword weight="0.63806">Workflow</keyword><keyword weight="0.45492">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><abstract>Workflow management systems (WFMSs) have attracteda lot of interest both in academia and the business community.A workflow consists of a collection of tasks that areorganized to facilitate some business process specification.To simplify the complexity of security administration, it iscommon to use role-based access control (RBAC) to grantauthorization to roles and users. Typically, security policiesare expressed as constraints on users, roles, tasks and theworkflow itself. A workflow system can become very complexand involve several organizations or different units ofan organization, thus the number of security policies may bevery large and their interactions very complex. It is clearlyimportant to know whether the existence of such constraintswill prevent certain instances of the workflow from completing.Unfortunately, no existing constraint models have consideredthis problem satisfactorily.In this paper we define a model for constrained workflowsystems that includes local and global cardinality constraints,separation of duty constraints and binding of dutyconstraints. We define the notion of a workflow specificationand of a constrained workflow authorization schema.Our main result is to establish necessary and sufficient conditionsfor the set of constraints that ensure a sound constrainedworkflow authorization schema, that is, for anyuser or any role who are authorized to a task, there is atleast one complete workflow instance when this user or thisrole executes this task.</abstract></paper>