<paper id="1755189310"><title>Computation Tree Logic CTL* and Path Quantifiers in the Monadic Theory of the Binary Tree</title><year>1987</year><authors><author org="RWTH Aachen" id="2497383978">Thilo Hafer</author><author org="RWTH Aachen" id="2121581756">Wolfgang Thomas</author></authors><n_citation>135</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>100744576</reference><reference>118337677</reference><reference>185780771</reference><reference>1491593738</reference><reference>1502942777</reference><reference>1967494119</reference><reference>2004306067</reference><reference>2010611844</reference><reference>2048355938</reference><reference>2054554282</reference><reference>2072887965</reference><reference>2170458819</reference><reference>2806619258</reference></references><venue id="1141821850" type="C">International Colloquium on Automata, Languages and Programming</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-18088-5_22</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.69018">Computation tree logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.45396">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.44716">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.6406">Zeroth-order logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.67844">Probabilistic CTL</keyword><keyword weight="0.70126">Linear temporal logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.63844">Intermediate logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.42182">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.62668">Dynamic logic (modal logic)</keyword><keyword weight="0.62956">Higher-order logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.68681">Monadic predicate calculus</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In this paper we study the expressive power of the full branching time logic CTL* (of Clarke, Emerson, Halpern and Sistla), by comparing it with fragments of monadic second-order logic over the binary tree. We show that over binary tree models the system CTL* has the same expressive power as monadic second-order logic in which set quantification is restricted to infinite paths (in particular, the full strength of first-order logic is captured here by CTL*). This generalizes Kampu0027s theorem on the equivalence between propositional linear time logic and first-order logic over the ordering of the natural numbers. For the proof an extension of CTL* by past operators is introduced. The transition from monadic formulas to CTL* rests on a model-theoretic decomposition lemma for trees that is justified by an application of the Ehrenfeucht-Fraisse game. The paper concludes by discussing variants of the main result, dealing for example with trees of higher branching index and the extended branching time logic ECTL*.</abstract></paper>