<paper id="114456054"><title>On the classification and existence of structures in default logic</title><year>1990</year><authors><author org="University of Kentucky" id="2232622618">Aidong Zhang</author><author org="University of Kentucky" id="2027206797">V. Wiktor Marek</author></authors><n_citation>20</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1505241859</reference><reference>1966552757</reference><reference>2029246084</reference><reference>2067326626</reference><reference>2155322595</reference><reference>2291179199</reference><reference>2611415697</reference></references><venue id="1180700458" type="C">Portuguese Conference on Artificial Intelligence</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-51665-4_80</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.50859">Default rule</keyword><keyword weight="0.55774">Default logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.46276">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.57663">Autoepistemic logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.49748">Ranking</keyword><keyword weight="0.49654">Zeroth-order logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.53853">Least fixed point</keyword><keyword weight="0.58782">Non-monotonic logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.49404">Logic programming</keyword><keyword weight="0.42916">Mathematics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We investigate possible belief sets of an agent reasoning with defaults. Besides of Reiteru0027s extensions which are based on a proof-theoretic paradigm (similar to Logic Programming), other structures for default theories, based on weaker or different methods of constructing belief sets are considered, in particular, weak extensions and minimal sets. The first of these concepts is known to be closely connected to autoepistemic expansions of Moore, the other to minimal stable autoepistemic theories containing the initial assumptions. We introduce the concept of ranking collection of defaults and investigate the properties of largest ranking subset of the family D, determined by W. We find a necessary and sufficient condition for a weak extension to be an extension in terms of ranking. We prove that for theories (D, W) without extension, the least fixed point of the associated operator (with weak extension or minimal set as a context) is an extension of suitably chosen (Du0027,W) with Du0027\(\subseteq\)D. We investigate conditions for existence of extensions and introduce the notion of perfectly-ranked set of defaults and its variant of maximally perfectly-ranked set. Existence of such set of defaults turns out to be equivalent to existence of extension. Finally, we investigate convergence of algorithm for computing extension.</abstract></paper>