<paper id="1602578031"><title>Software product lines, service-oriented architecture and frameworks: worlds apart or ideal partners?</title><year>2006</year><authors><author org="Universit채t Stuttgart, Information Systems, Business Software, Stuttgart, Germany" id="1241284821">Andreas Helferich</author><author org="Universit채t Stuttgart, Information Systems, Business Software, Stuttgart, Germany" id="2282024679">Georg Herzwurm</author><author org="Universit채t Stuttgart, Information Systems, Business Software, Stuttgart, Germany" id="2130116381">Stefan Jesse</author><author org="Universit채t Stuttgart, Information Systems, Business Software, Stuttgart, Germany" id="1839971207">Martin Mikusz</author></authors><n_citation>20</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1541290946</reference><reference>1554977156</reference><reference>1611760289</reference><reference>1978591382</reference><reference>2493112176</reference><reference>2562983288</reference></references><venue id="" type="">TEAA'06 Proceedings of the 2nd international conference on Trends in enterprise application architecture</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-75912-6_14</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46406">Software engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.45214">Systems engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.57982">Software architecture description</keyword><keyword weight="0.57631">Software system</keyword><keyword weight="0.60538">Component-based software engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.59307">Reference architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.58853">Resource-oriented architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.40078">Engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.57183">Service-oriented architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.59338">Software development</keyword><keyword weight="0.57667">Software framework</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Service-oriented Architectures and Software Product Lines are two concepts that currently get a lot of attention in research and practice. Both promise to make the development of flexible, cost-effective software systems and support high levels of reuse. But at the same time they are quite different from one another: while Software Product Lines focus on one producer alone developing a set of systems based on a common platform (often in the embedded systems-domain), most proponents of Service-oriented Architecture propose systems consisting of loosely coupled services or company-wide infrastructures including a variety of systems that are loosely coupled using services. In any case, the services are usually developed by various companies (e.g. SAP develops services for their platform itself, but explicitly allows other companies to develop and sell their services for the platform, too). Focus of this paper is the comparison of these concepts and the concept of component frameworks and show where they differ and analyze if they are mutually exclusive or (at least partially) complementary.</abstract></paper>