<paper id="1607684240"><title>Unified Hardware Architecture for 128-Bit Block Ciphers AES and Camellia</title><year>2003</year><authors><author org="IBM Japan ltd." id="2110212166">Akashi Satoh</author><author org="IBM Japan ltd." id="2104439210">Sumio Morioka</author></authors><n_citation>32</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1573725807</reference><reference>2112244944</reference></references><venue id="1127098075" type="C">Cryptographic Hardware and Embedded Systems</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-45238-6_25</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47533">Affine transformation</keyword><keyword weight="0.51498">Block cipher</keyword><keyword weight="0.41738">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.44492">Parallel computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.44869">Permutation</keyword><keyword weight="0.42216">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.44915">CMOS</keyword><keyword weight="0.4695">Standard cell</keyword><keyword weight="0.46827">Galois theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.56195">Hardware architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.48145">128-bit</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We proposed unified hardware architecture for the two 128-bit block ciphers AES and Camellia, and evaluated its performance using a 0.13-μm CMOS standard cell library. S-Boxes are the biggest hardware components in block ciphers, and some times they consume more than half of the design area. The S-Boxes in AES and Camellia are the combination of affine transformations and multiplicative inversions on a Galois fields. The size of the fields is same, but their structures are different. Therefore we converted the basis between the fields by using isomorphism transformations, and shared the inverter between AES and Camellia. The affine transformations were also merged by factoring common terms. In addition to the S-Box sharing, many other components such as permutation layers and key whiting are also merged. As a result, a compact hardware of 14.9K gates with throughputs of 469 Mbps for AES and of 661 Mbps for Camellia was achieved. The hardware synthesized with speed optimization obtained throughputs of 794 Mbps and 1.12 Gbps for each algorithm with 24.4K gates.</abstract></paper>