<paper id="1548599151"><title>Combining CTL, Trace Theory and Timing Models</title><year>1989</year><authors><author org="Carnegie - Mellon University#TAB#" id="2984343625">Jerry R. Burch</author></authors><n_citation>19</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1491037212</reference><reference>1607877490</reference><reference>2023984413</reference><reference>2111125619</reference><reference>2117189826</reference></references><venue id="1162450063" type="C">Computer Aided Verification</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-52148-8_28</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.51165">Asynchronous communication</keyword><keyword weight="0.41782">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.52499">Model checking</keyword><keyword weight="0.45038">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45447">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.46216">Electronic circuit</keyword><keyword weight="0.4791">Trace theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.37158">CTL*</keyword><keyword weight="0.50618">State space</keyword><keyword weight="0.55123">Mutual exclusion</keyword><keyword weight="0.44781">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.56108">Liveness</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>A system that combines CTL model checking and trace theory for verifying speed-independent asynchronous circuits is described. This system is able to verify a large and useful class of liveness and fairness properties, and is able to find safety violations after examining only a small fraction of the circuitu0027s state space in many cases. An extension has been implemented that allows the verification of circuits that are not speed-independent, but instead rely on assumptions about the relative delays of their components for correct operation. This greatly expands the class of circuits that can be automatically verified, making the verifier a more useful tool in the design of asynchronous circuits. The system is demonstrated on several fair mutual exclusion circuits, including a speed-independent version that is verified correct. It is also shown that given quite weak assumptions about the relative delays of components, the problem of designing a fair mutual exclusion circuit using a potentially unfair mutual exclusion element becomes almost trivial.</abstract></paper>