<paper id="1531486736"><title>Human information processing in information and decisoin support systems</title><year>1982</year><authors><author org="" id="2076228660">Daniel Robey</author><author org="" id="2160088983">William Taggart</author></authors><n_citation>59</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1564930140</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/249283</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.59499">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.4717">Heuristic</keyword><keyword weight="0.57829">Information processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.46528">Lateralization of brain function</keyword><keyword weight="0.44283">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Support system</keyword><keyword weight="0.59885">Decision support system</keyword><keyword weight="0.43371">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.45798">Human–computer interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.44463">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.49779">Cognitive style</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Decision maker</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>This article explores the relevance of human information processing to the development and use of computer based information and decision support systems. Human information processing is related to the biological specializations of the human brain. Basically, the left cerebral hemisphere performs rational, sequential, analytical functions, while the right hemisphere operates intuitively, simultaneously, and holistically. In contrast, the electronic computer performs only logical, sequential operations. The electronic computer is in this sense a model of the left brain and no the :[80],"implications emerge from this understanding. First, research using cognitive style to predict decision behavior should include intuitive styles as well as heuristic and analytical styles, even though intuition cannot be modeled in the traditional sense. Second, labor between electronic computer and human "bio-computer" for various types of organizational decision making. Third, information systems should be designed to support the type of processing required by the task, including both right and left hemisphere processes. Information systems which engage both hemispheres of the decision maker are likely to be more useful in complex tasks than those which support only the activities of the logical, left hemisphere.</abstract></paper>