<paper id="1973536616"><title>Transaction processing monitors</title><year>1990</year><authors><author org="Digital Equipment Corp., Cambridge, MA" id="2304774990">Philip A. Bernstein</author></authors><n_citation>59</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1545155892</reference><reference>1572808209</reference><reference>1602701629</reference><reference>2002564548</reference><reference>2005383603</reference><reference>2021838450</reference><reference>2028650062</reference><reference>2095471802</reference><reference>2113926942</reference><reference>2130493426</reference><reference>2150581873</reference></references><venue id="103482838" type="J">Communications of The ACM</venue><doi>10.1145/92755.92767</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44773">Transaction processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.46973">Applied mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.55805">Monte Carlo method</keyword><keyword weight="0.46715">Mathematical optimization</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Homogeneous</keyword><keyword weight="0.43205">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.58842">Markov chain</keyword><keyword weight="0.51868">Stochastic process</keyword><keyword weight="0.44964">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.5287">Score</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Gradient estimation</keyword><keyword weight="0.55983">Estimator</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>@(·) is typically difficult to evaluate analytically, Monte Carlo optimization is an attractive methodology. By analogy with deterministic mathematical programming, efficient Monte Carlo gradient estimation is an important ingredient of simulation-based optimization algorithms. As a consequence, gradient estimation has recently attracted considerable attention in the simulation community. It is our goal, in this article, to describe one efficient method for estimating gradients in the Monte Carlo setting, namely the likelihood ratio method (also known as the efficient score method). This technique has been previously described (in less general settings than those developed in this article) in [6, 16, 18, 21]. An alternative gradient estimation procedure is infinitesimal perturbation analysis; see [11, 12] for an introduction. While it is typically more difficult to apply to a given application than the likelihood ratio technique of interest here, it often turns out to be statistically more accurate. In this article, we first describe two important problems which motivate our study of efficient gradient estimation algorithms. Next, we will present the likelihood ratio gradient estimator in a general setting in which the essential idea is most transparent. The section that follows then specializes the estimator to discrete-time stochastic processes. We derive likelihood-ratio-gradient estimators for both time-homogeneous and non-time homogeneous discrete-time Markov chains. Later, we discuss likelihood ratio gradient estimation in continuous time. As examples of our analysis, we present the gradient estimators for time-homogeneous continuous-time Markov chains; non-time homogeneous continuous-time Markov chains; semi-Markov processes; and generalized semi-Markov processes. (The analysis throughout these sections assumes the performance measure that defines</abstract></paper>