<paper id="1513272470"><title>Nets in Office Automation</title><year>1986</year><authors><author org="Institut für Methodische Grundlagen Gesellschaft für Mathematik und Datenverarbeitung (GMD)" id="2713919043">Klaus Voss</author></authors><n_citation>13</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1537537640</reference><reference>1564931906</reference><reference>1573845675</reference><reference>1584241354</reference><reference>1590171192</reference><reference>1991353419</reference><reference>1996809012</reference><reference>1997422892</reference><reference>2041592704</reference><reference>2113355185</reference><reference>2137865376</reference><reference>2341767296</reference></references><venue id="" type="">Proceedings of an Advanced Course on Petri Nets: Central Models and Their Properties, Advances in Petri Nets 1986-Part II</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-17906-2_28</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.468">ISA100.11a</keyword><keyword weight="0.45843">Human resources</keyword><keyword weight="0.46471">Engineering management</keyword><keyword weight="0.44831">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.4994">Discretion</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Information object</keyword><keyword weight="0.70637">Office automation</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>An office is a socio-technical system which exhibits a great variety of aspects of different nature. Essential components not only include the office functions and their informational interrelationships but also technical and human resources, aims and rules etc. An office is characterized among others by partly autonomous distributed tasks, by the discretion in performing tasks, by incomplete and ambiguous data, and by its ongoing structural and behavioural evolution. Because of this high complexity, the design or analysis of offices must be based on simplifying models, each one representing the office under a particular perspective. To relate these models to each other, a common conceptual basis is needed. This contribution presents an approach to office modelling on the basis of General Net Theory. It discusses possibilities to represent the most crucial components and properties of offices, aiming at the development of more and more comprehensive models.</abstract></paper>