<paper id="1541593857"><title>Extended ML: an institution-independent framework for formal program development</title><year>1986</year><authors><author org="University of Edinburgh," id="2063404503">D Sannella</author><author org="Polish Academy of Sciences" id="2352948">A Tarlecki</author></authors><n_citation>56</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1496607686</reference><reference>1528430173</reference><reference>1549434492</reference><reference>1586272280</reference><reference>1925601792</reference><reference>1970554275</reference><reference>1971240584</reference><reference>1983608286</reference><reference>1999862696</reference><reference>2017041211</reference><reference>2055364993</reference><reference>2099305192</reference><reference>2136241690</reference><reference>2224144252</reference><reference>2914821813</reference></references><venue id="164884734" type="J">Annales Des Télécommunications</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-17162-2_133</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.6052">Specification language</keyword><keyword weight="0.76935">Extended ML</keyword><keyword weight="0.57698">Programming language specification</keyword><keyword weight="0.47101">Programming language</keyword><keyword weight="0.59722">Standard ML</keyword><keyword weight="0.45063">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.53152">High-level programming language</keyword><keyword weight="0.55798">Formal methods</keyword><keyword weight="0.51422">First-generation programming language</keyword><keyword weight="0.51003">Executable</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer Berlin Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The Extended ML specification language provides a framework for the formal stepwise development of modular programs in the Standard ML programming language from specifications. The object of this paper is to equip Extended ML with a semantics which is completely independent of the logical system used to write specifications, building on Goguen and Burstallu0027s work on the notion of an institution as a formalisation of the concept of a logical system. One advantage of this is that it permits freedom in the choice of the logic used in writing specifications; an intriguing side-effect is that it enables Extended ML to be used to develop programs in languages other than Standard ML since we view programs as simply Extended ML specifications which happen to include only “executable” axioms. The semantics of Extended ML is defined in terms of the primitive specification-building operations of the ASL kernel specification language which itself has an institution-independent semantics.</abstract></paper>