<paper id="1514361308"><title>Perfectly-Secure Key Distribution for Dynamic Conferences</title><year>1992</year><authors><author org="UNIVERSITÀ DI SALERNO" id="1854929514">Carlo Blundo</author><author org="UNIVERSITÀ DI SALERNO" id="1931511623">Alfredo De Santis</author><author org="IBM T.J. Watson research center" id="2178836961">Amir Herzberg</author><author org="IBM T.J. Watson research center" id="2297071937">Shay Kutten</author><author org="UNIVERSITÀ DI SALERNO" id="54027764">Ugo Vaccaro</author><author org="IBM T.J. Watson research center" id="2097786798">Moti Yung</author></authors><n_citation>725</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1481743830</reference><reference>1491242664</reference><reference>1493241500</reference><reference>1506030643</reference><reference>1516788100</reference><reference>1519891470</reference><reference>1539979035</reference><reference>1569083856</reference><reference>1974152067</reference><reference>2004881597</reference><reference>2016898589</reference><reference>2033535959</reference><reference>2047925852</reference><reference>2102802476</reference><reference>2146973388</reference><reference>2147172043</reference><reference>2156186849</reference><reference>2243821431</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-48071-4_33</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.64421">Key distribution</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Common key</keyword><keyword weight="0.47509">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47408">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.4959">Network topology</keyword><keyword weight="0.46772">Computation</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><abstract>A key distribution scheme for dynamic conferences is a method by which initially an (off-line) trusted server distributes private individual pieces of information to a set of users. Later any group of users of a given size (a dynamic conference) is able to compute a common secure key. In this paper we study the theory and applications of such perfectly secure systems. In this setting, any group of t users can compute a common key by each user computing using only his private piece of information and the identities of the other t - 1 group users. Keys are secure against coalitions of up to k users, that is, even if k users pool together their pieces they cannot compute anything about a key of any t-size conference comprised of other users.First we consider a non-interactive model where users compute the common key without any interaction. We prove a lower hound on the size of the useru0027s piece of information of (k+t-1 t-1) times the size of the common key. We then establish the optimality of this bound, by describing and analyzing a scheme which exactly meets this limitation (the construction extends the one in [2]). Then, we consider the model where interaction is allowed in the common key computation phase, and show a gap between the models by exhibiting an interactive scheme in which the useru0027s information is only k + t - 1 times the size of the common key. We further show various applications and useful modifications of our basic scheme. Finally, we present its adaptation to network topologies with neighborhood constraints.</abstract></paper>