<paper id="1984954427"><title>GORDIAN: VLSI placement by quadratic programming and slicing optimization</title><year>1991</year><authors><author org="Siemens Corp. Res. &amp; Dev., Munich, Germany" id="2669438049">J.M. Kleinhans</author><author org="" id="1240847681">G. Sigl</author><author org="" id="2168851700">F.M. Johannes</author><author org="" id="2761117201">K.J. Antreich</author></authors><n_citation>499</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1528724172</reference><reference>1976473589</reference><reference>1980746862</reference><reference>1990556031</reference><reference>2044944864</reference><reference>2062902020</reference><reference>2072974175</reference><reference>2095117703</reference><reference>2097481005</reference><reference>2104573358</reference><reference>2121535159</reference><reference>2122380282</reference><reference>2139763182</reference><reference>2156894251</reference><reference>2161455936</reference><reference>2171470054</reference></references><venue id="100835903" type="J">IEEE Transactions on Computer-Aided Design of Integrated Circuits and Systems</venue><doi>10.1109/43.67789</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.4614">Mathematical optimization</keyword><keyword weight="0.59111">Global optimization</keyword><keyword weight="0.43394">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46862">Slicing</keyword><keyword weight="0.58495">Placement</keyword><keyword weight="0.46986">Maxima and minima</keyword><keyword weight="0.57852">Quadratic programming</keyword><keyword weight="0.49973">Very-large-scale integration</keyword><keyword weight="0.5425">Constrained optimization</keyword><keyword weight="0.45338">Computation</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>The authors present a placement method for cell-based layout styles. It is composed of alternating and interacting global optimization and partitioning steps that are followed by an optimization of the area utilization. Methods using the divide-and-conquer paradigm usually lose the global view by generating smaller and smaller subproblems. In contrast, GORDIAN maintains the simultaneous treatment of all cells over all global optimization steps, thereby considering constraints that reflect the current dissection of the circuit. The global optimizations are performed by solving quadratic programming problems that possess unique global minima. Improved partitioning schemes for the stepwise refinement of the placement are introduced. The area utilization is optimized by an exhaustive slicing procedure. The placement method is applied to real-world problems, and excellent results in terms of placement quality and computation time are obtained. u003e</abstract></paper>