<paper id="1589637227"><title>Research on semantic Web service-oriented MMFI for complex information registration</title><year>2005</year><authors><author org="State Key lab. of Software Eng., Wuhan Univ., China" id="1479783131">He Yangfan</author><author org="He Keqing#TAB#" id="2087449931">He Keqing</author><author org="Wang Chong#TAB#" id="2150826522">Wang Chong</author></authors><n_citation>6</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1965313825</reference><reference>1973950298</reference><reference>1989140425</reference></references><venue id="1135185882" type="C">Service Oriented Software Engineering</venue><doi>10.1109/SOSE.2005.30</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.52746">Ontology</keyword><keyword weight="0.45421">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.548">Semantic Web Stack</keyword><keyword weight="0.45956">Information retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.44816">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.49929">Interoperability</keyword><keyword weight="0.57346">Interoperation</keyword><keyword weight="0.54053">Semantic Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.46308">Domain of discourse</keyword><keyword weight="0.59967">Upper ontology</keyword><keyword weight="0.51293">Metamodeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.43982">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>Information registration is a key problem in semantic Web service. Current registration standards are relatively weak in the description of complex relationship between information resources. The metamodel framework for interoperability (MMFI) is proposed in this paper to address this problem. The theoretical foundation of MMFI is metamodeling and ontology, which describe the common features of models in universe of discourse. Models based on the same metamodel or ontology can have certain extent of interoperation. MMFI provides a mechanism to record the relationship between metamodel and corresponding models, which contributes to the automatic discovery of compatible services. More specifically, MMFI for ontology registration defines a framework for registration and interoperation of ontology models, which then facilitate the interoperation of the other kind of models by means of common logical background.</abstract></paper>