<paper id="1976420017"><title>Improving privacy and security in multi-authority attribute-based encryption</title><year>2009</year><authors><author org="Microsoft Research, , Redmond, WA , USA" id="2138923407">Melissa Chase</author><author org="New York University, New York , NY, USA#TAB#" id="2309300153">Sherman S.M. Chow</author></authors><n_citation>452</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1498316612</reference><reference>1510795740</reference><reference>1569083856</reference><reference>1578237955</reference><reference>1583834646</reference><reference>1756608328</reference><reference>1763482972</reference><reference>1983238288</reference><reference>2076046175</reference><reference>2108072891</reference><reference>2138001464</reference><reference>2165210192</reference><reference>2165297797</reference><reference>2520042450</reference></references><venue id="1198471430" type="C">Computer and Communications Security</venue><doi>10.1145/1653662.1653678</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46689">USable</keyword><keyword weight="0.4437">Internet privacy</keyword><keyword weight="0.49306">Identifier</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Central authority</keyword><keyword weight="0.447">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46437">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.47622">Pooling</keyword><keyword weight="0.66159">Attribute-based encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.59822">Encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.57484">Ciphertext</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>Attribute based encryption (ABE) [13] determines decryption ability based on a useru0027s attributes. In a multi-authority ABE scheme, multiple attribute-authorities monitor different sets of attributes and issue corresponding decryption keys to users, and encryptors can require that a user obtain keys for appropriate attributes from each authority before decrypting a message. Chase [5] gave a multi-authority ABE scheme using the concepts of a trusted central authority (CA) and global identifiers (GID). However, the CA in that construction has the power to decrypt every ciphertext, which seems somehow contradictory to the original goal of distributing control over many potentially untrusted authorities. Moreover, in that construction, the use of a consistent GID allowed the authorities to combine their information to build a full profile with all of a useru0027s attributes, which unnecessarily compromises the privacy of the user. In this paper, we propose a solution which removes the trusted central authority, and protects the usersu0027 privacy by preventing the authorities from pooling their information on particular users, thus making ABE more usable in practice.</abstract></paper>