<paper id="1984758304"><title>Modeling computer interest in older adults: the role of age, education, computer knowledge, and computer anxiety.</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="Wayne State U, Inst of Gerontology, Detroit, MI, US" id="2170945711">R. Darin Ellis</author><author org="Wayne State University" id="2332816889">Jason C. Allaire</author></authors><n_citation>174</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1991272408</reference><reference>2060923988</reference><reference>2065340789</reference></references><venue id="83386566" type="J">Human Factors</venue><doi>10.1518/001872099779610996</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44858">Social psychology</keyword><keyword weight="0.46109">Developmental psychology</keyword><keyword weight="0.5065">Structural equation modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Older Populations</keyword><keyword weight="0.55129">Anxiety</keyword><keyword weight="0.45225">Psychology</keyword><keyword weight="0.63498">Computer literacy</keyword><keyword weight="0.47644">Mediation (Marxist theory and media studies)</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Computer anxiety</keyword><keyword weight="0.50844">Digital literacy</keyword></keywords><publisher>SAGE PublicationsSage CA: Los Angeles, CA</publisher><abstract>We proposed a mediation model to examine the effects of age, education, computer knowledge, and computer anxiety on computer interest in older adults. We hypothesized that computer knowledge and computer anxiety would fully mediate the effects of age and education on computer interest. A sample of 330 older adults from local senior-citizen apartment buildings completed a survey that included an assessment of the constructs included in the model. Using structural equation modeling, we found that the results supported the hypothesized mediation model. In particular, the effect of computer knowledge operated on computer interest through computer anxiety. The effect of age was not fully mitigated by the other model variables, indicating the need for future research that identifies and models other correlates of age and computer interest. The most immediate application of this research is the finding that a simple 3-item instrument can be used to assess computer interest in older populations. This will help pr...</abstract></paper>