<paper id="1540770095"><title>A petri net based approach for process model driven deduction of BPEL code</title><year>2005</year><authors><author org="Institute of Applied Informatics and Formal Description Methods, Universität Karlsruhe (TH), Karlsruhe, Germany#TAB#" id="128624645">Agnes Koschmider</author><author org="Institute of Applied Informatics and Formal Description Methods, Universität Karlsruhe (TH), Karlsruhe, Germany#TAB#" id="677720030">Marco Mevius</author></authors><n_citation>10</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>56738844</reference><reference>81250683</reference><reference>1239375374</reference><reference>1511461976</reference><reference>1602569358</reference><reference>1634168340</reference><reference>1759712729</reference><reference>1962632332</reference><reference>2010816857</reference><reference>2038691138</reference><reference>2068480972</reference><reference>2099529102</reference><reference>2129328050</reference><reference>2174382227</reference></references><venue id="2754624328" type="C">International Conference on Move to Meaningful Internet Systems</venue><doi>10.1007/11575863_69</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.64388">Artifact-centric business process model</keyword><keyword weight="0.64352">Petri net</keyword><keyword weight="0.47566">Software engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.60374">Business process</keyword><keyword weight="0.42777">Simulation</keyword><keyword weight="0.46247">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.64203">Process architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.70354">Business Process Execution Language</keyword><keyword weight="0.65381">Business process modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.55139">Web service</keyword><keyword weight="0.66445">Business Process Model and Notation</keyword><keyword weight="0.46362">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The management of collaborative business processes refers to the design, analysis, and execution of interrelated production, logistics and information processes, which are usually performed by different independent enterprises in order to produce and to deliver a specified range of goods or services. The effort to interconnect independently developed business process models and to map them to process-implementing software components is particularly high. The implementation of such collaborative inter-organizational business process models is assisted by so-called choreography languages that can be executed by software applications. In this paper, we present a Petri net based approach for process-model driven deduction of BPEL code. Our approach is based on a specific type of high-level Petri nets, so-called XML nets. We use XML nets both for modeling and coordinating business processes implemented as Web services and for deriving BPEL elements of the Web service based components. Our approach provides a seamless concept for modeling, analysis and execution of business processes.</abstract></paper>