<paper id="1568780897"><title>True Random Number Generator Embedded in Reconfigurable Hardware</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="université Jean Monnet" id="2113817715">Viktor Fischer</author><author org="Technical University of Kosice" id="2085255016">Milos Drutarovský</author></authors><n_citation>140</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1641348075</reference><reference>1660562555</reference><reference>1793054443</reference></references><venue id="1127098075" type="C">Cryptographic Hardware and Embedded Systems</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-36400-5_30</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.50616">Clock signal</keyword><keyword weight="0.49964">Phase-locked loop</keyword><keyword weight="0.419">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48278">NIST</keyword><keyword weight="0.56096">Jitter</keyword><keyword weight="0.56229">Random number generation</keyword><keyword weight="0.50721">Randomness</keyword><keyword weight="0.48971">Reconfigurable computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.42822">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.51589">Programmable logic device</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>This paper presents a new True Random Number Generator (TRNG) based on an analog Phase-Locked Loop (PLL) implemented in a digital Altera Field Programmable Logic Device (FPLD). Starting with an analysis of the one available on chip source of randomness - the PLL synthesized low jitter clock signal, a new simple and reliable method of true randomness extraction is proposed. Basic assumptions about statistical properties of jitter signal are confirmed by testing of mean value of the TRNG output signal. The quality of generated true random numbers is confirmed by passing standard NIST statistical tests. The described TRNG is tailored for embedded System-On-a-Programmable-Chip (SOPC) cryptographic applications and can provide a good quality true random bit-stream with throughput of several tens of kilobits per second. The possibility of including the proposed TRNG into a SOPC design significantly increases the system security of embedded cryptographic hardware.</abstract></paper>