<paper id="1544724616"><title>Consultant engagement for computer system selection: a pro-active client role in small businesses</title><year>1991</year><authors><author org="Department of Information Systems &amp; Computer Science, National University of Singapore, Singapore," id="2147294894">Guy G. Gable</author></authors><n_citation>100</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1500319018</reference><reference>1547879404</reference><reference>1956454221</reference><reference>2043085286</reference><reference>2120564026</reference><reference>2124330866</reference></references><venue id="38883057" type="J">Information &amp; Management</venue><doi>10.1016/0378-7206(91)90046-5</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.48043">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.51051">Management information systems</keyword><keyword weight="0.56226">Small business</keyword><keyword weight="0.46082">Custom software</keyword><keyword weight="0.45563">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.48274">Vendor</keyword><keyword weight="0.40664">Software</keyword><keyword weight="0.3836">Engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Delegation (computing)</keyword><keyword weight="0.45777">Marketing</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Project success</keyword></keywords><publisher>Elsevier Science Publishers B. V.</publisher><abstract>Abstract Because of their limited number of senior positions and fewer alternative career paths, small businesses have a more difficult time attracting and retaining skilled information systems (IS) staff and are thus dependent upon external expertise. Small businesses are particularly dependent on outside expertise when first computerizing. Because small businesses suffer from severe financial constraints, it is often difficult to justify the cost of custom software. Hence, for many small businesses, engaging a consultant to help with identifying suitable packaged software and related hardware, is their first critical step toward computerization. This study explores the importance of pro-active client involvement when engaging a consultant to assist with computer system selection in small businesses. Client involvement throughout consultant engagement is found to be integral to project success and frequently lacking due to mis-conceptions of small businesses regarding their role. Small businesses often overestimate the impact of consultant and vendor support in achieving succesful computer system selection and implementation. For consultant engagement to be successful, the process must be viewed as being directed toward the achievement of specific organizational results where the client accepts responsibility for direction of the process.</abstract></paper>