<paper id="1530008367"><title>Graph-theoretic arguments in low-level complexity</title><year>1977</year><authors><author org="University of Edinburgh," id="2000097935">Leslie G. Valiant</author></authors><n_citation>262</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1655990431</reference><reference>1979469777</reference><reference>2002616520</reference><reference>2007464118</reference><reference>2035081987</reference><reference>2035873428</reference><reference>2044196316</reference><reference>2045064738</reference><reference>2089366856</reference><reference>2094454303</reference><reference>2138170131</reference><reference>2293895605</reference><reference>2911396724</reference></references><venue id="1163686456" type="C">Mathematical Foundations of Computer Science</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-08353-7_135</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46715">Rigidity (psychology)</keyword><keyword weight="0.45709">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.44868">Binary logarithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.4689">Algebraic number</keyword><keyword weight="0.47126">Linear form</keyword><keyword weight="0.44805">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46314">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.53531">Model of computation</keyword><keyword weight="0.49769">Turing machine</keyword><keyword weight="0.55814">Time complexity</keyword><keyword weight="0.47813">Corollary</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We have surveyed one approach to understanding complexity issues for certain easily computable natural functions. Shifting graphs have been seen to account accurately and in a unified way for the superlinear complexity of several problems for various restricted models of computation. To attack "unrestricted" models (in the present context combinational circuits or straight-line arithmetic programs,) a first attempt, through superconcentrators, fails to provide any lower bounds although it does give counter-examples to alternative approaches. The notion of rigidity, however, does offer for the first time a reduction of relevant computational questions to noncomputional properties. The "reduction" consists of the conjunction of Corollary 6.3 and Theorem 6.4 which show that "for most sets of linear forms over the reals the stated algebraic and combinatorial reasons account for the fact that they cannot be computed in linear time and depth O(log n) simultaneously." We have outlined some problem areas which our preliminary results raise, and feel that further progress on most of these is humanly feasible. We would be interested in alternative approaches also.</abstract></paper>