<paper id="1500025880"><title>The Web of Computing: Computer Technology as Social Organization</title><year>1982</year><authors><author org="Department of Information and Computer Science and Public Policy Research Organization, University of California at Irvine, Irvine, California" id="2093688085">Rob Kling</author><author org="Department of Computer Science School of Engineering University of Southern California Los Angeles, California" id="2135597515">Walt Scacchi</author></authors><n_citation>544</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1593505641</reference><reference>1803220188</reference><reference>1978265467</reference><reference>1983404816</reference><reference>1986566426</reference><reference>1991353419</reference><reference>1997931117</reference><reference>2013601309</reference><reference>2017874393</reference><reference>2044220712</reference><reference>2049317929</reference><reference>2073957514</reference><reference>2144124724</reference></references><venue id="183285281" type="J">Advances in Computers</venue><doi>10.1016/S0065-2458(08)60567-7</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.4445">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45131">Social organization</keyword><keyword weight="0.62957">Web modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.45274">Explanatory power</keyword><keyword weight="0.52552">Social informatics</keyword><keyword weight="0.53058">Social dynamics</keyword><keyword weight="0.61813">Social Semantic Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.46395">Management science</keyword><keyword weight="0.57296">Computer technology</keyword></keywords><publisher>Elsevier</publisher><abstract>Publisher Summary This chapter examines web models for understanding the dynamics of computing development and its use in organizational life. The chapter describes the study of the relative explanatory power of the discrete-entity model and web model by drawing upon the existing research literature and three case studies. The chapter explores different kinds of insights each model provides into the social dynamics of computing development and use. The chapter also illustrates the ways by which each model provides analytical power for making evaluations and predictions. Five major propositions that web analysts essentially make about the dynamics of computing development and use are also presented. The chapter concludes by examining two additional cases of computer developmentand use. It is noted that web models allow better predictions of the outcomes of using socially-complex computing developments in contrast to the discrete-entity models. Web analysts examine the interaction between people and technologies as part of a larger social and technical mosaic, in which the development and use of the focal technology is embedded.</abstract></paper>