<paper id="1977633095"><title>Institutional Factors in Information Technology Innovation</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="CRITO, University of California, Irvine, Irvine, California 92717-4650#TAB#" id="2169311774">John Leslie King</author><author org="University of California-Irvine, Irvine, California." id="2278087827">Vijay Gurbaxani</author><author org="University of California-Irvine, Irvine, California." id="1487244519">Kenneth L. Kraemer</author><author org="Harvard Business School, Soldiers Field, Boston, Massachusetts" id="1632414716">F. Warren McFarlan</author><author org=", National University of Singapore, Singapore" id="2641013131">K. S. Raman</author><author org=", National University of Singapore, Singapore" id="2472728933">C. S. Yap</author></authors><n_citation>681</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1978345473</reference><reference>2073266805</reference><reference>2127089424</reference></references><venue id="202812398" type="J">Information Systems Research</venue><doi>10.1287/isre.5.2.139</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.4419">Economics</keyword><keyword weight="0.48933">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.6379">Innovation economics</keyword><keyword weight="0.45445">Ideology</keyword><keyword weight="0.56592">New institutionalism</keyword><keyword weight="0.53945">Public policy</keyword><keyword weight="0.64531">Innovation management</keyword><keyword weight="0.48462">Organizational theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.45957">Marketing</keyword><keyword weight="0.5179">Government</keyword></keywords><publisher>INFORMS</publisher><abstract>Innovation in information technology is well established in developed nations; newly industrializing and developing nations have been creating governmental interventions to accelerate IT innovation within their borders. The lack of coherent policy advice for creating government policy for IT innovation signals a shortfall in research understanding of the role of government institutions, and institutions more broadly, in IT innovation. This paper makes three points. First, long-established intellectual perspectives on innovation from neoclassical economics and organization theory are inadequate to explain the dynamics of actual innovative change in the IT domain. A broader view adopted from economic history and the new institutionalism in sociology provides a stronger base for understanding the role of institutions in IT innovation. Second, institutional intervention in IT innovation can be constructed at the intersection of the influence and regulatory powers of institutions and the ideologies of supply-push and demand-pull models of innovation. Examples of such analysis are provided. Third, institutional policy formation regarding IT innovation is facilitated by an understanding of the multifaceted role of institutions in the innovative process, and on the contingencies governing any given institution/innovation mix.</abstract></paper>