<paper id="1979706237"><title>Model checking the full modal mu-calculus for infinite sequential processes</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="University of Edinburgh , Edinburgh UK" id="2677700656">Olaf Burkart</author><author org="Univ. Passau, Passau, Germany#TAB#" id="2063423718">Bernhard Steffen</author></authors><n_citation>27</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>22002794</reference><reference>1490526406</reference><reference>1504739534</reference><reference>1564221482</reference><reference>1571376505</reference><reference>1658032593</reference><reference>1963646041</reference><reference>1971416129</reference><reference>1974672595</reference><reference>2015640848</reference><reference>2037314755</reference><reference>2051856671</reference><reference>2168498451</reference><reference>2268014521</reference><reference>2401216365</reference></references><venue id="90727058" type="J">Theoretical Computer Science</venue><doi>10.1016/S0304-3975(99)00034-1</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.49028">Graph theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.45712">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.57234">Context-free language</keyword><keyword weight="0.4457">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.54578">Model checking</keyword><keyword weight="0.46093">Algebra</keyword><keyword weight="0.43364">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47367">Automaton</keyword><keyword weight="0.53518">Decidability</keyword><keyword weight="0.49084">Backtracking</keyword><keyword weight="0.46739">Monad (functional programming)</keyword><keyword weight="0.50058">Modal</keyword></keywords><publisher>Elsevier Science Publishers Ltd.</publisher><abstract>Abstract It is known that pushdown processes have a decidable monadic second-order theory (Muller and Schupp, Theoret. Comput. Sci. 37 (1985) 51–;75) and that this result covers the model-checking problem for the modal mu-calculus. Unfortunately, the corresponding decidability procedure is not practical due to its nonelementary complexity. Recently, however, a very intricate elementary algorithm for model checking the full modal mu-calculus for pushdown processes based on games was presented by Walukiewicz (CAVu002796, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 1102, Springer, Berlin, 1996, pp. 62–;74). Lifting the classical finite-state model checking technique to second-order, we develop here a more structural and transparent elementary algorithm for model-checking infinite sequential processes, including context-free processes, pushdown processes , and regular graphs , that captures the full modal mu-calculus as well. Whereas the actual model-checking algorithm simply resorts to backtracking in order to capture alternation, the corresponding correctness proof requires to introduce the stronger framework of dynamic environments which are modelled by finite-state automata.</abstract></paper>