<paper id="1966755847"><title>Work group structures and computer support: a field experiment</title><year>1988</year><authors><author org="The Rand Corporation, Santa Monica, CA#TAB#" id="1999416181">J. D. Eveland</author><author org="The Rand Corporation, Santa Monica, CA#TAB#" id="2077664662">T. K. Bikson</author></authors><n_citation>155</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1500025880</reference><reference>2066018679</reference></references><venue id="87067389" type="J">ACM Transactions on Information Systems</venue><doi>10.1145/58566.58568</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.5188">Working group</keyword><keyword weight="0.46962">Retirement planning</keyword><keyword weight="0.41516">Leverage (finance)</keyword><keyword weight="0.48437">Structured interview</keyword><keyword weight="0.41439">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.43955">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.47787">Phone</keyword><keyword weight="0.42788">Software</keyword><keyword weight="0.44156">Data manipulation language</keyword><keyword weight="0.5736">Computer technology</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>It is frequently suggested that work groups that have computer technology to support activities such as text editing, data manipulation, and communication develop systematically different structures and working processes from groups that rely on more conventional technologies such as memos, phone calls, and meetings. However, cross-sectional or retrospective research designs do not allow this hypothesis to be tested with much power. This field experiment created two task forces, each composed equally of recently retired employees and employees still at work but eligible to retire. They were given the identical tasks of preparing reports for their company on retirement planning issues, but they were randomly assigned to different technology conditions. One group had full conventional office support; the other had, in addition, networked microcomputers with electronic mail and routine office software. Structured interviews were conducted four times during the year-long project; in addition, electronic mail activity was logged in the on-line group. Although both groups produced effective reports, the two differed significantly in the kind of work they produced, the group structures that emerged, and evaluations of their own performance. Although the standard group was largely dominated by the employees through the extensive reliance on informal meetings, the electronic technology used by the other task force allowed the retirees to exercise primary leverage. We conclude that use of computer support for cooperative work results in both quantitative and qualitative changes but that effective participation in such electronically supported groups requires significant investments of time and energy on the part of its members to master the technology and a relatively high level of assistance during the learning process.</abstract></paper>