<paper id="1546441687"><title>Universal Hashing and k-Wise Independent Random Variables via Integer Arithmetic without Primes</title><year>1996</year><authors><author org="Universitat Dortmund" id="2174199062">Martin Dietzfelbinger</author></authors><n_citation>107</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>41435888</reference><reference>1970011858</reference><reference>1984992697</reference><reference>2003519998</reference><reference>2006727395</reference><reference>2019038806</reference><reference>2019807548</reference><reference>2024312599</reference><reference>2026143151</reference><reference>2031934066</reference><reference>2037514418</reference><reference>2042037097</reference><reference>2052207834</reference><reference>2077229436</reference><reference>2083368929</reference><reference>2100061495</reference><reference>2107371087</reference><reference>2136616826</reference><reference>2138292650</reference><reference>2144399314</reference><reference>2163137752</reference><reference>2165621523</reference></references><venue id="1178070762" type="C">Symposium on Theoretical Aspects of Computer Science</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-60922-9_46</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.4646">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.58473">Random element</keyword><keyword weight="0.5705">Convergence of random variables</keyword><keyword weight="0.46588">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.56971">Central limit theorem</keyword><keyword weight="0.57611">Universal hashing</keyword><keyword weight="0.57809">Multivariate random variable</keyword><keyword weight="0.63401">K-independent hashing</keyword><keyword weight="0.58893">Sum of normally distributed random variables</keyword><keyword weight="0.41788">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.56386">Random function</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Let u, m≥1 be arbitrary integers and let k≥u. The central result of this paper is that the multiset H={itha,b¦0≤a, bu003ckm} of functions from U=0,..., u }-1 to M={0,..., m −1, where h a,b (x)=((ax+b) mod km) div k, for x∈ U, is a (c, 2)-universal class of hash functions from U to M in the sense of Carter and Wegman [7, 25], with c=5/4. More precisely, we show that if x1, x2 are distinct elements of U and i1,i2∈ M are arbitrary, and if h is chosen at random from H, then ¦Prob (h(x1)=i1 ∧ h(x2)=i2-1/m2¦≤(1/2km)2≤1/4m2. Among the many known constructions of (c, 2)-universal classes there was none that would get by with such a small number of pure integer arithmetic operations without the assumption that a prime number of size the order of¦U¦ or at least ¦M¦ was available. — Varying this result, we obtain: (a) two-independent sequences of random variables; (b) universal hash classes of higher degree (“(c, l)-universal” classes) and l-wise independent random variables, for l ≥ 2; (c) algorithms for static and dynamic perfect hashing with an optimal number of random bits; all using pure integer arithmetic without the need for providing prime numbers (arbitrary or random) of a certain size. It should be noted that the focus here is not on minimizing the size of the probability space used, as in much of the recent work on “almost k-independent random variables”, but on the realization of such variables or hash classes using the most natural and most widely available operations, viz., integer arithmetic.</abstract></paper>