<paper id="1499144570"><title>The Potential of the Language Action Perspective in Ethnographic Analysis</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="State University of New York" id="2098379432">Heinz K. Klein</author><author org="State University of New York" id="2497414537">Minh Q. Huynh</author></authors><n_citation>9</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>2100272769</reference><reference>2148277253</reference></references><venue id="" type="">Proceedings of the IFIP TC8 WG8.2 International Working Conference on New Information Technologies in Organizational Processes: Field Studies and Theoretical Reflections on the Future of Work</venue><doi>10.1007/978-0-387-35566-5_7</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.558">Language/action perspective</keyword><keyword weight="0.5102">Meaning (philosophy of language)</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Language analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.42448">A priori and a posteriori</keyword><keyword weight="0.42532">Psychology</keyword><keyword weight="0.46493">Typology</keyword><keyword weight="0.4737">Coding (social sciences)</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.45295">Natural language processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.41389">Ethnography</keyword><keyword weight="0.4684">Linguistics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Kluwer, B.V.</publisher><abstract>The purpose of this paper is to explore the potential value of applying language-based methods of analyses to textual ethnographic field records (like e-mail records) in addition to thick descriptions. Even though language analysis imports many a priori assumptions, they could provide more concise summaries than thick descriptions and add value to them. The methods of conversational analysis investigated here a based on a coding scheme derived from the Wittgenstein “language use” theory of meaning combined with Habermas’ social action typology. The paper presents some coding issues fordiscussion that we encountered along with illustrative tabulations of sample coding results. Our purpose is to illustrate the potential value of language action coding to ethnographers both during the analysis and reporting stages of research.</abstract></paper>