<paper id="1841463954"><title>On the Pseudorandomness of Top-Level Schemes of Block Ciphers</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="NTT Laboratories" id="2776953426">Shiho Moriai</author><author org="Swiss Federal Institute of Technology (EPFL)" id="22805272">Serge Vaudenay</author></authors><n_citation>48</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1485064528</reference><reference>1537206908</reference><reference>1598307445</reference><reference>1602941974</reference><reference>1607844659</reference><reference>1830378742</reference><reference>1888315134</reference><reference>1979802565</reference><reference>2052207834</reference><reference>2077300005</reference><reference>2152187672</reference></references><venue id="2535638237" type="C">International Conference on the Theory and Application of Cryptology and Information Security</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-44448-3_22</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.60511">Block size</keyword><keyword weight="0.62351">Key schedule</keyword><keyword weight="0.59397">Block cipher</keyword><keyword weight="0.52299">Pseudorandomness</keyword><keyword weight="0.44393">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46744">Communication complexity</keyword><keyword weight="0.45005">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.57771">Decorrelation theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.48014">Public-key cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.49171">Randomness</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Block ciphers are usually basedon one top-level scheme into which we plug "roundf unctions". To analyze security, it is important to study the intrinsic security provided by the top-level scheme from the viewpoint of randomness: given a block cipher in which we replaced the lower-level schemes by idealized oracles, we measure the security (in terms of best advantage for a distinguisher) depending on the number of rounds and the number of chosen plaintexts. We then extrapolate a sufficient number of secure rounds given the regular bounds provided by decorrelation :[89],"approach allows the comparison of several generalizations of the Feistel schemes and others. In particular, we compare the randomness provided by the schemes used by the AES :[117],"addition we provide a general paradigm for analyzing the security provided by the interaction between the different levels of the block cipher structure.</abstract></paper>