<paper id="1877652378"><title>On the Power of Bounded Concurrency II: The Pushdown Automata Level</title><year>1990</year><authors><author org="#N##TAB##TAB##TAB##TAB# Bar-Ilan University#N##TAB##TAB##TAB#" id="2225739748">Tirza Hirst</author><author org="The Weizmann Institute of Science" id="427806604">David Harel</author></authors><n_citation>5</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1494489447</reference><reference>1571245733</reference><reference>2064650227</reference><reference>2090921231</reference><reference>2099529102</reference><reference>2110425399</reference><reference>2113355185</reference><reference>2137865376</reference><reference>2157390113</reference></references><venue id="2756386172" type="C">Colloquium on trees in Algebra and Programming</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-52590-4_37</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.55023">Deterministic context-free grammar</keyword><keyword weight="0.57687">Embedded pushdown automaton</keyword><keyword weight="0.58722">Context-free language</keyword><keyword weight="0.44419">Programming language</keyword><keyword weight="0.59517">Nested word</keyword><keyword weight="0.56439">Concurrency</keyword><keyword weight="0.63066">Deterministic pushdown automaton</keyword><keyword weight="0.62018">Pushdown automaton</keyword><keyword weight="0.4025">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.60047">Bounded function</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>This is the second in a series of papers on the inherent power of bounded cooperative concurrency, whereby an automaton can be in some bounded number of states that cooperate in accepting the input. In this paper we deal with the level of pushdown automata. We are interested in differencies in power of expression and in discrepencies in succinctness between variants of pdau0027s that incorporate nondeterminism, pure parallelism and bounded cooperative concurrency. In particular, our results provide further evidence for the general observation that the latter feature provides inherent exponential power, in both upper and lower bound senses, regardless of whether or not the two former features are also present. While we use the language of statecharts to capture these features, our results are extremely robust, and hold also for bounded versions of virtually all other concurrent languages.</abstract></paper>