<paper id="1851253658"><title>Characterization of Elliptic Curve Traces under FR-Reduction</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="Japan Advanced Institute of Science and Technology,,,,," id="1454195615">Atsuko Miyaji</author><author org="Japan Advanced Institute of Science and Technology,,,,," id="2577659333">Masaki Nakabayashi</author><author org="Japan Advanced Institute of Science and Technology,,,,," id="2569293140">Shunzo Takano</author></authors><n_citation>63</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>137840954</reference><reference>1489132985</reference><reference>1569862725</reference><reference>1803405874</reference><reference>1830587842</reference><reference>1969728959</reference><reference>1979485530</reference><reference>1981455414</reference><reference>1996360405</reference><reference>2003736153</reference><reference>2028358228</reference><reference>2046569422</reference><reference>2071680489</reference><reference>2098377074</reference><reference>2105861506</reference><reference>2108834246</reference></references><venue id="1171774888" type="C">International Conference on Information Security and Cryptology</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-45247-8_8</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44184">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.74046">Supersingular elliptic curve</keyword><keyword weight="0.73841">Modular elliptic curve</keyword><keyword weight="0.76101">Elliptic curve point multiplication</keyword><keyword weight="0.68845">Jacobian curve</keyword><keyword weight="0.70548">Elliptic curve cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.71507">Hessian form of an elliptic curve</keyword><keyword weight="0.71656">Schoof's algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.40521">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.7244">Tripling-oriented Doche–Icart–Kohel curve</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Elliptic curve cryptosystems([19,25]) are based on the elliptic curve discrete logarithm problem (ECDLP). If elliptic curve cryptosystems avoid FR-reduction([11,17]) and anomalous elliptic curve over Fq ([34,3,36]), then with current knowledge we can construct elliptic curve cryptosystems over a smaller definition field. ECDLP has an interesting property that the security deeply depends on elliptic curve traces rather than definition fields, which does not occur in the case of the discrete logarithm problem (DLP). Therefore it is important to characterize elliptic curve traces explicitly from the security point of view. As for FR-reduction, supersingular elliptic curves or elliptic curve E/Fq with trace 2 have been reported to be vulnerable. However unfortunately these have been only results that characterize elliptic curve traces explicitly for FR- or MOV-reductions. More importantly, the secure trace against FR-reduction has not been reported at all. Elliptic curves with the secure trace means that the reduced extension degree is always higher than a certain level.In this paper, we aim at characterizing elliptic curve traces by FR-reduction and investigate explicit conditions of traces vulnerable or secure against FR-reduction. We show new explicit conditions of elliptic curve traces for FR-reduction. We also present algorithms to construct such elliptic curves, which have relation to famous number theory problems.</abstract></paper>