<paper id="1971238646"><title>Two algorithms for nearest-neighbor search in high dimensions</title><year>1997</year><authors><author org="IBM Almaden Research Center, San Jose CA" id="2261367123">Jon M. Kleinberg</author></authors><n_citation>327</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1554385128</reference><reference>1970319631</reference><reference>1985123706</reference><reference>1985269159</reference><reference>1997744504</reference><reference>1997790894</reference><reference>2008196645</reference><reference>2010471713</reference><reference>2022266599</reference><reference>2024668293</reference><reference>2029388714</reference><reference>2038199856</reference><reference>2054011861</reference><reference>2061845601</reference><reference>2062083887</reference><reference>2067994867</reference><reference>2069816168</reference><reference>2074429597</reference><reference>2084224084</reference><reference>2106136378</reference><reference>2122111042</reference><reference>2144679084</reference><reference>2147152072</reference><reference>2165558283</reference><reference>2427881153</reference><reference>2571821494</reference></references><venue id="1190910084" type="C">Symposium on the Theory of Computing</venue><doi>10.1145/258533.258653</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.49824">Incremental heuristic search</keyword><keyword weight="0.44765">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.56001">Search algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.44048">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45553">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.52008">Search engine indexing</keyword><keyword weight="0.51625">Beam search</keyword><keyword weight="0.48785">Euclidean space</keyword><keyword weight="0.52821">Linear search</keyword><keyword weight="0.54526">Combinatorial search</keyword><keyword weight="0.61099">Nearest neighbor search</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>Representing data as points in a high-dimensional space, so as to use geometric methods for indexing, is an algorithmic technique with a wide array of uses. It is central to a number of areas such as information retrieval, pattern recognition, and statistical data analysis; many of the problems arising in these applications can involve several hundred or several thousand dimensions. We consider the nearest-neighbor problem for d-dimensional Euclidean space: we wish to pre-process a database of n points so that given a query point, one can efficiently determine its nearest neighbors in the database. There is a large literature on algorithms for this problem, in both the exact and approximate cases. The more sophisticated algorithms typically achieve a query time that is logarithmic in n at the expense of an exponential dependence on the dimension d; indeed, even the averagecase analysis of heuristics such as k-d trees reveals an exponential dependence on d in the query time. In this work, we develop a new approach to the nearest-neighbor problem, based on a method for combining randomly chosen one-dimensional projections of the underlying point set. From this, we obtain the following two results. (i) An algorithm for finding e-approximate nearest neighbors with a query time of O((d log d)(d + log n)). (ii) An e-approximate nearest-neighbor algorithm with near-linear storage and a query time that improves asymptotically on linear search in all dimensions. ∗Department of Computer Science, Cornell University, Ithaca NY 14853. Email: kleinber@cs.cornell.edu. This work was performed in large part while on leave at the IBM Almaden Research Center, San Jose CA 95120. The author is currently supported by an Alfred P. Sloan Research Fellowship and by NSF Faculty Early Career Development Award CCR-9701399.</abstract></paper>