<paper id="1766932551"><title>How to summarize the universe: dynamic maintenance of quantiles</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="AT&amp;T Labs- Research, Florham Park, NJ" id="2157039722">Anna C. Gilbert</author><author org="AT&amp;T Labs- Research, Florham Park, NJ" id="306802008">Yannis Kotidis</author><author org="AT&amp;T Labs- Research, Florham Park, NJ" id="2921339358">S. Muthukrishnan</author><author org="AT&amp;T Labs- Research, Florham Park, NJ" id="2911631061">Martin J. Strauss</author></authors><n_citation>170</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>161142484</reference><reference>1487093789</reference><reference>1489255272</reference><reference>1526735133</reference><reference>1573284583</reference><reference>1983560552</reference><reference>1984566373</reference><reference>1996641400</reference><reference>2000473687</reference><reference>2028660080</reference><reference>2043843644</reference><reference>2047424291</reference><reference>2080745194</reference><reference>2105175890</reference><reference>2106163100</reference><reference>2112452856</reference><reference>2114944618</reference><reference>2134786002</reference><reference>2137783381</reference><reference>2161463763</reference><reference>2166559705</reference><reference>2171903035</reference></references><venue id="1133523790" type="C">Very Large Data Bases</venue><doi>10.1016/B978-155860869-6/50047-0</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.57957">Query optimization</keyword><keyword weight="0.47239">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.46036">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.51955">Quantile</keyword><keyword weight="0.37149">Universe</keyword><keyword weight="0.52939">Database server</keyword><keyword weight="0.53604">Order statistic</keyword><keyword weight="0.49366">User interface</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Dynamic maintenance</keyword><keyword weight="0.45027">Database</keyword></keywords><publisher>VLDB Endowment</publisher><abstract>Order statistics, i.e., quantiles, are frequently used in databases both at the database server as well as the application level. For example, they are useful in selectivity estimation during query optimization, in partitioning large relations, in estimating query result sizes when building user interfaces, and in characterizing the data distribution of evolving datasets in the process of data :[58],"present a new algorithm for dynamically computing quantiles of a relation subject to insert as well as delete operations. The algorithm monitors the operations and maintains a simple, small-space representation (based on random subset sums or RSSs) of the underlying data distribution. Using these RSSs, we can quickly estimate, without having to access the data, all the quantiles, each guaranteed to be accurate to within user-specified precision. Previously-known one-pass quantile estimation algorithms that provide similar quality and performance guarantees can not handle deletions. Other algorithms that can handle delete operations cannot guarantee performance without rescanning the entire :[58],"present the :[156],"algorithm, its theoretical performance analysis and extensive experimental results with synthetic and real datasets. Independent of the rates of insertions and deletions, our algorithm is remarkably precise at estimating quantiles in small space, as our experiments demonstrate.</abstract></paper>