<paper id="1983959468"><title>Concepts and capabilities of a database computer</title><year>1978</year><authors><author org="Ohio State University , Columbus#TAB#" id="2251854863">Jayanta Banerjee</author><author org="Ohio State University , Columbus#TAB#" id="2951965222">David K. Hsiao</author><author org="IBM Poughkeepsie Lab, Poughkeepsie, NY#TAB#" id="2306165356">Richard I. Baum</author></authors><n_citation>64</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1979631724</reference><reference>1982405273</reference><reference>1987209055</reference><reference>2026731931</reference><reference>2026929157</reference><reference>2040640592</reference><reference>2041415271</reference><reference>2055818490</reference><reference>2062978544</reference><reference>2074302481</reference><reference>2082354091</reference><reference>2084455637</reference><reference>2116314098</reference><reference>2116731840</reference><reference>2159931520</reference></references><venue id="90119964" type="J">ACM Transactions on Database Systems</venue><doi>10.1145/320289.320292</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45885">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.52292">Data structure</keyword><keyword weight="0.45754">Content-addressable memory</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Architectural principles</keyword><keyword weight="0.47683">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.4924">Theory of operation</keyword><keyword weight="0.51054">Software</keyword><keyword weight="0.50928">dBc</keyword><keyword weight="0.49384">Cluster analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.46624">Database</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>The concepts and capabilities of a database computer (DBC) are given in this paper. The proposed design overcomes many of the traditional problems of database system software and is one of the first to describe a complete data-secure computer capable of handling large databases. This paper begins by characterizing the major problems facing todayu0027s database system designers. These problems are intrinsically related to the nature of conventional hardware and can only be solved by introducing new architectural concepts. Several such concepts are brought to bear in the later sections of this paper. These architectural principles have a major impact upon the design of the system and so they are discussed in some detail. A key aspect of these principles is that they can be implemented with near-term technology. The rest of the paper is devoted to the functional characteristics and the theory of operation of the DBC. The theory of operation is based on a series of abstract models of the components and data structures employed by the DBC. These models are used to illustrate how the DBC performs access operations, manages data structures and security specifications, and enforces security requirements. Short Algol-like algorithms are used to show how these operations are carried out. This part of the paper concludes with a high-level description of the DBC organization. The actual details of the DBC hardware are quite involved and so their presentation is not the subject of this paper. A sample database is included in the Appendix to illustrate the working of the security and clustering mechanisms of the DBC.</abstract></paper>