<paper id="1793463258"><title>On the relation between the ideal cipher and the random oracle models</title><year>2006</year><authors><author org="Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, New York University" id="1259442811">Yevgeniy Dodis</author><author org="Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, New York University" id="2058592591">Prashant Puniya</author></authors><n_citation>25</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>299586966</reference><reference>1482922493</reference><reference>1526778951</reference><reference>1549228503</reference><reference>1552695147</reference><reference>1566256504</reference><reference>1589034595</reference><reference>1600432225</reference><reference>1689385595</reference><reference>1727535721</reference><reference>1939171670</reference><reference>1972464518</reference><reference>1987960290</reference><reference>2002930326</reference><reference>2052267638</reference><reference>2064939672</reference><reference>2077300005</reference><reference>2085797166</reference><reference>2095708839</reference><reference>2114673105</reference><reference>2120154759</reference><reference>2152688060</reference><reference>2162653919</reference><reference>2166462813</reference><reference>2568739026</reference><reference>2613214081</reference><reference>2615274042</reference></references><venue id="1137528458" type="C">Theory of Cryptography Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/11681878_10</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.62175">Pseudorandom function family</keyword><keyword weight="0.63491">Transposition cipher</keyword><keyword weight="0.61579">Cipher</keyword><keyword weight="0.44861">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.62892">Affine cipher</keyword><keyword weight="0.58139">Block cipher</keyword><keyword weight="0.43128">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.61484">Random oracle</keyword><keyword weight="0.61737">Running key cipher</keyword><keyword weight="0.44509">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.62615">Pseudorandom permutation</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The Random Oracle Model and the Ideal Cipher Model are two of the most popular idealized models in cryptography. It is a fundamentally important practical and theoretical problem to compare the relative strengths of these models and to see how they relate to each other. Recently, Coron et al. [8] proved that one can securely instantiate a random oracle in the ideal cipher model. In this paper, we investigate if it is possible to instantiate an ideal block cipher in the random oracle model, which is a considerably more challenging question. We conjecture that the Luby-Rackoff construction [19] with a sufficient number of rounds should suffice to show this implication. This does not follow from the famous Luby-Rackoff result [19] showing that 4 rounds are enough to turn a pseudorandom function into a pseudorandom permutation, since the results of the intermediate rounds are known to everybody. As a partial step toward resolving this conjecture, we show that random oracles imply ideal ciphers in the honest-but-curious model, where all the participants are assumed to follow the protocol, but keep all their intermediate results. Namely, we show that the Luby-Rackoff construction with a superlogarithmic number of rounds can be used to instantiate the ideal block cipher in any honest-but-curious cryptosystem, and result in a similar honest-but-curious cryptosystem in the random oracle model. We also show that securely instantiating the ideal cipher using the Luby Rackoff construction with upto a logarithmic number of rounds is equivalent in the honest-but-curious and malicious models.</abstract></paper>