<paper id="1489174353"><title>Causal understanding of patient illness in medical diagnosis</title><year>1981</year><authors><author org="Laboratory for Computer Science, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Massachusetts," id="2117913535">Ramesh S. Patil</author><author org="Laboratory for Computer Science, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Massachusetts," id="29903417">Peter Szolovits</author><author org="New England Medical Center, Tufts University, Boston, Massachusetts." id="2923275460">William B. Schwartz</author></authors><n_citation>201</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>17682891</reference><reference>30492759</reference><reference>1895928490</reference><reference>2052222137</reference></references><venue id="1203999783" type="C">International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence</venue><doi>10.1007/978-1-4612-5108-8_16</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.4218">Disease</keyword><keyword weight="0.40297">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.43202">Cognitive psychology</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Delegation (computing)</keyword><keyword weight="0.4286">Management science</keyword><keyword weight="0.49465">Medical diagnosis</keyword><keyword weight="0.40927">Machine learning</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, New York, NY</publisher><abstract>First generation AI in Medicine programs have clearly demonstrated the usefulness of AI techniques However, il has also been recognized that the use. of notions such as causal relationships, temporal patterns, and aggregate disease categories in these programs has been too weak From our study of clinicianu0027s behavior we realized that a diagnostic or therapeutic program must consider a case at various levels of detail to integrate overall understanding with detailed knowledge, To explore these issues, we have undertaken a study of the problem of providing expert consultation for electrolyte and acid-base disturbances We have partly completed an implementation of ABEL, the diagnostic component of the overall effort. In this paper we concentrate on ABLL.s mechanism for describing a patient. Called the patient-specific model, this description includes data about the patient as well as the programu0027s hypothetical interpretations of these data in a multilevel causal network. The lowest level of this description consists of pathophysiological knowledge about the patient, which is successively aggregated into higher level concepts and relations, gradually shifting the content from pathophysiological to syndromic knowledge The aggregate level of this description summarizes the patient data providing a global perspective for efficient exploration of the diagnostic possibilities The pathophysiological level description provides the ability to handle complex clinical situations arising in illnesses with multiple etiologies, to evaluate the physiological validity of diagnostic possibilities being explored, and to organize large amounts of seemingly unrelated facts into coherent causal descriptions.</abstract></paper>