<paper id="142232905"><title>Structure and perceived effectiveness of software development subunits: a task contingency analysis</title><year>1992</year><authors><author org="" id="2696467629">K. Kyu Kim</author><author org="" id="220705178">Narayan S. Umanath</author></authors><n_citation>52</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>96126854</reference><reference>1483468980</reference><reference>1498240737</reference><reference>1509283903</reference><reference>1520103841</reference><reference>1568507576</reference><reference>1648431347</reference><reference>1982272301</reference><reference>2127455238</reference><reference>2142464495</reference></references><venue id="9954729" type="J">Journal of Management Information Systems</venue><doi>10.1080/07421222.1992.11517972</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47711">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.41222">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.44013">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.52385">Information processing theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Work flow</keyword><keyword weight="0.51996">Software development</keyword><keyword weight="0.47262">Contingency</keyword></keywords><publisher>M. E. Sharpe, Inc.</publisher><abstract>The nature of the task to be performed by the information systems (IS) unit as a contextual factor has received little attention in the IS research literature. In addition, prior empirical work examining IS structure lacks theoretical foundation. In this paper, we first clarify the multidimensional nature of an organizationu0027s subunit structure. Then, we examine the impact of the structure variables on the perceived effectiveness of a subunit of IS - software development - using "task" as the contex- tual contingency influencing this relationship. Organizational information processing theory provides the theoretical foundation for this study. Analysis of data from thirty hospitals reveals that a contingency relationship exists between task context and structural dimensions of software development subunits in determining their effec- tiveness. Task complexity and decision-making structure in interaction exhibit a nonmonotonic effect on the software development subunitu0027s effectiveness. While the interaction of subunit work flow interdependence with both decision-making structure and control structure was significant, the direction of effect was unexpected. Implica- tions of these findings for practicing managers, and IS planners and researchers are discussed. Acknowledgments: The authors gratefully acknowledge the insightful suggestions of Carol Saundcrs and the two anonymous reviewers.</abstract></paper>