<paper id="1842135878"><title>Detection of specularity using colour and multiple views</title><year>1992</year><authors><author org="University of Pennsylvania" id="2548768375">Sang Wook Lee</author><author org="University of Pennsylvania" id="1601293841">Ruzena Bajcsy</author></authors><n_citation>76</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2045932639</reference><reference>2106805947</reference><reference>2136955756</reference><reference>2145599611</reference><reference>2154217002</reference><reference>2914331897</reference></references><venue id="1124077590" type="C">European Conference on Computer Vision</venue><doi>10.1016/0262-8856(92)90009-R</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44219">Computer vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.44504">Colored</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Surface reflection</keyword><keyword weight="0.57197">Specularity</keyword><keyword weight="0.42914">Pattern recognition</keyword><keyword weight="0.45547">Parallel algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.36923">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.50482">Specular reflection</keyword><keyword weight="0.54126">Image segmentation</keyword><keyword weight="0.40872">Irradiance</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.56962">Color image</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>This paper presents a model and an algorithm for the detection of specularities from Lambertian reflections using multiple color images from different viewing directions. The algorithm, called spectral differencing, is based on the Lambertian consistency that color image irradiance from Lambertian reflection at an object surface does not change depending on viewing directions, but color image irradiance from specular reflection or from a mixture of Lambertian and specular reflections does change. The spectral differencing is a pixelwise parallel algorithm, and it detects specularities by color differences between a small number of images without using any feature correspondence or image segmentation. Applicable objects include uniformly or nonuniformly colored dielectrics and metals, under extended and multiply colored scene illumination. Experimental results agree with the model, and the algorithm performs well within the limitations discussed.</abstract></paper>