<paper id="1484589875"><title>Better Logging through Formality</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="CERIAS Purdue University#TAB#" id="2030732385">Chapman Flack</author><author org="CERIAS Purdue University#TAB#" id="1984264859">Mikhail J. Atallah</author></authors><n_citation>9</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1644882639</reference><reference>1828150029</reference><reference>1992872109</reference><reference>2132625653</reference><reference>2166332868</reference></references><venue id="1198121106" type="C">Recent Advances in Intrusion Detection</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-39945-3_1</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.43838">Audit</keyword><keyword weight="0.43548">Formality</keyword><keyword weight="0.47528">Interoperability</keyword><keyword weight="0.43596">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.46414">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.51273">Audit trail</keyword><keyword weight="0.45086">Vendor</keyword><keyword weight="0.53805">Formal specification</keyword><keyword weight="0.46532">Robustness (computer science)</keyword><keyword weight="0.49577">Documentation</keyword><keyword weight="0.46547">Database</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We rely on programs that consume audit logs to do so successfully (a robustness issue) and form the correct interpretations of the input (a semantic issue). The vendoru0027s documentation of the log format is an important part of the specification for any log consumer. As a specification, it is subject to improvement using formal specification techniques. This work presents a methodology for formalizing and refining the description of an audit log to improve robustness and semantic accuracy of programs that use the log. Ideally applied during design of a new format, the methodology is also profitably applied to existing log formats. Its application to Solaris BSM (an existing, commercial format) demonstrated utility by detecting ambiguities or errors of several types in the documentation or implementation of BSM logging, and identifying opportunities to improve the content of the logs. The products of this work are the methodology itself for use in refining other log formats and their consumers, and an annotated, machine-readable grammar for Solaris BSM that can be used by the community to quickly construct applications that consume BSM logs.</abstract></paper>