<paper id="1519452812"><title>Analysis of Mobile Business Processes for the Design of Mobile Information Systems</title><year>2004</year><authors><author org="University of Leipzig &gt;  &gt;  &gt;  &gt;" id="2078616088">André Köhler</author><author org="University of Leipzig &gt;  &gt;  &gt;  &gt;" id="2970700853">Volker Gruhn</author></authors><n_citation>22</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>172896666</reference><reference>1511509087</reference><reference>1945368949</reference><reference>2020430556</reference><reference>2082116209</reference><reference>2133356293</reference></references><venue id="2627069240" type="C">International Conference on Electronic Commerce</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-30077-9_24</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.65985">Artifact-centric business process model</keyword><keyword weight="0.63873">Mobile technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.66537">Mobile computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.45785">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.68715">Mobile business development</keyword><keyword weight="0.68712">Business process modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.64738">Business process discovery</keyword><keyword weight="0.65262">Business Process Model and Notation</keyword><keyword weight="0.63893">Business rule</keyword><keyword weight="0.47452">Process management</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The adoption of mobile technologies into companies frequently follows a technology-driven approach without precise knowledge about the potential benefits that may be realised. Especially in larger organisations with complex business processes, a systematic procedure is required if a verifiable economic benefit is to be created by the use of mobile technologies. Therefore, the term “mobile business process”, as well as requirements for information systems applied in such processes, are defined in this paper. Subsequently, we introduce a procedure for the systematical analysis of the distributed structure of a business process model in order to identify mobile sub-processes. For that purpose, the method Mobile Process Landscaping is used to decompose a process model into different levels of detail. The method aims to manage the complexity and limit the process analysis to the potentially mobile sub-processes from the beginning. The result of the analysis can be used on the one hand as a foundation for the redesign of the business processes and on the other hand for the requirements engineering of mobile information systems. An application of this method is shown by the example of business processes in the insurance industry.</abstract></paper>