<paper id="1971267722"><title>BS*: an admissible bidirectional staged heuristic search algorithm</title><year>1989</year><authors><author org="Republic of Singapore#TAB#" id="2645154669">James B.H. Kwa</author></authors><n_citation>59</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1595943972</reference><reference>1646038686</reference><reference>1965469937</reference><reference>1969483458</reference><reference>2023624803</reference><reference>2083355299</reference><reference>2097038466</reference><reference>2134634502</reference><reference>2144050074</reference><reference>2152475379</reference></references><venue id="196139623" type="J">Artificial Intelligence</venue><doi>10.1016/0004-3702(89)90069-6</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.51466">Heuristic</keyword><keyword weight="0.63308">Incremental heuristic search</keyword><keyword weight="0.44959">Mathematical optimization</keyword><keyword weight="0.64422">Search algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.66809">Beam search</keyword><keyword weight="0.44429">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.6432">Bidirectional search</keyword><keyword weight="0.63131">A* search algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.37821">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.65894">Best-first search</keyword><keyword weight="0.44596">Machine learning</keyword><keyword weight="0.64252">Iterative deepening depth-first search</keyword></keywords><publisher>Elsevier</publisher><abstract>Abstract In order to reap the potential advantage of less extensive searching which bidirectional heuristic search algorithms offer, strategies are needed to influence the two search wavefronts to meet such that early termination will occur. The principled search control strategy aims to achieve this without trading running time, but can be found wanting still. An improved algorithm BS∗ is described which expands significantly less nodes on average than any other algorithm in the same class of non-wave-shaping admissible bidirectional algorithms. When pitted against BHPA, the only other heuristically guided member in this class, BS∗u0027s average search efficiency in time and space is about 30% better. BS∗u0027s superior performance stems from the use of all opportunities to achieve early termination and the elimination of unfruitful avenues by search reduction operations: nipping, pruning, trimming and screening. Such operations exploit information gathered during search and have several spin-offs: more accurate guidance of search control, early exposure of nonpromising nodes and reduced bookkeeping overheads, all of which further enhance BS∗u0027s performance. A further noteworthy feature of BS∗ is that it is the first staged search algorithm which preserves admissibility.</abstract></paper>