<paper id="1537808693"><title>Agent-Mediated Integrative Negotiation for Retail Electronic Commerce</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="MIT, Media Laboratory" id="2052250968">Robert H. Guttman</author><author org="MIT, Media Laboratory" id="2650378090">Pattie Maes</author></authors><n_citation>233</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1522524128</reference><reference>1546783168</reference><reference>1574410118</reference><reference>1697090051</reference><reference>1969200693</reference><reference>2026080185</reference><reference>2029459238</reference><reference>2098755476</reference><reference>2124591829</reference><reference>2157740753</reference></references><venue id="" type="">AMET '98 Selected Papers from the First International Workshop on Agent Mediated Electronic Trading on Agent Mediated Electronic Commerce</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-48835-9_5</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.42606">Constraint satisfaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.49085">Conjoint analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.51178">Software agent</keyword><keyword weight="0.51067">Common value auction</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Retail market</keyword><keyword weight="0.45977">Marketing</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Utility theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.48943">The Internet</keyword><keyword weight="0.44428">Business</keyword><keyword weight="0.51473">Negotiation</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Software agents help automate a variety of tasks including those involved in buying and selling products over the Internet. Although shopping agents provide convenience for consumers and yield more efficient markets, todayu0027s first-generation shopping agents are limited to comparing merchant offerings only on price instead of their full range of value. As such, they do a disservice to both consumers and retailers by hiding important merchant value-added services from consumer consideration. Likewise, the increasingly popular online auctions pit sellers against buyers in distributive negotiation tugof-wars over price. This paper analyzes these approaches from economic, behavioral, and software agent perspectives then proposes integrative negotiation as a more suitable approach to retail electronic commerce. Finally, we identify promising techniques (e.g., multi-attribute utility theory, distributed constraint satisfaction, and conjoint analysis) for implementing agent-mediated integrative negotiation.</abstract></paper>