<paper id="1603832532"><title>An Efficient Micropayment System Based on Probabilistic Polling</title><year>1997</year><authors><author org="MIT — Laboratory for Computer Science" id="1760644356">Stanislaw Jarecki</author><author org="AT&amp;T Labs — research" id="2029350574">Andrew M. Odlyzko</author></authors><n_citation>53</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1483141932</reference><reference>1494038444</reference><reference>1516873380</reference><reference>1605348813</reference><reference>1639145229</reference><reference>2163065624</reference><reference>2336151121</reference></references><venue id="2606870472" type="C">Financial Cryptography</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-63594-7_77</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.53887">Electronic money</keyword><keyword weight="0.47409">Authentication</keyword><keyword weight="0.44395">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.452">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.47337">Vendor</keyword><keyword weight="0.55234">Polling</keyword><keyword weight="0.55469">Micropayment</keyword><keyword weight="0.48156">Probabilistic logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.52743">Database transaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.47829">Payment</keyword><keyword weight="0.44036">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Existing software proposals for electronic payments can be divided into “on-line” schemes that require participation of a trusted party (the bank) in every transaction and are secure against overspending, and the “off-line” schemes that do not require a third party and guarantee only that overspending is detected when vendors submit their transaction records to the bank (usually at the end of the day). We propose a new hybrid scheme that combines the advantages of both of the above traditional design strategies. It allows for control of overspending at a cost of only a modest increase in communication compared to the off-line schemes. Our protocol is based on probabilistic polling. During each transaction, with some small probability, the vendor forwards information about this transaction to the bank. This enables the bank to maintain an accurate approximation of a customeru0027s spending. The frequency of polling messages is related to the monetary value of transactions and the amount of overspending the bank is willing to risk.</abstract></paper>