<paper id="1880896921"><title>Automated composition of semantic web services into executable processes</title><year>2004</year><authors><author org="ITC, IRST, Trento, Italy#TAB#" id="2252134122">Paolo Traverso</author><author org="University of Trento, Italy" id="2408543465">Marco Pistore</author></authors><n_citation>348</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>70402205</reference><reference>163778656</reference><reference>1479764148</reference><reference>1487268018</reference><reference>1510794891</reference><reference>1524265748</reference><reference>1529693658</reference><reference>1547792609</reference><reference>1599083726</reference><reference>1601102605</reference><reference>1607137257</reference><reference>1772822243</reference><reference>1994451575</reference><reference>1997420616</reference><reference>2054618740</reference><reference>2122054842</reference><reference>2161536823</reference><reference>2166309559</reference><reference>2170408876</reference></references><venue id="1155608529" type="C">International Semantic Web Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-30475-3_27</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.48985">Observability</keyword><keyword weight="0.47171">Programming language</keyword><keyword weight="0.48252">Model checking</keyword><keyword weight="0.48183">Nondeterministic algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.4704">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46408">Process modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.46081">Planner</keyword><keyword weight="0.5913">Semantic Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.58661">Web service</keyword><keyword weight="0.45856">Database</keyword><keyword weight="0.46214">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.57407">Executable</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Different planning techniques have been applied to the problem of automated composition of web services. However, in realistic cases, this planning problem is far from trivial: the planner needs to deal with the nondeterministic behavior of web services, the partial observability of their internal status, and with complex goals expressing temporal conditions and preference requirements. We propose a planning technique for the automated composition of web services described in OWLS process models, which can deal effectively with nondeterminism, partial observability, and complex goals. The technique allows for the synthesis of plans that encode compositions of web services with the usual programming constructs, like conditionals and iterations. The generated plans can thus be translated into executable processes, e.g., BPEL4WS programs. We implement our solution in a planner and do some preliminary experimental evaluations that show the potentialities of our approach, and the gain in performance of automating the composition at the semantic level w.r.t. the automated composition at the level of executable processes.</abstract></paper>