<paper id="1515402129"><title>Perceived usefulness, ease of use, and usage of information technology: a replication</title><year>1992</year><authors><author org="" id="2129955189">Dennis A. Adams</author><author org="" id="2303465258">R. Ryan Nelson</author><author org="" id="2115788441">Peter A. Todd</author></authors><n_citation>2263</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1595575146</reference><reference>1791587663</reference><reference>2007275742</reference><reference>2048108246</reference><reference>2072047708</reference><reference>2100408980</reference><reference>2167602338</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/249577</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">System usage</keyword><keyword weight="0.45355">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.55312">Discriminant validity</keyword><keyword weight="0.49204">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.43652">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.50193">Usability</keyword><keyword weight="0.53743">Technology acceptance model</keyword><keyword weight="0.47368">Implementation</keyword><keyword weight="0.41864">Replicate</keyword><keyword weight="0.58461">Convergent validity</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>This paper presents the findings of two studies that replicate previous work by Fred Davis on the subject of perceived usefulness, ease of use, and usage of information technology. The two studies focus on evaluating the psychometric properties of the ease of use and usefulness scales, while examining the relationship between ease of use, usefulness, and system usage. Study 1 provides a strong assessment of the convergent validity of the two scales by examining heterogeneous user groups dealing with heterogeneous implementations of messaging technology. In addition, because one might expect users to share similar perspectives about voice and electronic mail, the study also represents a strong test of discriminant validity. In this study a total of 118 respondents from 10 different organizations were surveyed for their attitudes toward two messaging technologies: voice and electronic mail.</abstract></paper>