<paper id="1850505544"><title>How to Strengthen DES Using Existing Hardware</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="Technion: Israel Institute of Technology" id="34241300">Eli Biham</author><author org="Technion: Israel Institute of Technology" id="2167814525">Alex Biryukov</author></authors><n_citation>40</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>380217570</reference><reference>1481631217</reference><reference>1573944628</reference><reference>1580171445</reference><reference>1759918341</reference><reference>1834680620</reference><reference>1964723977</reference><reference>1979802565</reference><reference>1991374982</reference><reference>2007326055</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0000451</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.52146">Cipher</keyword><keyword weight="0.52157">Brute-force search</keyword><keyword weight="0.4628">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46063">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.50056">Invariant (mathematics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.44058">Computer hardware</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Differential, linear and improved Daviesu0027 attacks are capable of breaking DES faster than exhaustive search, but are usually impractical due to enormous amounts of data required. In [20] Wiener designed a million dollar special purpose computer capable of breaking DES in 3.5 hours in average by exhaustive search. In this paper we describe methods of strengthening DES against exhaustive search, differential attacks, linear attacks and improved Daviesu0027 attacks that can be applied on existing DES hardware. We use the fact that there are DES chips in the market that permit replacement of the S-boxes. We introduce the concept of key-dependent invariant S-box transformations. Differential and linear properties of the cipher are invariant under these transformations. We show how to expand the key using such transformations. Possible reorderings of S-boxes are discussed; we present orders of the original DES S-boxes which are slightly stronger than the standard order of S-boxes. Finally we suggest a concrete scheme to strengthen DES which uses the methods described above. This modified DES can be used with existing DES hardware and is much stronger than the standard DES.</abstract></paper>