<paper id="1970457902"><title>Case systems for natural language</title><year>1975</year><authors><author org="Bolt Beranek and Newman Inc., Cambridge, Mass. 02138, U.S.A." id="2122129460">Bertram C. Bruce</author></authors><n_citation>142</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>72151562</reference><reference>102890288</reference><reference>135363680</reference><reference>136155523</reference><reference>150354164</reference><reference>162133286</reference><reference>1555340092</reference><reference>1596869943</reference><reference>2018125432</reference><reference>2035032881</reference><reference>2049347837</reference><reference>2089253078</reference></references><venue id="196139623" type="J">Artificial Intelligence</venue><doi>10.1016/0004-3702(75)90020-X</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.55399">Noun phrase</keyword><keyword weight="0.47489">Turkish</keyword><keyword weight="0.57627">Word order</keyword><keyword weight="0.4073">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.5548">Noun</keyword><keyword weight="0.50894">Natural language</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.43381">Natural language processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.49986">Syntax</keyword><keyword weight="0.51555">Sentence</keyword><keyword weight="0.47754">Semantics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Elsevier</publisher><abstract>Abstract In many languages (e.g. Latin, Greek, Russian, Turkish, German) the relationship of a noun phrase to the rest of a sentence is indicated by altered forms of the noun. The possible relationships are called (surface) “cases”. Because (1) it is difficult to specify semantic-free selection rules for the cases, and (2) related phenomena based on prepositions or word order appear in apparently case-less languages, many have argued that studies of cases should focus on meaning, i.e. on “deep cases”. Deep cases bear a close relationship to the modifiers of a concept. In fact, one could consider a deep case to be a special, or distinguishing, modifier. Several criteria for recognizing deep cases are considered here in the context of the problem of describing an event. Unfortunately, none of the criteria serves as a completely adequate decision procedure. A notion based on the context-dependent “importance” of a relation appears as useful as any rule for selecting deep cases. A representative sample of proposed case systems is examined. Issues such as surface versus deep versus conceptual levels of cases, and the efficiency of the representations implicit in a case system are also discussed.</abstract></paper>