<paper id="1583530357"><title>Petri Net Based Certification of Event-Driven Process Chains</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="INNOBIS Unternehmensberatung und Software GmbH" id="2014253854">Peter Langner</author><author org="Christoph Schneider, cke-schneider.de dataservice" id="2553413898">Christoph Schneider</author><author org="Softlab GmbH" id="2308169095">Joachim Wehler</author></authors><n_citation>68</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2045497409</reference><reference>2058791725</reference><reference>2162868766</reference></references><venue id="1204434967" type="C">Applications and Theory of Petri Nets</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-69108-1_16</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.43019">Synchronization</keyword><keyword weight="0.627">Petri net</keyword><keyword weight="0.46855">Business process</keyword><keyword weight="0.42723">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47599">Propositional calculus</keyword><keyword weight="0.42748">Systems design</keyword><keyword weight="0.42391">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.44029">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.41556">Business process reengineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.45454">Workflow</keyword><keyword weight="0.41967">Semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.42337">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>One of the widespread methods for modeling business processes is the method of event-driven process chains (EPCs) (Ereignisgesteuerte Prozesskette [EPK]). The paper shows that EPCs can be translated into a simple class of colored Petri nets, which have a single color of type Boole and formulas from propositional logic as guards. The structure of the resulting Boolean net is a tree of bipolar synchronization (bp) graphs. This property simplifies considerably the behavioral analysis of EPCs, because Genrich and Thiagarajan proved, that well-formedness of bp schemes can be tested by a reduction algorithm. If the Boolean net resulting from the translation of an EPC is well-formed, it can be eventually translated into a free-choice net showing the same behavior. Therefore the translation of EPCs into Boolean Petri nets fixes the semantics of EPCs and allows a formal analysis of the EPC-method. In the domain of business process engineering only those EPCs, which have been certified as well-formed, can be recommended for further steps like simulation, activity based cost analysis or workflow.</abstract></paper>