<paper id="1522351020"><title>Efficient Kerberized Multicast in a Practical Distributed Setting</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="Telcordia Technologies, Inc.#TAB#" id="2019977874">Giovanni Di Crescenzo</author><author org="University of Michigan" id="2271304997">Olga Kornievskaia</author></authors><n_citation>12</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1600192790</reference><reference>2037515303</reference><reference>2054251041</reference><reference>2057440455</reference><reference>2064967060</reference><reference>2131123432</reference><reference>2143545186</reference><reference>2146973388</reference><reference>2156186849</reference></references><venue id="2754249383" type="C">International Conference on Information Security</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-45439-X_3</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.63754">Protocol Independent Multicast</keyword><keyword weight="0.62792">Multicast encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.45564">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47656">Computer network</keyword><keyword weight="0.62782">Kerberos</keyword><keyword weight="0.60795">Generic Security Service Algorithm for Secret Key Transaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.62916">Internet Group Management Protocol</keyword><keyword weight="0.63111">Kerberized Internet Negotiation of Keys</keyword><keyword weight="0.64638">Multicast</keyword><keyword weight="0.62737">IP multicast</keyword><keyword weight="0.46875">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Many of todayu0027s distributed applications are based on group communication. Given the openness of todayu0027s networks, communication among group members must be secure and, at the same time, efficient. In this paper we consider a realistic distributed setting modeling general networks, including the Internet, that suggests the use of Kerberos, and, more specifically, a distributed mode of operation of Kerberos, called crossrealm authentication protocol, as a desirable choice for distributed applications.We design an efficient protocol for secure group communication via multicast, using Kerberos. While developing the main components of our protocol, we construct an efficient paradigmfor crossrealmauthen tication protocols that decreases communication over the Internet, makes most operations local, and reduces the workload of the involved components. We also design extensions of single-center multicast encryption schemes to multiple-center schemes.</abstract></paper>