<paper id="1562161142"><title>Information distribution aspects of design methodology</title><year>1971</year><authors><author org="Carnegie - Mellon University#TAB#" id="88694571">David Lorge. Parnas</author></authors><n_citation>277</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2076397927</reference><reference>2113695972</reference><reference>2134594099</reference></references><venue id="2755927266" type="C">IFIP Congress</venue><doi>10.1184/R1/6606470.v1</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45773">Data science</keyword><keyword weight="0.49228">Axiomatic design</keyword><keyword weight="0.45069">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.51536">Information hiding</keyword><keyword weight="0.51921">Design technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.49581">Design methods</keyword><keyword weight="0.49335">Originality</keyword><keyword weight="0.48147">Iterative design</keyword><keyword weight="0.57778">Documentation</keyword><keyword weight="0.49947">Generative Design</keyword></keywords><publisher>Carnegie Mellon University</publisher><abstract>The role of documentation in the design and implementation of complex systems is explored, resulting in suggestions in sharp contrast with current practice. The concept of system structure is studied by examining the meaning of the phrase "connections between modules. It is shown that several system design goals (each suggesting a partial time ordering of the decisions) may be inconsistent. Some properties of programmers are discussed. System documentation, which makes all information accessible to anyone working on the project, is discussed. The thesis that such information "broadcasting is harmful, that it is helpful if most system information is hidden from most programmers, is supported by use of the above mentioned considerations as well as by examples. An information hiding technique of documentation is exhibited in the appendix. IFIP CLASSIFICATION: 3 Language of Oral Presentation; English Statement of Originality: In the opinion of the author the paper contains a number of conclusions which have not been discussed or published elsewhere. No paper similar in scope to this paper is being presented for publication elsewhere. INFORMATION DISTRIBUTION ASPECTS OF DESIGN METHODOLOGY D. L. Parnas Department of Computer Science Carnegie-MelIon University Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania</abstract></paper>