<paper id="1549271673"><title>Extending The BFA Workflow Authorization Model to Express Weighted Voting</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="" id="2143505607">Savith Kandala</author><author org="" id="1996714504">Ravi S. Sandhu</author></authors><n_citation>9</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1502450710</reference><reference>2124080036</reference><reference>2134167896</reference><reference>2152505375</reference><reference>2166602595</reference><reference>2169620043</reference></references><venue id="" type="">Proceedings of the IFIP WG 11.3 Thirteenth International Conference on Database Security: Research Advances in Database and Information Systems Security</venue><doi>10.1007/978-0-387-35508-5_10</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45103">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.46565">Expression (mathematics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.45754">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Authorization</keyword><keyword weight="0.4613">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.56588">Weighted voting</keyword><keyword weight="0.48936">Access control</keyword><keyword weight="0.44217">Database transaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.53454">Workflow management system</keyword><keyword weight="0.49382">Workflow</keyword></keywords><publisher>Kluwer, B.V.</publisher><abstract>Bertino, Ferrari and Atluri (BFA) have recently presented a model for specifying and enforcing authorization constraints for Workflow Management Systems (WFMS). The model is comprehensive and exhibits strong properties such as (1) a language to express constraints, (2) formal notions of constraint consistency and (3) algorithms for role-task and user-task assignments. In this paper, we extend the BFA model to include primitives for weighted voting. We show that the BFA model cannot express weighted voting in a straightforward manner, whereas Transaction Control Expressions (TCEs) proposed by Sandhu [5] incorporates this notion. Since, all other aspects of TCEs can be easily simulated in BFA, we believe that the notion of weighted voting is a fundamental operation which is missing in the BFA model. Although, we do not formally prove that BFA cannot simulate weighted voting, we make a strong case that this cannot be done easily or directly. We also show that the extended-BFA model retains all the strong properties of the BFA model.</abstract></paper>