<paper id="1573420096"><title>Creating a Strategic IT Architecture Competency: Learning in Stages</title><year>2003</year><authors><author org="Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) - Center for Information Systems Research (CISR)" id="2133648158">Jeanne W. Ross</author></authors><n_citation>348</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>97579959</reference><reference>1587903092</reference><reference>2056488422</reference><reference>2098925541</reference></references><venue id="48312676" type="J">Mis Quarterly Executive</venue><doi>10.2139/ssrn.416180</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.66921">Data architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.66633">Enterprise architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.6921">Applications architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.45225">Systems engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.68578">Solution architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.4666">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.67536">Reference architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.41132">Engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.68659">Enterprise architecture framework</keyword><keyword weight="0.70611">Business architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.66233">Enterprise architecture management</keyword></keywords><publisher>Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT), Sloan School of Management</publisher><abstract>IT architecture is often assumed to follow business strategy, to align IT with the businessu0027s strategic objectives. Increasingly, though, many business strategies depend on specific underlying IT capabilities. To develop a synergy between business strategy and IT architecture, firms must develop organizational competencies in IT architecture. My research has identified four IT architectural stages, each with its own requisite competencies. The "application silo architecture stage" consists of IT architectures of individual applications. The "standardized technology architecture stage" has an enterprise-wide IT architecture that provides efficiencies through technology standardization. The "rationalized data architecture stage" extends the enterprise-wide IT standards to data and processes. And the "modular architecture stage" builds onto enterprise-wide global standards with loosely coupled IT components to preserve the global standards while enabling local differences. Each stage demands different organizational competencies to implement the architecture and prepare the firm to move to the next stage</abstract></paper>