<paper id="1520746637"><title>Perfectly secure password protocols in the bounded retrieval model</title><year>2006</year><authors><author org="Telcordia Technologies, Piscataway, NJ" id="2923602960">Giovanni Di Crescenzo</author><author org="Georgia Inst of Tech, Atlanta, GA" id="2668464570">Richard Lipton</author><author org="New York Univ., New York NY" id="2306345715">Shabsi Walfish</author></authors><n_citation>106</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1520603994</reference><reference>1535972735</reference><reference>1548067747</reference><reference>1585149031</reference><reference>1591302859</reference><reference>1595293097</reference><reference>1797136128</reference><reference>1968372742</reference><reference>1976907131</reference><reference>2022068408</reference><reference>2074861055</reference><reference>2085355422</reference><reference>2091020476</reference><reference>2104965768</reference><reference>2106110343</reference><reference>2111443676</reference><reference>2125927592</reference><reference>2142515424</reference><reference>2149929743</reference><reference>2155506366</reference></references><venue id="1137528458" type="C">Theory of Cryptography Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/11681878_12</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.62919">Zero-knowledge password proof</keyword><keyword weight="0.6349">Password strength</keyword><keyword weight="0.56104">Cryptographic protocol</keyword><keyword weight="0.45845">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.45604">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45959">Computer network</keyword><keyword weight="0.63511">S/KEY</keyword><keyword weight="0.63837">One-time password</keyword><keyword weight="0.61739">Password policy</keyword><keyword weight="0.62926">Password</keyword><keyword weight="0.59473">Security parameter</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We introduce a formal model, which we call the Bounded Retrieval Model, for the design and analysis of cryptographic protocols remaining secure against intruders that can retrieve a limited amount of partiesu0027 private memory. The underlying model assumption on the intrudersu0027 behavior is supported by real-life physical and logical considerations, such as the inherent superiority of a partyu0027s local data bus over a remote intruderu0027s bandwidth-limited channel, or the detectability of voluminous resource access by any local intruder. More specifically, we assume a fixed upper bound on the amount of a partyu0027s storage retrieved by the adversary. Our model could be considered a non-trivial variation of the well-studied Bounded Storage Model, which postulates a bound on the amount of storage available to an adversary attacking a given :[127],"this model we study perhaps the simplest among cryptographic tasks: user authentication via a password protocol. Specifically, we study the problem of constructing efficient password protocols that remain secure against offline dictionary attacks even when a large (but bounded) part of the storage of the server responsible for password verification is retrieved by an intruder through a remote or local connection. We show password protocols having satisfactory performance on both efficiency (in terms of the serveru0027s running time) and provable security (making the offline dictionary attack not significantly stronger than the online attack). We also study the tradeoffs between efficiency, quantitative and qualitative security in these protocols. All our schemes achieve perfect security (security against computationally-unbounded adversaries). Our main schemes achieve the interesting efficiency property of the serveru0027s lookup complexity being much smaller than the adversaryu0027s retrieval bound.</abstract></paper>