<paper id="1527478789"><title>Codes for interactive authentication</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="Sandia National Laboratories" id="2003732331">Peter Gemmell</author><author org="Weizmann Institute of Science, Rehovot, ISRAEL" id="1023361224">Moni Naor</author></authors><n_citation>47</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1578594943</reference><reference>1981670729</reference><reference>1985623009</reference><reference>1992558221</reference><reference>2010374466</reference><reference>2107561538</reference><reference>2122270497</reference><reference>2143670751</reference><reference>2912630013</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-48329-2_30</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.41206">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.46118">Authentication</keyword><keyword weight="0.45416">Upper and lower bounds</keyword><keyword weight="0.37861">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.44167">Secrecy</keyword><keyword weight="0.42734">Communication source</keyword><keyword weight="0.5457">Authentication protocol</keyword><keyword weight="0.45453">Hash function</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Authentication scheme</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>An authentication protocol is a procedure by which an informant tries to convey n bits of information, which we call an input message, to a recipient. An intruder, I, controls the network over which the informant and the recipient talk and may change any message before it reaches its destination. a If the protocol has security p, then the the recipient must detect this a cheating with probability at least 1 - p. This paper is devoted to characterizing the amount of secret information that the sender and receipient must share in a p-secure protocol. We provide a single-round authentication protocol which requires log(n) + 5 log(1/p) bits of secrecy. as well as a single-round protocol which requires log(n)+2 log(1/p) bits of secrecy based on non-constructive random codes. We prove a lower bound of log(n) + log(1/p) secret bits for single-round protocols.We introduce authentication protocols with more than one round of communication (multi-round protocols) and present a k-round protocol which reduces the amount of secret information that the two parties need to log(k)(n)+ 5 log(1/p). When the number of rounds is log*(n), our protocol requires 2 log(1/p) + O(1) bits. Hence interaction helps when log(n) u003e log(1/p). We also show a lower bound of log(k)(n) on the number of shared random bits in a k-round protocol.</abstract></paper>