<paper id="1619748997"><title>Near-Optimal Plans, Tractability, and Reactivity</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="AT&amp;T Bell laboratories, Murray Hill, NJ" id="1966117383">Bart Selman</author></authors><n_citation>34</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>15347821</reference><reference>109854102</reference><reference>141377150</reference><reference>1481882669</reference><reference>1545429346</reference><reference>1555519929</reference><reference>1555696599</reference><reference>1612069379</reference><reference>1966089223</reference><reference>2038225707</reference><reference>2045526507</reference><reference>2045717693</reference><reference>2046504293</reference><reference>2054497239</reference><reference>2061146398</reference><reference>2079473728</reference><reference>2095995891</reference><reference>2149611281</reference><reference>2161397207</reference><reference>2171798962</reference><reference>2225341423</reference><reference>2398918824</reference></references><venue id="1155137614" type="C">Principles of Knowledge Representation and Reasoning</venue><doi>10.1016/B978-1-4832-1452-8.50143-3</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.58147">Approximation algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.47314">Mathematical optimization</keyword><keyword weight="0.44902">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46155">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.43113">Approximations of π</keyword><keyword weight="0.56813">Combinatorial optimization</keyword><keyword weight="0.43377">STRIPS</keyword><keyword weight="0.52524">Time complexity</keyword><keyword weight="0.47751">Rotation formalisms in three dimensions</keyword></keywords><publisher>Morgan Kaufmann</publisher><abstract>Abstract Many planning problems have recently been shown to be inherently intractable. For example, finding the shortest plan in the blocks-world domain is NP-hard, and so is planning in even some of the most limited STRIPS-style planning formalisms. We explore the question as to what extent these negative results can be attributed to the insistence on finding plans of minimal length. Using recent results form the theory of combinatorial optimization, we show that for domain-independent planning, one cannot efficiently generate any reasonable approximation of the optimal plan. Our result holds for a very restricted form of STRIPS. So, the negative complexity results for domain-independent planning are not just a consequence of searching for the optimal plans, because even finding reasonable approximations is hard. Next we consider domain-dependent planning. For blocks-world planning one can generate in polynomial time good approximations of the minimal plan — within a factor of two of optimal. We show, however, that one cannot efficiently generate arbitrarily good approximations. This result places a limit on the usefulness of certain anytime approximation algorithms for generating better and better plans in the basic blocks-world domain. Finally, we consider further several examples of tractable domain-dependent planning. We show how they can be solved using reactive style plans. Our analysis reveals a surprisingly close connection between tractable domain-dependent planning (optimal and near-optimal) and reactive style planning.</abstract></paper>