<paper id="1530768763"><title>Fuzzy partitioning applied to VLSI-floorplanning and placement</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="Inst. fur Theor. Elektrotech. und Messtech., Karlsruhe Univ., Germany" id="2974305588">C.F. Ball</author><author org="Inst. fur Theor. Elektrotech. und Messtech., Karlsruhe Univ., Germany" id="2974506588">P.V. Kraus</author><author org="Inst. fur Theor. Elektrotech. und Messtech., Karlsruhe Univ., Germany" id="1974125176">D.A. Mlynski</author></authors><n_citation>6</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1900591845</reference><reference>1984954427</reference><reference>2095117703</reference><reference>2161455936</reference></references><venue id="1192710900" type="C">International Symposium on Circuits and Systems</venue><doi>10.1109/ISCAS.1994.408784</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44291">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.57227">Fuzzy logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.46467">Network topology</keyword><keyword weight="0.45909">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46843">Minification</keyword><keyword weight="0.47861">Physical design</keyword><keyword weight="0.54552">Cluster analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.41493">Electronic circuit</keyword><keyword weight="0.50202">Very-large-scale integration</keyword><keyword weight="0.51822">Floorplan</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>Fast hierarchical optimization methods applied to VLSI-floorplanning and placement play a major role in advancing the state of the art in physical design, because circuits get more and more complex. This paper presents a new approach for floorplanning and placement using fuzzy logic as the framework for optimal partitioning. Two hierarchical partitioning strategies are described, both based on the fuzzy c-means algorithm (FCM), well known in the area of clustering and pattern recognition. The first method outlined is applied to a modified GORDIAN procedure, combining wire-length minimization by force directed relaxation (FDR) and a fast clustering technique instead of min-cut. The second approach outlined specifies different similarities between the cells using one fuzzy similarity relation for each feature. A simple example with 16 mesh connected cells and a benchmark example with 33 cells are given to demonstrate the performance of the strategy. u003e</abstract></paper>