<paper id="1596831155"><title>Models for Superimposed Information</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="Oregon Graduate Institute" id="169157075">Lois M. L. Delcambre</author><author org="Oregon Graduate Institute" id="2064546257">David Maier</author></authors><n_citation>30</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2492106958</reference></references><venue id="2757548706" type="C">Evolution and Change in Data Management</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-48054-4_22</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44985">Open research</keyword><keyword weight="0.5541">Information structure</keyword><keyword weight="0.59159">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.60877">Information integration</keyword><keyword weight="0.44847">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.45576">Information retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.45994">Conceptual model</keyword><keyword weight="0.48032">Database model</keyword><keyword weight="0.44326">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.60513">Information space</keyword><keyword weight="0.49207">RDF</keyword><keyword weight="0.43616">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The ubiquitous World Wide Web presents a simple interface for a vast array of heterogeneous information. We see the Web as one enabler for what we call superimposed information. Superimposed information serves to highlight, annotate, connect and supplement information in a base information space. Superimposed information is already pervasive for the Web, with a variety of models and accompanying :[59],"this paper, we introduce superimposed information and analyze a range of conceptual models for it using a three-part feature space consisting of information elements, links, and marks. Information elements in the superimposed layer and links among those information elements are analogous to the classical entities and relationships of database models. The novelty is in the marks that reference underlying information elements. Superimposed information can serve as proxies for underlying information elements, can provide new access paths, and can introduce new information as well as new links among existing information elements. We conclude with a discussion of open research questions regarding superimposed information.</abstract></paper>