<paper id="1529653289"><title>Modeling Phenomena in Spatiotemporal Databases: Desiderata and Solutions</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org=", Aalborg University" id="306216343">Nectaria Tryfona</author></authors><n_citation>19</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1521143303</reference><reference>1522504723</reference><reference>1593007803</reference><reference>1606211267</reference><reference>1849301553</reference><reference>1992732065</reference><reference>2011468699</reference><reference>2015612071</reference><reference>2020868945</reference><reference>2057807152</reference><reference>2086916990</reference><reference>2163815134</reference><reference>2294081347</reference></references><venue id="1192664773" type="C">Database and Expert Systems Applications</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0054477</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44364">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.42915">Geographic information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.48137">Conceptual design</keyword><keyword weight="0.54396">Data modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.48899">Valid time</keyword><keyword weight="0.49362">Spatial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.43805">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.43413">Syntax</keyword><keyword weight="0.41885">Database</keyword><keyword weight="0.48144">Semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.54692">Entity–relationship model</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>This paper focuses on the database modeling of spatiotemporal phenomena. Their components and behavior are analyzed and a formal framework with a small set of concepts-namely objects, attributes, relationships, fields, and constraints, with spatial and temporal dimension-for their definition is provided. A mathematical model for the expression of spatiotemporal constraints, based on the aforementioned concepts, is presented. Next, all the described concepts are translated into modeling constructs-namely entities, attributes, relationships, fields, phenomena and constraints-to enrich the Entity-Relationship (ER) model for the conceptual design of spatiotemporal applications dealing with phenomena. We give the semantics and syntax of the prototypical extended ER; any other model augmented by the same constructs can be used for this purpose. An example demonstrates the applicability, modeling power and ease-of-use of this proposal.</abstract></paper>