<paper id="1527721836"><title>Flexible, Dynamic, and Scalable Service Composition for Active Routers</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="Lancaster University ()" id="2803893998">Stefan Schmid</author><author org="Lancaster University ()" id="2012980173">Tim Chart</author><author org="Lancaster University ()" id="2974139478">Manolis Sifalakis</author><author org="Lancaster University ()" id="2117394811">Andrew Scott</author></authors><n_citation>16</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1493518229</reference><reference>1599629390</reference><reference>1709767083</reference><reference>2112106563</reference><reference>2121469812</reference><reference>2135304718</reference><reference>2156874421</reference><reference>2172094098</reference></references><venue id="106296714" type="J">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-36199-5_20</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Service profile</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Data path</keyword><keyword weight="0.44226">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.51027">Network packet</keyword><keyword weight="0.47059">Computer network</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Service composition</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Active components</keyword><keyword weight="0.50057">Component-based software engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.5958">Router</keyword><keyword weight="0.4696">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.5155">Scalability</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>This paper describes a novel model for the provision of service composites for active routers. The service composition framework enables flexible programmability of the routeru0027s data path through dynamically loadable software components, called u0027active componentsu0027. The composition model promotes transparent and dynamic creation of network-side services and allows independent users to partake in this process. A prototype implementation has revealed that the composition model using packet filters and a classification graph structure as a means to integrate active components into the forwarding path enables the dynamic alteration of the elements of a composite at run-time and permits scalability in the generation of such composites. Furthermore, it allows the flexible provision of a unique service profile for each packet passing through an active router. We show that the overhead of this composition model does not significantly affect the performance of the router.</abstract></paper>