<paper id="1578671095"><title>Assessing Business-IT Alignment Maturity</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="Stevens Institute of Technology - USA" id="1577430427">Jerry N. Luftman</author></authors><n_citation>674</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1500222399</reference><reference>1598905156</reference><reference>1680962750</reference><reference>1991355547</reference><reference>2012701631</reference><reference>2055493529</reference><reference>2084416133</reference><reference>2120525070</reference><reference>2163476580</reference></references><venue id="7020383" type="J">Communications of The Ais</venue><doi>10.4018/978-1-878289-87-2.ch006</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.52679">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.65092">Strategic alignment</keyword><keyword weight="0.53054">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.54682">Competitive advantage</keyword><keyword weight="0.47611">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.69881">Business-IT alignment</keyword><keyword weight="0.52352">Senior management</keyword><keyword weight="0.56025">Information technology management</keyword><keyword weight="0.40743">Engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.54062">Strategic planning</keyword><keyword weight="0.47628">Process management</keyword></keywords><publisher>IGI Global</publisher><abstract>Business and IT practitioners, researchers, and consultants have been asking for an effective tool to assess IT-business alignment. Until now, none was available. This chapter introduces the strategic alignment maturity assessment. This assessment tool is based on the authors research and consulting experience that identified the major enablers and inhibitors in the achievement of business-IT alignment and the methodology that leverages the most important enablers and inhibitors. Alignment focuses on the activities that management performs to achieve cohesive goals across the IT (information technology) and other functional (e.g., finance, marketing, H/R, manufacturing) organizations. Therefore, alignment addresses both how IT is in harmony with the business, and how the business should/could be in harmony with IT. Alignment evolves to a relationship where IT and business adapt their strategies together. Achieving alignment is evolutionary and dynamic. IT requires strong support from senior management, good working relationships, strong leadership, appropriate prioritization, trust, and effective communication, as well as a thorough understanding of the business and technical environments. Achieving and sustaining alignment demands focusing on maximizing the enablers and minimizing the inhibitors. The purpose of this chapter is to discuss an approach for assessing the maturity of the business-IT alignment. Once the maturity is understood, an organization can identify opportunities for enhancing the harmonious relationship of business and IT. INTRODUCTION Decades have passed. Billions of dollars have been invested on information technology (IT). Today, every organization is in the information business. Alignment  applying IT in an appropriate and timely way, in harmony with business strategies, goals and needs  remains a key concern of business executives. This This chapter appears in the book, Strategic Information Technology: Opportunities for Competitive Advantage by Raymond Papp. Copyright © 2001, Idea Group Publishing. 701 E. Chocolate Avenue, Hershey PA 17033-1117, USA Tel: 717/533-8845; Fax 717/533-8661; URL-http://www.idea-group.com ITB7957 IDEA GROUP PUBLISHING</abstract></paper>