<paper id="1483468980"><title>Evaluating information systems effectiveness - part i:: comparing evaluation approaches</title><year>1981</year><authors><author org="COMSERV Corporation" id="2427306303">Scott Hamilton</author><author org="Information and Decision Sciences" id="2431114534">Norman L. Chervany</author></authors><n_citation>386</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1970378145</reference><reference>2035544757</reference><reference>2074562477</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/249291</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.59134">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.60938">Management information systems</keyword><keyword weight="0.51407">Viewpoints</keyword><keyword weight="0.44825">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.52684">Internal audit</keyword><keyword weight="0.48894">Hierarchy</keyword><keyword weight="0.46828">Management science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47121">Multiple time dimensions</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>While the sue and costs of Management Information Systems (MIS) have become highly visible, little attention has been paid to assessing and communicating system effectiveness. Evaluation of system effectiveness is difficult due to its multidimensionality, its qualitative and quantitative aspects, and the multiple, and often conflicting, evaluator :[47],"article provides an overview of what system effectiveness means and how it should be measured. It is the first of two articles to appear in consecutive issues of the MIS Quarterly. Starting with a definition of system effectiveness, this :[47],"article examines evaluation of system effectiveness in terms of a conceptual hierarchy of system objectives. The hierarchy is used to discuss problems in, and recommendations for, evaluating system effectiveness, and to compare MIS evaluation approaches. The second :[47],"article characterizes and compares the evaluator viewpoints on system effectiveness for decision makers in several functional groups involved in MIS implementation ᾢ user, MIS, internal audit, and management. The second :[47],"article recommends several MIS evaluation approaches for incorporating multiple dimensions and multiple evaluator viewpoints into evaluations of information system effectiveness.</abstract></paper>