<paper id="1488219274"><title>BDD vs. Constraint-Based Model Checking: An Experimental Evaluation for Asynchronous Concurrent Systems</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="University of California" id="2279626640">Tevfik Bultan</author></authors><n_citation>12</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1500263346</reference><reference>1527654363</reference><reference>1535950032</reference><reference>1564947547</reference><reference>1586521426</reference><reference>1594722104</reference><reference>1777025722</reference><reference>1822301642</reference><reference>1854012871</reference><reference>1926085771</reference><reference>1965765860</reference><reference>1995151557</reference><reference>2080267935</reference><reference>2081553013</reference><reference>2114092850</reference><reference>2117189826</reference><reference>2124214533</reference><reference>2124778357</reference><reference>2151056896</reference></references><venue id="1159071770" type="C">Tools and Algorithms for Construction and Analysis of Systems</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-46419-0_30</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.54237">Computation tree logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.65131">Abstraction model checking</keyword><keyword weight="0.5083">Asynchronous communication</keyword><keyword weight="0.66066">Model checking</keyword><keyword weight="0.4498">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.49288">Binary decision diagram</keyword><keyword weight="0.45862">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48597">Boolean data type</keyword><keyword weight="0.68243">Symbolic trajectory evaluation</keyword><keyword weight="0.54517">Formal verification</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>BDD-based symbolic model checking has been successful in verification of a wide range of systems. Recently, constraint-based approaches, which use arithmetic constraints as a symbolic representation, have been used in symbolic model checking of infinite-state systems. We argue that use of constraint-based model checking is not limited to infinite-state systems. It can also be used as an alternative to BDD-based model checking for systems with integer variables which have finite but large domains. In this paper we investigate the trade-offs between these two approaches experimentally. We compare the performance of BDD-based model checker SMV to the performance of our constraint-based model checker on verification of several asynchronous concurrent systems. The results indicate that constraint-based model checking is a viable option for verification of asynchronous concurrent systems with large integer domains.</abstract></paper>