<paper id="1587945298"><title>Some Open Issues and New Directions in Group Signatures</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="USC Information Sciences Institute#TAB#" id="124599811">Giuseppe Ateniese</author><author org="USC Information Sciences Institute#TAB#" id="465425324">Gene Tsudik</author></authors><n_citation>156</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1497351799</reference><reference>1531945782</reference><reference>1565067294</reference><reference>1577274403</reference><reference>1763199136</reference><reference>2131123432</reference><reference>2153193245</reference><reference>2911424200</reference></references><venue id="2606870472" type="C">Financial Cryptography</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-48390-X_15</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44235">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.49029">Authentication</keyword><keyword weight="0.4495">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46023">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.54593">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.54386">Encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.61992">Digital signature</keyword><keyword weight="0.47416">Revocation</keyword><keyword weight="0.63424">Group signature</keyword><keyword weight="0.54912">Public-key cryptography</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><abstract>Group signatures allow any member of a potentially large group to sign on behalf of the group. Group signatures are anonymous and unlinkable for everyone with the exception of a designated group manager who can co-relate signatures and reveal the identity of the actual signer. At the same time, no one (including a group manager) can misattribute a valid group signature. Group signatures are claimed to have many practical applications in e-commerce as well as in military and legal :[79],"some interesting and eclectic results, group signatures remain confined to academic literature. The focus of this paper is two-fold. First, it discusses certain issues that stand in the way of practical applications of group signatures and uses the example of on recent group signature scheme to illustrate certain problems. Second, this paper (informally) introduces :[79],"some practical security services that can be constructed using any group signature scheme. Sample realizations of these services are provided.</abstract></paper>