<paper id="1585389879"><title>Minimizing the use of random oracles in authenticated encryption schemes</title><year>1997</year><authors><author org="University of california at San Diego" id="2052950829">Mihir Bellare</author><author org="Univ. of California at Davis" id="2106597688">Phillip Rogaway</author></authors><n_citation>59</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1569930334</reference><reference>1996360405</reference><reference>2052267638</reference><reference>2073210531</reference><reference>2077300005</reference><reference>2109365488</reference><reference>2131300413</reference><reference>2162653919</reference><reference>2166462813</reference></references><venue id="1135668280" type="C">International Conference on Information and Communication Security</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0028457</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.63833">Pseudorandom function family</keyword><keyword weight="0.44686">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.65955">Collision resistance</keyword><keyword weight="0.64488">Cryptographic hash function</keyword><keyword weight="0.63244">Random oracle</keyword><keyword weight="0.43761">Computer network</keyword><keyword weight="0.64375">Cryptographic primitive</keyword><keyword weight="0.44896">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.68457">SWIFFT</keyword><keyword weight="0.64786">Security of cryptographic hash functions</keyword><keyword weight="0.62964">Secure Hash Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.43711">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>A cryptographic scheme is “provably secure” if an attack on the scheme implies an attack on the underlying primitives it employs. A cryptographic scheme is “provably secure in the random-oracle model” if it uses a cryptographic hash function F and is provably secure when F is modeled by a public random function. Demonstrating that a crypto graphic scheme is provably secure in the random-oracle model engenders much assurance in the schemeu0027s correctness. But there may remain some lingering fear that the concrete hash function which instantiates the random oracle differs from a random function in some significant way. So it is good to limit reliance on random oracles. Here we describe two encryption schemes which use their random oracles in a rather limited way. The schemes achieve semantic security and plaintext awareness under specified assumptions. One scheme uses the RSA primitive; another uses Diffie-Hellman. In either case messages longer than the modulus length can be safely and directly encrypted without relying on the hash functions modeled as random-oracles to be good for private-key encryption.</abstract></paper>