<paper id="1715153959"><title>A principles-based enterprise architecture: lessons from Texaco and Star Enterprise</title><year>1990</year><authors><author org="" id="2703526513">Gary L. Richardson</author><author org="" id="2466882066">Brad M. Jackson</author><author org="" id="2116943069">Gary W. Dickson</author></authors><n_citation>174</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>2112970519</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/249787</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.69007">Enterprise architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.66364">Solution architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.46959">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.65733">NIST Enterprise Architecture Model</keyword><keyword weight="0.43728">Engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.68518">Enterprise architecture framework</keyword><keyword weight="0.63682">Enterprise integration</keyword><keyword weight="0.66003">Enterprise life cycle</keyword><keyword weight="0.6568">Business architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.67394">Enterprise architecture management</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>Star Enterprise is a joint venture partnership between Texaco Inc. and the Saudi Arabian Oil Company. Created in 1988, it became fully operational on January 1, 1989. This new organization inherited staff, facilities, and information resources existing within Texaco Inc. at the time of formation. A significant opportunity for the new organization was to create a new Enterprise Information Technology Architecture to support business functions and management decision making. While this venture was an opportunity, it was also a challenge because of the existing information technology that was comprised of incompatible hardware and nonintegrated systems. This paper describes the architecture that emerged and reviews its current status. Two major contributions of the paper are to identify the principles upon which the architecture is being created and to review what has been learned to date in the process of implementing the architecture.</abstract></paper>