<paper id="1577870632"><title>Oblivious transfers and privacy amplification</title><year>1997</year><authors><author org="Département IRO, Université de Montréal, Montréal, Québec, Canada" id="2041502760">Gilles Brassard</author><author org="Département IRO, Université de Montréal, Montréal, Québec, Canada" id="2293660417">Claude Crépeau</author></authors><n_citation>38</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1537539847</reference><reference>1543411476</reference><reference>1572330878</reference><reference>1584560347</reference><reference>1965206353</reference><reference>1970606468</reference><reference>1985623009</reference><reference>1987667503</reference><reference>2007661134</reference><reference>2016443801</reference><reference>2051996064</reference><reference>2123789695</reference><reference>2134959754</reference><reference>2153708829</reference><reference>2154300278</reference><reference>2160125021</reference><reference>2229572253</reference></references><venue id="1140213147" type="C">Theory and Application of Cryptographic Techniques</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-69053-0_23</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46352">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.51528">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Probability of failure</keyword><keyword weight="0.46645">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.51051">Information-theoretic security</keyword><keyword weight="0.61399">Oblivious transfer</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Assume A owns two secret k-bit strings. She is willing to disclose one of them to B, at his choosing, provided he does not learn anything about the other string. Conversely, B does not want A to learn which secret he chose to learn. A protocol for the above task is said to implement One-out-of-two String Oblivious Transfer, denoted (2 1)-OTk. This primitive is particularly useful in a variety of cryptographic settings. An apparently simpler task corresponds to the case k = 1 of two one-bit secrets: this is known as One-out-of-two Bit Oblivious Transfer, denoted (2 1)-OT. We address the question of reducing (2 1)-OTk to (2 1)-OT. This question is not new: it was introduced in 1986. However, most solutions until now have implicitly or explicitly depended on the notion of self-intersecting codes. It can be proved that this restriction makes it asymptotically impossible to implement (2 1)-OTk with fewer than about 3.5277k instances of (2 1)-OT. The current paper introduces the idea of using privacy amplification as underlying technique to reduce (2 1)-OTk to (2 1)-OT. This allows for more efficient solutions at the cost of an exponentially small probability of failure: it is sufficient to use slightly more than 2k instances of (2 1)-OT in order to implement (2 1)-OTk. Moreover, we show that privacy amplification allows for the efficient implementation of (2 1)-OTk from generalized versions of (2 1)-OT that would not have been suitable for the earlier techniques based on self-intersecting codes. An application of this more general reduction is given.</abstract></paper>