<paper id="1574098530"><title>Exploring the factors associated with expert systems success</title><year>1995</year><authors><author org="" id="2306843524">Youngohc Yoon</author><author org="" id="1993352060">Tor Guimaraes</author><author org="" id="1990681686">Quinton O'Neal</author></authors><n_citation>209</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>206280253</reference><reference>1488405089</reference><reference>1498240737</reference><reference>1500319018</reference><reference>1507934814</reference><reference>1516320044</reference><reference>1522870456</reference><reference>1539628043</reference><reference>1544848115</reference><reference>1568106064</reference><reference>1574834327</reference><reference>1582170352</reference><reference>1601792741</reference><reference>1791587663</reference><reference>1829139082</reference><reference>1889097283</reference><reference>1958421068</reference><reference>1963608591</reference><reference>2017994007</reference><reference>2042664747</reference><reference>2054555539</reference><reference>2057012437</reference><reference>2058595961</reference><reference>2068606963</reference><reference>2089376693</reference><reference>2107258608</reference><reference>2127455238</reference><reference>2138672502</reference><reference>2147470311</reference><reference>2154163681</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/249712</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.48747">IBM</keyword><keyword weight="0.4317">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.51428">Expert system</keyword><keyword weight="0.50715">People skills</keyword><keyword weight="0.47968">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.46525">Management science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Project success</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>As the widespread use and company dependency on expert systems (ES) incease, so does the need to assess their value and to ensure implementation success. This study identifies and empirically tests eight major variables proposed in the literature as determinants of ES success, in this case measured in terms of user satisfactions. IBMu0027s Corporate Manufacturing Expert Systems Project Center collected information from 69 project managers to support the study. The results clearly support the hypothesized relationships and suggest the need for ES project managers to pay special attention to these determinants of ES implementation success. ES success is directily related to the quality of developers and the ES shells used, end-user characteristcs, and degree of user involvement in ES development, as each has been defined in this study. For exploratory purposes, the component items for each of these major variables were correlated with the components of user satisfaction. Based on the results, several recommendations are proposed for ES project managers to enhance the likelihood of project success, including: adding problem difficulty as a criteriaon for ES application selection; increasing ES developer training to improve people skills; having the ability to model and use a systems approach in solving business problems; sharping end-user attitudes and expectations regarding ES; improving the selction of domain experts; more thoroughly understanding the ES impact on end-user jobs; restricting the acquistion of ES shells based on a rpopsoed set of criteria; and ensuring a proper match of ES development techniques and tools to the business problem at hand.</abstract></paper>