<paper id="1747723070"><title>Dynamic load balancing in geographically distributed heterogeneous Web servers</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="Dipt. di Inf. e Sistemistica, Rome Univ., Italy" id="349443823">M. Colajanni</author><author org="IBM" id="2125104194">P.S. Yu</author><author org="Univ. of Rome La Sapienza" id="2111996256">V. Cardellini</author></authors><n_citation>119</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1581144645</reference><reference>2022013117</reference><reference>2037842078</reference><reference>2075666301</reference><reference>2099374284</reference><reference>2138403394</reference><reference>2157571634</reference></references><venue id="1200222865" type="C">International Conference on Distributed Computing Systems</venue><doi>10.1109/ICDCS.1998.679729</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.58407">Web traffic</keyword><keyword weight="0.65918">Network Load Balancing Services</keyword><keyword weight="0.44864">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.63072">Load balancing (computing)</keyword><keyword weight="0.71234">Server</keyword><keyword weight="0.57901">Domain Name System</keyword><keyword weight="0.47334">Computer network</keyword><keyword weight="0.74876">Round-robin DNS</keyword><keyword weight="0.47228">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.62449">Web server</keyword><keyword weight="0.62602">Client–server model</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><abstract>With ever increasing Web traffic, a distributed multi server Web site can provide scalability and flexibility to cope with growing client demands. Load balancing algorithms to spread the requests across multiple Web servers are crucial to achieve the scalability. Various domain name server (DNS) based schedulers have been proposed in the literature, mainly for multiple homogeneous servers. The presence of heterogeneous Web servers not only increases the complexity of the DNS scheduling problem, but also makes previously proposed algorithms for homogeneous distributed systems not directly applicable. This leads us to propose new policies, cabled adaptive TTL algorithms, that take into account both the uneven distribution of client request rates and heterogeneity of Web servers to adaptively set the time-to-live (TTL) value for each address mapping request. Extensive simulation results show that these strategies are robust and effective in balancing load among geographically distributed heterogeneous Web servers.</abstract></paper>