<paper id="1506039304"><title>Superstring: a scalable service discovery protocol for the wide-area pervasive environment</title><year>2003</year><authors><author org="the University of Queensland" id="2200475569">R. Robinson</author><author org="" id="2269912393">J. Indulska</author></authors><n_citation>23</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1527463082</reference><reference>1563315162</reference><reference>1576337687</reference><reference>1985815525</reference><reference>1989163006</reference><reference>2033938536</reference><reference>2118428193</reference><reference>2125855750</reference><reference>2127754538</reference><reference>2158049821</reference><reference>2163059190</reference><reference>2167898414</reference><reference>2280940837</reference></references><venue id="1174934631" type="C">International Conference on Networks</venue><doi>10.1109/ICON.2003.1266272</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.49555">Peer-to-peer</keyword><keyword weight="0.46892">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.44722">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47483">Workstation</keyword><keyword weight="0.46754">Computer network</keyword><keyword weight="0.45327">Bandwidth (signal processing)</keyword><keyword weight="0.52051">Ubiquitous computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.56232">Web service</keyword><keyword weight="0.64885">Service discovery</keyword><keyword weight="0.46203">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.5147">Scalability</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>Arguably, the world has become one large pervasive computing environment. Our planet is growing a digital skin of a wide array of sensors, hand-held computers, mobile phones, laptops, web services and publicly accessible web-cams. Often, these devices and services are deployed in groups, forming small communities of interacting devices. Service discovery protocols allow processes executing on each device to discover services offered by other devices within the community. These communities can be linked together to form a wide-area pervasive environment, allowing processes in one p u p tu interact with services in another. However, the costs of communication and the protocols by which this communication is mediated in the wide-area differ from those of intra-group, or local-area, communication. Communication is an expensive operation for small, battery powered devices, but it is less expensive for servem and workstations, which have a constant power supply and 81u0027e connected to high bandwidth networks. This paper introduces Superstring, a peer to-peer service discovery protocol optimised fur use in the wide-area. Its goals are to minimise computation and memory overhead in the face of large numbers of resources. It achieves this memory and computation scalability by distributing the storage cost of service descriptions and the computation cost of queries over multiple resolvers.</abstract></paper>