<paper id="1554090281"><title>Cryptanalysis of alleged A5 stream cipher</title><year>1997</year><authors><author org="School of Electrical Engineering, University of Belgrade, Beograd, Yugoslavia" id="1237859792">Jovan Dj. Golic</author></authors><n_citation>278</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1549665762</reference><reference>1563606623</reference><reference>1981205339</reference><reference>2061168187</reference><reference>2151564283</reference><reference>2158376794</reference></references><venue id="1140213147" type="C">Theory and Application of Cryptographic Techniques</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-69053-0_17</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.63014">Keystream</keyword><keyword weight="0.42813">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.39729">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.60879">Fluhrer, Mantin and Shamir attack</keyword><keyword weight="0.52155">Cryptanalysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.41398">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.58719">Running key cipher</keyword><keyword weight="0.60075">Stream cipher</keyword><keyword weight="0.57607">Stream cipher attack</keyword><keyword weight="0.6086">Slide attack</keyword><keyword weight="0.51163">Session key</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer Berlin Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>A binary stream cipher, known as A5, consisting of three short LFSRs of total length 64 that are mutually clocked in the stop/go manner is cryptanalyzed. It is allegedly used in the GSM standard for digital cellular mobile telephones. Very short keystream sequences are generated from different initial states obtained by combining a 64-bit secret session key and a known 22-bit public key. A basic divide-and-conquer attack recovering the unknown initial state from a known keystream sequence is first introduced. It exploits the specific clocking rule used and has average computational complexity around 240. A time-memory trade-off attack based on the birthday paradox which yields the unknown internal state at a known time for a known keystream sequence is then pointed out. The attack is successful if T ċ M ≥ 2633.32, where T and M are the required computational time and memory (in 128-bit words), respectively. The precomputation time is O(M) and the required number of known keystream sequences generated from different public keys is about T/102. For example, one can choose T ≅ 227.67 and M ≅ 235.65. To obtain the secret session key from the determined internal state, a so-called internal state reversion attack is proposed and analyzed by the theory of critical and subcritical branching processes.</abstract></paper>