<paper id="1760182598"><title>Analysis of LSB based image steganography techniques</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="Dept. of Electr. &amp; Comput. Eng., Stevens Inst. of Technol., Hoboken, NJ, USA#TAB#" id="2048908780">R. Chandramouli</author><author org="Center for Cyber Security" id="2140730868">N. Memon</author></authors><n_citation>335</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1527181506</reference><reference>2061397706</reference></references><venue id="1163163559" type="C">International Conference on Image Processing</venue><doi>10.1109/ICIP.2001.958299</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46145">Information theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.43527">Computer vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.55745">Steganography</keyword><keyword weight="0.50451">Digital watermarking</keyword><keyword weight="0.50502">False alarm</keyword><keyword weight="0.44026">Pattern recognition</keyword><keyword weight="0.42522">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45518">Adaptive filter</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.46994">Data compression</keyword><keyword weight="0.47455">Copy protection</keyword><keyword weight="0.50685">Least significant bit</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>There have been many techniques for hiding messages in images in such a manner that the alterations made to the image are perceptually indiscernible. However, the question whether they result in images that are statistically indistinguishable from untampered images has not been adequately explored. We look at some specific image based steganography techniques and show that an observer can indeed distinguish between images carrying a hidden message and images which do not carry a message. We derive a closed form expression of the probability of detection and false alarm in terms of the number of bits that are hidden. This leads us to the notion of steganographic capacity, that is, how many bits can we hide in a message without causing statistically significant modifications? Our results are able to provide an upper bound on the this capacity. Our ongoing work relates to adaptive steganographic techniques that take explicit steps to foil the detection mechanisms. In this case we hope to show that the number of bits that can be embedded increases significantly.</abstract></paper>