<paper id="1984715534"><title>Unfounded sets and well-founded semantics for general logic programs</title><year>1988</year><authors><author org="Univ. of Calif. at Santa Cruz" id="2155530763">Allen Van Gelder</author><author org="Stanford, University" id="2116418223">Kenneth Ross</author><author org="University of Cincinnati" id="2004860627">John S. Schlipf</author></authors><n_citation>357</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1526625950</reference><reference>1766332311</reference><reference>2003531456</reference><reference>2057124712</reference><reference>2108911687</reference><reference>2111353076</reference><reference>2120465900</reference><reference>2143382644</reference></references><venue id="1184151122" type="C">Symposium on Principles of Database Systems</venue><doi>10.1145/308386.308444</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.42256">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Logic program</keyword><keyword weight="0.50177">Converse</keyword><keyword weight="0.46725">Programming language</keyword><keyword weight="0.60487">Deductive database</keyword><keyword weight="0.4549">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45853">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.64587">Stable model semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.5171">Semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.67964">Well-founded semantics</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>A general logic program (abbreviated to “program” hereafter) is a set of rules that have both positive and negative subgoals. It is common to view a deductive database as a general logic program consisting of rules (IDB) sitting above elementary relations (EDB, facts). It is desirable to associate one Herbrand model with a program and think of that model as the “meaning of the program,” or its “declarative semantics.” Ideally, queries directed to the program would be answered in accordance with this model. We introduce unfounded sets and well-founded partial models , and define the well-founded semantics of a program to be its well-founded partial model. If the well-founded partial model is in fact a model, we call it the well-founded model, and say the program is “well-behaved”. We show that the class of well-behaved programs properly includes previously studied classes of “stratified” and “locally stratified” programs Gelfand and Lifschits have proposed a definition of “unique stable model” for general logic programs. We show that a program has a unique stable model if it has a well-founded model, in which case they are the same. We discuss why the converse is not true.</abstract></paper>