<paper id="1492023286"><title>Completeness of the Pool Calculus with an Open Built-in Theory</title><year>1993</year><authors><author org="Universität Leipzig" id="2124250417">Uwe Petermann</author></authors><n_citation>15</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1514729613</reference><reference>1559159242</reference><reference>1571591500</reference><reference>1860592703</reference><reference>1970861542</reference><reference>1971043386</reference><reference>1975701431</reference><reference>1999336350</reference><reference>2018221833</reference><reference>2061877402</reference><reference>2740900434</reference><reference>2884120893</reference></references><venue id="" type="">KGC '93 Proceedings of the Third Kurt Gödel Colloquium on Computational Logic and Proof Theory</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0022576</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Theorem provers</keyword><keyword weight="0.52118">Query language</keyword><keyword weight="0.47896">Matrix (mathematics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.51937">Unification</keyword><keyword weight="0.52671">Disjunctive normal form</keyword><keyword weight="0.52528">Rule of inference</keyword><keyword weight="0.52295">Gas meter prover</keyword><keyword weight="0.57835">Completeness (statistics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.47156">Calculus</keyword><keyword weight="0.42966">Mathematics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We present an approach for building-in theories into theorem provers which are based on the connection method. The approach may be applied to a wide class of open, i.e. quantifier-free, theories, among them taxonomic, constraint and equational theories. We generalize the concepts of a spanning mating and of a unifier of a connection towards the theory case. We introduce the notion of the completeness of a set of theory connections with respect to a given query language. This completeness means that for a given theory there are “enough” theory connections in order to refute all theory unsatisfiable matrices which belong to the considered query language. Moreover we define the solvability of the theory unification problem in a set of theory connections. This property means that a complete set of theory unifiers may be constructed for each given theory connection. In order to prove the completeness of a prover with a built-in theory it is sufficient to construct a complete set of theory connections such that the theory unification problem in that set is solvable.</abstract></paper>