<paper id="1561479548"><title>Extensible database systems</title><year>1986</year><authors><author org="" id="2157114695">Michael J Carey</author><author org="University of Wisconsin" id="1979791317">David J DeWitt</author></authors><n_citation>34</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1520815598</reference><reference>1552081212</reference><reference>1582616830</reference><reference>1964093362</reference><reference>1967261084</reference><reference>1977101058</reference><reference>2000869830</reference><reference>2011839903</reference><reference>2153667796</reference><reference>2389944897</reference></references><venue id="" type="">On knowledge base management systems: integrating artificial intelligence and d atabase technologies</venue><doi>10.1007/978-1-4612-4980-1_26</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.59754">Data modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.61527">Data administration</keyword><keyword weight="0.56404">Concurrency control</keyword><keyword weight="0.46545">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.57227">Systems design</keyword><keyword weight="0.62922">Database testing</keyword><keyword weight="0.67274">Database design</keyword><keyword weight="0.60417">Intelligent database</keyword><keyword weight="0.63447">Database theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.46416">Database</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer-Verlag New York, Inc.</publisher><abstract>The design of database systems capable of supporting non-traditional application areas such as expert systems and related AI applications, CAD/CAM and VLSI data management, scientific and statistical applications, and image/voice applications has recently emerged as an important direction of database system research. These new applications differ from conventional applications in a number of critical aspects, including data modeling requirements, processing functionality, concurrency control and recovery mechanisms, and access methods and storage structures. The goal of this project is to simplify the development of database management systems for new applications by designing and prototyping a new generation of database systems. Our research is directed towards producing a core database system that can be easily extended to meet the demands of new applications. This system will permit extensions to the data modeling, query processing, access method, storage structure, concurrency control, and recovery components of the system. We are currently considering the use of object-oriented programming and rule-based specification techniques as bases for this work.</abstract></paper>