<paper id="1972072126"><title>Index selection in a self-adaptive data base management system</title><year>1976</year><authors><author org="Laboratory for Computer Science, MIT, Cambridge, Massachusetts#TAB#" id="2170630515">Michael Hammer</author><author org="Laboratory for Computer Science, MIT, Cambridge, Massachusetts#TAB#" id="2157979715">Arvola Chan</author></authors><n_citation>108</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1967627943</reference><reference>1968878257</reference><reference>1995311648</reference><reference>1999407826</reference><reference>2074687738</reference><reference>2087927750</reference><reference>2123209274</reference><reference>2165467455</reference><reference>2901608006</reference></references><venue id="1175089206" type="C">International Conference on Management of Data</venue><doi>10.1145/509383.509385</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.54069">Exponential smoothing</keyword><keyword weight="0.47905">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.52703">Heuristic (computer science)</keyword><keyword weight="0.46885">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Self adaptive</keyword><keyword weight="0.50503">Index selection</keyword><keyword weight="0.50691">Management system</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Usage model</keyword><keyword weight="0.46333">Database</keyword><keyword weight="0.46468">Overhead (business)</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>We address the problem of automatically adjusting the physical organization of a data base to optimize its performance as its access requirements change. We describe the principles of the automatic index selection facility of a prototype self-adaptive data base management system that is currently under development. The importance of accurate usage model acquisition and data characteristics estimation is stressed. The statistics gathering mechanisms that are being incorporated into our prototype system are discussed. Exponential smoothing techniques are used for averaging statistics observed over different periods of time in order to predict future characteristics. An heuristic algorithm for selecting indices to match projected access requirements is presented. The cost model on which the decision procedure is based is flexible enough to incorporate the overhead costs of index creation, index storage and application program recompilation.</abstract></paper>