<paper id="1963701527"><title>Congestion control in high-speed communication networks using the Smith principle</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="Dipartimento di Elettrotecnica ed Elettronica, Politecnico di Bari, Via Orabona 4, 70125 Bari, Italy#TAB#" id="2463486390">Saverio Mascolo</author></authors><n_citation>232</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1528455493</reference><reference>1714781699</reference><reference>1970131865</reference><reference>1986753211</reference><reference>2026204386</reference><reference>2054256732</reference><reference>2055641345</reference><reference>2096597645</reference><reference>2098289156</reference><reference>2101182788</reference><reference>2101214690</reference><reference>2114398912</reference><reference>2121291720</reference><reference>2121510411</reference><reference>2122745457</reference><reference>2129453085</reference><reference>2133094699</reference><reference>2138873376</reference><reference>2142090496</reference><reference>2143427921</reference><reference>2146778806</reference><reference>2156594910</reference><reference>2158733823</reference><reference>2164636495</reference><reference>2753542457</reference></references><venue id="51360982" type="J">Automatica</venue><doi>10.1016/S0005-1098(99)00128-4</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.56734">Internet Protocol</keyword><keyword weight="0.43917">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.62242">Networked control system</keyword><keyword weight="0.6208">Packet loss</keyword><keyword weight="0.46125">Computer network</keyword><keyword weight="0.60206">Transmission Control Protocol</keyword><keyword weight="0.60944">Flow control (data)</keyword><keyword weight="0.63688">Network congestion</keyword><keyword weight="0.62088">TCP Friendly Rate Control</keyword><keyword weight="0.62918">Network traffic control</keyword></keywords><publisher>Pergamon Press, Inc.</publisher><abstract>High-speed communication networks are characterized by large bandwidth-delay products. This may have an adverse impact on the stability of closed-loop congestion control algorithms. In this paper, classical control theory and Smithu0027s principle are proposed as key tools for designing an effective and simple congestion control law for high-speed data networks. Mathematical analysis shows that the proposed control law guarantees stability of network queues and full utilization of network links in a general network topology and traffic scenario during both transient and steady-state condition. In particular, no data loss is guaranteed using buffers with any capacity, whereas full utilization of links is ensured using buffers with capacity at least equal to the bandwidth-delay product. The control law is transformed to a discrete-time form and is applied to ATM networks. Moreover a comparison with the ERICA algorithm is carried out. Finally, the control law is transformed to a window form and is applied to Internet. The resulting control law surprisingly reveals that todayu0027s Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol implements a Smith predictor for congestion control. This provides a theoretical insight into the congestion control mechanism of TCP/IP along with a method to modify and improve this mechanism in a way that is backward compatible.</abstract></paper>