<paper id="1879384276"><title>When e-th roots become easier than factoring</title><year>2007</year><authors><author org="DGA and Université de Versailles, Versailles cedex, France#TAB#" id="2755216431">Antoine Joux</author><author org="École Normale Supérieure, Équipe de Cryptographie, Paris cedex 05, France#TAB#" id="2005500650">David Naccache</author><author org="INRIA Lorraine, LORIA, CACAO, Villiers-lès-Nancy cedex, France#TAB#" id="2096529159">Emmanuel Thomé</author></authors><n_citation>18</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1490637410</reference><reference>1495360227</reference><reference>1505920856</reference><reference>1540276440</reference><reference>1679474142</reference><reference>1996360405</reference><reference>2032080903</reference><reference>2054482077</reference><reference>2092705148</reference><reference>2100300741</reference><reference>2101041451</reference><reference>2162904415</reference><reference>2612997896</reference></references><venue id="2535638237" type="C">International Conference on the Theory and Application of Cryptology and Information Security</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-76900-2_2</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.42456">Affine transformation</keyword><keyword weight="0.49199">Integer</keyword><keyword weight="0.45383">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.47543">Polynomial</keyword><keyword weight="0.42427">Of the form</keyword><keyword weight="0.45453">Modulo</keyword><keyword weight="0.50229">Special number field sieve</keyword><keyword weight="0.50125">Oracle</keyword><keyword weight="0.4438">Factoring</keyword><keyword weight="0.41278">Mathematics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We show that computing e-th roots modulo n is easier than factoring n with currently known methods, given subexponential access to an oracle outputting the roots of numbers of the form xi + :[33],"c is fixed and xi denotes small integers of the attackeru0027s choosing. The attack comes in two flavors: - A first version is illustrated here by producing selective roots of the form xi + :[33],"c in Ln(1/3, 3√32/9). This matches the special number field sieveu0027s (SNFS) complexity. - A second variant computes arbitrary e-th roots in Ln (1/3, γ) after a subexponential number of oracle queries. The constant γ depends on the type of oracle :[109],"addresses in particular the One More rsa Inversion problem, where the e-th root oracle is not restricted to numbers of a special form. The aforementioned constant γ is then 3√32/9. Constraining the oracle to roots of the form e√xi + :[33],"c mod n increases :[154],"methods are faster than factoring n using the GNFS (Ln(1/3, :[165],"sheds additional light on rsau0027s malleability in general and on rsau0027s resistance to affine forgeries in particular - a problem known to be polynomial for xi u003e 3√n, but for which no algorithm faster than factoring was known before this work.</abstract></paper>