<paper id="1578343209"><title>Identifying and Addressing Stakeholder Interests in Design Science Research: An Analysis Using Critical Systems Heuristics</title><year>2009</year><authors><author org="Curtin Univ. of Technol." id="2139509818">John R. Venable</author></authors><n_citation>18</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>282864490</reference><reference>1507629439</reference><reference>2062114445</reference><reference>2099593285</reference><reference>2136451344</reference><reference>2141002742</reference><reference>2151461605</reference><reference>2158342889</reference><reference>2169571673</reference><reference>2171422629</reference></references><venue id="" type="">CreativeSME</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-642-02388-0_7</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.41191">Political science</keyword><keyword weight="0.54927">Stakeholder</keyword><keyword weight="0.63256">Stakeholder analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.54172">Heuristics</keyword><keyword weight="0.60681">Design science research</keyword><keyword weight="0.47624">Management science</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>This paper utilises the Critical Systems Heuristics (CSH) framework developed by Werner Ulrich to critically consider the stakeholders and design goals that should be considered as relevant by researchers conducing Design Science Research (DSR). CSH provides a philosophically and theoretically grounded framework and means for critical consideration of the choices of stakeholders considered to be relevant to any system under design consideration. The paper recommends that legitimately undertaken DSR should include witnesses to represent the interests of the future consumers of the outcomes of DSR, i.e., the future clients, decision makers, professionals, and other non-included stakeholders in the future use of the solution technologies to be invented in DSR. The paper further discusses options for how witnesses might be included, who should be witnessed for and obstacles to implementing the recommendations.</abstract></paper>