<paper id="1687531700"><title>A Unified Model of Internet Scale Alerting Services</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="Freie Universität Berlin." id="2005242334">Annika Hinze</author><author org="Freie Universität Berlin." id="1912145959">Daniel Faensen</author></authors><n_citation>21</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>45890117</reference><reference>1483969214</reference><reference>1491807955</reference><reference>1607537678</reference><reference>1671717292</reference><reference>1747208294</reference><reference>1952843833</reference><reference>1977658425</reference><reference>1991247646</reference><reference>1997556136</reference><reference>2050070548</reference><reference>2097432384</reference><reference>2102852063</reference><reference>2129074680</reference><reference>2140970291</reference><reference>2141375288</reference></references><venue id="1134101006" type="C">International Conference on Semantic Computing</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-46652-9_28</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.50578">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.46285">Software engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.45793">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.46345">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47997">Implementation</keyword><keyword weight="0.46084">Electronic document</keyword><keyword weight="0.42345">Information Dissemination</keyword><keyword weight="0.49552">Systems architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.43375">Digital library</keyword><keyword weight="0.44845">Unified Model</keyword><keyword weight="0.48005">The Internet</keyword><keyword weight="0.46118">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In the last years, alerting systems have gained strengthened attention. Several systems have been implemented. For the evaluation and cooperation of these systems, the following problems arise: The systems and their models are not compatible, and existing models are only appropriate for a subset of conceivable application domains. Due to modeling differences, a simple integration of different alerting systems is impossible. What is needed, is a unified model that covers the whole variety of alerting service applications. This paper provides a unified model for alerting services that captures the special constraints of most application areas. The model can serve as a basis for an evaluation of alerting service implementations. In addition to the unified model, we define a general profile structure by which clients can specify their interest. This structure is independent of underlying profile definition languages. To eliminate drawbacks of the existing non-cooperating solitary services we introduce a new technique, the Mediating Alerting Service (MediAS). It establishes the cooperation of alerting services in an hierarchical and parallel way.</abstract></paper>