<paper id="1581994447"><title>Lower bounds on generic algorithms in groups</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="Swiss Federal Institute of Technology (ETH) Zurich," id="2068596995">Ueli M. Maurer</author><author org="Swiss Federal Institute of Technology (ETH) Zurich," id="2242008111">Stefan Wolf</author></authors><n_citation>64</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1491251281</reference><reference>1963716248</reference><reference>1981455414</reference><reference>2080132708</reference><reference>2096832922</reference><reference>2156186849</reference><reference>2164988972</reference><reference>2170293373</reference><reference>2612543848</reference></references><venue id="1140213147" type="C">Theory and Application of Cryptographic Techniques</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0054118</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.55796">Prime (order theory)</keyword><keyword weight="0.53223">Cyclic group</keyword><keyword weight="0.4902">Equivalence (measure theory)</keyword><keyword weight="0.41753">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.47289">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.46915">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.5568">Computational problem</keyword><keyword weight="0.60586">Generic point</keyword><keyword weight="0.45453">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.65412">Generic group model</keyword><keyword weight="0.53164">Prime factor</keyword><keyword weight="0.4335">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.56933">Discrete logarithm</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In this paper we consider generic algorithms for computational problems in cyclic groups. The model of a generic algorithm was proposed by Shoup at Eurocrypt u002797. A generic algorithm is a generalpurpose algorithm that does not make use of any particular property of the representation of the group elements. Shoup proved the hardness of the discrete logarithm problem and the Diffie-Hellman problem with respect to such algorithms for groups whose order contains a large prime factor. By extending Shoupu0027s technique we prove lower bounds on the complexity of generic algorithms solving different problems in cyclic groups, and in particular of a generic reduction of the discrete logarithm problem to the Diffie-Hellman problem. It is shown that the two problems are not computationally equivalent in a generic sense for groups whose orders contain a multiple large prime factor. This complements earlier results which stated this equivalence for all other groups. Furthermore, it is shown that no generic algorithm exists that computes p-th roots efficiently in a group whose order is divisible by p2 if p is a large prime.</abstract></paper>