<paper id="1571440521"><title>Applying feature models in industrial settings</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="Corporate Research and Development - FV/SLD" id="2495599671">Andreas Hein</author><author org="Corporate Research and Development - FV/SLD" id="2588175228">Michael Schlick</author><author org="Corporate Research and Development - FV/SLD" id="2276021855">Renato Vinga-Martins</author></authors><n_citation>43</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1503901053</reference><reference>1787802610</reference><reference>2099958466</reference><reference>2114152285</reference><reference>2159765281</reference><reference>2913211075</reference><reference>2914524660</reference></references><venue id="1190643002" type="C">Software Product Lines</venue><doi>10.1007/978-1-4615-4339-8_3</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.51499">Domain analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.40993">Praise</keyword><keyword weight="0.40873">Commission</keyword><keyword weight="0.45957">Software engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.46026">Systems engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.48285">Unified Modeling Language</keyword><keyword weight="0.44406">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Product line</keyword><keyword weight="0.46372">Software</keyword><keyword weight="0.53002">Software product line</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Expressivity</keyword></keywords><publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher><abstract>A software product line is a collection of products sharing a common set of features that address the specific needs of a given business. The PRAISE (product-line realization and assessment in industrial settings) project, partly funded by the European Commission under Esprit contract 28651 and pursued by Thomson-CSF/LCR (France), Robert Bosch GmbH (Germany), and the European Software Institute (Spain), is currently investigating product-line realization and its assessment in industrial settings. A part of the project is dedicated to the validation and consolidation of proposed product-line technologies in full-scale industrial experiments. This paper presents the first experimental results obtained by Bosch. The Bosch experiment is located in the car periphery supervision (CPS) domain. One focus has been on feasibility of variability modeling with feature-oriented domain analysis (FODA. The experiment has shown that the FODA model does not provide the necessary expressiveness to represent the different types of crosslinks that are necessary to describe the domain. This paper presents an extension to overcome this shortcoming.</abstract></paper>