<paper id="19949041"><title>Data flow and data structure modeling for database requirements determination: a comparative study</title><year>1987</year><authors><author org="Univ. Laval, Quebec, Canada#TAB#" id="2343842647">Robert W. Mantha</author></authors><n_citation>18</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>242227645</reference><reference>1584215834</reference><reference>1594158518</reference><reference>2055079566</reference><reference>2066900729</reference><reference>2086229396</reference><reference>2097680763</reference><reference>2120794142</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/248983</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.5656">Data structure</keyword><keyword weight="0.46236">Information retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.45901">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.64652">Logical data model</keyword><keyword weight="0.43511">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.4675">Completeness (statistics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.57323">Data flow diagram</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Requirements determination</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>This study investigated, in an experimental setting, the existence, nature and causes of the differences in the completeness of logical data specifications generated by professional systems analysts having training and experience in the use of one of two modeling approaches. The approach used primarily modeled either the data flows or the data structure of an object system. The systems analysts were asked to analyze a case and to generate logical file specifications which were evaluated for completeness. The results of the study indicate that the data structure analysts produced logical data specifications which contained a greater number of entity views and attributes than those of the data flow analysts. Data flow analysts had greater difficulty with the concepts involved in specifying logical data specifications and consequently derived less complete data specifications than data structure analysts.</abstract></paper>