<paper id="1481882669"><title>The synthesis of digital machines with provable epistemic properties</title><year>1986</year><authors><author org="Stanford, University" id="2194844055">Stanley J. Rosenschein</author><author org="Stanford, University" id="299753924">Leslie Pack Kaelbling</author></authors><n_citation>278</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2009844825</reference><reference>2014471917</reference><reference>2148717074</reference></references><venue id="1190377140" type="C">Theoretical Aspects of Rationality and Knowledge</venue><doi>10.1016/B978-0-934613-04-0.50009-0</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.58683">Epistemic modal logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.49573">Data structure</keyword><keyword weight="0.45486">Information flow (information theory)</keyword><keyword weight="0.45724">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47178">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45708">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.3878">Epistemology</keyword><keyword weight="0.45413">Syntax</keyword><keyword weight="0.46759">Modal</keyword><keyword weight="0.49976">Recursion</keyword></keywords><publisher>Morgan Kaufmann Publishers Inc.</publisher><abstract>Researchers using epistemic logic as a formal framework for studying knowledge properties of AI systems often interpret the knowledge formula K(x, φ) to mean that machine x encodes φ in its state as a syntactic formula or can derive it inferentially. By defining K(x, φ), instead, in terms of the correlation between the state of the machine and that of its environment, the formal properties of modal system S5 can be satisfied without having to store representations of formulas as data structures. In this paper, we apply the correlational definition of knowledge to machines with composite structure. In particular, we describe how epistemic properties of synchronous digital machines can be analyzed, starting at the level of gates and delays, by modeling the machineu0027s components as agents in a multi-agent system and reasoning about the flow of information among them. We also introduce Rex, a language for recursively computing machine descriptions, and illustrate how it can be used to construct machines with provable knowledge properties.</abstract></paper>