<paper id="1482005385"><title>Non-interactive deniable ring authentication</title><year>2003</year><authors><author org="University of Wollongong," id="2114127059">Willy Susilo</author><author org="University of Wollongong," id="2050318273">Yi Mu</author></authors><n_citation>36</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1484826441</reference><reference>1500682127</reference><reference>1610688607</reference><reference>1757910331</reference><reference>1763199136</reference><reference>1788452017</reference><reference>1922219439</reference><reference>2042226948</reference><reference>2102632861</reference><reference>2107561818</reference><reference>2129483619</reference><reference>2143832005</reference><reference>2151413173</reference><reference>2151433956</reference><reference>2153906688</reference><reference>2612336730</reference><reference>2911424200</reference><reference>2911473785</reference></references><venue id="1171774888" type="C">International Conference on Information Security and Cryptology</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-24691-6_29</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.62919">Deniable encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.51646">Authentication</keyword><keyword weight="0.50205">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.42545">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.42964">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.6228">Ring signature</keyword><keyword weight="0.43576">Formal specification</keyword><keyword weight="0.42863">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.51342">Digital signature</keyword><keyword weight="0.44009">Wireless ad hoc network</keyword><keyword weight="0.43539">Special case</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In this paper, we propose a new primitive called non interactive deniable ring authentication: it is possible to convince a verifier that a member of an ad hoc collection of participants is authenticating a message m without revealing which one and the verifier V cannot convince any third party that the message m was indeed authenticated in a non-interactive way. Unlike the deniable ring authentication proposed [19], we require this primitive to be non-interactive. Having this restriction, the primitive can be used in practice without having to use the anonymous routing channel (eg. MIX-nets) introduced [19]. In this paper, we provide the formal definition of non-interactive deniable ring authentication schemes together with a generic construction of such schemes from any ring signature schemes. The generic construction can be used to convert any existing ring signature schemes for example [20, 1], to non-interactive deniable ring authentication schemes. We also present an extension of this idea to allow a non-interactive deniable ring to threshold ring authentication. In this scenario, the signature can convince a group of verifiers, but the verifiers cannot convince any other third party about this fact, because any collusion of t verifiers can always generate a valid message-signature pair. We also present a generic construction of this scheme. A special case of this scenario is a deniable ring-to-ring authentication scheme, where the collaboration of all verifiers is required to generate a valid message-signature pair.</abstract></paper>