<paper id="1974895492"><title>The semantics of Scheme control-flow analysis</title><year>1991</year><authors><author org="School of Computer Science, Carnegie Mellon Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania#TAB#" id="2114688855">Olin Shivers</author></authors><n_citation>58</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>171384505</reference><reference>1979240050</reference><reference>2004971560</reference><reference>2009953498</reference><reference>2043100293</reference><reference>2057085278</reference><reference>2062823821</reference><reference>2095460218</reference><reference>2133979298</reference></references><venue id="1149542749" type="C">Partial Evaluation and Semantic-Based Program Manipulation</venue><doi>10.1145/115866.115884</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47549">Programming language</keyword><keyword weight="0.46355">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.57485">Compile time</keyword><keyword weight="0.66472">Denotational semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.45777">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Formal description</keyword><keyword weight="0.5896">Control flow analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.60773">Programming language theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.58573">Semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.58054">Semantic computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.40968">Government</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>This is a follow-on to my 1988 PLDI paper, "Control-Row Analysis in Scheme" [9]. I use the method of abstract semantic interpretations to explicate the control-flow analysis technique presented in that paper. I begin with a denotational semantics for CPS Scheme. I then present an alternate semantics that precisely expresses the control-flow analysis problem. I abstract this semantics in a natural way, arriving at two different semantic interpretations giving approximate solutions to the flow analysis problem, each computable at compile time. The development of the final abstract semantics provides a clear, formal description of the analysis technique presented in "Control-How Analysis in Scheme." This research was supported in part by the Office of Naval Research and in part by the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DOD), monitored by the Office of Naval Research under Contract N00014-84-K-0415, ARPA Order No. 5404. The views and conclusions contained in this document are those of the author and should not be interpreted as representing the official policies, either expressed or implied, of ONR, DARPA or the U.S. government.</abstract></paper>