<paper id="1985557852"><title>Evaluating expertise recommendations</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="FX Palo Alto Laboratory, Inc., Palo Alto, CA" id="2162252092">David W. McDonald</author></authors><n_citation>69</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>93765870</reference><reference>1480112030</reference><reference>1514499253</reference><reference>1516600607</reference><reference>1966553486</reference><reference>1966992441</reference><reference>1995620802</reference><reference>1999047234</reference><reference>2026917949</reference><reference>2030144199</reference><reference>2043403353</reference><reference>2051766512</reference><reference>2069380438</reference><reference>2083973186</reference><reference>2093432797</reference><reference>2096208837</reference><reference>2100359690</reference><reference>2146660913</reference><reference>2155048531</reference><reference>2155106456</reference><reference>2919963289</reference></references><venue id="2606280534" type="C">International Conference on Supporting Group Work</venue><doi>10.1145/500286.500319</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.55067">Recommender system</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Organizational context</keyword><keyword weight="0.51165">Computer-supported cooperative work</keyword><keyword weight="0.44438">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.4665">Knowledge management</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>Finding a person who has the expertise to solve a specific problem is an important application of recommender systems to a difficult organizational problem. Prior systems have made attempts to implement solutions to this problem, but few systems have undergone systematic user evaluation. This work describes a systematic evaluation of the Expertise Recommender (ER), a system that recommends people who are likely to have expertise in a specific problem. ER and the organizational context for which it was designed are described to provide a basis for understanding this evaluation. Prior to conducting the evaluation, a baseline experiment showed that people are relatively good at judging coworkersu0027 expertise when given an appropriate context. This finding provides a way to demonstrate the effectiveness of ER by comparing ERu0027s performance to ratings by coworkers. The evaluation, the design, and results are described in detail. The results suggest that the participants agree with the recommendations made by ER, and that ER significantly outperforms other expertise recommender systems when compared using similar metrics.</abstract></paper>