<paper id="1536385904"><title>Selective Materialization: An Efficient Method for Spatial Data Cube Construction</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="Simon  Fraser University" id="2121939561">Jiawei Han</author><author org="Simon  Fraser University" id="2110558983">Nebojsa Stefanovic</author><author org="Simon  Fraser University" id="2279782171">Krzysztof Koperski</author></authors><n_citation>135</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1591450657</reference><reference>2044240774</reference><reference>2072764742</reference><reference>2103127236</reference><reference>2103201239</reference><reference>2124199440</reference><reference>2143401113</reference><reference>2150950420</reference></references><venue id="1130985203" type="C">Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-64383-4_13</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.54949">Data warehouse</keyword><keyword weight="0.58918">Spatial analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.45834">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.50212">Geographic information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.4428">Information processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.43635">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.62952">Spatial query</keyword><keyword weight="0.64883">Online analytical processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.65568">Spatial database</keyword><keyword weight="0.44338">Computation</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><abstract>On-line analytical processing (OLAP) has gained its popularity in database industry. With a huge amount of data stored in spatial databases and the introduction of spatial components to many relational or object-relational databases, it is important to study the methods for spatial data warehousing and on-line analytical processing of spatial data. In this paper, we study methods for spatial OLAP, by integration of nonspatial on-line analytical processing (OLAP) methods with spatial database implementation techniques. A spatial data warehouse model, which consists of both spatial and nonspatial dimensions and measures, is proposed. Methods for computation of spatial data cubes and analytical processing on such spatial data cubes are studied, with several strategies proposed, including approximation and partial materialization of the spatial objects resulted from spatial OLAP operations. Some techniques for selective materialization of the spatial computation results are worked out, and the performance study has demonstrated the effectiveness of these techniques.</abstract></paper>