<paper id="1539979035"><title>A Key Distribution Paradox</title><year>1990</year><authors><author org="Bellcore" id="2627905977">Yacov Yacobi</author></authors><n_citation>41</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1519891470</reference><reference>1972792640</reference><reference>1975688140</reference><reference>1996360405</reference><reference>2028907144</reference><reference>2033535959</reference><reference>2057777667</reference><reference>2073210531</reference><reference>2151413173</reference><reference>2156186849</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-38424-3_19</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.56773">Key distribution</keyword><keyword weight="0.60329">Semantic security</keyword><keyword weight="0.6006">Ciphertext indistinguishability</keyword><keyword weight="0.42799">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.43195">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.58094">Chosen-ciphertext attack</keyword><keyword weight="0.56627">One-way function</keyword><keyword weight="0.58989">Threshold cryptosystem</keyword><keyword weight="0.55915">Public-key cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.60607">Key authentication</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The so called, Rabin "paradox" is a proof that a given signature system, which is secure under ciphertext only attack is insecure under chosen message attack. The construction that is used to prove the first clause is also used to prove the second. For several years it was believed to be inherent to public key signature systems. A similar problem existed for public key cryptosystems (under chosen ciphertext attack). Trap-door functions were inherent in the construction of the "paradox."In 1984 Goldwasser, Micali and Rivest constructively showed that one can overcome the "paradox." Naor and Yung (1989) resolved the similar problem for public key cryptosystems. Both solution actually solve two problems. They resolve the "paradox," with the strictest definition of security (for a cryptosystem it amounts to the demand that for a given cryptogram c and two messages m0, m1 it should be infeasible to decide whether c resulted from m0 or m1 with probability significantly greater than half). Both solutions are very complicated.We show that a similar "paradox" exists foT many key distribution systems, even if non-trapdoor one way functions are used (like in the Diffie-Hellrnan variations). Using the simple basic definition of security (given the messages exchanged during the protocol it should be impossible to find the resulting session key in probabilistic polynomial time) we show a simple and practical key distribution system which is provably free of the paradox.</abstract></paper>