<paper id="1492639787"><title>Service selection algorithms for composing complex services with multiple qos constraints</title><year>2005</year><authors><author org="Dept. of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, University of California, Irvine, California" id="2202110290">Tao Yu</author><author org="Dept. of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, University of California, Irvine, California" id="2101757531">Kwei-Jay Lin</author></authors><n_citation>126</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>142750658</reference><reference>1239375374</reference><reference>1505256950</reference><reference>1589571834</reference><reference>1758853865</reference><reference>2103087994</reference><reference>2144651846</reference><reference>2148837283</reference><reference>2179016548</reference></references><venue id="1158589615" type="C">International Conference on Service Oriented Computing</venue><doi>10.1007/11596141_11</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.52126">Graph theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.51002">Service quality</keyword><keyword weight="0.46715">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.44478">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.53826">Quality of service</keyword><keyword weight="0.53647">Combinatorial optimization</keyword><keyword weight="0.50404">Distributed algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.49185">Test case</keyword><keyword weight="0.56889">Knapsack problem</keyword><keyword weight="0.50957">Web service</keyword><keyword weight="0.473">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>One of the promises of the service-oriented architecture (SOA) is that complex services can be composed using individual services. Individual services can be selected and integrated either statically or dynamically based on the service functionalities and performance constraints. For many distributed applications, the runtime performance (e.g. end-to-end delay, cost, reliability and availability) of complex services are very important. In our earlier work, we have studied the service selection problem for complex services with only one QoS constraint. This paper extends the service selection problem to multiple QoS constraints. The problem can be modelled in two ways: the combinatorial model and the graph model. The combinatorial model defines the problem as the multi-dimension multi-choice 0-1 knapsack problem (MMKP). The graph model defines the problem as the multi-constraint optimal path (MCOP) problem. We propose algorithms for both models and study their performances by test cases. We also compare the pros u0026 cons between the two models.</abstract></paper>