<paper id="1984907457"><title>Information loss in three cell-level control techniques for summary tables</title><year>1993</year><authors><author org="Department of Computer Engineering and Science and Center for Automation and Intelligent Systems, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Ohio 44106 U.S.A." id="2012318693">Gultekin Ozsoyoglu</author><author org="Department of Computer Engineering and Science and Center for Automation and Intelligent Systems, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Ohio 44106 U.S.A." id="2394703021">Jiyong Chung</author><author org="Department of Computer Science and Engineering, University of Toledo, Toledo, Ohio 43606 U.S.A." id="2974424348">Tzong-an Su</author></authors><n_citation>1</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>74739834</reference><reference>1505238579</reference><reference>1954820475</reference><reference>2052754975</reference><reference>2065626942</reference><reference>2093467213</reference><reference>2097140886</reference><reference>2113904485</reference><reference>2171673462</reference></references><venue id="192650101" type="J">Information Sciences</venue><doi>10.1016/0020-0255(93)90077-Y</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.49712">Aggregate function</keyword><keyword weight="0.44972">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Information loss</keyword><keyword weight="0.46521">Heuristic</keyword><keyword weight="0.41512">Lattice (order)</keyword><keyword weight="0.51505">Database security</keyword><keyword weight="0.51751">Statistical database</keyword><keyword weight="0.45453">Hypercube</keyword><keyword weight="0.39999">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.42773">Cube</keyword></keywords><publisher>Elsevier</publisher><abstract>Abstract A statistical database (SDB) is a database that provides simple summary statistics (e.g., SUM, COUNT, MAX, MEDIAN, etc.) about individuals in the database and that supports statistical data analysis. When SDB users infer protected information in the SDB from responses to queries, we say that the SDB is compromised. Summary tables are tabular representations of summary data. For a given aggregate function and a set of attributes to specify subsets of individuals in the SDB, all possible summary tables form a lattice. The SDB security problem in the lattice model is defined as preventing the users from obtaining the information that a table element (i.e., cell) is of size one. In this paper, to solve the SDB security problem in the lattice model, we generalize three cell-level control techniques, namely, cell suppression by merging, m -cube, axis merging, into the lattice model. We define the concept of information loss, derive various properties of the minimum information loss, and then investigate the effectiveness of heuristic algorithms for the minimum information loss in each of the three cell-level control techniques.</abstract></paper>