<paper id="1533121298"><title>Multi-channel Attacks</title><year>2003</year><authors><author org="IBM, Watson Research Center" id="2134142736">Dakshi Agrawal</author><author org="IBM, Watson Research Center" id="2114007677">Josyula R. Rao</author><author org="IBM, Watson Research Center" id="2121267894">Pankaj Rohatgi</author></authors><n_citation>96</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1511843316</reference><reference>1519539754</reference><reference>1536508214</reference><reference>1548656471</reference><reference>1613874182</reference><reference>1671031071</reference><reference>1724890242</reference><reference>1897761346</reference><reference>2914572864</reference></references><venue id="1127098075" type="C">Cryptographic Hardware and Embedded Systems</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-45238-6_2</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47455">Power analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.43706">Maximum principle</keyword><keyword weight="0.51514">Information leakage</keyword><keyword weight="0.61256">Robust random early detection</keyword><keyword weight="0.4366">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.44306">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.48953">Cryptanalysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.47357">Communication channel</keyword><keyword weight="0.47236">Electronic countermeasure</keyword><keyword weight="0.57787">Side channel attack</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We introduce multi-channel attacks, i.e., side-channel attacks which utilize multiple side-channels such as power and EM simultaneously. We propose an adversarial model which combines a CMOS leakage model and the maximum-likelihood principle for performing and analyzing such attacks. This model is essential for deriving the optimal and very often counter-intuitive techniques for channel selection and data analysis. We show that using multiple channels is better for template attacks by experimentally showing a three-fold reduction in the error probability. Developing sound countermeasures against multi-channel attacks requires a rigorous leakage assessment methodology. Under suitable assumptions and approximations, our model also yields a practical assessment methodology for net information leakage from the power and all available EM channels in constrained devices such as chip-cards. Classical DPA/DEMA style attacks assume an adversary weaker than that of our model. For this adversary, we apply the maximum-likelihood principle to such design new and more efficient single and multiple-channel DPA/DEMA attacks.</abstract></paper>