<paper id="1543832299"><title>A Hierarchical Spatial Index for Cell Complexes</title><year>1993</year><authors><author org="Elsag Bailey S.p.A. Research and Development" id="2004439588">Elisabetta Bruzzone</author><author org="University of Genova" id="999226360">Leila De Floriani</author><author org="University of Genova" id="2111410040">Monica Pellegrinelli</author></authors><n_citation>6</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1603382969</reference><reference>1931818007</reference><reference>1974381159</reference><reference>2020151400</reference><reference>2022266599</reference><reference>2048095461</reference><reference>2074429597</reference><reference>2075495470</reference><reference>2091791609</reference><reference>2094757725</reference><reference>2124074289</reference><reference>2132675033</reference><reference>2135368250</reference><reference>2145935370</reference></references><venue id="" type="">SSD '93 Proceedings of the Third International Symposium on Advances in Spatial Databases</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-56869-7_7</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.42831">Pattern recognition</keyword><keyword weight="0.45875">Point location</keyword><keyword weight="0.40479">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.44289">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.44874">Subdivision</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.50229">Spatial query</keyword><keyword weight="0.46057">Operator (computer programming)</keyword><keyword weight="0.60354">Cellular decomposition</keyword><keyword weight="0.4584">Recursion</keyword><keyword weight="0.50056">Spatial database</keyword><keyword weight="0.54861">Octree</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>A new hierachical spatial index for object representation schemes based on three-dimensional cell complexes is introduced. We consider a domain consisting of general n-dimensional spatial objects described by n-dimensional cell complexes. The new hierarchical spatial index, called a cellular n-tree, generalizes similar structures developed for planar maps, and is defined as a recursive subdivision of a universe containing the cell complex into regular blocks. Terminal blocks may be completely inside a cell or outside the complex, or may contain indices to sets of cells within the complex. We briefly review the properties of n-dimensional cell complexes, that we call cellular decompositions, and introduce a few basic atomic operators for building them in the three-dimensional case. We shortly describe algorithms for building a cellular octree from a 3D cellular decomposition and for updating the cellular octree, when the cellular decomposition is modified by applying the atomic constructive operators introduced. Algorithms for solving point location and proximity queries on a cellular decomposition with a cellular octree superimposed are presented.</abstract></paper>