<paper id="1591606898"><title>A Comparison of the Resolution Caculus and the Connection Method, and a new Calculus Generalizing Both Methods</title><year>1988</year><authors><author org="Universitat Dortmund" id="2119923813">Elmar Eder</author></authors><n_citation>9</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>17889614</reference></references><venue id="1165958984" type="C">Computer Science Logic</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0026296</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46023">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.43213">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47043">Generalization</keyword><keyword weight="0.59521">Automated theorem proving</keyword><keyword weight="0.59111">Mathematical proof</keyword><keyword weight="0.47901">Calculus</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In this paper a comparison is made of several proof methods used for Automated Theorem Proving. The main emphasis here lies on the comparison of the Resolution and the Connection methods. We compare the lengths and complexities of proofs in the two proof methods and investigate whether and how a proof in one method can be simulated in the other and at which cost with respect to increase of its length. Finally a new calculus is introduced that incorporates both the connection calculus and the resolution calculus. In Section 2 an outline of W. Bibelu0027s connection method is given. The basic calculus of the connection method is presented. In Section 3 we show how any proof in the connection method can be directly simulated step by step in the resolution calculus. In Section 4 it is proved that the reverse is not possible. There is a class of formulas for which the length of the shortest proof in the connection calculus grows superpolynomially with respect to the length of their shortest resolution proof. The two main reasons for this inefficiency are pointed out, the unability of the connection calculus considered here to forget variables</abstract></paper>