<paper id="1527353115"><title>A scientific methodology for MIS case studies</title><year>1989</year><authors><author org="Northeastern Univ. Boston MA" id="2158578300">A. S. Lee</author></authors><n_citation>1105</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1500025880</reference><reference>2013601309</reference><reference>2044779067</reference><reference>2135492276</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/248698</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.50426">Management information systems</keyword><keyword weight="0.53833">Rigour</keyword><keyword weight="0.42362">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.41751">Natural science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46447">Management science</keyword><keyword weight="0.55645">Scientific method</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>A methodology for conducting the case study of a management information system (MIS) is presented. Suitable for the study of a single case, the methodology also satisfies the standard of the natural science model of scientific research.This article provides an overview of the methodological problems involved in the study of a single case, describes scientific method, presents an elucidation of how a previously published MIS case study captures the major features of scientific method, responds to the problems involved in the study of a single case, and summarizes what a scientific methodology for MIS case studies does, and does not, involve.The article also has ramifications that go beyond matters of MIS case studies alone. For MIS researchers, the article might prove interesting for addressing such fundamental issues as whether MIS research must be mathematical, statistical, or quantitative in order to be called "scientific". For MIS practitioners, the articleu0027s view of scientific method might prove interesting for empowering them to identify, for themselves, the pint at which scientific rigor is achieved in an MIS research effort, and beyond which further rigor can be called into question, especially if pursued at the expense of professional relevance.</abstract></paper>