<paper id="1985223393"><title>Properties and update semantics of consistent views</title><year>1988</year><authors><author org="Institute for Applied Mathematics, C.N.R., Genoa, Italy and Stanford Univ., Stanford, CA" id="1873538321">Georg Gottlob</author><author org="Politecnico di Milano, Milan, Italy and A.R.G., Milan, Italy#TAB#" id="2192981890">Paolo Paolini</author><author org="Politecnico di Milano, Milan, Italy and Univ. of California, Berkeley" id="2679634565">Roberto Zicari</author></authors><n_citation>136</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>30253544</reference><reference>52829598</reference><reference>86497608</reference><reference>99115120</reference><reference>1482365409</reference><reference>1483655851</reference><reference>1489772924</reference><reference>1490966766</reference><reference>1496148388</reference><reference>1504393915</reference><reference>1975519850</reference><reference>1979591385</reference><reference>1985867353</reference><reference>1988391412</reference><reference>1991199257</reference><reference>2001623199</reference><reference>2015103436</reference><reference>2026299058</reference><reference>2031445697</reference><reference>2031993032</reference><reference>2035442103</reference><reference>2038524853</reference><reference>2040293060</reference><reference>2054666843</reference><reference>2061850638</reference><reference>2064585098</reference><reference>2081251433</reference><reference>2085528940</reference><reference>2086397699</reference><reference>2111112637</reference><reference>2113582770</reference><reference>2116436709</reference><reference>2124299249</reference><reference>2133384222</reference><reference>2153754624</reference><reference>2162830660</reference><reference>2168787502</reference></references><venue id="90119964" type="J">ACM Transactions on Database Systems</venue><doi>10.1145/49346.50068</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44184">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.43617">Abstraction</keyword><keyword weight="0.52036">Concurrency control</keyword><keyword weight="0.40623">Know-how</keyword><keyword weight="0.53267">Concurrency</keyword><keyword weight="0.45972">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46367">Operator (computer programming)</keyword><keyword weight="0.50115">Functional specification</keyword><keyword weight="0.46879">Semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.43908">Database</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>The problem of translating view updates to database updates is considered. Both databases and views are modeled as data abstractions. A data abstraction consists of a set of states and of a set of primitive update operators representing state transition functions. It is shown how complex update programs can be built from primitive update operators and how view update programs are translated into database update programs. Special attention is paid to a class of views that we call “consistent.” Loosely speaking, a consistent view is a view with the following property: If the effect of a view update program on a view state is determined, then the effect of the corresponding database update is unambiguously determined. Thus, in order to know how to translate a given view update into a database update, it is sufficient to be aware of a functional specification of such a program. We show that consistent views have a number of interesting properties with respect to the concurrency of (high-level) update transactions. Moreover we show that the class of consistent views includes as a subset the class of views that translate updates under maintenance of a constant complement. However, we show that there exist consistent views that do not translate under constant complement. The results of Bancilhon and Spyratos [6] are generalized in order to capture the update semantics of the entire class of consistent views. In particular we show that the class of consistent views is obtained if we relax the requirement of a constant complement by allowing the complement to decrease according to a suitable partial order.</abstract></paper>