<paper id="1826589537"><title>On Component Identification Approaches --- Classification, State of the Art, and Comparison</title><year>2009</year><authors><author org="Component and Service Engineering Group, Business Informatics and Systems Engineering Chair, University of Augsburg, Augsburg, Germany" id="1963734396">Dominik Birkmeier</author><author org="Component and Service Engineering Group, Business Informatics and Systems Engineering Chair, University of Augsburg, Augsburg, Germany" id="2468195161">Sven Overhage</author></authors><n_citation>36</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>86823043</reference><reference>1488814887</reference><reference>1491303215</reference><reference>1501419121</reference><reference>1591726984</reference><reference>1593845965</reference><reference>1594445969</reference><reference>1896185571</reference><reference>1963853349</reference><reference>2108264163</reference><reference>2134119432</reference><reference>2141352548</reference><reference>2142692607</reference><reference>2144804646</reference><reference>2144952577</reference><reference>2166000263</reference><reference>2167500728</reference></references><venue id="1190589269" type="C">Component-Based Software Engineering</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-642-02414-6_1</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Design space</keyword><keyword weight="0.45391">Systems engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.49029">Research question</keyword><keyword weight="0.50306">Business process</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Component type</keyword><keyword weight="0.46417">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Classification scheme</keyword><keyword weight="0.5438">Software development process</keyword><keyword weight="0.50977">Strengths and weaknesses</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Partitioning a design space to identify components with desired non-functional and behavioral characteristics is a crucial task in the component-based software development process. Accordingly, the issue of how to analyze design models in order to systematically derive a set of components constitutes a research question which has been investigated repeatedly. Component identification approaches that have been published in literature, however, make use of different component definitions and identification strategies. Furthermore, they vary from ad-hoc findings and general recommendations to more formalized methods and techniques which aim at an optimized partitioning. In this paper, we elaborate on the state of the art in component identification and provide a classification of approaches that highlights their respective strengths and weaknesses. To classify component identification approaches, we introduce a classification scheme that contains important distinguishing factors. It is used to compare existing approaches which have been compiled during a literature survey. In addition, it provides the basis to discuss significant differences between them and to identify remaining issues which give information about future research directions.</abstract></paper>