<paper id="194823677"><title>An Algebra of Graphs and Graph Rewriting</title><year>1991</year><authors><author org="Universita di Pisa" id="2024647070">Andrea Corradini</author><author org="Universita di Pisa" id="2925215115">Ugo Montanari</author></authors><n_citation>15</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>18076284</reference><reference>1546418577</reference><reference>1574796876</reference><reference>1585801412</reference><reference>1587127227</reference><reference>1587555185</reference><reference>1600820878</reference><reference>1963498955</reference><reference>1984413137</reference><reference>1992353213</reference><reference>2016113382</reference><reference>2120995755</reference><reference>2132179319</reference><reference>2536118580</reference><reference>2911877972</reference><reference>2911887602</reference></references><venue id="" type="">Proceedings of the 4th International Conference on Category Theory and Computer Science</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0013469</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.6096">Graph algebra</keyword><keyword weight="0.47324">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.47176">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.59552">Outerplanar graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.58605">Vertex-transitive graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.60447">Line graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.59213">Graph property</keyword><keyword weight="0.47065">Algebra</keyword><keyword weight="0.58704">Distance-hereditary graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.64547">Graph rewriting</keyword><keyword weight="0.6103">Symmetric graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.41902">Mathematics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In this paper we propose an axiomatization of ‘partially abstract graphs’, i.e., of suitable classes of monomorphisms in a category of graphs, which may be interpreted as graphs having both a concrete part and an abstract part (defined up to isomorphism). Morphisms between pa-graphs are pushout squares. We show that the basic notions of the algebraic theory of graph grammars [Eh79] (instantiated to a suitable category of graphs) can be rephrased in a natural way using partially abstract graphs. The terms of the algebra we propose are built over a small set of operators, including parallel composition, substitution application, and restriction. By equipping the algebra of terms with a categorical structure (arrows are equivalence classes of monadic contexts), we show that there is a full and faithful embedding (with a right adjoint) of the category of partially abstract graphs into the category of (well-formed) terms. This embedding is exploited to show that rewriting (in the sense of term rewriting systems) over this algebra models faithfully the direct derivations of graphs, described by a double pushout construction along the guidelines of [Eh79]. In particular, we show that also graph productions having non-discrete gluing graphs can be represented as term rewrite rules without loss of information, unlike a similar approach proposed in [BC87].</abstract></paper>