<paper id="1673564859"><title>On Affine Invariant Clustering and Automatic Cast Listing in Movies</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="The University of Oxford#TAB#" id="2106076158">Andrew W. Fitzgibbon</author><author org="The University of Oxford#TAB#" id="2469405535">Andrew Zisserman</author></authors><n_citation>130</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1484228140</reference><reference>1566724908</reference><reference>1579142030</reference><reference>1600737329</reference><reference>1958762911</reference><reference>2029727948</reference><reference>2037591004</reference><reference>2088871573</reference><reference>2102909657</reference><reference>2124722975</reference><reference>2137291015</reference><reference>2138835141</reference><reference>2140000690</reference><reference>2140151376</reference><reference>2143902103</reference><reference>2152942156</reference><reference>2158416517</reference><reference>2163301840</reference><reference>2163893325</reference></references><venue id="1124077590" type="C">European Conference on Computer Vision</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-47977-5_20</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.64336">Affine transformation</keyword><keyword weight="0.6204">Fuzzy clustering</keyword><keyword weight="0.65032">Affine shape adaptation</keyword><keyword weight="0.45272">Computer vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.64032">Clustering high-dimensional data</keyword><keyword weight="0.62583">Affine combination</keyword><keyword weight="0.63553">Correlation clustering</keyword><keyword weight="0.43984">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.63451">Cluster analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.61245">Affine hull</keyword><keyword weight="0.44894">Machine learning</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We develop a distance metric for clustering and classification algorithms which is invariant to affine transformations and includes priors on the transformation parameters. Such clustering requirements are generic to a number of problems in computer vision.We extend existing techniques for affine-invariant clustering, and show that the new distance metric outperforms existing approximations to affine invariant distance computation, particularly under large transformations. In addition, we incorporate prior probabilities on the transformation parameters. This further regularizes the solution, mitigating a rare but serious tendency of the existing solutions to diverge. For the particular special case of corresponding point sets we demonstrate that the affine invariant measure we introduced may be obtained in closed form.As an application of these ideas we demonstrate that the faces of the principal cast of a feature film can be generated automatically using clustering with appropriate invariance. This is a very demanding test as it involves detecting and clustering over tens of thousands of images with the variances including changes in viewpoint, lighting, scale and expression.</abstract></paper>