<paper id="1554946552"><title>Graphical user interfaces for business information systems</title><year>1982</year><authors><author org="" id="2160064358">Blake Ives</author></authors><n_citation>118</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1504986418</reference><reference>1531486736</reference><reference>1570858782</reference><reference>1963548951</reference><reference>2108117906</reference><reference>2124233783</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/248990</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.62272">Graphics</keyword><keyword weight="0.53333">Management information systems</keyword><keyword weight="0.60088">Data visualization</keyword><keyword weight="0.45407">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.74512">Graphics software</keyword><keyword weight="0.55969">User interface</keyword><keyword weight="0.69587">Computer graphics</keyword><keyword weight="0.63956">Scientific visualization</keyword><keyword weight="0.46534">Multimedia</keyword><keyword weight="0.55341">Computer technology</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>Proponents of computer graphics foresee them having a dramatic impact on decision maker productivity. The availability of inexpensive graphic computer technology permits organizations to rely extensively on graphics for standard information :[31],"the claims of :[31],"the proponents, however, there is little substantial evidence linking :[31],"the use of graphics with increased management productivity and/or higher quality decisions. Moreover, :[31],"the use of powerful graphics capabilities by end users, unskilled in graphics design, presents :[31],"the likelihood that information presentations will suffer rather than improve as computer generated graphics grow in :[87],"article discusses typical and atypical applications of computer graphics for presenting business information. Existing evidence relating :[31],"the use of graphics with improvements in user productivity is discussed. Much of :[31],"the :[87],"article is focused on computer graphics design within :[31],"the organization including: who should do design, :[31],"the conceptual foundations of good graphics design, and a set of guidelines and cautions applicable to :[31],"the design of quality graphics. The :[87],"article concludes with a list of suggested research topics.</abstract></paper>