<paper id="1979479253"><title>Graph nonisomorphism has subexponential size proofs unless the polynomial-time hierarchy collapses</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="Department of Mathematics, MIT, Cambridge, MA" id="224211078">Adam R. Klivans</author><author org="Department of Computer Science, The University of Chicago, Chicago, IL" id="197743522">Dieter van Melkebeek</author></authors><n_citation>19</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>25285532</reference><reference>178840757</reference><reference>1485836178</reference><reference>1517959386</reference><reference>1530008367</reference><reference>1544226958</reference><reference>1562313898</reference><reference>1566084191</reference><reference>1594883013</reference><reference>1901622511</reference><reference>1907609371</reference><reference>1973322735</reference><reference>1976781283</reference><reference>1998918799</reference><reference>2008671178</reference><reference>2011112377</reference><reference>2019038806</reference><reference>2020114845</reference><reference>2021736779</reference><reference>2024970686</reference><reference>2036265926</reference><reference>2039302045</reference><reference>2041210515</reference><reference>2057512592</reference><reference>2069652878</reference><reference>2069919161</reference><reference>2073136473</reference><reference>2083553352</reference><reference>2096390054</reference><reference>2107324709</reference><reference>2117427692</reference><reference>2129113961</reference><reference>2137407595</reference><reference>2139709458</reference><reference>2148957455</reference><reference>2156184725</reference><reference>2160403361</reference><reference>2162763810</reference><reference>2165676867</reference><reference>2295428206</reference><reference>2611754984</reference><reference>2741390383</reference></references><venue id="1190910084" type="C">Symposium on the Theory of Computing</venue><doi>10.1145/301250.301428</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47596">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.47046">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.59533">Boolean circuit</keyword><keyword weight="0.51074">Polynomial</keyword><keyword weight="0.55713">Nondeterministic algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.43766">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.50503">Satisfiability</keyword><keyword weight="0.50491">Oracle</keyword><keyword weight="0.56098">True quantified Boolean formula</keyword><keyword weight="0.56853">Time complexity</keyword><keyword weight="0.55052">Bounded function</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>We establish hardness versus randomness trade-offs for a broad class of randomized procedures. In particular, we create efficient nondeterministic simulations of bounded round Arthur-Merlin games using a language in exponential time that cannot be decided by polynomial size oracle circuits with access to satisfiability. We show that every language with a bounded round Arthur-Merlin game has subexponential size membership proofs for infinitely many input lengths unless the polynomial-time hierarchy collapses. This provides the first strong evidence that graph nonisomorphism has subexponential size proofs. We set up a general framework for derandomization which encompasses more than the traditional model of randomized computation. For a randomized procedure to fit within this framework, we only require that for any fixed input the complexity of checking whether the procedure succeeds on a given random bit sequence is not too high. We then apply our derandomization technique to four fundamental complexity theoretic constructions: The Valiant-Vazirani random hashing technique which prunes the number of satisfying assignments of a Boolean formula to one, and related procedures like computing satisfying assignments to Boolean formulas non-adaptively given access to an oracle for satisfiability. The algorithm of Bshouty et al. for learning Boolean circuits. Constructing matrices with high rigidity. Constructing polynomial-size universal traversal sequences. We also show that if linear space requires exponential size circuits, then space bounded randomized computations can be simulated deterministically with only a constant factor overhead in space.</abstract></paper>