<paper id="1563938429"><title>Electronic commerce: structures and issues</title><year>1996</year><authors><author org="" id="2502131234">Vladimir Zwass</author></authors><n_citation>635</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>107249574</reference><reference>117811270</reference><reference>1482698170</reference><reference>1483026109</reference><reference>1495405808</reference><reference>1499512608</reference><reference>1515344919</reference><reference>1539624384</reference><reference>1566310586</reference><reference>1604380167</reference><reference>1862276743</reference><reference>1908359675</reference><reference>2008580934</reference><reference>2027251845</reference><reference>2045033074</reference><reference>2088159811</reference><reference>2094006716</reference><reference>2118936359</reference><reference>2119614939</reference><reference>2178030295</reference><reference>2251774999</reference></references><venue id="18436875" type="J">International Journal of Electronic Commerce</venue><doi>10.1080/10864415.1996.11518273</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.66373">Electronic business</keyword><keyword weight="0.38929">Economics</keyword><keyword weight="0.53529">Business information</keyword><keyword weight="0.60924">Electronic data interchange</keyword><keyword weight="0.52849">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.44627">Commerce</keyword><keyword weight="0.4812">Intermediation</keyword><keyword weight="0.55634">Information infrastructure</keyword><keyword weight="0.66646">E-commerce</keyword><keyword weight="0.44231">Marketing</keyword><keyword weight="0.56751">The Internet</keyword></keywords><publisher>M. E. Sharpe, Inc.</publisher><abstract>Electronic commerce (E-commerce) is sharing business information, maintaining business relationships, and conducting business transactions by means of telecommunications networks. Traditional E-commerce, conducted with the use of information technologies centering on electronic data interchange (EDI) over proprietary value-added networks, is rapidly moving to the Internet. The Internetu0027s World Wide Web has become the prime driver of contemporary E-commerce. This paper presents a hierarchical framework of E-commerce, consisting of three meta-levels: infrastructure, services, and products and structures, which, in turn, consist of seven functional levels. These levels of E-commerce development, as well as of analysis, range from the wide-area telecommunications infrastructure to electronic marketplaces and electronic hierarchies enabled by E-commerce. Several nodal problems are discussed that will define future development in E-commerce, including integrating electronic payment into the buying process, building a consumer marketplace, the governance of electronic business, and the new intermediation. The paper also introduces the International Journal of Electronic Commerce, which will provide an integrated view of the new E-commerce.</abstract></paper>