<paper id="1559179949"><title>Viewpoints: principles, problems and a practical approach to requirements engineering</title><year>1997</year><authors><author org="Computing Department, Lancaster University, Lancaster LA1 4YR, UK#TAB#" id="2093398104">Ian Sommerville</author><author org="Computing Department, Lancaster University, Lancaster LA1 4YR, UK#TAB#" id="2133238635">Pete Sawyer</author></authors><n_citation>191</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1734354652</reference><reference>1976028377</reference><reference>1989160441</reference><reference>1990090837</reference><reference>1996756475</reference><reference>2044301784</reference><reference>2046795207</reference><reference>2105603754</reference><reference>2115937516</reference><reference>2120248232</reference><reference>2130493984</reference><reference>2135920852</reference><reference>2138782822</reference><reference>2148611855</reference><reference>2152954823</reference><reference>2912885751</reference></references><venue id="104191512" type="J">Annals of Software Engineering</venue><doi>10.1023/A:1018946223345</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46803">Systems engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.45598">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.52861">Viewpoints</keyword><keyword weight="0.51843">Quality function deployment</keyword><keyword weight="0.69744">Requirements engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.63962">Requirements analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.63514">Requirements elicitation</keyword><keyword weight="0.63968">Requirement</keyword><keyword weight="0.62988">Non-functional requirement</keyword><keyword weight="0.59859">Software requirements</keyword></keywords><publisher>J. C. Baltzer AG, Science Publishers</publisher><abstract>The paper includes a survey and discussion of viewpointdoriented approaches to requirements engineering and a presentation of new work in this area which has been designed with practical application in mind. We describe the benefits of viewpointdoriented requirements engineering and describe the strengths and weaknesses of a number of viewpointdoriented methods. We discuss the practical problems of introducing viewpointdoriented requirements engineering into industrial software engineering practice and why these have prevented the widespread use of existing :[76],"then introduce a new model of viewpoints called Preview. Preview viewpoints are flexible, generic entities which can be used in different ways and in different application domains. We describe the novel characteristics of the Preview viewpoints model and the associated processes of requirements discovery, analysis and negotiation. Finally, we discuss how well this approach addresses some outstanding problems in requirements engineering (RE) and the practical industrial problems of introducing new requirements engineering methods.</abstract></paper>