<paper id="1593411550"><title>Specifying Quality Characteristics and Attributes for Websites</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="UNLPam" id="2109584776">Luis Olsina</author><author org="LIFIA, Informatics School at UNLP" id="2141279370">Guillermo Lafuente</author><author org="LIFIA, Informatics School at UNLP" id="2119015089">Gustavo Rossi</author></authors><n_citation>140</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1487272950</reference><reference>1607809203</reference><reference>2089470434</reference><reference>2112140746</reference><reference>2337675690</reference></references><venue id="106296714" type="J">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-45144-7_26</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47414">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.52426">Ranking</keyword><keyword weight="0.45995">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.49653">Visitor pattern</keyword><keyword weight="0.45431">Product lifecycle</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Web site</keyword><keyword weight="0.53372">The Internet</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In this work, we outline more than a hundred characteristics and attributes for the domain of academic sites in order to analyze the quality requirement tree and a way to specify them. These elements are used in a quantitative methodology for assessment, comparison, and ranking processes. The proposed Web-site Quality Evaluation Methodology (QEM) can be a useful approach to assess the quality in different phases of a Web product life cycle. In the academic study, we have observed three different evaluation audiences regarding visitor users: current and prospective students, academic personnel, and research sponsors. Besides, the aim of this work is to show a hierarchical and descriptive specification framework for characteristics, subcharacteristics and attributes. This framework is a key underlying piece in the construction of a hyperdocumented evaluation tool. Finally, some results are presented and concluding remarks are discussed.</abstract></paper>