<paper id="1512766599"><title>Augmenting concept languages by transitive closure of roles: an alternative to terminological cycles</title><year>1991</year><authors><author org="German Research Center for Artificial Intelligence, Kaiserslautem, Germany" id="2037598615">Franz Baader</author></authors><n_citation>145</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1484873633</reference><reference>1496545610</reference><reference>1527818723</reference><reference>1936956611</reference><reference>1989040088</reference><reference>1989913409</reference><reference>2057513565</reference><reference>2093584016</reference><reference>2155246250</reference><reference>2159525276</reference><reference>2175140350</reference></references><venue id="1203999783" type="C">International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence</venue><doi>10.22028/D291-24902</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.42972">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.44324">Algebra</keyword><keyword weight="0.51488">Negation</keyword><keyword weight="0.43009">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.42423">Pure mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.45852">Operator (computer programming)</keyword><keyword weight="0.60555">Transitive closure</keyword><keyword weight="0.50709">Semantics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Morgan Kaufmann Publishers Inc.</publisher><abstract>In Baader (1990,1990a), we have considered different types of semantics for terminologicial cycles in the concept language TLQ which allows only conjunction of concepts and value-restrictions. It turned out that greatest fixed-point semantics (gfp-semantics) seems to be most appropriate for cycles in this language. In the present paper we shall show that the concept defining facilities of FLO with cyclic definitions and gfp-semantics can also be obtained in a different way. One may replace cycles by role definitions involving union, composition, and transitive closure of :[85],"proposes a way of retaining, in an extended language, the pleasant features of gfp-semantics for FLQ with cyclic definitions without running into the troubles caused by cycles in larger languages. Starting with the language ALC of Schmidt-Schausu0026Smolka (1988)--which allows negation, conjunction and disjunction of concepts as well as value-restrictions and exists-in-restrictions--we shall disallow cyclic concept definitions, but instead shall add the possibility of role definitions involving union, composition, and transitive closure of roles. In contrast to other terminological KR-systems which incorporate the transitive closure operator for roles, we shall be able to give a sound and complete algorithm for concept subsumption.</abstract></paper>