<paper id="1579904842"><title>Local Views on Distributed Systems and Their Communication</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="INTERNATIONAL COMPUTER SCIENCE INSTITUTE" id="2124762606">Ingrid Fischer</author><author org="Technical University of Berlin" id="2107774731">Manuel Koch</author><author org="Technical University of Berlin" id="1978163079">Gabriele Taentzer</author></authors><n_citation>8</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1512007370</reference><reference>2039242922</reference></references><venue id="" type="">TAGT'98 Selected papers from the 6th International Workshop on Theory and Application of Graph Transformations</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-46464-8_12</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.534">Asynchronous communication</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.54669">Operational semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.4724">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45648">Grammar</keyword><keyword weight="0.47658">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.49526">Local system</keyword><keyword weight="0.62514">Distributed algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.61782">Graph rewriting</keyword><keyword weight="0.47328">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Distributed graph transformation has been used to specify static as well as dynamic aspects of distributed systems. To support distributed designs by different developers, local views are introduced. A local view on a distributed system consists of one local system, its import and export interfaces, and connected remote interfaces. The behavior of a local system is specified by a set of graph rules that are applicable only to the local view of the local system. Local systems communicate either synchronously or asynchronously via their import and export interfaces. Asynchronous communication is modeled by sequential application of graph rules, synchronous communication by the amalgamation of graph rules. We compose a distributed system grammar from the rule sets for local systems. The operational semantics of the distributed system is given by distributed transformation sequences.</abstract></paper>