<paper id="1543010140"><title>Timing analysis of asynchronous circuits using timed automata</title><year>1995</year><authors><author org="Miniparc-zirst" id="694493417">Oded Maler</author><author org="Weizmann Institute,#TAB#" id="2171343426">Amir Pnueli</author></authors><n_citation>76</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1482233117</reference><reference>1529059198</reference><reference>1562169374</reference><reference>1569051713</reference><reference>1981808971</reference><reference>2004463571</reference><reference>2093964259</reference><reference>2101508170</reference><reference>2117511231</reference><reference>2130773092</reference><reference>2142091551</reference><reference>2151612633</reference><reference>2152744148</reference><reference>2176837466</reference></references><venue id="" type="">CHARME '95 Proceedings of the IFIP WG 10.5 Advanced Research Working Conference on Correct Hardware Design and Verification Methods</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-60385-9_12</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.49013">Boolean function</keyword><keyword weight="0.53646">Asynchronous communication</keyword><keyword weight="0.50888">Digital electronics</keyword><keyword weight="0.43921">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.50455">Automaton</keyword><keyword weight="0.50306">Reachability</keyword><keyword weight="0.44876">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.53601">Static timing analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.71593">Timed automaton</keyword><keyword weight="0.45808">Verifiable secret sharing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer Berlin Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In this paper we present a method for modeling asynchronous digital circuits by timed automata. The constructed timed automata serve as “mechanical” and verifiable objects for asynchronous sequential machines in the same sense that (untimed) automata do for synchronous machines. These results, combined with recent results concerning the analysis and synthesis of timed automata provide for the systematic Treatment of a large class of problems that could be treated by conventional simulation methods only in an ad-hoc fashion. The problems that can be solved due to the results presented in this paper include: the reachability analysis of a circuit with uncertainties in gate delays and input arrival times, inferring the necessary timing constraints on input signals that guarantee a proper functioning of a circuit and calculating the delay characteristics of the components required in order to meet some given behavioral specifications.</abstract></paper>