<paper id="1487614255"><title>Domain Knowledge-Based Automatic Workflow Generation</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="Rutgers University" id="2170702075">Soon Ae Chun</author><author org="Rutgers University" id="2100792061">Vijayalakshmi Atluri</author><author org="Rutgers University" id="2300106300">Nabil R. Adam</author></authors><n_citation>48</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1511461976</reference><reference>1574901384</reference><reference>1595655245</reference><reference>1610745951</reference><reference>1909893457</reference><reference>1996983098</reference><reference>2015234709</reference><reference>2020233318</reference><reference>2067609246</reference><reference>2133109597</reference></references><venue id="1192664773" type="C">Database and Expert Systems Applications</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-46146-9_9</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.73203">Workflow technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.56584">Domain knowledge</keyword><keyword weight="0.56452">Business process</keyword><keyword weight="0.46453">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.68052">Windows Workflow Foundation</keyword><keyword weight="0.65904">XPDL</keyword><keyword weight="0.74489">Workflow engine</keyword><keyword weight="0.65297">Workflow</keyword><keyword weight="0.73418">Workflow management system</keyword><keyword weight="0.45854">Database</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><abstract>The traditional workflow design paradigm relies heavily on humans who statically specify business processes. However, such a manual design approach is not suitable for many cases: (a) Inter-agency work-flows that cross autonomous organizational boundaries require experts who possess knowledge required for defining workflows composed of services from the constituent organizations; (b) Customized workflows that require many variations make it infeasible and error-prone to predefine the complex workflow in advance. This paper presents an alternative design paradigm that allows automatic on-the-fly generation of a workflow schema. This dynamically integrated workflow composition approach utilizes conceptual ontologies of domain services (tasks) and domain integration knowledge that serves as a model for workflow integration (composition) rules. It also uses user profiles (preferences) as part of (transient) compositional rule base. We present a prototype system for "registering a new business" in the State of New Jersey that implements this automatic workflow design methodology.</abstract></paper>