<paper id="1942766326"><title>Grids as production computing environments: the engineering aspects of NASA's Information Power Grid</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="Numerical Aerosp. Simulation Div., NASA Ames Res. Center, Moffett Field, CA, USA" id="2424667166">W.E. Johnston</author><author org="(Indiana University)" id="2167405706">D. Gannon</author><author org="NASA" id="2310488852">B. Nitzberg</author></authors><n_citation>162</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1510543252</reference><reference>1644882639</reference><reference>1989377994</reference><reference>2091257550</reference><reference>2111996486</reference></references><venue id="1141854641" type="C">High Performance Distributed Computing</venue><doi>10.1109/HPDC.1999.805298</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.63342">Grid computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.45111">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.56019">Distributed design patterns</keyword><keyword weight="0.51627">Distributed algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.61667">Utility computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.5279">Data management</keyword><keyword weight="0.52552">Grid</keyword><keyword weight="0.54537">Distributed management</keyword><keyword weight="0.45612">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.56471">Cloud computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><abstract>Information Power Grid (IPG) is the name of NASAu0027s project to build a fully distributed computing and data management environment-a Grid. The IPG project has near, medium, and long-term goals that represent a continuum of engineering, development, and research topics. The overall goal is to provide the NASA scientific and engineering communities a substantial increase in their ability to solve problems that depend on use of large-scale and/or dispersed resources: aggregated computing, diverse data archives, laboratory instruments and engineering test facilities, and human collaborators. The approach involves infrastructure and services than can locate, aggregate, integrate, and manage resources from across the NASA enterprise. An important aspect of IPG is to produce a common view of these resources, and at the same time provide for distributed management and local control. In addition to addressing the overall goal of enhanced science and engineering, there is a potential important side effect. With a large collection of resources that have common use interfaces and a common management approach, the potential exists for a considerable pool of computing capability that could relatively easily, for example, be called on in extraordinary situations such as crisis response.</abstract></paper>