<paper id="1590165779"><title>Examining the shareholder wealth effects of announcements of newly created CIO positions</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="Washington State University, Pullman WA#TAB#" id="2127609075">Debabroto Chatterjee</author><author org="University of Kansas Lawrence KS" id="1966094467">Vernon J. Richardson</author><author org="Univ of Oklahoma, Norman, OK" id="101071923">Robert W. Zmud</author></authors><n_citation>292</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1494802451</reference><reference>1526421749</reference><reference>1534734121</reference><reference>1562922706</reference><reference>1605836707</reference><reference>1966809117</reference><reference>2012124698</reference><reference>2013593749</reference><reference>2122224612</reference><reference>2122593986</reference><reference>2171272451</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/3250958</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.52831">Corporate governance</keyword><keyword weight="0.50017">Empirical evidence</keyword><keyword weight="0.51435">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.3797">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Top management</keyword><keyword weight="0.57087">Information technology management</keyword><keyword weight="0.50965">Event study</keyword><keyword weight="0.53882">Shareholder</keyword><keyword weight="0.46582">Marketing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>While information technology (IT) has been transforming the business landscape for a long time now, it is only recently that empirical evidence demonstrating the positive impact of IT on firm performance has begun to accumulate. The strategic importance of a firmu0027s IT capabilities is prompting an increasing number of companies to appoint chief information officers (CIOs) to effectively manage these assets. Such moves are reflective of changes in top management thinking and policy regarding the role of IT and firmsu0027 approaches to IT governance. This paper uses the event study methodology to examine market reactions to announcements of new CIO positions. Findings strongly support the notion that, for firms competing in industries undergoing IT-driven transformation, announcements of newly created CIO positions do indeed provoke positive reactions from the marketplace.</abstract></paper>