<paper id="1480443256"><title>Domain-Specific Runtime Variability in Product Line Architectures</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="University of Essen" id="2250860430">Michael Goedicke</author><author org="University of Essen" id="2108763669">Klaus Pohl</author><author org="University of Essen" id="2344120076">Uwe Zdun</author></authors><n_citation>12</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1554977156</reference><reference>1587517569</reference><reference>1825558883</reference><reference>1843304713</reference><reference>1965013462</reference><reference>1967246009</reference><reference>2407682414</reference><reference>2464949168</reference></references><venue id="106296714" type="J">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-46102-7_41</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.50115">Multimedia Home Platform</keyword><keyword weight="0.49496">Indirection</keyword><keyword weight="0.46086">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48742">Subject-matter expert</keyword><keyword weight="0.65123">Software product line</keyword><keyword weight="0.4872">Modular design</keyword><keyword weight="0.54961">Software architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.53462">Software development</keyword><keyword weight="0.46466">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.53323">Personalization</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>A software product line primarily structures the software architecture around the commonalities of a set of products within a specific organization. Common alities can be implemented in prefabricated components, and product differences are typically treated by well-defined variation points that are actualized later on. Dyna mic, domain-specific aspects, such as ad hoc customization by domian experts, are hard to model with static extension techniques. In this paper, we will discuss open issues for dynamic and domain-specific customizations of product line architectures. We will also present an indirection architecture based on Component Wrapper objects and message redirection for dynamically composing and customizing generic components for the use in concrete products. As a case study, we will discuss two designs from a Multimedia Home Platform product line: end-user personalization across different new media platforms and customization of interactive applications by content editors.</abstract></paper>