<paper id="1547409410"><title>On the Relationship of CCS and CSP</title><year>1983</year><authors><author org="Carnegie - Mellon University#TAB#" id="2115786145">Stephen D. Brookes</author></authors><n_citation>71</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1589421353</reference><reference>1883772204</reference><reference>2102097307</reference><reference>2107733072</reference><reference>2110287808</reference><reference>2110425399</reference><reference>2140919105</reference><reference>2147169623</reference></references><venue id="1141821850" type="C">International Colloquium on Automata, Languages and Programming</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0036899</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.43299">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.57286">Equivalence relation</keyword><keyword weight="0.45529">Notation</keyword><keyword weight="0.47916">Concurrency</keyword><keyword weight="0.48848">Axiom</keyword><keyword weight="0.42214">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.55078">Communicating sequential processes</keyword><keyword weight="0.61203">Calculus of communicating systems</keyword><keyword weight="0.43939">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.57388">Equivalence (measure theory)</keyword><keyword weight="0.63539">Process calculus</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>This paper compares two models of concurrency, Milneru0027s Calculus of Communicating Systems (CCS) and the failures model of Communicating Sequential Processes (CSP) developed by Hoare, Brookes and Roscoe. By adapting Milneru0027s synchronisation trees to serve as notation for both CCS and CSP, we are able to define a representation mapping for CSP processes. We define an equivalence relation on synchronisation trees which corresponds precisely to the notion of failure equivalence. Milneru0027s calculus is founded on a different notion, observation equivalence. We show how these two equivalences are related. Just as Milneru0027s equivalence can be characterised as the smallest relation satisfying a set of axioms, we find a suitable set of axioms for the failures equivalence relation. This again makes explicit the differences between the two systems, as well as revealing that the semantic models underlying CCS and CSP are comparable.</abstract></paper>