<paper id="1525139965"><title>A loosely coupled interface to an object-oriented geographic database</title><year>1995</year><authors><author org="Cedric CNAM" id="1995152578">Jean Paul Peloux</author><author org="CEDRIC, CNAM#TAB#" id="2124612568">Philippe Rigaux</author></authors><n_citation>6</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1491937094</reference><reference>1528311867</reference><reference>1533694765</reference><reference>1547485590</reference><reference>1562735428</reference><reference>1588194222</reference><reference>1590655251</reference><reference>1605657873</reference><reference>1945128294</reference><reference>2161109697</reference></references><venue id="1169227017" type="C">Conference On Spatial Information Theory</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-60392-1_9</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44997">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.6356">Query language</keyword><keyword weight="0.46981">Programming language</keyword><keyword weight="0.51397">Open architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.52345">Object-oriented programming</keyword><keyword weight="0.45947">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.54859">Logical data model</keyword><keyword weight="0.54993">Graphical user interface</keyword><keyword weight="0.6307">Spatial query</keyword><keyword weight="0.52101">Software architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.57786">Spatial database</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Communication between end-users and spatial databases raises important and specific issues. Unlike classical systems, it requires strong cooperation between two major tools: spatial query language and graphical interface. This paper addresses the problem of building an interactive querying system for spatial databases with an open architecture. We focus on the following issues: (i) design of a database-independent Graphical User Interface (GUI) providing query expression support and advanced user-database interaction functionnalities (ii) software architecture for dealing with exchanges between the database logical representation and a graphical representation at the interface level (iii) implementation of spatial data and functionnalities within a DBMS without requiring changes in the logical data model or query language syntax. We present a prototype coupling the O2 DBMS, its query language O2Sql, and C++/X-Window-based toolkits as graphical components for the interface implementation.</abstract></paper>