<paper id="1683908335"><title>Early quantification and partitioned transition relations</title><year>1996</year><authors><author org="Dept. of Electr. Eng. and Comput. Sci., California Univ., Berkeley, CA, USA" id="2135689897">R. Hojati</author><author org="" id="2423642938">S.C. Krishnan</author><author org="" id="2038038819">R.K. Brayton</author></authors><n_citation>59</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>164685601</reference><reference>1503973138</reference><reference>2029448190</reference><reference>2080267935</reference><reference>2107385565</reference><reference>2113251992</reference><reference>2137331557</reference><reference>2138436751</reference><reference>2149479807</reference></references><venue id="1186985151" type="C">International Conference on Computer Design</venue><doi>10.1109/ICCD.1996.563525</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.51975">Heuristic</keyword><keyword weight="0.45113">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.57187">Binary decision diagram</keyword><keyword weight="0.52869">Binary tree</keyword><keyword weight="0.46884">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.47097">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.55613">Finite-state machine</keyword><keyword weight="0.4851">Multiplication</keyword><keyword weight="0.56916">Graph bandwidth</keyword><keyword weight="0.5061">Formal verification</keyword><keyword weight="0.56918">Computational complexity theory</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><abstract>Hardware systems are generally specified as a set of interacting finite state machines (FSMs). An important problem in formal verification using Binary Decision Diagrams (BDDs) is forming the transition relation of the product machine. This problem reduces to conjuncting (or multiplying) the BDDs representing the transition relations of the individual machines, and then existentially quantifying out the set of input and output variables. The resulting graph is called the product graph. Computing the set of reachable states of the product graph is the central verification problem. In this paper, we discuss two related problems. The early quantification problem is the problem of interleaving multiplication of a set of BDDs with the quantification of a set of variables so that the size of the largest BDD encountered is minimized. We show that an abstraction of this problem is NP-complete, and provide heuristic solutions for it. In some cases, the size of the BDD representing the transition relation of the product graph is too large. The partitioned transition relations problem deals with partially combining the BDDu0027s and quantifying as many variables as possible, so that the time for computing the set of reachable states of the product graph is minimized. We offer heuristic solutions to this problem based on our algorithms for early quantification. The algorithms have been implemented and good experimental results have been achieved.</abstract></paper>