<paper id="1545394216"><title>Global enterprise resource planning implementation</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="Bus. Sch., Manchester Univ., UK" id="2171059931">C.P. Holland</author><author org="University of Manchester" id="2101865476">B. Light</author></authors><n_citation>82</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2092013815</reference><reference>2100867954</reference><reference>2126762059</reference><reference>2141898774</reference><reference>2152632927</reference></references><venue id="1164519180" type="C">Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences</venue><doi>10.1109/HICSS.1999.772762</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.49926">Multinational corporation</keyword><keyword weight="0.56742">Enterprise resource planning</keyword><keyword weight="0.57185">Enterprise software</keyword><keyword weight="0.40961">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.5168">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.4765">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.58546">Human resource management system</keyword><keyword weight="0.58271">Enterprise planning system</keyword><keyword weight="0.48888">Globalization</keyword><keyword weight="0.54976">Strategic planning</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>The globalisation of markets is having a profound effect on business and information technology strategies of individual organisations. The move away from nationally focused business units to a global product-market focus requires an effective international coordination of a firmu0027s activities. To support a global outlook, many firms are implementing enterprise resource planning (ERP) systems. Although ERP has become the de facto standard for international organisations there are few documented examples of implementation. This paper seeks to make a contribution to this important area. A case study analysis of the strategic context and implementation of a global ERP project in a multinational textiles group is presented. It illustrates the transformation of a conglomerate of nationally organised businesses into a pan-European organisation. The case analysis demonstrates the organisational and technical complexity of ERP implementation and identifies the factors that determined the total cost of the system. Opportunities for future research are outlined.</abstract></paper>