<paper id="1571245733"><title>On the power of cooperative concurrency</title><year>1988</year><authors><author org="The Weizmann Institute of Science Rehovot, Israel" id="104298892">Doron Drusinsky</author><author org="The Weizmann Institute of Science Rehovot, Israel" id="427806604">David Harel</author></authors><n_citation>21</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>196640945</reference><reference>1964845238</reference><reference>1982129592</reference><reference>1986188250</reference><reference>2026191634</reference><reference>2034243894</reference><reference>2039529128</reference><reference>2054801208</reference><reference>2064650227</reference><reference>2090921231</reference><reference>2094912129</reference><reference>2099529102</reference><reference>2110425399</reference><reference>2113355185</reference><reference>2137865376</reference><reference>2184717506</reference></references><venue id="1145706541" type="C">International Conference on Concurrency Theory</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-50403-6_34</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45129">Exponential function</keyword><keyword weight="0.52244">Petri net</keyword><keyword weight="0.6231">Concurrency</keyword><keyword weight="0.55921">Succinctness</keyword><keyword weight="0.43983">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.53214">Upper and lower bounds</keyword><keyword weight="0.45263">Parallel computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.46144">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.51581">Finite-state machine</keyword><keyword weight="0.52686">Turing machine</keyword><keyword weight="0.44078">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.47544">Alternation (linguistics)</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The framework of finite-state systems is used to investigate the relative power of three fundamental notions: nondeterminism and pure parallelism, the two facets of alternation, and cooperative concurrency, whereby configurations consist of states between which communication can occur. To formalize cooperative concurrency, which appears to be the closest finite-state analog to real-world distributed concurrency, we use the recent statecharts, though our results hold for many other approaches, such as Petri nets, CSP or CCS. We exhibit an exhaustive set of upper and lower bounds on the ability to inter-simulate these features over Σ*, and an almost exhaustive set for the Σω case, establishing that (a) each of the three features represents an exponential saving in succinctness of the representation, in a manner that is independent of the other two and additive with respect to them, and (b) of the three, cooperative concurrency is the strongest, representing a similar exponential saving when it is substituted for each of the others. For example, we prove an exponential lower bound on the simulation of deterministic statecharts by AFAs and a triple-exponential lower bound on the simulation of alternating statecharts by DFAs.</abstract></paper>