<paper id="1505389040"><title>Towards a formal integrated model of collaborative healthcare workflows</title><year>2011</year><authors><author org="UNU/IIST, Macau#TAB#" id="1978273152">Cristiano Bertolini</author><author org="UNU/IIST, Macau#TAB#" id="2085044985">Martin Schäf</author><author org="UNU-IIST, Macau,Dept. of Informatics, University of Oslo, Norway#TAB#" id="1925871413">Volker Stolz</author></authors><n_citation>20</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>142659957</reference><reference>175157178</reference><reference>1503973138</reference><reference>2024034783</reference><reference>2110425399</reference><reference>2129466958</reference><reference>2130825897</reference><reference>2131918784</reference><reference>2144179633</reference><reference>2159181605</reference><reference>2568081765</reference></references><venue id="" type="">FHIES'11 Proceedings of the First international conference on Foundations of Health Informatics Engineering and Systems</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-642-32355-3_4</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46214">Systems engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.47596">Software engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.52412">Unified Modeling Language</keyword><keyword weight="0.46222">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.53405">Separation of concerns</keyword><keyword weight="0.47451">Graphical model</keyword><keyword weight="0.45418">Health informatics</keyword><keyword weight="0.52497">Process calculus</keyword><keyword weight="0.50251">Workflow</keyword><keyword weight="0.49183">Semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.54692">Formal verification</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Health information systems (HIS) are becoming increasingly integrated through network communication technologies. Collaborative healthcare workflows (CHWF) are inherently complex, involving interactions among human actors, and (legacy) digital and physical systems. They are mission safety critical, privacy sensitive, and open to changes of requirements and environments. The complexity makes the definition, understanding, analysis, management, and monitoring of CHWF a software engineering challenge. We propose an approach to formal modeling and analysis of CHWF. The main problems that the approach addresses are abstraction and separation of concerns through algebraic manipulation. We use the CSP process algebra for modeling and verifying the dynamic interaction behavior of processes, and discuss the relation between the dynamic model and the static model of healthcare cases and resources. We use UML models to visualize the systemu0027s behavior and structure, but definitions of the syntax and semantics of these graphical models and their relation to the CSP models are left for future work.</abstract></paper>