<paper id="1977220278"><title>A Methodology for Using a Default and Abductive Reasoning System</title><year>1989</year><authors><author org="Department of Computer Science, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, B.C., Canada, V6T 1W5" id="2066970836">David Poole</author></authors><n_citation>84</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>100105580</reference><reference>203924617</reference><reference>1489174353</reference><reference>1534361892</reference><reference>1575798436</reference><reference>1784061619</reference><reference>1966552757</reference><reference>1976303542</reference><reference>1983382292</reference><reference>1998363560</reference><reference>1999410326</reference><reference>2020153579</reference><reference>2029246084</reference><reference>2052222137</reference><reference>2061560303</reference><reference>2072291277</reference><reference>2105505307</reference><reference>2108309071</reference><reference>2140627345</reference><reference>2144386448</reference><reference>2147096558</reference><reference>2155322595</reference></references><venue id="57950554" type="J">International Journal of Intelligent Systems</venue><doi>10.1002/int.4550050506</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47608">Normality</keyword><keyword weight="0.60526">Default logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.56639">Semantic reasoner</keyword><keyword weight="0.43553">Convention</keyword><keyword weight="0.45882">Default</keyword><keyword weight="0.45758">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.50534">If and only if</keyword><keyword weight="0.61612">Abductive reasoning</keyword><keyword weight="0.58387">Reasoning system</keyword><keyword weight="0.44751">Machine learning</keyword><keyword weight="0.39876">Mathematics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Wiley</publisher><abstract>This paper investigates two different activities that involve making assumptions: predicting what one expects to be true and explaining observations. In a companion paper, a logic-based architecture for both prediction and explanation is proposed and an implementation is outlined. In this paper, we show how such a hypothetical reasoning system can be used to solve recognition, diagnostic and prediction problems. As part of this is the assumption that the default reasoner must be ``programmedu0027u0027u0027u0027 to get the right answer and it is not just a matter of ``stating what is trueu0027u0027u0027u0027 and hoping the system will magically find the right answer. A number of distinctions have been found in practice to be important: between predicting whether something is expected to be true versus explaining why it is true; and between conventional defaults (assumptions as a communication convention), normality defaults (assumed for expediency) and conjectures (assumed only if there is evidence). The effects of these distinctions on recognition and prediction problems are presented. Examples from a running system are given.</abstract></paper>