<paper id="1813719546"><title>A Linear Local Model Checking Algorithm for CTL</title><year>1993</year><authors><author org="K. U.Leuven" id="2169121438">Bart Vergauwen</author><author org="K. U.Leuven" id="2574432194">Johan Lewi</author></authors><n_citation>43</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1490526406</reference><reference>1501794589</reference><reference>1520238628</reference><reference>1550474961</reference><reference>1607877490</reference><reference>1765381916</reference><reference>1992582873</reference><reference>2002570665</reference><reference>2012841134</reference><reference>2015640848</reference><reference>2057260173</reference><reference>2075662707</reference><reference>2090398333</reference><reference>2117189826</reference><reference>2171536993</reference></references><venue id="1145706541" type="C">International Conference on Concurrency Theory</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-57208-2_31</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.55088">Transition system</keyword><keyword weight="0.61632">Computation tree logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.58298">Abstraction model checking</keyword><keyword weight="0.44063">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.61357">Model checking</keyword><keyword weight="0.43548">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.53265">Concurrency</keyword><keyword weight="0.56123">Probabilistic CTL</keyword><keyword weight="0.46013">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.57595">Linear temporal logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.45248">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.52831">Time complexity</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Transition systems play a central role as formal models for reactive and concurrent systems. A promising technique for automatically verifying transition systems is model checking. In the model-theoretic approach one mechanically determines whether a given transition system S0 meets a specification f by checking whether S0 is a model for f. In this paper Computation Tree Logic, a form of branching time temporal logic, is used as a specification tool. The paper presents a local model checking algorithm ALMC for CTL. Given a system state S0 (typically the initial system state) and a CTL formula S0, algorithm ALMC mechanically checks whether S0 satisfies formula S0. ALMC has time complexity linear in both the size of the system and the size of the formula to be checked. Furthermore ALMC is goal-oriented, i.e., in order to decide whether a formula S0 is true in a state S0, only a necessary part of the system-formula space is investigated. This is to be contrasted with the well-known global labeling algorithm of [4,5], where a priori all subformulae of S0 are checked for all states.</abstract></paper>