<paper id="1614483814"><title>Netvertising: content-based subgeneric variations in a digital genre</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="Jaume I University, Spain" id="2973248721">I. Fortanet</author><author org="" id="2118448648">J.C. Palmer</author><author org="" id="2707558503">S. Posteguillo</author></authors><n_citation>20</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1912684809</reference></references><venue id="1164519180" type="C">Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences</venue><doi>10.1109/HICSS.1998.651687</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.48966">Noun phrase</keyword><keyword weight="0.48717">Hypertext</keyword><keyword weight="0.42553">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.49638">Personal pronoun</keyword><keyword weight="0.45334">Web page</keyword><keyword weight="0.39455">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46874">Imperative mood</keyword><keyword weight="0.38386">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.47845">Web banner</keyword><keyword weight="0.4395">Linguistics</keyword><keyword weight="0.49701">Punctuation</keyword><keyword weight="0.50921">The Internet</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>We have endeavored to define a new emerging digital genre in the world of the Internet: netvertising. We present an analysis divided into two stages. An initial survey of 20 randomly selected Internet advertisements (netads) reveals that texts in this genre are formed by very brief sentences and noun phrases, the systematic use of imperative and simple present tenses, second-person personal pronouns, a higher use of punctuation marks, a combination of different types of images with various texts, and the use of diverse hypertext linkers. A second survey, however, unfolds a significant series of subgeneric variations depending on the contents of the netad. These content-based variations seem to be directly related to the product advertised. We have carried out a linguistic study of a complementary corpus of 50 first-page target ads, linked to those banner ads appearing while browsing through a good number of Internet servers (Infoseck, Webcrawler, AOL, and so on).</abstract></paper>