<paper id="1522953023"><title>Place and Route for Secure Standard Cell Design</title><year>2004</year><authors><author org="UC Los Angeles," id="2583218792">Kris Tiri</author><author org="UC Los Angeles," id="2044881251">Ingrid Verbauwhede</author></authors><n_citation>88</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1837001584</reference><reference>1897761346</reference><reference>2049389210</reference><reference>2099724084</reference><reference>2144630005</reference></references><venue id="1183877910" type="C">Smart Card Research and Advanced Application Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/1-4020-8147-2_10</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.48708">Power analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.53917">Logic gate</keyword><keyword weight="0.42467">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.44555">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.58822">Place and route</keyword><keyword weight="0.48193">Power factor</keyword><keyword weight="0.55242">Design flow</keyword><keyword weight="0.47811">Design methods</keyword><keyword weight="0.55367">Side channel attack</keyword><keyword weight="0.59478">Standard cell</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Boston, MA</publisher><abstract>Side channel attacks can be effectively addressed at the circuit level by using dynamic differential logic styles. A key problem is to guarantee a balanced capacitive load at the differential outputs of the logic gates. The main contribution to this load is the capacitance associated with the routing between cells. This paper describes a novel design methodology to route a design in which multiple differential pairs are present. The methodology is able to route 20K+ differential routes. The differential routes are always routed in adjacent tracks and the parasitic effects between the two wires of each differential pair are balanced. The methodology is developed on top of a commercially available EDA tool. It has been developed as part of a secure digital design flow to protect security applications against Differential Power Analysis attacks. Experimental results indicate that a perfect protection is attainable with the aid of the proposed differential routing strategy.</abstract></paper>