<paper id="1518402653"><title>Feature-Based steganalysis for JPEG images and its implications for future design of steganographic schemes</title><year>2004</year><authors><author org="Dept. of Electrical Engineering, SUNY Binghamton, Binghamton, NY#TAB#" id="2114798098">Jessica Fridrich</author></authors><n_citation>448</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1512190422</reference><reference>1527181506</reference><reference>1532906507</reference><reference>1760530029</reference><reference>1806317803</reference><reference>2031591609</reference><reference>2061397706</reference><reference>2062821417</reference><reference>2068740952</reference><reference>2096050104</reference><reference>2117500881</reference><reference>2119199090</reference><reference>2169354802</reference><reference>2484649938</reference><reference>2576355915</reference></references><venue id="1175805213" type="C">Information Hiding</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-30114-1_6</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.40897">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.50393">Discrete cosine transform</keyword><keyword weight="0.41761">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.4351">Computer vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.51489">Steganography</keyword><keyword weight="0.52261">Feature vector</keyword><keyword weight="0.44493">Embedding</keyword><keyword weight="0.44695">Pattern recognition</keyword><keyword weight="0.5743">JPEG</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Feature based</keyword><keyword weight="0.57421">Steganalysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.49727">Linear classifier</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In this paper, we introduce a new feature-based steganalytic method for JPEG images and use it as a benchmark for comparing JPEG steganographic algorithms and evaluating their embedding mechanisms. The detection method is a linear classifier trained on feature vectors corresponding to cover and stego images. In contrast to previous blind approaches, the features are calculated as an L1 norm of the difference between a specific macroscopic functional calculated from the stego image and the same functional obtained from a decompressed, cropped, and recompressed stego image. The functionals are built from marginal and joint statistics of DCT coefficients. Because the features are calculated directly from DCT coefficients, conclusions can be drawn about the impact of embedding modifications on detectability. Three different steganographic paradigms are tested and compared. Experimental results reveal new facts about current steganographic methods for JPEGs and new de-sign principles for more secure JPEG steganography.</abstract></paper>