<paper id="1541035956"><title>Improvements on security proofs of some identity based encryption schemes</title><year>2005</year><authors><author org="Institute of Industrial Science, The Univ. of Tokyo" id="2665622727">Rui Zhang</author><author org="Institute of Industrial Science, The Univ. of Tokyo" id="2101807108">Hideki Imai</author></authors><n_citation>7</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1514242548</reference><reference>1569083856</reference><reference>1589034595</reference><reference>1589586740</reference><reference>1607264302</reference><reference>2002930326</reference><reference>2052267638</reference><reference>2086042811</reference><reference>2122987162</reference><reference>2152688060</reference><reference>2613557339</reference></references><venue id="1147707288" type="C">Information Security and Cryptology</venue><doi>10.1007/11599548_3</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.42524">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.44464">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.4377">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.55081">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.63822">Concrete security</keyword><keyword weight="0.56803">Encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.54116">Mathematical proof</keyword><keyword weight="0.47391">Adversary</keyword><keyword weight="0.54954">Diffie–Hellman problem</keyword><keyword weight="0.44669">Bilinear interpolation</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Concrete security reduction plays an important role in practice, because it explicitly bounds an adversary’s success probability as a function of their resources. In this paper, we study the security reductions of Boneh-Franklin identity based encryption (IBE) schemes and its variants, focusing on the efficiency of their security on :[48],"proofs of Boneh-Franklin IBE and variants. The proof of the Boneh-Franklin IBE (BF-IBE) scheme was long believed to be correct until recently, Galindo pointed out a flawed step in the proof and gave a new proof, however, the new reduction was even looser. We give a new proof of the BF-IBE scheme that essentially improves previously known results. Very interestingly, our result is even better than the original underestimated one. Similar analysis can also be applied to Galindo’s BF-IBE variant, resulting in a tighter new BF-IBE :[134],"variant with tighter security reductions. We propose another :[134],"variant of the BF-IBE that admits better security reduction, however, the scheme relies on a stronger assumption, namely the Gap Bilinear Diffie-Hellman (GBDH) assumption.</abstract></paper>