<paper id="1911825786"><title>A Paradoxical Indentity-Based Signature Scheme Resulting from Zero-Knowledge</title><year>1988</year><authors><author org="CCETT" id="2615942320">Louis C. Guillou</author><author org="Philips Research Laboratory Brussels" id="2195205560">Jean-Jacques Quisquater</author></authors><n_citation>392</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>57300150</reference><reference>1493969756</reference><reference>1556859816</reference><reference>1569083856</reference><reference>1589034595</reference><reference>1591541592</reference><reference>1606273473</reference><reference>1882430379</reference><reference>1952573265</reference><reference>1996360405</reference><reference>2031618446</reference><reference>2034762886</reference><reference>2151433956</reference><reference>2167989228</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/0-387-34799-2_16</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.58161">Authentication</keyword><keyword weight="0.4486">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.53197">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.45623">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.53699">Smart card</keyword><keyword weight="0.55638">Digital signature</keyword><keyword weight="0.45522">Redundancy (engineering)</keyword><keyword weight="0.52651">Unique user</keyword><keyword weight="0.45577">Database transaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.51277">Zero-knowledge proof</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, New York, NY</publisher><abstract>At EUROCRYPTu002788, we introduced an interactive zero-knowledge protocol (Guillou and Quisquater [13]) fitted to the authentication of tamper-resistant devices (e.g. smart cards, Guillou and Ugon [14]).Each security device stores its secret authentication number, an RSA-like signature computed by an authority from the device identity. Any transaction between a tamper-resistant security device and a verifier is limited to a unique interaction: the device sends its identity and a random test number, then the verifier tells a random large question; and finally the device answers by a witness number. The transaction is successful when the test number is reconstructed from the witness number, the question and the identity according to numbers published by the authority and rules of redundancy possibly standardized.This protocol allows a cooperation between users in such a way that a group of cooperative users looks like a new entity, having a shadowed identity the product of the individual shadowed identities, while each member reveals nothing about its secret.In another scenario, the secret is partitioned between distinct devices sharing the same identity. A group of cooperative users looks like a unique user having a larger public exponent which is the greater common multiple of each individual exponent.In this paper, additional features are introduced in order to provide: firstly, a mutual interactive authentication of both communicating entities and previously exchanged messages, and, secondly, a digital signature of messages, with a non-interactive zero-knowledge protocol. The problem of multiple signature is solved here in a very smart way due to the possibilities of cooperation between users.The only secret key is the factors of the composite number chosen by the authority delivering one authentication number to each smart card. This key is not known by the user. At the user level, such a scheme may be considered as a keyless identity-based integrity scheme. This integrity has anew and important property: it cannot be misused, i.e. derived into a confidentiality scheme.</abstract></paper>