<paper id="1587299948"><title>Partial orderings descriptions and observations of nondeterministic concurrent processes</title><year>1988</year><authors><author org="Universita di Pisa" id="2352208385">Pierpaolo Degano</author><author org="Instituto di Elaborazione dell'Informazione, C.N.R." id="2266521850">Rocco De Nicola</author><author org="Universita di Pisa" id="2925215115">Ugo Montanari</author></authors><n_citation>74</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>10403265</reference><reference>122760469</reference><reference>1483314534</reference><reference>1547562281</reference><reference>1572904664</reference><reference>1585042602</reference><reference>1882941837</reference><reference>1979462141</reference><reference>1991052229</reference><reference>1994350081</reference><reference>2001748564</reference><reference>2027256978</reference><reference>2035959929</reference><reference>2050298454</reference><reference>2061288205</reference><reference>2113355185</reference><reference>2134326845</reference><reference>2137865376</reference><reference>2150320481</reference><reference>2179445399</reference><reference>2475115995</reference><reference>2914421362</reference></references><venue id="" type="">Linear Time, Branching Time and Partial Order in Logics and Models for Concurrency, School/Workshop</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0013030</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.68097">Operational semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.54714">Observational equivalence</keyword><keyword weight="0.55679">Concurrency</keyword><keyword weight="0.66754">Denotational semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.62668">Communicating sequential processes</keyword><keyword weight="0.61446">Action semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.61763">Failure semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.4565">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.39812">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.63723">Well-founded semantics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>A methodology is introduced for defining truly concurrent semantics of processes as equivalence classes of Labelled Event Structures (LES). The construction of a les providing the operational semantics of systems consists of three main steps. First, systems are decomposed into sets of sequential processes and a set of rewriting rules is introduced which describe both the actions sequential processes may perform and their causal relation. Then, the rewriting rules are used to build an occurrence net. Finally, the required event structure is easily derived from the occurrence net. As a test case, a partial ordering operational semantics is introduced first for a subset of Milneru0027s CCS and then for the whole calculus. The proposed semantics are consistent with the original interleaving semantics of the calculus and are able to capture all and only the parallelism present in its multiset semantics. In order to obtain more abstract semantic definitions, new notions of observational equivalence on Labelled Event Structures are introduced that preserve both concurrency and nondeterminism.</abstract></paper>