<paper id="161490498"><title>An IS research relevancy manifesto</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="California Polytechnic Univ., Pomona#TAB#" id="2339226960">Ralph Westfall</author></authors><n_citation>29</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>16905354</reference><reference>1521462814</reference><reference>1532520187</reference><reference>1552845745</reference><reference>1567733789</reference><reference>1580996832</reference><reference>1961867604</reference><reference>1985462370</reference><reference>2001877431</reference><reference>2066041127</reference><reference>2100044008</reference><reference>2102748455</reference><reference>2102990852</reference><reference>2104153957</reference><reference>2105980456</reference><reference>2123952056</reference><reference>2144081870</reference></references><venue id="7020383" type="J">Communications of The Ais</venue><doi>10.17705/1cais.00214</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.52384">Market analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.44021">Resizing</keyword><keyword weight="0.47201">Public relations</keyword><keyword weight="0.50707">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.45557">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.4898">Vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.40463">Engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.51592">Manifesto</keyword></keywords><publisher>Association for Information Systems</publisher><abstract>Many practitioners believe academic IS research is not relevant. I argue that our research, and the underlying rewards system that drives it, needs to respond to these concerns. We need to be more relevant to meet the increasing needs of our students, the organizations that hire them, and the larger society. To analyze the issues, I develop three different scenarios of where the IS field could be 10 years from now. The following visions of the future identify the implications of different levels of adaptation to relevance-related environmental pressures. Scenario 1: Minimal Adaptation. The IS field is shrinking, largely due to competition from newly established schools of information technology. The traditional paper-based journals continue to dominate. Their slow publication cycles, in contrast to the rapid rate of change in the IT industries, mean that most technical topics and many current managerial issues are excluded from the research that generates the greatest institutional rewards. However a market analysis indicates that we can still do relevant research in categories such as: 1) issues contrary to commercial interests; 2) unsolved problems; 3) issues economically unattractive to commercial researchers; 4) issues where 1 With apologies to James Martin for the similarity to the title of one [Martin, 1984] of his many books.</abstract></paper>