<paper id="1523271408"><title>Publicly Verifiable Lotteries: Applications of Delaying Functions</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="Divx" id="735586330">David M. Goldschlag</author><author org="AT&amp;T Labs — research" id="2576570037">Stuart G. Stubblebine</author></authors><n_citation>51</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>340987026</reference><reference>1481492327</reference><reference>1504280744</reference><reference>1510273591</reference><reference>1561395581</reference><reference>1601379374</reference><reference>1660562555</reference><reference>1993445749</reference><reference>2005734486</reference><reference>2024279477</reference><reference>2031618446</reference><reference>2047925852</reference><reference>2066747384</reference><reference>2123735079</reference></references><venue id="2606870472" type="C">Financial Cryptography</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0055485</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.447">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.44775">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.49224">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.58653">Lottery</keyword><keyword weight="0.54098">Ticket</keyword><keyword weight="0.50276">Verifiable secret sharing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>This paper uses delaying functions, functions that require significant calculation time, in the development of a one-pass lottery scheme in which winners are chosen fairly using only internal information. Since all this information may be published (even before the lottery closes), anyone can do the calculation and therefore verify that the winner was chosen correctly. Since the calculation uses a delaying function, ticket purchasers cannot take advantage of this information. Fraud on the part of the lottery agent is detectable and no single ticket purchaser needs to be trusted. Coalitions of purchasers attempting to control the winning ticket calculation are either unsuccessful or are detected. The scheme can be made resistant to coalitions of arbitrary size. Since we assume that coalitions of larger size are harder to assemble, the probability that the lottery is fair can be made arbitrarily high. The paper defines delaying functions and contrasts them with pricing functions [8] and time-lock puzzles [15].</abstract></paper>