<paper id="1494759436"><title>Randomized polynomials, threshold circuits, and the polynomial hierarchy</title><year>1991</year><authors><author org="University of Rochester;" id="2776780181">Jun Tarui</author></authors><n_citation>37</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1481255006</reference><reference>1485836178</reference><reference>1495935433</reference><reference>2007671490</reference><reference>2033323875</reference><reference>2057512592</reference><reference>2059442002</reference><reference>2069124970</reference><reference>2070678975</reference><reference>2114527013</reference><reference>2147786227</reference><reference>2151536080</reference></references><venue id="1178070762" type="C">Symposium on Theoretical Aspects of Computer Science</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0020802</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.60753">Alternating polynomial</keyword><keyword weight="0.57741">Karp–Lipton theorem</keyword><keyword weight="0.46222">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.46359">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.57383">Stable polynomial</keyword><keyword weight="0.63199">Square-free polynomial</keyword><keyword weight="0.62854">Polynomial remainder theorem</keyword><keyword weight="0.62527">Degree of a polynomial</keyword><keyword weight="0.59554">Reciprocal polynomial</keyword><keyword weight="0.61925">Homogeneous polynomial</keyword><keyword weight="0.41239">Mathematics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>A randomized polynomial over the integers is a multivariate polynomial whose coefficients are integer-valued random variables. A randomized polynomial uses m random bits if its coefficients jointly depend on m independently and uniformly distributed random bits. We show that every Boolean function family in AC0 can be computed with small error by randomized polynomials over the integers that have degree (log n)O(1) and use (log n)O(1) random bits. Applying this result, we further show the following: (a) Every Boolean function family in AC0 is computable by depth-two probabilistic threshold circuits of size \(n^{(\log n)^{O(1)} }\) with one-sided error and is also computable by depth-three deterministic threshold circuits with linear number of threshold gates and \(n^{(\log n)^{O(1)} }\)AND gates. (b) Every language in the polynomial hierarchy is reducible to some language in the class PP (in fact, to some language in the class C=P) by a randomized polynomial-time reduction with one-sided error.</abstract></paper>