<paper id="1981096457"><title>Providing integrated toolkit-level support for ambiguity in recognition-based interfaces</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="College of Computing and GVU Center, Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA" id="1987134293">Jennifer Mankoff</author><author org="Human-Computer Interaction Institute, Carnegie-Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA" id="2171298838">Scott E. Hudson</author><author org="College of Computing and GVU Center, Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA" id="620732773">Gregory D. Abowd</author></authors><n_citation>100</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1510762221</reference><reference>1970863077</reference><reference>1985324117</reference><reference>1993704986</reference><reference>2003822754</reference><reference>2017719916</reference><reference>2019036574</reference><reference>2023192402</reference><reference>2024196580</reference><reference>2031793755</reference><reference>2032176385</reference><reference>2059216172</reference><reference>2077770823</reference><reference>2089318047</reference><reference>2117081378</reference><reference>2125082607</reference><reference>2131415946</reference><reference>2148644727</reference><reference>2155180547</reference><reference>2166130518</reference><reference>2166858357</reference><reference>2296244466</reference></references><venue id="1163450153" type="C">Human Factors in Computing Systems</venue><doi>10.1145/332040.332459</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.63506">Intelligent character recognition</keyword><keyword weight="0.45948">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.60846">User Interface Toolkit</keyword><keyword weight="0.47777">Human–computer interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.53831">Ambiguity</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>Interfaces based on recognition technologies are used extensively in both the commercial and research worlds. But recognizers are still error-prone, and this results in human performance problems, brittle dialogues, and other barriers to acceptance and utility of recognition systems. Interface techniques specialized to recognition systems can help reduce the burden of recognition errors, but building these interfaces depends on knowledge about the ambiguity inherent in recognition. We have extended a user interface toolkit in order to model and to provide structured support for ambiguity at the input event level. This makes it possible to build re-usable interface components for resolving ambiguity and dealing with recognition errors. These interfaces can help to reduce the negative effects of recognition errors. By providing these components at a toolkit level, we make it easier for application writers to provide good support for error handling. Further, with this robust support, we are able to explore new types of interfaces for resolving a more varied range of ambiguity.</abstract></paper>