<paper id="1596153847"><title>Fast Encryption and Authentication: XCBC Encryption and XECB Authentication Modes</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="VDG Inc." id="417821493">Virgil D. Gligor</author><author org="VDG Inc." id="2198346268">Pompiliu Donescu</author></authors><n_citation>158</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>206097255</reference><reference>1526163409</reference><reference>1571187854</reference><reference>1635413415</reference><reference>1656028867</reference><reference>1660562555</reference><reference>1966591963</reference><reference>1993257560</reference><reference>2077300005</reference><reference>2083562020</reference><reference>2104578476</reference><reference>2133065964</reference><reference>2139172211</reference><reference>2154209576</reference><reference>2167569963</reference><reference>2614796589</reference></references><venue id="2758283624" type="C">Fast Software Encryption</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-45473-X_8</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.66394">Multiple encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.43611">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.4405">Computer network</keyword><keyword weight="0.64918">Disk encryption theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.43687">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.6761">Encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.66105">Probabilistic encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.63618">40-bit encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.65213">On-the-fly encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.63678">Filesystem-level encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.63657">56-bit encryption</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We present the eXtended Ciphertext Block Chaining (XCBC) and the eXtended Electronic Codebook (XECB) encryption schemes or modes of encryption that can detect encrypted-message forgeries with high probability even when used with typical noncryptographic Manipulation Detection Code (MDC) functions (e.g., bitwise exclusive-or and cyclic redundancy code (CRC) functions). These modes detect encrypted-message forgeries at low cost in performance, power, and implementation, and preserve both message secrecy and integrity in a single pass over the message data. Their performance and security scale directly with those of the underlying block cipher function. We also present the XECB message authentication (XECB-MAC) modes that have all the operational properties of the XOR-MAC modes (e.g., fully parallel and pipelined operation, incremental updates, and out-of-order verification), and have better performance. They are intended for use either stand-alone or with encryption modes that have similar properties (e.g., counter-based XOR encryption). However, the XECB-MAC modes have higher upper bounds on the probability of adversaryu0027s success in producing a forgery than the XOR-MAC modes.</abstract></paper>