<paper id="1973642705"><title>An implementation of an efficient algorithm for bisimulation equivalence</title><year>1990</year><authors><author org="IMAG-LGI, BP 53X, 38041 Grenoble Cedex, France" id="2974545111">J.-C. Fernandez</author></authors><n_citation>181</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>129716784</reference><reference>1547562281</reference><reference>1551752238</reference><reference>1605061766</reference><reference>1655990431</reference><reference>1971321632</reference><reference>2021473546</reference><reference>2050872276</reference><reference>2068361557</reference><reference>2294826973</reference></references><venue id="21029587" type="J">Science of Computer Programming</venue><doi>10.1016/0167-6423(90)90071-K</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.5651">Partition problem</keyword><keyword weight="0.48724">Binary logarithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.62604">Equivalence relation</keyword><keyword weight="0.54545">Binary relation</keyword><keyword weight="0.40991">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.44331">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.57012">Equivalence (measure theory)</keyword><keyword weight="0.65641">Bisimulation</keyword><keyword weight="0.54932">Time complexity</keyword><keyword weight="0.50727">Partition (number theory)</keyword></keywords><publisher>Elsevier North-Holland, Inc.</publisher><abstract>Abstract We present an efficient algorithm for bisimulation equivalence. Generally, bisimulation equivalence can be tested in O(mn) for a labeled transition system with m transitions and n states. In order to come up with a more efficient algorithm, we establish a relationship between bisimulation equivalence and the relational coarsest partition problem, solved by Paige and Tarjan in O(m log n) time. Given an initial partition and a binary relation, the problem is to find the coarsest partition compatible with them. Computing bisimulation equivalence can be viewed both as an instance and as a generalization of this problem: an instance, because only the universal partition is considered as an initial partition and a generalization since we want to find a partition compatible with a family of binary relations instead of one single binary relation. We describe how we have adapted the Paige-Tarjan algorithm of complexity O(m log n) to minimize labeled transition systems modulo bisimulation equivalence. This algorithm has been implemented in C and is used in Aldebaran, a tool for the verification of concurrent systems.</abstract></paper>