<paper id="1984200150"><title>Measuring e-government impact: existing practices and shortcomings</title><year>2004</year><authors><author org="University of Amsterdam, Zenc" id="2162651051">Rob M. Peters</author><author org="Delft University of Technology Delft The Netherlands" id="2036611447">Marijn Janssen</author><author org="University of Amsterdam, Zenc" id="2103107147">Tom M. van Engers</author></authors><n_citation>89</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1487725643</reference><reference>1491353680</reference><reference>2004902747</reference><reference>2064512996</reference><reference>2085556111</reference><reference>2109286118</reference><reference>2128466244</reference><reference>2128677857</reference><reference>2160196038</reference><reference>2164151586</reference></references><venue id="2627069240" type="C">International Conference on Electronic Commerce</venue><doi>10.1145/1052220.1052281</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">E-Government</keyword><keyword weight="0.48183">Business process</keyword><keyword weight="0.44386">Interoperability</keyword><keyword weight="0.41995">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.44789">Marketing</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>Public administrations of all over the world invest an enormous amount of resources in e-government. How the success of e-government can be measured is often not clear. E-government involves many aspects of public administration ranging from introducing new technology to business process (re-)engineering. The measurement of the effectiveness of e-government is a complicated endeavor.In this paper current practices of e-government measurement are evaluated. A number of limitations of current measurement instruments are identified. Measurement focuses predominantly on the front (primarily counting the number of services offered) and not on the back-office processes. Interpretation of measures is difficult as all existing measurement instruments lack a framework depicting the relationships between the indicators and the use of resources. The different measures may fit the aim of the owners of the e-governmental services, however, due to conflicting aims and priorities little agreement exists on a uniform set of measures, needed for comparison of e-government development. Traditional methods of measuring e-government impact and resource usage fall short of the richness of data required for the effective evaluation of e-government strategies.</abstract></paper>