<paper id="86197"><title>Securing Mobile Device-Based Machine Interactions with User Location Histories</title><year>2012</year><authors><author org="Ludwig—Maximilian University of Munich" id="2108178048">Philipp Marcus</author><author org="Ludwig—Maximilian University of Munich" id="2168893805">Moritz Kessel</author><author org="Ludwig—Maximilian University of Munich" id="259619398">Claudia Linnhoff-Popien</author></authors><n_citation>8</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1515263535</reference><reference>1532834808</reference><reference>1556367165</reference><reference>1639227833</reference><reference>2036110521</reference><reference>2038953226</reference><reference>2115973169</reference><reference>2148575440</reference><reference>2160769609</reference><reference>2294206256</reference><reference>2546775511</reference></references><venue id="1160389874" type="C">Security and Privacy in Mobile Information and Communication Systems</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-642-33392-7_10</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.40626">Imperfect</keyword><keyword weight="0.46143">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46278">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.54351">Usability</keyword><keyword weight="0.46568">Computer network</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Location based access control</keyword><keyword weight="0.56224">Mobile device</keyword><keyword weight="0.52051">Workflow</keyword><keyword weight="0.47726">restrict</keyword><keyword weight="0.44079">Trajectory</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Mobile devices are more and more integrated in workflows, especially when interacting with stationary resources like machines in order to improve productivity or usability, but risk unauthorized access or unwanted unattended operation. Systems for location based access control have been developed to restrict the user to be in specific locations in order to proceed in a workflow. However, these approaches do not consider the movement pattern of a user nor do they distinguish the severity of false-positives that might arise from imperfect location measurements which is crucial in certain workflows. In this paper, focusing on mobile users interacting with stationary machines, an approach for workflow policies is presented using three types of location constraints to enforce movement patterns. The evaluation of these constraints is based on a user’s location history which is generated in a tamper-proof environment on his mobile device and describes his geographical trajectory for a given timespan.</abstract></paper>