<paper id="1520276881"><title>Cross-Organizational Transaction Support for Virtual Enterprises</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="UNIVERSITY OF TWENTE" id="2427435393">Jochem Vonk</author><author org="KPN Research" id="2052877539">Wijnand Derks</author><author org="UNIVERSITY OF TWENTE" id="330448013">Paul W. P. J. Grefen</author><author org="UNIVERSITY OF TWENTE" id="1953466341">Marjanca Koetsier</author></authors><n_citation>26</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1488996954</reference><reference>1522974305</reference><reference>1556531117</reference><reference>1855065956</reference><reference>2013754195</reference><reference>2099282316</reference><reference>2101074054</reference><reference>2117304302</reference><reference>2118305052</reference><reference>2129338772</reference><reference>2129674434</reference><reference>2153938134</reference><reference>2160180123</reference><reference>2161486662</reference><reference>2626304854</reference></references><venue id="1147734270" type="C">Cooperative Information Systems</venue><doi>10.1007/10722620_30</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.62503">Compensating transaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.71145">Workflow technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.62941">Workflow Management Coalition</keyword><keyword weight="0.45488">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.63849">Windows Workflow Foundation</keyword><keyword weight="0.63051">XPDL</keyword><keyword weight="0.71898">Workflow engine</keyword><keyword weight="0.6251">Workflow</keyword><keyword weight="0.69998">Workflow management system</keyword><keyword weight="0.45599">Database</keyword><keyword weight="0.45732">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.47376">Process management</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer</publisher><abstract>In recent years, workflow management systems have become an accepted technology to support automation in process-centric environments. Lately, organizations concentrate more and more on their core business processes while outsourcing supporting processes to other organizations, thereby forming virtual enterprises. To apply workflow management technology in these virtual enterprises, support for cross-organizational processes is necessary. Transaction support, already considered an important issue in intra-organizational workflow management systems, must be extended to deal with the cross-organizational aspects as well. This paper presents a high-level transaction model and architecture for cross-organizational workflow processes. Characteristic of the model is the flexibility in rollback semantics by combining rollback modes and rollback scopes, supported by a dynamically generated architecture that is configured conforming to an electronic contract that has been established between the different organizations. The transaction model and architecture are independent of the underlying workflow management system platform, however, in the CrossFlow project the presented technology is being implemented on top of IBM’s MQ Series Workflow.</abstract></paper>