<paper id="1653313196"><title>Intelligent Interface Technology</title><year>1997</year><authors><author org="Napier Univ" id="1988881304">David Benyon</author></authors><n_citation>10</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2147859400</reference><reference>2153166272</reference></references><venue id="1127419992" type="C">International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction</venue><doi>10.1007/978-0-387-35175-9_129</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.51521">Domain knowledge</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Intelligent interface</keyword><keyword weight="0.45252">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45745">Adaptive system</keyword><keyword weight="0.53869">Usability</keyword><keyword weight="0.59486">Adaptive hypermedia</keyword><keyword weight="0.47439">Human–computer interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.59407">User interface</keyword></keywords><publisher>Chapman &amp; Hall, Ltd.</publisher><abstract>Applying intelligent interface technology (IIT) will increasingly become an option for the interface designer. Although there have been many applications of IIT there are few general principles, guidelines or methods as to when designers could and should use IIT. This tutorial looks in detail at applications of IIT and at the techniques which it employs. It covers the construction of user, domain and interaction models and looks at how these have been applied in adaptive hypermedia systems, intelligent multi-media, agent-based interaction and other intelligent user interfaces. The tutorial follows on from the introductory tutorial and illustrates the methodology presented there. It also covers the enhanced methods of analysis and design which are needed in order to make effective use of IIT. Given a better understanding of both methods and structure, IIT not only becomes a solution to some usability problems, it opens up new horizons for a radical change in HCI through the use of interface agents and a more equitable sharing of domain knowledge.</abstract></paper>