<paper id="1533632780"><title>Comparison of Natural Deduction and Locking Resolution Implementations</title><year>1982</year><authors><author org="University of Illinois." id="2179156526">Steven Greenbaum</author><author org="University of Illinois." id="2711188327">A. Nagasaka</author><author org="University of Illinois." id="2707006967">Paul O'Rorke</author><author org="University of Illinois." id="174197633">David A. Plaisted</author></authors><n_citation>10</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>147900504</reference><reference>1530765221</reference><reference>1966048066</reference><reference>1998113645</reference><reference>2018221833</reference><reference>2023139438</reference><reference>2046511504</reference><reference>2087253627</reference><reference>2088350978</reference></references><venue id="1134440762" type="C">Conference on Automated Deduction</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0000058</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.42458">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.46556">Natural deduction</keyword><keyword weight="0.44312">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46339">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.39443">Implementation</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Two versions of the simplified problem reduction format are compared with locking resolution on some examples. The simplified problem reduction format is a complete strategy which has a goal-subgoal structure and combines features of resolution and natural deduction. Checking subgoals against previously generated subgoals to avoid solving the same subproblems repeatedly was found to be a significant benefit in the simplified problem reduction format. In general, the simplified problem reduction format with checking for repeated subgoals was found to be a better strategy than locking resolution in terms of total computing time used, although the search spaces for locking resolution were often smaller. The smaller search spaces and longer times for locking resolution persisted when the deletion method was replaced by a faster, less powerful deletion method, indicating that the difference with the problem reduction format is not due to the choice of a deletion method. The use of a faster, less powerful deletion method did lead to better performance in the looking resolution prove, however.</abstract></paper>