<paper id="1963857427"><title>Data analysis and learning: an experimental study of data modeling tools</title><year>1989</year><authors><author org="Department of Management Science and Information Systems, Graduate School of Business, University of Texas at Austin, Austin, TX 78712, USA" id="229437117">S. L. Jarvenpaa</author><author org="Systems Research Group" id="59661605">J. J. Machesky</author></authors><n_citation>54</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1572700383</reference><reference>2031681640</reference><reference>2058819922</reference><reference>2097680763</reference><reference>2100625161</reference></references><venue id="129573059" type="J">International Journal of Human-computer Studies / International Journal of Man-machine Studies</venue><doi>10.1016/0020-7373(89)90001-1</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.48403">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.65507">Data modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.49695">Notation</keyword><keyword weight="0.45762">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.63495">Logical data model</keyword><keyword weight="0.56303">RDM</keyword><keyword weight="0.46686">Human–computer interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.52706">Relational model</keyword><keyword weight="0.48264">Visual appearance</keyword></keywords><publisher>Academic Press</publisher><abstract>Abstract The purpose of the current study was to seek insight into the ease of learning logical data modeling among novices. The two tools examined in the three learning experiments were the Logical Data Structure (LDS), which is based on the entity-relationship concept, and the Relational Data Model (RDM). For a series of trials, naive analysts were asked to generate data models using one of the tools. Feedback regarding the correct model was provided after each trial. The results suggest that when given structured tasks, novices are able to learn rather quickly how to produce small, good quality models using either of the tools. Comparatively, the LDS tool promoted significantly more top-down directed analysis and resulted in more accurate data models than the RDM tool. The significant differences are explained in terms of the visual appearance of the notation associated with the tools. The results have implications for data modeling training and for the development of data modeling tools.</abstract></paper>