<paper id="1548644447"><title>Behavioural Equivalence Relations Induced by Programming Logics</title><year>1983</year><authors><author org="Carnegie - Mellon University#TAB#" id="2115786145">Stephen D. Brookes</author><author org="University of Michigan" id="2223843038">William C. Rounds</author></authors><n_citation>72</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1546981056</reference><reference>1547409410</reference><reference>1547562281</reference><reference>1589421353</reference><reference>1992072860</reference><reference>1994350081</reference><reference>2023808162</reference><reference>2054801208</reference><reference>2075920544</reference><reference>2102097307</reference><reference>2107733072</reference><reference>2120411588</reference><reference>2137865376</reference><reference>2140919105</reference></references><venue id="1141821850" type="C">International Colloquium on Automata, Languages and Programming</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0036900</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.4396">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.62869">Autoepistemic logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.41006">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.63357">Zeroth-order logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.62505">Multimodal logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.62771">Modal logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.65505">Many-valued logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.6704">Intermediate logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.64468">Dynamic logic (modal logic)</keyword><keyword weight="0.62516">Higher-order logic</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In this paper we compare the descriptive power of three programming logics by studying the elementary equivalence relations which the logics induce on nondeterministic state-transition systems. In addition, we compare these relations with other natural state-equivalence relations for nondeterministic systems. We find that the notions of bisimilarity (Park [P], Ogden [O]) and observation equivalence (Milner [M]) are very strong equivalences compared with those induced by the logics. These three comprise regular trace logic (RTL), propositional dynamic logic (PDL), and Hennessy-Milner logic (HML). Regular trace logic is a new logic which can be used to give behavioural specifications for concurrent systems (e.g. Wolper [W], but with significant differences). It is a way of formalising those properties of programs which have been given informally in terms of path expressions [CH]. The model theory and axiomatics of this logic are interesting in their own right. Propositional dynamic logic is well-known; our treatment differs from the standard one only in that we regard the modalities as specifying intended behaviour instead of being programs. Hennessy-Milner logic is a simplified modal logic which those authors used as a characterisation of their notion of observation equivalence, which we call weak observation equivalence in this paper. We also include a brief treatment in this context of two other natural equivalences for nondeterministic systems: failure equivalence [HBR] and trace equivalence [H], both of which are weaker than the relations induced by the logics but can be characterised using appropriate logical subsets.</abstract></paper>