<paper id="1883290498"><title>A non-monotonic logic for reasoning about speech acts and belief revision</title><year>1989</year><authors><author org="Artificial Intelligence Center, Center for the Study of Language and Information, SRI International" id="2308608303">Douglas E. Appelt</author><author org="Artificial Intelligence Center, Center for the Study of Language and Information, SRI International" id="2079032315">Kurt Konolige</author></authors><n_citation>17</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1534011928</reference><reference>1581384476</reference><reference>1966552757</reference><reference>2076439421</reference><reference>2109878893</reference><reference>2155322595</reference><reference>2158467128</reference><reference>2169602487</reference><reference>2913309218</reference></references><venue id="1181711330" type="C">Non-Monotonic Reasoning</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-50701-9_26</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.6094">Default logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.66245">Autoepistemic logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.43676">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.40999">Collateral</keyword><keyword weight="0.41305">Default</keyword><keyword weight="0.72131">Non-monotonic logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.60284">Deductive reasoning</keyword><keyword weight="0.44374">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.48839">Formalism (philosophy)</keyword><keyword weight="0.58791">Belief revision</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>A prerequisite to a theory of the way agents understand speech acts is a theory of how their beliefs and intentions are revised as a consequence of events. This process of attitude revision is an interesting domain for the application of nonmonotonic reasoning because speech acts have a conventional aspect that is readily represented by defaults, but that interacts with an agentu0027s beliefs and intentions in many complex ways that may override the defaults. Perrault has developed a theory of speech acts, based on Rieteru0027s default logic, that captures the conventional aspect; it does not, however, adequately account for certain easily observed facts about attitude revision resulting from speech acts. A natural theory of attitude revision seems to require a method of stating preferences among competing defaults. We present here a speech act theory, formalized in hierarchic autoepistemic logic (a refinement of Mooreu0027s autoepistemic logic), in which revision of both the speakeru0027s and heareru0027s attitudes can be adequately described. As a collateral benefit, efficient automatic reasoning methods for the formalism exist. The theory has been implemented and is now being employed by an utterance-planning system.</abstract></paper>