<paper id="1984776916"><title>Network locality at the scale of processes</title><year>1991</year><authors><author org="Digital Equipment Corporation, Western Research Laboratory, 250 University Avenue, Palo Alto, California" id="2018433396">Jeffrey C. Mogul</author></authors><n_citation>88</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>148622740</reference><reference>1555915743</reference><reference>1589576271</reference><reference>1629946144</reference><reference>1661326830</reference><reference>1674145689</reference><reference>1971660842</reference><reference>1971886849</reference><reference>1984707196</reference><reference>2012182306</reference><reference>2019235753</reference><reference>2022371412</reference><reference>2029677496</reference><reference>2039061026</reference><reference>2041279698</reference><reference>2048712467</reference><reference>2094863561</reference><reference>2095000200</reference><reference>2096733429</reference><reference>2113440470</reference><reference>2117271294</reference><reference>2122401729</reference><reference>2124906592</reference><reference>2129159633</reference><reference>2134423494</reference><reference>2139150553</reference><reference>2144426378</reference><reference>2153964544</reference><reference>2160314792</reference><reference>2913277331</reference></references><venue id="1152462849" type="C">ACM Special Interest Group on Data Communication</venue><doi>10.1145/115994.116017</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.5311">Permission</keyword><keyword weight="0.55313">Locality</keyword><keyword weight="0.43914">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45209">Scheduling (computing)</keyword><keyword weight="0.50772">Network packet</keyword><keyword weight="0.44205">Computer network</keyword><keyword weight="0.50445">Copying</keyword><keyword weight="0.42889">Implementation</keyword><keyword weight="0.46613">Notice</keyword><keyword weight="0.42978">Tracing</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>Packets on a LAN can be viewed as a series of references to and from the objects they address. The amount of locality in this reference stream may be critical to the efficiency of network implementations, if the locality can be exploited through caching or scheduling mechanisms. Most previous studies have treated network locality with an addressing granularity of networks or individual hosts. This paper describes some experiments tracing locality at a finer grain, looking at references to individual processes, and with finegrained time resolution. Observations of typical LANs show high perprocess locality; that is, packets to a host usually arrive for the process that most recently sent a packet, and often with little intervening delay. This Research Report is an expanded version of a paper that appeared in the Proceedings of the SIGCOMM ’91 Conference on Communications Architectures and Protocols. Permission to copy without fee all or part of this material is granted provided that the copies are not made or distributed for direct commercial advantage, the ACM copyright notice and the title of the publication and its date appear, and notice is given that copying is by permission of the Association for Computing Machinery. To copy otherwise, or to republish, requires a fee and/or specific permission. d i g i t a l Western Research Laboratory 250 University Avenue Palo Alto, California 94301 USA</abstract></paper>