<paper id="1985861836"><title>A Computer Intermediary for Interactive Database Searching. I. Design</title><year>2007</year><authors><author org="Drexel University; Philadelphia; PA" id="2779870576">Charles T. Meadow</author><author org="Drexel University; Philadelphia; PA" id="2043328536">Thomas T. Hewett</author><author org="Drexel University; Philadelphia; PA" id="2597293787">Elizabeth Smith Aversa</author></authors><n_citation>39</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>2106350297</reference></references><venue id="80113298" type="J">Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology</venue><doi>10.1002/asi.4630330514</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.41509">Intermediary</keyword><keyword weight="0.58346">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.52547">Computer-Assisted Instruction</keyword><keyword weight="0.47596">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.46881">Information retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.5455">End user</keyword><keyword weight="0.45688">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.53663">Expert system</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Individualized instruction</keyword><keyword weight="0.47561">Multimedia</keyword><keyword weight="0.50627">Data access</keyword><keyword weight="0.45506">Database</keyword></keywords><publisher>Wiley Subscription Services, Inc., A Wiley Company</publisher><abstract>This is the first of two articles that report on the development, testing, and evaluation of the Individualized Instruction for Data Access System (IIDA). IIDA is an ex. ample of a class of computer systems which serve as intermediaries, enabling their users to perform a complex task on another computer, and which are coming to be known as expert systems. The system was designed to encourage end users of information retrieval systems to perform their own searches by (1) instructing them in how to search, using computer‐assisted instruction, and (2) assisting with the performance of the search by providing diagnostic analyses of the usersu0027 performance as well as answering their questions about how to use system commands. The systemu0027s design is described, as well as the various tests of its performance and the evaluation of test results. The conclusion is drawn that end users can become successful searchers through such an assistant, for the kinds of searches tested.</abstract></paper>