<paper id="1885634701"><title>Managing escalation of collaboration processes in crisis mitigation situations</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="MCC, Austin, TX, USA" id="2252115663">D. Georgakopoulos</author><author org="" id="2297191827">H. Schuster</author><author org="" id="2974424312">D. Baker</author><author org="" id="2973424052">A. Cichocki</author></authors><n_citation>50</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>39280257</reference><reference>1492174193</reference><reference>1570265525</reference><reference>1973322711</reference><reference>2015234709</reference><reference>2034873286</reference><reference>2035244158</reference><reference>2039657254</reference><reference>2089975742</reference><reference>2114459684</reference><reference>2124431248</reference><reference>2147513755</reference><reference>2156879624</reference><reference>2913036292</reference></references><venue id="1163988186" type="C">International Conference on Data Engineering</venue><doi>10.1109/ICDE.2000.839386</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Management model</keyword><keyword weight="0.47664">Collaborative software</keyword><keyword weight="0.42908">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45565">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.54709">Crisis management</keyword><keyword weight="0.46251">Delegation</keyword><keyword weight="0.50016">Workflow</keyword><keyword weight="0.4227">Database</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Federated Architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.47119">Process management</keyword><keyword weight="0.44199">Data flow diagram</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>Processes for crisis mitigation must permit coordination flexibility and dynamic change to empower crisis mitigation coordinators and experts to deal with unexpected situations. However, such mitigation processes must also provide enough structure to prevent chaotic response and increase mitigation effectiveness. Such combination of structure and flexibility cannot be effectively supported by existing workflow or groupware technologies. In this paper, we introduce the Collaboration Management Infrastructure (CMI) and describe its capabilities for supporting crisis mitigation processes. CMI provides a comprehensive Collaboration Management Model (CMM) and a corresponding federated system. CMM supports process templates that provide the initial activities, control and data flow structure, and resources needed to start mitigating a variety of crisis situations. In the event of a crisis, the appropriate process template is selected and instantiated. Crisis mitigation is achieved by escalating the instantiated process template. Escalation involves selecting and adding new process templates, creating new activities, roles, and task forces as needed to deal with the current demands in the crisis, and delegating responsibilities to process participants and task forces. CMM provides advanced composable primitives that empower crisis mitigation coordinators and experts to escalate the process. We provide an overview of the implementation of a federated CMI system and discuss our initial experience with various applications in the area of crisis management.</abstract></paper>