<paper id="1597910678"><title>On Changing Continuous Attributes into Ordered Discrete Attributes</title><year>1991</year><authors><author org="Basser Department of Computer Science, University of Sydney, Australia#TAB#" id="2146299793">Jason Catlett</author></authors><n_citation>379</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1490514105</reference><reference>1494236755</reference><reference>1534707631</reference><reference>1570286060</reference><reference>1573772481</reference><reference>1579460831</reference><reference>1580142630</reference><reference>1985624473</reference><reference>2000613518</reference><reference>2018642704</reference><reference>2128420091</reference><reference>2149706766</reference></references><venue id="" type="">EWSL'91 Proceedings of the 5th European Conference on European Working Session on Learning</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0017012</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.49374">Small number</keyword><keyword weight="0.48632">Discretization</keyword><keyword weight="0.59312">Semi-supervised learning</keyword><keyword weight="0.6075">Active learning (machine learning)</keyword><keyword weight="0.53423">CPU time</keyword><keyword weight="0.46409">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.46845">Real number</keyword><keyword weight="0.47204">Machine learning</keyword><keyword weight="0.58172">Discretization of continuous features</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The large real-world datasets now commonly tackled by machine learning algorithms are often described in terms of attributes whose values are real numbers on some continuous interval, rather than being taken from a small number of discrete values. Many algorithms are able to handle continuous attributes, but learning requires far more CPU time than for a corresponding task with discrete attributes. This paper describes how continuous attributes can be converted economically into ordered discrete attributes before being given to the learning system. Experimental results from a wide variety of domains suggest this change of representation does not often result in a significant loss of accuracy (in fact it sometimes significantly improves accuracy), but offers large reductions in learning time, typically more than a factor of 10 in domains with a large number of continuous attributes.</abstract></paper>