<paper id="1525318746"><title>Integrating Active and Deductive Rules</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="(University of Queensland)" id="2193305860">John V. Harrison</author><author org="Arizona State University" id="2079206143">Suzanne W. Dietrich</author></authors><n_citation>19</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>35947464</reference><reference>180056467</reference><reference>1521751987</reference><reference>1524011117</reference><reference>1528738961</reference><reference>1972376013</reference><reference>1978108034</reference><reference>1990337493</reference><reference>2012670464</reference><reference>2037035101</reference><reference>2037504708</reference><reference>2054086422</reference><reference>2086906616</reference><reference>2094867116</reference><reference>2150974577</reference></references><venue id="" type="">Rules in Database Systems</venue><doi>10.1007/978-1-4471-3225-7_17</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Logic program</keyword><keyword weight="0.46151">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.46595">Programming language</keyword><keyword weight="0.66714">Deductive database</keyword><keyword weight="0.50053">Partial evaluation</keyword><keyword weight="0.46236">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.40155">Detector</keyword><keyword weight="0.62317">Active database</keyword><keyword weight="0.41832">Sophistication</keyword><keyword weight="0.50135">Recursion</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Expressivity</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, London</publisher><abstract>This paper describes how active and deductive rules can be integrated to form an expressive representation for declaring and reasoning about events and conditions. Specifically, this paper describes an extension and optimizations to the PF algorithm, which detects events, i.e. updates, that affect derived relations (or views), even when the derived relation is recursively defined. This capability improves the expressiveness of the event-condition-action (ECA) rules, which can then be used to detect more complex events and express conditions that reason with the updates to both stored and derived relations. The updates to the derived relations can be detected without having to materialize the derived relations. The PF algorithm can detect these updates when certain modifications to the definition of the derived relation are made. This approach has been implemented to form an event detector and condition evaluator for an active deductive database. These enhancements increase the sophistication of an active database since ECA rules can be defined that react to a larger scope of real-world situations.</abstract></paper>