<paper id="203975620"><title>Perceived chargeback system fairness in decentralized organizations: an examination of the issues</title><year>1989</year><authors><author org="College of Business Administration, University of South Florida, Tampa, Florida." id="2429959197">Ellen M. Hufnagel</author><author org="Joseph M. Katz Graduate School of Business, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania" id="296001079">Jacob G. Birnberg</author></authors><n_citation>25</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>37833980</reference><reference>100321389</reference><reference>1521129734</reference><reference>1992843595</reference><reference>2011524901</reference><reference>2014580550</reference><reference>2041781852</reference><reference>2042273965</reference><reference>2044790070</reference><reference>2056515390</reference><reference>2059557122</reference><reference>2062414588</reference><reference>2081737649</reference><reference>2137515990</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/248726</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.481">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.42453">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.4875">Environmental full-cost accounting</keyword><keyword weight="0.44812">Market price</keyword><keyword weight="0.52031">Transfer pricing</keyword><keyword weight="0.45575">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.46833">Resource allocation</keyword><keyword weight="0.47053">Interim</keyword><keyword weight="0.46437">Industrial organization</keyword><keyword weight="0.5746">Chargeback</keyword><keyword weight="0.51484">Cost allocation</keyword><keyword weight="0.45977">Marketing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>Problems can arise in decentralized organizations when usage-based chargeback systems are implemented to control computing resources. A case study of a company that is changing from negotiated pricing to full cost pricing illustrates the fact that concerns about fairness can arise not only with respect to specific characteristics of the chargeback system (e.g., understandability, controllability), but also as a result of central management policies governing internal transactions between the users and MIS. In particular, this examination identifies three factors that affect the fairness perceptions of autonomous divisional managers: (1) a high degree of interdependence between user divisions and MIS such that the behavior of MIS could have a significant impact on divisional performance; (2) restrictions on divisional managersu0027 freedom to purchase computer services from external sources; and (3) the tendency for full cost to exceed market prices early in the life of a data center. A dual pricing approach may be an interim solution to reduce conflict and improve user perceptions of fairness.</abstract></paper>