<paper id="1775744160"><title>On the concrete complexity of zero-knowledge proofs</title><year>1989</year><authors><author org="University of Chicago" id="2086600314">Joan Boyar</author><author org="University of Wisconsin" id="2148338499">René Peralta</author></authors><n_citation>4</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1494965429</reference><reference>1498590645</reference><reference>1510190168</reference><reference>1970606468</reference><reference>1979215153</reference><reference>2002032317</reference><reference>2030087828</reference><reference>2036265926</reference><reference>2045717693</reference><reference>2096604262</reference><reference>2099188893</reference><reference>2119436952</reference><reference>2151433956</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/0-387-34805-0_45</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.63678">Probabilistically checkable proof</keyword><keyword weight="0.43587">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.47266">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.44515">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.43317">Digital signature</keyword><keyword weight="0.451">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.52543">Mathematical proof</keyword><keyword weight="0.46587">Multiplication</keyword><keyword weight="0.45326">Greatest common divisor</keyword><keyword weight="0.43458">Modular design</keyword><keyword weight="0.50888">Zero-knowledge proof</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, New York, NY</publisher><abstract>The fact that there are zero-knowledge proofs for all languages in NP has, potentially, enormous implications to cryptography. For cryptographers, the issue is no longer "which languages in NP have zero-knowledge proofs" but rather "which languages in NP have practical zero-knowledge proofs". Thus, the concrete complexity of zero-knowledge proofs for different languages must be established.In this paper, we study the concrete complexity of the known general methods for constructing zero-knowledge proofs. We establish that circuit-based methods have the potential of producing proofs which can be used in practice. Then we introduce several techniques which greatly reduce the concrete complexity of circuit-based proofs. In order to show that our protocols yield proofs of knowledge, we show how to extend the Feige-Fiat-Shamir definition for proofs of knowledge to the model of Brassard-Chaum-Crepeau. Finally, we present techniques for improving the efficiency of protocols which involve arithmetic computations, such as modular addition, subtraction, and multiplication, and greatest common divisor.</abstract></paper>