<paper id="1506660274"><title>SAT-Based Image Computation with Application in Reachability Analysis</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="NEC USA CCRL" id="2129619966">Aarti Gupta</author><author org="NEC USA CCRL" id="2265437558">Zijiang Yang</author><author org="NEC USA CCRL" id="1987321661">Pranav Ashar</author><author org="NEC USA CCRL" id="2304711325">Anubhav Gupta</author></authors><n_citation>102</n_citation><doc_type>Patent</doc_type><references><reference>164685601</reference><reference>1494481937</reference><reference>1787074469</reference><reference>1814068099</reference><reference>1822320350</reference><reference>2048051309</reference><reference>2062897452</reference><reference>2080267935</reference><reference>2099120582</reference><reference>2113251992</reference><reference>2117783862</reference><reference>2118837621</reference><reference>2120925552</reference><reference>2146663969</reference><reference>2160444875</reference><reference>2161677825</reference></references><venue id="1166230065" type="C">Formal Methods in Computer-Aided Design</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-40922-X_22</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47818">Decision tree</keyword><keyword weight="0.45369">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47085">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.52321">Reachability</keyword><keyword weight="0.49647">Heuristics</keyword><keyword weight="0.51127">Conjunctive normal form</keyword><keyword weight="0.44596">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.63945">#SAT</keyword><keyword weight="0.44121">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.60157">Boolean satisfiability problem</keyword><keyword weight="0.4684">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.4859">Image (mathematics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.50595">Formal verification</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Image computation finds wide application in VLSI CAD, such as state reachability analysis in formal verification and synthesis, combinational verification, combinational and sequential test. Existing BDD-based symbolic algorithms for image computation are limited by memory resources in practice, while SAT-based algorithms that can obtain the image by enumerating satisfying assignments to a CNF representation of the Boolean relation are potentially limited by time resources. We propose new algorithms that combine BDDs and SAT in order to exploit their complementary benefits, and to offer a mechanism for trading off space vs. time. In particular, (1) our integrated algorithm uses BDDs to represent the input and image sets, and a CNF formula to represent the Boolean relation, (2) a fundamental enhancement called BDD Bounding is used whereby the SAT solver uses the BDDs for the input set and the dynamically changing image set to prune the search space of all solutions, (3) BDDs are used to compute all solutions below intermediate points in the SAT decision tree, (4) a fine-grained variable quantification schedule is used for each BDD subproblem, based on the CNF representation of the Boolean relation. These enhancements coupled with more engineering heuristics lead to an overall algorithm that can potentially handle larger problems. This is supported by our preliminary results on exact reachability analysis of ISCAS benchmark circuits.</abstract></paper>