<paper id="1982922705"><title>The first BOWS Contest (Break Our Watermarking System)</title><year>2007</year><authors><author org="University of Florence, Italy," id="2104832305">Alessandro Piva</author><author org="University of Siena Italy" id="2029038940">Mauro Barni</author></authors><n_citation>8</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2162752880</reference></references><venue id="2759400282" type="C">Conference on Security, Steganography, and Watermarking of Multimedia Contents</venue><doi>10.1117/12.704969</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.43576">Acronym</keyword><keyword weight="0.48785">Digital watermarking</keyword><keyword weight="0.43738">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.42985">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.44724">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.44321">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.55601">CONTEST</keyword><keyword weight="0.45484">Information protection policy</keyword><keyword weight="0.49145">Watermark</keyword><keyword weight="0.4365">Excellence</keyword></keywords><publisher>International Society for Optics and Photonics</publisher><abstract>In the framework of the activities carried out by the European Network of Excellence for Cryptology ECRYPT, a of :[18],"excellence funded within the Information Societies Technology (IST) Programme of the European :[32],"Framework Programme (FP6), it was proposed to launch the BOWS Contest. BOWS, acronym of Break :[48],"System, was designed to allow to investigate how and when an image watermarking system can be :[65],"preserving the highest possible quality of the modified content, in case that the watermarking system is subjected :[83],"world-wide attack. BOWS contest was not intended as an attempt to prove how well-performing a watermarking :[100],"but it was expected by means of this test to better understand which are the disparate possible attacks, perhaps the :[120],"moment of the start of the contest, the BOWS participants could carry out to perform their action and this :[140],"way the degree of difficulty of breaking the embedded watermark. This paper describes how the Contest has and :[159],"analyzes the general progress of the attacks during the Contest.</abstract></paper>