<paper id="1520901926"><title>What's in an Electronic Business Model?</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="FREE UNIVERSITY, AMSTERDAM" id="2115979219">Jaap Gordijn</author><author org="Free University, Amsterdam" id="2957086205">Hans Akkermans</author><author org="Free University—Amsterdam" id="2105014955">Hans van Vliet</author></authors><n_citation>79</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1600126100</reference><reference>1982747710</reference><reference>2018113587</reference><reference>2102724588</reference><reference>2133109597</reference><reference>2145570862</reference><reference>2146439955</reference><reference>2165242406</reference><reference>2914417762</reference><reference>2914859070</reference></references><venue id="1148330047" type="C">Knowledge Acquisition, Modeling and Management</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-39967-4_19</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.62587">New business development</keyword><keyword weight="0.63072">Artifact-centric business process model</keyword><keyword weight="0.54618">Ontology</keyword><keyword weight="0.59215">Electronic business</keyword><keyword weight="0.46075">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46758">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.53074">Business decision mapping</keyword><keyword weight="0.64185">Business domain</keyword><keyword weight="0.61229">Business model</keyword><keyword weight="0.63412">Business rule</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><abstract>An electronic business model is an important baseline for the development of e-commerce system applications. Essentially, it provides the design rationale for e-commerce systems from the business point of view. However, how an e-business model must be defined and specified is a largely open issue. Business decision makers tend to use the notion in a highly informal way, and usually there is a big gap between the business view and that of IT developers. Nevertheless, we show that conceptual modelling techniques from IT provide very useful tools for precisely pinning down what e-business models actually are, as well as for their structured specification. We therefore present a (lightweight) ontology of what should be in an e-business model. The key idea we propose and develop is that an e-business model ontology centers around the core concept of value, and expresses how value is created, interpreted and exchanged within a multi-party stakeholder network. Our e-business model ontology is part of a wider methodology for e-business modelling, called e3 -value, that is currently under development. It is based on a variety of industrial applications we are involved in, and it is illustrated by discussing a free Internet access service as an example.</abstract></paper>