<paper id="1784115556"><title>Indexing the current positions of moving objects using the lazy update R-tree</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="Sch. of Electr. Eng. &amp; Comput. Sci., Seoul Nat. Univ., South Korea#TAB#" id="2114011712">Dongseop Kwon</author><author org="Sch. of Electr. Eng. &amp; Comput. Sci., Seoul Nat. Univ., South Korea#TAB#" id="2981010927">Sangjun Lee</author><author org="Sch. of Electr. Eng. &amp; Comput. Sci., Seoul Nat. Univ., South Korea#TAB#" id="2188342900">Sukho Lee</author></authors><n_citation>147</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1553193704</reference><reference>1758702441</reference><reference>1771592512</reference><reference>1796251476</reference><reference>1872366378</reference><reference>1979207937</reference><reference>1982042357</reference><reference>2046144220</reference><reference>2055385473</reference><reference>2101429492</reference><reference>2106642566</reference><reference>2118269922</reference><reference>2141394101</reference><reference>2149921886</reference><reference>2151135734</reference><reference>2158713459</reference></references><venue id="1134031032" type="C">Mobile Data Management</venue><doi>10.1109/MDM.2002.994387</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44502">Mobile computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.54582">R-tree</keyword><keyword weight="0.5789">Minimum bounding rectangle</keyword><keyword weight="0.44891">Wireless</keyword><keyword weight="0.45588">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.50464">Tree (data structure)</keyword><keyword weight="0.50155">Search engine indexing</keyword><keyword weight="0.44346">Computer network</keyword><keyword weight="0.45963">Linear function</keyword><keyword weight="0.5193">Spatial database</keyword><keyword weight="0.45732">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><abstract>With the rapid advances of wireless communications and positioning techniques, tracking the positions of moving objects is becoming increasingly feasible and necessary. Traditional spatial index structures are not suitable for storing these positions because of numerous update operations. To reduce the number of update operations, many existing approaches use a linear function to describe the movements of objects. In many real applications, however, the movements of objects are too complicated to be represented as a simple linear function. In this case, such approaches based on a linear function cannot reduce update cost efficiently. In this paper we propose a novel R-tree based indexing technique called LUR-tree. This technique updates the structure of the index only when an object moves out of the corresponding MBR (minimum bounding rectangle). If a new position of an object is in the MBR, it changes only the position of the object in the leaf node. It can update the position of the object quickly and reduce update cost greatly. Since it is based on the R-tree, the LUR-tree also uses the same algorithms to process various types of queries as the R-tree. We present the experimental results which show that our technique outperforms other techniques.</abstract></paper>