<paper id="1963871081"><title>Towards dissolution of the IS research debate: from polarization to polarity</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="University College cork, Ireland" id="2567530875">Brian Fitzgerald</author><author org="IS Research Centre, University of Salford, UK" id="2015537985">Debra Howcroft</author></authors><n_citation>121</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1498245362</reference><reference>1527353115</reference><reference>1968847360</reference><reference>2033469757</reference><reference>2073849932</reference><reference>2122418187</reference><reference>2128992662</reference><reference>2135492276</reference></references><venue id="135086714" type="J">Journal of Information Technology</venue><doi>10.1057/jit.1998.9</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.4815">Argument</keyword><keyword weight="0.45723">Isolationism</keyword><keyword weight="0.46586">Dichotomy</keyword><keyword weight="0.4675">Soft systems methodology</keyword><keyword weight="0.4276">Sociology</keyword><keyword weight="0.50323">Pluralism (political theory)</keyword><keyword weight="0.43841">Strategic information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.40432">Management science</keyword><keyword weight="0.4639">Metaphor</keyword><keyword weight="0.4308">Supremacism</keyword></keywords><publisher>Palgrave Macmillan, London</publisher><abstract>The debate between ‘hard’ and ‘soft’ research approaches continues in the IS field, but with little prospect of resolution. The debate is typically characterized by tendentious arguments as advocates from each approach offer a somewhat one-sided condemnation of the counterpart from the inimical research tradition. This paper begins by relating two fictitious tales which serve to highlight the futility of research conducted at the extremity of each research approach. The dichotomies which characterize these rival factions are also summarized. The debate is then framed in terms of the polarization problem whereby IS researchers are divided geographically and paradigmatically into ‘hard’ and ‘soft’ camps. A variety of different strategies have been proposed for resolving the debate and these are discussed in detail. They are grouped into four categories, referred to as supremacism, isolationism, integration, and pluralism. Finally, the paper contends that the debate cannot be resolved, and offers the metaphor of magnetic polarity as a means of reflecting this. The paper concludes by arguing that it would be more appropriate to recast the debate at a macro level in order to accommodate different research agenda and recognize the strengths within each tradition.</abstract></paper>