<paper id="1518250450"><title>Inter-operability of Workflow Applications: Local Criteria for Global Soundness</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="Humboldt-UniversitäT Zu Berlin" id="1994860295">Ekkart Kindler</author><author org="Humboldt-UniversitäT Zu Berlin" id="2138666784">Axel Martens</author><author org="Humboldt-UniversitäT Zu Berlin" id="531013306">Wolfgang Reisig</author></authors><n_citation>95</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>80370608</reference><reference>1517193498</reference><reference>1998017916</reference><reference>2162868766</reference></references><venue id="1152238068" type="C">Business Process Management</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-45594-9_15</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47952">Sequence diagram</keyword><keyword weight="0.67561">Workflow technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.51531">Business process</keyword><keyword weight="0.45573">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46535">Deadlock</keyword><keyword weight="0.46563">Operability</keyword><keyword weight="0.6336">Workflow application</keyword><keyword weight="0.53717">Soundness</keyword><keyword weight="0.60526">Workflow</keyword><keyword weight="0.45529">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Automatic analysis techniques for business processes are crucial for todayu0027s workflow applications. Since business processes are rapidly changing, only fully automatic techniques can detect processes which might cause deadlocks or :[30],"a complete workflow application, however, is much too complex to be performed fully automatically. Therefore, techniques for analyzing single processes in isolation and corresponding soundness criteria have been proposed. Though these techniques may detect errors such as deadlocks or congestion, problems arising from an incorrect inter-operation with other processes are completely ignored. The situation becomes even worse for cross-organizational workflow applications, where some processes are not even available for analysis due to confidentiality :[104],"propose :[30],"a technique which allows to detect but :[30],"a few errors of workflow applications which arise from incorrect inter-operation of workflows. To this end, the dynamics of the inter-operation of different workflows must be specified by the help of sequence diagrams. Then, each single workflow can be checked for local soundness with respect to this specification. If each single workflow is locally sound, :[30],"a composition theorem guarantees global soundness of the complete workflow application. This way, each organization can check its own workflows without knowing the workflows of other organizations--still global soundness is guaranteed.</abstract></paper>