<paper id="1919478738"><title>A multi-language text-to-speech module</title><year>1982</year><authors><author org="Department of Speech, Communication and Music Acoustics, KTH, Stockholm, Sweden" id="2172253309">R. Carlson</author><author org="" id="2086159839">B. Granstrom</author><author org="" id="1945887708">S. Hunnicutt</author></authors><n_citation>57</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1895213947</reference><reference>2133630471</reference></references><venue id="1121227772" type="C">International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing</venue><doi>10.1109/ICASSP.1982.1171433</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.53987">Speech processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.51666">Words per minute</keyword><keyword weight="0.52443">Cross compiler</keyword><keyword weight="0.55553">Speech synthesis</keyword><keyword weight="0.4615">Programming language</keyword><keyword weight="0.45674">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48432">Digital signal processor</keyword><keyword weight="0.50797">Microprocessor</keyword><keyword weight="0.58438">Assembly language</keyword><keyword weight="0.53289">Vocabulary</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>Recent advances in microprocessor, memory and signal processor technology have made it feasible to put complete speech processing equipment into a portable form. At our laboratory a higher-level programming language has been developed that is especially suitable for rule description of linguistic processes. Text-to-speech systems for several languages have been written in this framework. Now also a cross compiler has been designed for the 16-bit microprocessor MC 68000, which makes transportation of programs from our research computer trivial. The language-independent parts of the program for the microprocessor are written in efficient assembler code. Special hardware development has resulted in a portable, battery-operated unit that is capable of transforming text-to-speech at a speaking rate of 250 wpm (words per minute). This opens up the possibility of speech options on computer terminals, portable, large vocabulary talking language translators, etc. The module has been tried in several applications for people with communication handicaps.</abstract></paper>