<paper id="1580766749"><title>A Task-Specific Ontology for the Application and Critiquing of Time-Oriented Clinical Guidelines</title><year>1997</year><authors><author org="Stanford, University" id="700636827">Yuval Shahar</author><author org="Vienna University of Technology." id="193994343">Silvia Miksch</author><author org="Stanford, University" id="2127268142">Peter Johnson</author></authors><n_citation>20</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>135956032</reference><reference>1552135236</reference><reference>1967931674</reference><reference>1979045129</reference><reference>1999014868</reference><reference>2005329829</reference><reference>2016449808</reference><reference>2040784953</reference><reference>2054680307</reference><reference>2130182605</reference><reference>2130455574</reference><reference>2163883713</reference><reference>2166957636</reference></references><venue id="1127759574" type="C">Artificial Intelligence in Medicine in Europe</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0029435</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.57516">Procedural knowledge</keyword><keyword weight="0.52062">Ontology</keyword><keyword weight="0.4289">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.45742">Suite</keyword><keyword weight="0.44328">Reuse</keyword><keyword weight="0.44405">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45813">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.45075">Medical record</keyword><keyword weight="0.54803">Guideline</keyword><keyword weight="0.47042">Schema (psychology)</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Clinical guidelines reuse existing clinical procedural knowledge while leaving room for flexibility by the care provider applying that knowledge. Guidelines can be viewed as generic skeletal-plan schemata that are instantiated and refined dynamically by the care provider over significant periods of time and in highly dynamic environments. In the Asgaard project, we are investigating a set of tasks that support the application of clinical guidelines by a care provider other than the guidelineu0027s designer. We are focusing on application of the guideline, recognition of care providersu0027 intentions from their actions, and critique of care providersu0027 actions given the guideline and the patientu0027s medical record. We are developing methods that perform these tasks in multiple clinical domains, given an instance of a properly represented clinical guideline and an electronic medical patient record. In this paper, we point out the precise domain-specific knowledge required by each method, such as the explicit intentions of the guideline designer (represented as temporal patterns to be achieved or avoided). We present a machine-readable language, called Asbru, to represent and to annotate guidelines based on the taskspecific ontology. We also introduce an automated tool for acquisition of clinical guidelines based on the same ontology; the tool was developed using the PROTEGE-II frameworku0027s suite of tools.</abstract></paper>