<paper id="1870669718"><title>Discovery of Spatial Association Rules in Geographic Information Databases</title><year>1995</year><authors><author org="Simon  Fraser University" id="2279782171">Krzysztof Koperski</author><author org="Simon  Fraser University" id="2121939561">Jiawei Han</author></authors><n_citation>611</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1571035772</reference><reference>1575476631</reference><reference>1578959085</reference><reference>1581321178</reference><reference>1844476468</reference><reference>1967617712</reference><reference>2005314985</reference><reference>2058903936</reference><reference>2074429597</reference><reference>2118269922</reference><reference>2129150932</reference><reference>2161109697</reference><reference>2166559705</reference></references><venue id="" type="">SSD '95 Proceedings of the 4th International Symposium on Advances in Spatial Databases</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-60159-7_4</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.58769">Geospatial analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.60432">Spatial analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.46123">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.45952">Information retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.43874">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Spatial data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Implicit knowledge</keyword><keyword weight="0.61002">Association rule learning</keyword><keyword weight="0.40696">Predicate (grammar)</keyword><keyword weight="0.43222">Database</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Concept hierarchy</keyword><keyword weight="0.42745">Computation</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><abstract>Spatial data mining, i.e., discovery of interesting, implicit knowledge in spatial databases, is an important task for understanding and use of spatial data- and knowledge-bases. In this paper, an efficient method for mining strong spatial association rules in geographic information databases is proposed and studied. A spatial association rule is a rule indicating certain association relationship among a set of spatial and possibly some nonspatial predicates. A strong rule indicates that the patterns in the rule have relatively frequent occurrences in the database and strong implication relationships. Several optimization techniques are explored, including a two-step spatial computation technique (approximate computation on large sets, and refined computations on small promising patterns), shared processing in the derivation of large predicates at multiple concept levels, etc. Our analysis shows that interesting association rules can be discovered efficiently in large spatial databases.</abstract></paper>