<paper id="1979064760"><title>Individual differences and conceptual models in training novice users</title><year>1989</year><authors><author org="Department of Decision Sciences and Information Systems, College of Business Administration, Florida International University, University Park, Miami, FL#TAB#" id="2281147955">Maung K. Sein</author><author org="Department of Management, College of Business Administration, University of Georgia, Athens, GA" id="2302943154">Robert P. Bostrom</author></authors><n_citation>131</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1969640700</reference><reference>1986587794</reference><reference>2008084531</reference><reference>2026161499</reference><reference>2038564082</reference><reference>2042316632</reference><reference>2049650335</reference><reference>2059311901</reference><reference>2100625161</reference><reference>2169294099</reference></references><venue id="2481449237" type="J">Human-Computer Interaction</venue><doi>10.1207/s15327051hci0403_2</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Mental model</keyword><keyword weight="0.56665">Conceptual model</keyword><keyword weight="0.46765">Empirical evidence</keyword><keyword weight="0.43639">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.44834">Psychology</keyword><keyword weight="0.55689">Cognition</keyword></keywords><publisher>L. Erlbaum Associates Inc.</publisher><abstract>Although there is a strong theoretical basis for concluding that conceptual models are effective in aiding users build mental models of computer systems, very little empirical evidence exists to support such a conclusion. Frequently, the effect has been weak. Subjects trained with a conceptual model often perform better than control group subjects in learning tests, but seldom at a statistically significant level. One possible reason for this is the influence of individual differences such as basic cognitive abilities. This study examined the influence of two cognitive variables - visual ability and learning mode - in the mental model formation process of novice users of an electronic mail filing system. We compared the effectiveness of two types of conceptual models-analogical and abstract. It was found that high-visual subjects performed significantly better than low-visual subjects. Abstract learners also performed better than concrete learners.</abstract></paper>