<paper id="1769219634"><title>Awareness, Negation and Logical Omniscience</title><year>1990</year><authors><author org="University of Amsterdam" id="2141621278">Zhisheng Huang</author><author org="University of Amsterdam" id="2209334507">Karen L. Kwast</author></authors><n_citation>9</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1497906457</reference><reference>1525141167</reference><reference>1588085858</reference><reference>1994227541</reference><reference>2091343125</reference><reference>2099143991</reference><reference>2148717074</reference></references><venue id="" type="">JELIA '90 Proceedings of the European Workshop on Logics in AI</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0018448</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.55198">Intuitionistic logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.57296">Epistemic modal logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.49167">Kripke structure</keyword><keyword weight="0.57627">Negation</keyword><keyword weight="0.53848">Omniscience</keyword><keyword weight="0.49785">Closure (mathematics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.40918">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Intuition</keyword><keyword weight="0.56348">Multimodal logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.40702">Natural language processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.43777">Epistemology</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>General Epistemic Logics suffer from the problem of logical omniscience, which is that an agentu0027s knowledge and beliefs are closed under implication. There have been many attempts to solve the problem of logical omniscience. However, according to our intuition, sometimes an agentu0027s knowledge and beliefs are indeed closed under implication. Based on the notion of awareness, we introduce two kinds of negations: general negation and strong negation. Moreover, four kinds of implications, general implication, strong implication, weak implication, and semi-strong implication, are introduced to correspond with the two kinds of negations. In our logics of regular awareness, explicit beliefs are not necessarily closed under general implication, which means that agents are not logically omniscient. However, explicit beliefs are closed under strong implication and semi-strong implication, which captures an intuitive closure property of beliefs.</abstract></paper>