<paper id="1528438050"><title>Software protection: myth or reality?</title><year>1985</year><authors><author org="Sandia National Laboratory;" id="2281442694">James R. Gosler</author></authors><n_citation>26</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2045071956</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-39799-X_13</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.55933">Software deployment</keyword><keyword weight="0.4655">Hardware security module</keyword><keyword weight="0.46495">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.43683">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.50725">Software analysis pattern</keyword><keyword weight="0.59957">Software security assurance</keyword><keyword weight="0.58169">Commercial software</keyword><keyword weight="0.50429">Software</keyword><keyword weight="0.42636">Denial</keyword><keyword weight="0.43801">Government</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Staggering amounts of commercial software are marketed to fulfill needs from the PC explosion. Unfortunately, such software is trivial to duplicate! From the vendorsu0027 viewpoint a way to protect profit is needed. Typically, they have resorted to various schemes that attempt to inhibit the duplication process.Although protection of future profit is important, so is protection against current loss. Commercial and business related software must be adequately protected lest data be stolen or manipulated. However, more important than any of these classes is protection of government computer resources, especially classified and operational software and data. Loss of control in this realm could be detrimental to national security.This paper addresses current technologies employed in protection schemes: signatures (magnetic and physical) on floppy disks, Software Analysis Denial (SAD), Hardware security Devices (HSD), and Technology Denial Concepts (TDC) are presented, with an emphasis on SAD. Advantages and disadvantages of these schemes will be clarified.</abstract></paper>