<paper id="1849530807"><title>Secure Copyright Protection Techniques for Digital Images</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="security engineering ag" id="1458527247">Alexander Herrigel</author><author org="Univ of Geneva" id="2033246199">Joseph รณ Ruanaidh</author><author org="security engineering ag" id="2202890400">Holger Petersen</author><author org="Univ of Geneva" id="2118576730">Shelby Pereira</author><author org="Univ of Geneva" id="2097699192">Thierry Pun</author></authors><n_citation>94</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>79957971</reference><reference>1522884824</reference><reference>1571441458</reference><reference>1660562555</reference><reference>1838947981</reference><reference>2080302839</reference><reference>2092911763</reference><reference>2125671325</reference></references><venue id="1175805213" type="C">Information Hiding</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-49380-8_13</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44273">Computer vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.63782">Digital watermarking</keyword><keyword weight="0.50236">Cryptographic protocol</keyword><keyword weight="0.49572">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.4271">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.51666">Information protection policy</keyword><keyword weight="0.50575">Image processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.52931">Digital image</keyword><keyword weight="0.67123">Watermark</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.53236">Copy protection</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>This paper presents a new approach for the secure and robust copyright protection of digital images. A system for generating digital watermarks and for trading watermarked images is described. The system is based on a new watermarking technique, which is robust against image transformation techniques such as compression, rotation, translation, scaling and cropping. It uses modulation of the magnitude components in Fourier space to embed a watermark and an accompanying template and, during watermark extraction, reads a template in the log polar transform of the frequency domain. The template is used for analyzing scaling and rotation suffered by the watermarked stego-image. The detection of the watermarks is also possible without any need for the original cover-image. In addition, the system applies asymmetric cryptographic protocols for different purposes, namely embedding/detecting the watermark and transferring watermarked data. The public key technique is applied for the construction of a one-way watermark embedding and the verification function to identify and prove the uniqueness of the watermark. Legal dispute resolution is supported for the multiple watermarking of a digital image without revealing the confidential keying information.</abstract></paper>