<paper id="1559738570"><title>On the randomness of Legendre and Jacobi sequences</title><year>1990</year><authors><author org="Aarhus University," id="2682364181">Ivan Damgård</author></authors><n_citation>61</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1484206430</reference><reference>1594625647</reference><reference>2068149596</reference><reference>2741949592</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/0-387-34799-2_13</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.52609">Prime (order theory)</keyword><keyword weight="0.54579">Legendre's equation</keyword><keyword weight="0.45562">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.5712">Quadratic residue</keyword><keyword weight="0.45123">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.42274">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.56074">Legendre symbol</keyword><keyword weight="0.53208">Legendre function</keyword><keyword weight="0.51894">Pseudorandom number generator</keyword><keyword weight="0.52006">Randomness</keyword><keyword weight="0.52837">Discrete logarithm</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, New York, NY</publisher><abstract>Most of the work done in cryptography in the last few years depend on the hardness of a few specific number theoretic problems, such as factoring, discrete log, etc. Since no one has so far been able to prove that these problems are genuinely hard, it is clearly of interest to find new candidates for hard problems. In this paper, we propose such a new candidate problem. namely the problem of predicting a sequence of consecutive Legendre (Jacobi) symbols modulo a prime (composite), when the starting point and possibly also the prime is unknown. Clearly, if this problem turns out to be hard, it can be used directly to construct a cryptographically strong pseudorandom bitgenerator. Its complexity seems to be unrelated to any of the well known number theoretical problems, whence it may be able to survive the discovery of fast factoring or discrete log algorithms. Although the randomness of Legendre sequences has part of the folklore in number theory at least since the thirties, they have apparently not been considered for use in cryptography before.</abstract></paper>