<paper id="1488971269"><title>An Empirical Analysis of Design Choices in Neighborhood-Based Collaborative Filtering Algorithms</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="Department of Computer Science, Oregon State University, 102 Dearborn Hall, Corvallis, OR 97331-3202, USA. herlock@cs.orst.edu#TAB#" id="2681276027">Jon Herlocker</author><author org="GroupLens Research Project, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, University of Minnesota, USA. konstan@cs.umn.edu#TAB#" id="2002483998">Joseph A. Konstan</author><author org="GroupLens Research Project, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, University of Minnesota, USA. riedl@cs.umn.edu#TAB#" id="1986422195">John Riedl</author></authors><n_citation>484</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1532852017</reference><reference>1552227627</reference><reference>1673941785</reference><reference>1718512272</reference><reference>1973812756</reference><reference>1996283866</reference><reference>2028036481</reference><reference>2030144199</reference><reference>2085937320</reference><reference>2109992782</reference><reference>2110325612</reference><reference>2117354486</reference><reference>2124029832</reference><reference>2124591829</reference><reference>2155106456</reference></references><venue id="79460864" type="J">Information Retrieval</venue><doi>10.1023/A:1020443909834</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47175">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.5014">Weighting</keyword><keyword weight="0.46428">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.51287">Systems design</keyword><keyword weight="0.47953">Search engine indexing</keyword><keyword weight="0.47117">Implementation</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.49184">Empirical research</keyword><keyword weight="0.67687">Recommender system</keyword><keyword weight="0.67385">Collaborative filtering</keyword><keyword weight="0.47625">Filter (signal processing)</keyword><keyword weight="0.4421">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.47623">Machine learning</keyword></keywords><publisher>INFORMATION RETRIEVAL</publisher><abstract>Collaborative filtering systems predict a useru0027s interest in new items based on the recommendations of other people with similar interests. Instead of performing content indexing or content analysis, collaborative filtering systems rely entirely on interest ratings from members of a participating community. Since predictions are based on human ratings, collaborative filtering systems have the potential to provide filtering based on complex attributes, such as quality, taste, or aesthetics. Many implementations of collaborative filtering apply some variation of the neighborhood-based prediction algorithm. Many variations of similarity metrics, weighting approaches, combination measures, and rating normalization have appeared in each implementation. For these parameters and others, there is no consensus as to which choice of technique is most appropriate for what situations, nor how significant an effect on accuracy each parameter has. Consequently, every person implementing a collaborative filtering system must make hard design choices with little guidance. This article provides a set of recommendations to guide design of neighborhood-based prediction systems, based on the results of an empirical study. We apply an analysis framework that divides the neighborhood-based prediction approach into three components and then examines variants of the key parameters in each component. The three components identified are similarity computation, neighbor selection, and rating combination.</abstract></paper>