<paper id="1576314536"><title>Maintaining Security in the Presence of Transient Faults</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="Weizmann Institute,#TAB#" id="687553606">Ran Canetti</author><author org="IBM T.J. Watson research center" id="2178836961">Amir Herzberg</author></authors><n_citation>91</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1509967662</reference><reference>1542059364</reference><reference>1588297800</reference><reference>1967263393</reference><reference>2009125170</reference><reference>2012713361</reference><reference>2083798989</reference><reference>2091020476</reference><reference>2103228939</reference><reference>2107515440</reference><reference>2117362057</reference><reference>2148156724</reference><reference>2149929743</reference><reference>2169127491</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-48658-5_38</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.52495">Dictionary attack</keyword><keyword weight="0.44402">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45781">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.50253">Random oracle</keyword><keyword weight="0.49273">Adversary</keyword><keyword weight="0.4934">Randomness</keyword><keyword weight="0.41742">Computation</keyword><keyword weight="0.48522">Pseudorandom number generator</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Consider a multiparty system where parties may occasionally be "infected" by malicious, coordinated agents, called viruses. After some time the virus is expelled and the party wishes to regain its security. Since the leaving virus knows the entire contents of the infected partyu0027s memory, a source of "fresh" randomness seems essential for regaining security (e.g., for selecting new keys). However, such an "on-line" source of randomness may not be always readily available.We describe a scheme which, using randomness only at the beginning of the computation, supplies each party with a new pseudorandom number at each round of communication. Each generated number is unpredictable by an adversary controlling the viruses, even if the party was infected in previous rounds. Our scheme is valid as long as in each round there is at least one noninfected party, and some of the communication links are secure.We describe an important application of our scheme to secure sign-on protocols.</abstract></paper>