<paper id="1868359205"><title>Symbolic Algorithms for Infinite-State Games</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="University of California" id="2129359981">Luca de Alfaro</author><author org="University of California" id="2707196735">Thomas A. Henzinger</author><author org="University of California" id="2156286033">Rupak Majumdar</author></authors><n_citation>62</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>135426567</reference><reference>1481109946</reference><reference>1517157359</reference><reference>1525028586</reference><reference>1577248548</reference><reference>1606443439</reference><reference>1971138850</reference><reference>2015640848</reference><reference>2017759899</reference><reference>2021473546</reference><reference>2060095702</reference><reference>2101508170</reference><reference>2130773092</reference></references><venue id="1145706541" type="C">International Conference on Concurrency Theory</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-44685-0_36</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.62134">Combinatorial game theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.49804">Equivalence relation</keyword><keyword weight="0.44867">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.44861">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.46632">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48658">Reachability</keyword><keyword weight="0.49932">Equivalence (measure theory)</keyword><keyword weight="0.6074">Symbolic data analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.48223">Hybrid system</keyword><keyword weight="0.50589">State space</keyword><keyword weight="0.47671">Discrete system</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>A procedure for the analysis of state spaces is called symbolic if it manipulates not individual states, but sets of states that are represented by constraints. Such a procedure can be used for the analysis of infinite state spaces, provided termination is guaranteed. We present symbolic procedures, and corresponding termination criteria, for the solution of infinite-state games, which occur in the control and modular verification of infinite-state systems. To characterize the termination of symbolic procedures for solving infinite-state games, we classify these game structures into four increasingly restrictive categories: 1. Class 1 consists of infinite-state structures for which all safety and reachability games can be solved. 2. Class 2 consists of infinite-state structures for which all ω-regular games can be solved. 3. Class 3 consists of infinite-state structures for which all nested positive boolean combinations of ω-regular games can be solved. 4. Class 4 consists of infinite-state structures for which all nested boolean combinations of ω-regular games can be solved. We give a structural characterization for each class, using equivalence relations on the state spaces of games which range from game versions of trace equivalence to a game version of bisimilarity. We provide infinite-state examples for all four classes of games from control problems for hybrid systems. We conclude by presenting symbolic algorithms for the synthesis of winning strategies ("controller synthesis") for infinite-state games with arbitrary u-regular objectives, and prove termination over all class-2 structures. This settles, in particular, the symbolic controller synthesis problem for rectangular hybrid systems.</abstract></paper>