<paper id="1544442970"><title>The Persona Effect: How Substantial Is It?</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="German Research Centre for Artificial Intelligence (DFKI" id="416256883">Susanne Van Mulken</author><author org="German Research Centre for Artificial Intelligence (DFKI" id="2099360608">Elisabeth André</author><author org="German Research Centre for Artificial Intelligence (DFKI" id="2150939628">Jochen Müller</author></authors><n_citation>200</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1966279822</reference><reference>1971238833</reference><reference>2020773597</reference><reference>2024817162</reference><reference>2036653166</reference><reference>2075677013</reference><reference>2101698942</reference><reference>2117836007</reference><reference>2121965518</reference><reference>2156897926</reference><reference>2336741951</reference></references><venue id="" type="">HCI '98 Proceedings of HCI on People and Computers XIII</venue><doi>10.1007/978-1-4471-3605-7_4</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.56059">Credibility</keyword><keyword weight="0.40576">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.53414">Persona</keyword><keyword weight="0.46558">Cognitive psychology</keyword><keyword weight="0.43989">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Learning experience</keyword><keyword weight="0.4902">Perception</keyword><keyword weight="0.49667">Recall</keyword><keyword weight="0.5143">Empirical research</keyword><keyword weight="0.52043">Comprehension</keyword><keyword weight="0.47444">Software development</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, London</publisher><abstract>Personification of interface agents has been speculated to have several advantages, such as a positive effect on agent credibility and on the perception of learning experience. However, important questions less often addressed so far are what effect personification has on more objective measures, such as comprehension and recall, and furthermore, under what circumstances this effect (if any) occurs. We performed an empirical study with adult participants to examine the effect of the Ppp Persona not only on subjective but also on objective measures. In addition, we tested it both with technical and non-technical domain information. The results of the study indicate that the data from the subjective measures support the so called persona effect for the technical information but not for non-technical information. With regard to the objective measures, however, neither a positive nor a negative effect could be found. Implications for software development are discussed.</abstract></paper>