<paper id="1546788865"><title>The TELLTALE Dynamic Hypertext Environment: Approaches to Scalability</title><year>1997</year><authors><author org="U.S. Department of Defense" id="2227231817">Claudia Pearce</author><author org="Univ. of Maryland, Baltimore County#TAB#" id="2168190067">Ethan L. Miller</author></authors><n_citation>22</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1605089929</reference><reference>1956559956</reference><reference>1972508483</reference><reference>1979959238</reference><reference>2010027198</reference><reference>2016768890</reference><reference>2039116870</reference><reference>2050778532</reference><reference>2058929792</reference><reference>2061118645</reference><reference>2066766178</reference><reference>2068805526</reference><reference>2200839525</reference></references><venue id="2532863000" type="C">ACM Conference on Hypertext</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0023962</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46822">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.60557">Hypertext</keyword><keyword weight="0.45489">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46779">Natural language processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.55018">Document retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.48215">Data structure</keyword><keyword weight="0.45585">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.46991">Information retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.51138">Text corpus</keyword><keyword weight="0.53664">Optical character recognition</keyword><keyword weight="0.51214">User interface</keyword><keyword weight="0.47971">Scalability</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><abstract>Methods and tools for finding documents relevant to a useru0027s needs in document corpora can be found in the information retrieval, library science, and hypertext communities. Typically, these systems provide retrieval capabilities for fairly static corpora, their algorithms are dependent on the language for which they are written, e.g. English, and they donu0027t perform well when presented with misspelled words or text that has been degraded by OCR (optical character recognition) techniques. In this chapter, we present the TELLTALE system. TELLTALE is a dynamic hypertext environment that provides full-text search from a hypertextstyle user interface for text corpora that may be garbled by OCR or transmission errors, and that may contain languages other than English by using several techniques based on n-grams (n character sequences of text). In this chapter, we identify methods and techniques that we have applied to the n-gram data structures. We also discuss algorithms that we used to enhance the scalability of the TELLTALE Dynamic Hypertext System.</abstract></paper>