<paper id="1572559454"><title>Secure Mobile Agent Using Strong Non-designated Proxy Signature</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="ICU (Information and Communications Univ.)" id="2166319967">Byoungcheon Lee</author><author org="Information Security Technology Division ETRI (Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute)" id="2259029503">Heesun Kim</author><author org="ICU (Information and Communications Univ.)" id="2421077175">Kwangjo Kim</author></authors><n_citation>198</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1492137673</reference><reference>1495984676</reference><reference>1570296326</reference><reference>1591349227</reference><reference>1602560985</reference><reference>1660562555</reference><reference>2166462813</reference></references><venue id="1131830996" type="C">Australasian Conference on Information Security and Privacy</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-47719-5_37</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Proxy signature</keyword><keyword weight="0.41592">Decentralised system</keyword><keyword weight="0.42888">CPU cache</keyword><keyword weight="0.52143">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.43697">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.42966">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.57434">Mobile agent</keyword><keyword weight="0.52895">Public-key cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.61935">Reverse proxy</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>It is expected that mobile agent will be widely used for electronic commerce as an important key technology. If a mobile agent can sign a message in a remote server on behalf of a customer without exposingh is/her private key, it can be used not only to search for special products or services, but also to make a contract with a remote server. To construct mobile agents, [KBC00] used an RSA-based undetachable signature scheme, but it does not provide serveru0027s non-repudiation because the undetachable signature does not contain serveru0027s signature.Mobile agent is a very good application example of proxy signature, and the undetachable signature can be considered as an example of proxy signature. In this paper we show that secure mobile agent can be constructed using strong non-designated proxy signature [LKK01] which represents both the original signeru0027s (customer) and the proxy signeru0027s (remote server) signatures. We provide RSA-based and Schnorr-based constructions of secure mobile agent, and moreover we show that the Schnorr-based scheme can be used very efficiently in multi-proxy mobile agent situation.</abstract></paper>