<paper id="1969506361"><title>Designing and integrating user interfaces of geographic database applications</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="Freie Universität Berlin, Institut für Informatik, D-14195 Berlin, Germany#TAB#" id="59363697">Agnès Voisard</author></authors><n_citation>11</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>155796068</reference><reference>1491937094</reference><reference>1528311867</reference><reference>1588194222</reference><reference>1788850909</reference><reference>1804948232</reference><reference>1945128294</reference><reference>2001657718</reference><reference>2015612071</reference><reference>2072627547</reference></references><venue id="1134066369" type="C">Advanced Visual Interfaces</venue><doi>10.1145/192309.192339</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.42951">Architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Visual interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.45835">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.464">Human–computer interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.52064">Graphical user interface</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Geographic database</keyword><keyword weight="0.48129">Modular design</keyword><keyword weight="0.56559">User interface</keyword><keyword weight="0.45772">Grid</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Visual placement</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>In this paper, we investigate the problem of designing graphical geographic database user interfaces (GDUIs) and of integrating them into a database management system (DBMS). Geographic applications may vary widely but they all have common aspects due to the spatial component of their data: Geographic data are not standard and they require appropriate tools for (i) editing them (i.e., display and modify) and (ii) querying them. The conceptual problems encountered in designing GDUIs are partly due to the merger of two independent fields, geographic DBMSs on the one hand, and graphical user interfaces (GUIs) on the other hand. Although these areas have evolved considerably during the past ten years, only little effort has been made to understand the problems of connecting them in order to efficiently manipulate geographic data on a display. This issue raises the general problem of coupling a DBMS with specialized modules (in particular, the problem of strong vs. weak integration), and more generally the role of a DBMS in a specific application. After giving the functionalities that a GDUI should provide, we study the possible conceptual integrations between a GUI and a DBMS. Finally, a map editing model as well as a general and modular GDUI architecture are presented.</abstract></paper>