<paper id="1981893977"><title>Fast multilevel implementation of recursive spectral bisection for partitioning unstructured problems</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="NASA" id="2127234183">Stephen T. Barnard</author><author org="" id="2118805955">Horst D. Simon</author></authors><n_citation>423</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1575155528</reference><reference>1965057580</reference><reference>1966461475</reference><reference>1968128373</reference><reference>2069037000</reference><reference>2096159022</reference><reference>2125531986</reference><reference>2127374884</reference><reference>2127605247</reference><reference>2158598102</reference><reference>2161455936</reference></references><venue id="11065456" type="J">Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</venue><doi>10.1002/cpe.4330060203</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.50918">Data structure</keyword><keyword weight="0.48844">Polygon mesh</keyword><keyword weight="0.49674">Load balancing (computing)</keyword><keyword weight="0.45156">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47981">Parallel computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.55638">Distributed memory</keyword><keyword weight="0.44493">Computational fluid dynamics</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Interprocessor communication</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Recursive spectral bisection</keyword><keyword weight="0.46241">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.49679">Computation</keyword></keywords><publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd</publisher><abstract>SUMMARY If problems involving unstructured meshes are to be solved efficiently on distributed-memory parallel computers, the meshes must be partitioned and distributed across processors in a way that balances the computational load and minimizes communication. The recursive spectral bisection method (RSB) has been shown to be very effective for such partitioning problems compared to alternative methods, but RSB in its simplest form is expensive. Here a multilevel version of RSB is introduced that attains about an order-of-magnitude improvement in run time on typical examples. 1. INTRODUCTION Unstructured meshes are used in several large-scale scientific and engineering problems, including finite-volume methods for computational fluid dynamics and finite-element methods for structural analysis. If unstructured problems such as these are to be solved on distributed-memory parallel computers, their data structures must be partitioned and distributed across processors; if they are to be solved efficiently, the partitioning must niaximize load balance and minimize interprocessor communication. Recently, the recursive spectral bisection method (RSB)[l] has been shown to be very effective for such partitioning problems compared to alternative methods. Unfortunately, RSB in its simplest form is expensive. We shall describe a multilevel version of RSB that attains about im order-of-magnitude improvement in run time on typical examples.</abstract></paper>