<paper id="22271197"><title>Break our steganographic system: the ins and outs of organizing BOSS</title><year>2011</year><authors><author org="CNRS, LAGIS, Lille, France#TAB#" id="2302629638">Patrick Bas</author><author org="State University of New York at Binghamton, NY#TAB#" id="1920205315">Tomáš Filler</author><author org="Czech Technical University in Prague, Czech Republic" id="684590367">Tomáš Pevný</author></authors><n_citation>402</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>29798142</reference><reference>1590456553</reference><reference>1713630528</reference><reference>1955882805</reference><reference>1982922705</reference><reference>2030601587</reference><reference>2031466562</reference><reference>2106663508</reference><reference>2134527668</reference><reference>2154026545</reference><reference>2165049148</reference></references><venue id="1175805213" type="C">Information Hiding</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-642-24178-9_5</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45313">Acronym</keyword><keyword weight="0.45675">Steganography</keyword><keyword weight="0.44382">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.44498">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.52396">CONTEST</keyword><keyword weight="0.50514">Boss</keyword><keyword weight="0.50759">Steganalysis</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>This paper summarizes the first international challenge on steganalysis called BOSS (an acronym for Break Our Steganographic System). We explain the motivations behind the organization of the contest, its rules together with reasons for them, and the steganographic algorithm developed for the contest. Since the image databases created for the contest significantly influenced the development of the contest, they are described in a great detail. Paper also presents detailed analysis of results submitted to the challenge. One of the main difficulty the participants had to deal with was the discrepancy between training and testing source of images - the so-called cover-source mismatch, which forced the participants to design steganalyzers robust w.r.t. a specific source of images. We also point to other practical issues related to designing steganographic systems and give several suggestions for future contests in steganalysis.</abstract></paper>