<paper id="1566351760"><title>The Equi-Join Operation on a Multiprocessor Database Machine: Algorithms and the Evaluation of their Performance</title><year>1985</year><authors><author org="Northwestern University" id="2399012216">Ghassan Z. Qadah</author></authors><n_citation>19</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>82800629</reference><reference>220925779</reference><reference>1964111545</reference><reference>1970196737</reference><reference>2017495322</reference><reference>2088602658</reference><reference>2089827328</reference><reference>2124170481</reference><reference>2132692154</reference><reference>2133384222</reference><reference>2165467455</reference></references><venue id="" type="">IWDM</venue><doi>10.1007/978-1-4612-5144-6_3</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.43223">Architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.66587">Relational database</keyword><keyword weight="0.55311">Parallel algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.47129">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47142">Parallel computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.45581">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.49515">Multiprocessing</keyword><keyword weight="0.66178">Database machine</keyword><keyword weight="0.63484">Relational model</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Operation point</keyword><keyword weight="0.5277">Hash table</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, New York, NY</publisher><abstract>The equi-join operation is one of the most important operations of the relational data model. It participates in all queries which reference more than one relation. In this paper, a large set of parallel algorithms for implementing the equi-join operation on a multiprocessor database machine called MIRDM (MIchigan Relational Database Machine), is presented. An outline of a study for the performance of the proposed algorithms in carrying out the equi-Join operation on MIRDM, is also presented. The main objective of this study is twofold: the determination of the overall best performing equi-join algorithm and the investigation of the effectiveness (from the equi-join operation point of view) of performing some tuning to the architecture of MIRDM. This study shows, among others, that for a given MIRDM configuration; the overall best performing equi-join algorithm is not unique and different algorithms score the best performance depending on the characteristics of the data participating in the equi-join operation.</abstract></paper>