<paper id="1584555738"><title>A Comparison of Control Problems for Timed and Hybrid Systems</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="École centrale de Nantes" id="2025981285">Franck Cassez</author><author org="University of California" id="2707196735">Thomas A. Henzinger</author><author org="Université libre de Bruxelles" id="1979323527">Jean-François Raskin</author></authors><n_citation>83</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1555190167</reference><reference>1569051713</reference><reference>1577248548</reference><reference>1868359205</reference><reference>2004463571</reference><reference>2057842062</reference><reference>2085838366</reference><reference>2101508170</reference></references><venue id="2755881205" type="C">international workshop on Hybrid Systems: Computation and Control</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-45873-5_13</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45872">Integer</keyword><keyword weight="0.60739">Control theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.4301">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46034">Control theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.46552">Automaton</keyword><keyword weight="0.45463">A priori and a posteriori</keyword><keyword weight="0.49241">Sampling (statistics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.51976">Hybrid system</keyword><keyword weight="0.47989">Special case</keyword><keyword weight="0.42888">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.49735">Undecidable problem</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In the literature, we find several formulations of the control problem for timed and hybrid systems. We argue that formulations where a controller can cause an action at any point in dense (rational or real) time are problematic, by presenting an example where the controller must act faster and faster, yet causes no Zeno effects (say, the control actions are at times 0, 1/2, 1, 1 1/4, 2, 2 1/8, 3, 3 1/16, . . . ). Such a controller is, of course, not implementable in software. Such controllers are avoided by formulations where the controller can cause actions only at discrete (integer) points in time. While the resulting control problem is well-understood if the time unit, or "sampling rate" of the controller, is fixed a priori, we define a novel, stronger formulation: the discrete-time control problem with unknown sampling rate asks if a sampling controller exists for some sampling rate. We prove that this problem is undecidable even in the special case of timed automata.</abstract></paper>