<paper id="1726304021"><title>Efficient intrusion detection using automaton inlining</title><year>2005</year><authors><author org="Department of Computer Science, Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN USA" id="2069273547">R. Gopalakrishna</author><author org="Department of Computer Science, Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN USA" id="171783842">E.H. Spafford</author><author org="Department of Computer Science, Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN USA" id="2115991807">J. Vitek</author></authors><n_citation>57</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>34732858</reference><reference>123548525</reference><reference>1590452455</reference><reference>1600911019</reference><reference>1604221405</reference><reference>1884606608</reference><reference>1941427975</reference><reference>1947347140</reference><reference>2000194923</reference><reference>2003250112</reference><reference>2082600559</reference><reference>2106649514</reference><reference>2123886726</reference><reference>2135143063</reference><reference>2143776233</reference><reference>2167332015</reference><reference>2170973665</reference></references><venue id="1163618098" type="C">IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy</venue><doi>10.1109/SP.2005.1</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.4454">Automata theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.47096">Algorithm design</keyword><keyword weight="0.45086">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.43524">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.46818">Automaton</keyword><keyword weight="0.48293">Static analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.66038">Anomaly-based intrusion detection system</keyword><keyword weight="0.4672">Context model</keyword><keyword weight="0.64481">Intrusion detection system</keyword><keyword weight="0.47112">False positive paradox</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>Host-based intrusion detection systems attempt to identify attacks by discovering program behaviors that deviate from expected patterns. While the idea of performing behavior validation on-the-fly and terminating errant tasks as soon as a violation is detected is appealing, existing systems exhibit serious shortcomings in terms of accuracy and/or efficiency. To gain acceptance, a number of technical advances are needed. In this paper we focus on automated, conservative, intrusion detection techniques, i.e. techniques which do not require human intervention and do not suffer from false positives. We present a static analysis algorithm for constructing a flow- and context-sensitive model of a program that allows for efficient online validation. Context-sensitivity is essential to reduce the number of impossible control-flow paths accepted by the intrusion detection system because such paths provide opportunities for attackers to evade detection. An important consideration for on-the-fly intrusion detection is to reduce the performance overhead caused by monitoring. Compared to the existing approaches, our inlined automaton model (IAM) presents a good tradeoff between accuracy and performance. On a 32K line program, the monitoring overhead is negligible. While the space requirements of a naive IAM implementation can be quite high, compaction techniques can be employed to substantially reduce that footprint.</abstract></paper>