<paper id="1482087258"><title>The New Computing Archipelago: Intranet Islands of Practice</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="University of Hawaii," id="2327870015">Roberta Lamb</author><author org="University of Hawaii," id="2119264548">Elizabeth Davidson</author></authors><n_citation>46</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>39960478</reference><reference>150623189</reference><reference>1482315504</reference><reference>1499604882</reference><reference>1554953436</reference><reference>1568106064</reference><reference>1569420604</reference><reference>1583141478</reference><reference>1583342875</reference><reference>1601709094</reference><reference>1603160327</reference><reference>1633085561</reference><reference>1918444149</reference><reference>1991355547</reference><reference>2008059748</reference><reference>2021125268</reference><reference>2050475886</reference><reference>2055521902</reference><reference>2081950599</reference><reference>2087151730</reference><reference>2094647106</reference><reference>2123125327</reference><reference>2131050744</reference><reference>2158522377</reference><reference>2164095548</reference><reference>2171162639</reference></references><venue id="" type="">HOIT '00 Proceedings of the IFIP TC9 WG9.3 International Conference on Home Oriented Informatics and Telematics,: Information, Technology and Society</venue><doi>10.1007/978-0-387-35505-4_16</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Organizational boundaries</keyword><keyword weight="0.49485">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.5102">Critical success factor</keyword><keyword weight="0.40935">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.6689">Intranet</keyword><keyword weight="0.4692">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.44298">Archipelago</keyword><keyword weight="0.4485">Qualitative research</keyword></keywords><publisher>Kluwer, B.V.</publisher><abstract>This paper examines the growth of grass roots intranets as an extension of end-user computing. This perspective helps to characterize the nature of intranet development and use as “islands of practice” and provides a background against which the rapid proliferation of organizational intranets in the 1990s can be compared and contrasted with the explosion of personal computers and “islands of end-user computing” in the 1980s. This retrospective analysis of end-user computing is based on academic and business journal literature. The contemporary analysis of intranet development and use is based upon preliminary results from an ongoing qualitative study ofmidwest U.S. firms in various industries. These analyses highlight two phenomena that are likely to define the shape of intranets and future computing movements: (I) the integration of “intranet islands, ” not only within the firm but also across organizational boundaries, and (2) the role changes among IS and business area professionals as they work with intranet technologies. The discussion of these phenomena examines the ways in which intranets present unique opportunities for understanding the initiation and widespread uses of a new technology, while at the same time illuminating the changes in organizational roles that so often attend technological interventions.</abstract></paper>