<paper id="1567569629"><title>Structural Properties of One-way Hash Functions</title><year>1990</year><authors><author org="Yokohama Nat. Univ.#TAB#" id="2299933155">Yuliang Zheng</author><author org="Yokohama Nat. Univ.#TAB#" id="2253012118">Tsutomu Matsumoto</author><author org="Yokohama Nat. Univ.#TAB#" id="2648105993">Hideki Imai</author></authors><n_citation>33</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1493969756</reference><reference>1549228503</reference><reference>1600432225</reference><reference>1775939922</reference><reference>1972792640</reference><reference>1985623009</reference><reference>2052207834</reference><reference>2074594718</reference><reference>2107324709</reference><reference>2227130482</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-38424-3_21</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.65641">Primary clustering</keyword><keyword weight="0.46139">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.70663">Double hashing</keyword><keyword weight="0.4154">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.70841">Collision resistance</keyword><keyword weight="0.67619">Rolling hash</keyword><keyword weight="0.44014">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.71302">Hash function</keyword><keyword weight="0.67781">SWIFFT</keyword><keyword weight="0.68437">Security of cryptographic hash functions</keyword><keyword weight="0.67797">Hash chain</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We study the following two kinds of one-way hash functions: universal one-way hash functions (UOHs) and collision intractable hash functions (CIHs). The main property of the former is that given an initial-string x, it is computationally difficult to find a different string y that collides with x. And the main property of the latter is that it is computationally difficult to find a pair x ? y of strings such that x collides with y. Our main results are as follows. First we prove that UOHs with respect to initial-strings chosen arbitrarily exist if and only if UOHs with respect to initial-strings chosen uniformly at random exist. Then, as an application of the result, we show that UOHs with respect to initial-strings chosen arbitrarily can be constructed under a weaker assumption, the existence of one-way guasi-injections. Finally, we investigate relationships among various versions of one-way hash functions. We prove that some versions of one-way hash functions axe strictly included in others by explicitly constructing hash functions that are one-way in the sense of the former but not in the sense of the latter.</abstract></paper>