<paper id="206280253"><title>Implementation and use of expert systems in organizations: perceptions of knowledge engineers</title><year>1992</year><authors><author org="" id="2115848002">Terry Anthony Byrd</author></authors><n_citation>51</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>150317583</reference><reference>1516141096</reference><reference>1522870456</reference><reference>1601792741</reference><reference>1849121345</reference><reference>1994225596</reference><reference>2020785866</reference><reference>2023827842</reference><reference>2033020274</reference><reference>2040208190</reference><reference>2050525558</reference><reference>2054001586</reference><reference>2069529301</reference><reference>2135871035</reference><reference>2160610028</reference><reference>2733981320</reference></references><venue id="9954729" type="J">Journal of Management Information Systems</venue><doi>10.1080/07421222.1992.11517941</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.57763">Domain knowledge</keyword><keyword weight="0.50222">End user</keyword><keyword weight="0.42289">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.64111">Subject-matter expert</keyword><keyword weight="0.57207">Expert system</keyword><keyword weight="0.48055">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.61415">Knowledge engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.62872">Knowledge base</keyword><keyword weight="0.46264">Management science</keyword><keyword weight="0.64065">Knowledge acquisition</keyword><keyword weight="0.616">Legal expert system</keyword></keywords><publisher>M. E. Sharpe, Inc.</publisher><abstract>Abstract:This paper reports on the results of a survey of knowledge engineers from private organizations, and empirically examines the state of expert systems (ES) in organizational contexts. The knowledge engineers were asked to rate issues related to successful implementation, the extent of use in key areas, the original motivations for implementation, the perceived benefits, and the effects on end users of the systems. Factor analysis (varimax rotation) was used to reduce the number of issues so that reasonable conclusions in these areas could be drawn. The study resulted in several findings. Among these are: (i) knowledge acquisition and knowledge engineering should be separated in the overall ES development process and assigned to different ES team members; (ii) knowledge acquisition is the “bottleneck” in ES development; (iii) expert systems benefit organizations by helping personnel make more consistent, timely, and accurate decisions in hopes of improving competitiveness; and (iv) expert systems h...</abstract></paper>