<paper id="1533193701"><title>Corporate Intranet Implementation: Managing Emergent Technologies and Organizational Practices</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="Technical University of, Denmark" id="2086912546">Jorgen P. Bansler</author><author org="Department of Computer Science, The Technical Faculty of IT and Design, Aalborg University" id="1986729515">Jan Damsgaard</author><author org="" id="2146723926">Rens Scheepers</author><author org="" id="257953976">Erling C. Havn</author><author org="" id="2789637981">Jacob Thommesen</author></authors><n_citation>529</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1482315504</reference><reference>1546637313</reference><reference>1591918542</reference><reference>1593941822</reference><reference>1616268389</reference><reference>1866066149</reference><reference>1963608591</reference><reference>1969439151</reference><reference>2064045042</reference><reference>2068454915</reference><reference>2078678499</reference><reference>2087151730</reference><reference>2117150313</reference><reference>2148277253</reference></references><venue id="30879505" type="J">Journal of the Association for Information Systems</venue><doi>10.17705/1jais.00010</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.42675">Improvisation</keyword><keyword weight="0.40931">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.61434">Intranet</keyword><keyword weight="0.48019">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.5552">Management control system</keyword><keyword weight="0.59923">Planned change</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">System development</keyword><keyword weight="0.44013">Division of labour</keyword></keywords><publisher>Association for Information Systems</publisher><abstract>This paper examines the adoption and development of intranets in large business organizations. The authors demonstrate that intranet technology introduces a host of new managerial and technical challenges and requires new approaches to IS development. Evidence from two European corporations indicates that the traditional division of labor and definition of work roles in IS development breaks down. The distinction between developers and users becomes increasingly blurred and new organizational roles and structures associated with intranets are emerging. However, ready-made organizational models for implementing and managing intranets do not exist and the two organizations in this study have followed two different approaches. One organization favors a “planned change” approach, emphasizing management control and careful planning. The other organization prefers an “improvisational” approach, emphasizing experimentation, innovation and local initiative.</abstract></paper>