<paper id="1966673152"><title>About the relevance of accessibility barriers in the everyday interactions of older people with the web</title><year>2009</year><authors><author org="Universitat Pompeu Fabra, Tànger, Barcelona#TAB#" id="2156694926">Sergio Sayago</author><author org="Universitat Pompeu Fabra, Tànger, Barcelona#TAB#" id="2142948141">Josep Blat</author></authors><n_citation>48</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1526426957</reference><reference>1538633185</reference><reference>1978889947</reference><reference>1984623054</reference><reference>1994578330</reference><reference>2000662605</reference><reference>2011981538</reference><reference>2017390452</reference><reference>2027434413</reference><reference>2059498846</reference><reference>2060855836</reference><reference>2070265089</reference><reference>2090993919</reference><reference>2096138083</reference><reference>2103478220</reference><reference>2119405670</reference><reference>2129278302</reference><reference>2137587323</reference><reference>2151010882</reference><reference>2156353124</reference><reference>2166050198</reference></references><venue id="" type="">Proceedings of the 2009 International Cross-Disciplinary Conference on Web Accessibililty (W4A)</venue><doi>10.1145/1535654.1535682</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.71536">Web Accessibility Initiative</keyword><keyword weight="0.50062">Jargon</keyword><keyword weight="0.46016">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.40351">GRASP</keyword><keyword weight="0.49144">Terminology</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Prioritization</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Social exclusion</keyword><keyword weight="0.48398">Emerging technologies</keyword><keyword weight="0.37057">Engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.66611">Web accessibility</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>This paper reports key findings of a 3-year ethnographical study of the everyday interactions of older people with the web. The data consisted of in-situ observations and conversations with 388 older people while using myriads of web and computer technologies daily. The results revealed that the accessibility barriers that had a more negative effect on the daily interactions of older people with the web were due to their difficulties in remembering steps, understanding web and computer jargon and using the mouse, despite their willingness to use it. These obstacles were much more important than those caused by their difficulties perceiving visual information, understanding icons and using the keyboard. The prioritization of barriers was explained by two key aspects in ageing with new technologies, independency and inclusiveness, and a desired condition of web (user) interfaces, consistency in terminology. These results suggest that these three aspects should be considered carefully in enhancing web accessibility for older people, as well as allowing us to grasp older peopleu0027s everyday web accessibility barriers. The paper discusses possible ways of making use of these findings to make the web more accessible to older people.</abstract></paper>