<paper id="60616127"><title>Protocols for Secret Key Agreement by Public Discussion Based on Common Information</title><year>1992</year><authors><author org="ETH Zürich" id="2068596995">Ueli M. Maurer</author></authors><n_citation>61</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1516438277</reference><reference>1968372742</reference><reference>1985623009</reference><reference>2001466659</reference><reference>2007661134</reference><reference>2043769961</reference><reference>2106833918</reference><reference>2109394932</reference><reference>2144007657</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-48071-4_32</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47804">Parity bit</keyword><keyword weight="0.45602">Random variable</keyword><keyword weight="0.60193">Alice and Bob</keyword><keyword weight="0.42649">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.42464">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.5002">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.47586">Communication channel</keyword><keyword weight="0.42323">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46941">Probability distribution</keyword><keyword weight="0.56326">Shared secret</keyword><keyword weight="0.46637">Special case</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Consider the following scenario: Alice and Bob, two parties who share no secret key initially but whose goal it is to generate a (large amount of) information-theoretically secure (or unconditionally secure) shared secret key, are connected only by an insecure public channel to which an eavesdropper Eve has perfect (read) access. Moreover, there exists a satelite broadcasting random bits at a very low signal power. Alice and Bob can receive these bits with certain bit error probabilities ?A and ?B, respectively (e.g. ?A = ?B = 30%) while Eve is assumed to receive the same bits much more reliably with bit error probability ?E ? ?A, ?B (e.g. ?E = 1%). The errors on the three channels are assumed to occur at least partially independently. Practical protocols are discussed by which Alice and Bob can generate a secret key despite the facts that Eve possesses more information than both of them and is assumed to have unlimited computational resources as well as complete knowledge of the protocols.The described scenario is a special case of a much more general setup in which Alice, Bob and Eve are assumed to know random variables X, Y and Z jointly distributed according to some probability distribution PXYZ, respectively. The results of this paper suggest to build cryptographic systems that are provably secure against enemies with unlimited computing power under realistic assumptions about the partial independence of the noise on the involved communication channels.</abstract></paper>