<paper id="1606729219"><title>Simultaneous Hardcore Bits and Cryptography against Memory Attacks</title><year>2009</year><authors><author org="IAS and DIMACS,#TAB#" id="187628680">Adi Akavia</author><author org="MIT and Weizmann Insitute" id="1728759264">Shafi Goldwasser</author><author org="MIT and IBM Research,#TAB#" id="330291328">Vinod Vaikuntanathan</author></authors><n_citation>361</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>111085860</reference><reference>236432643</reference><reference>1510582395</reference><reference>1519539754</reference><reference>1530181486</reference><reference>1533121298</reference><reference>1536683582</reference><reference>1567930774</reference><reference>1590654318</reference><reference>1592625985</reference><reference>1608415167</reference><reference>1613874182</reference><reference>1663689473</reference><reference>1819824216</reference><reference>1839785783</reference><reference>1856342626</reference><reference>1969694673</reference><reference>1979828147</reference><reference>2020981190</reference><reference>2027528470</reference><reference>2038761522</reference><reference>2058330889</reference><reference>2061949491</reference><reference>2101040389</reference><reference>2108104892</reference><reference>2130410178</reference><reference>2133701468</reference><reference>2138669153</reference><reference>2147436724</reference><reference>2152783950</reference><reference>2153145614</reference><reference>2154021956</reference><reference>2164500771</reference><reference>2167236842</reference><reference>2175377689</reference><reference>2583174008</reference><reference>2914572864</reference></references><venue id="1137528458" type="C">Theory of Cryptography Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-642-00457-5_28</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.43359">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.53125">Semantic security</keyword><keyword weight="0.55051">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.41293">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.42542">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.54288">Encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.53142">Cryptosystem</keyword><keyword weight="0.58349">Trapdoor function</keyword><keyword weight="0.56394">Security parameter</keyword><keyword weight="0.59401">Key size</keyword><keyword weight="0.57314">56-bit encryption</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>This paper considers two questions in :[6],"Secure Against Memory Attacks. A particularly devastating side-channel attack against cryptosystems, termed the "memory attack", was proposed recently. In this attack, a significant fraction of the bits of a secret key of a cryptographic algorithm can be measured by an adversary if the secret key is ever stored in a part of memory which can be accessed even after power has been turned off for a short amount of time. Such an attack has been shown to completely compromise the security of various cryptosystems in use, including the RSA cryptosystem and :[98],"show that the public-key encryption scheme of Regev (STOC 2005), and the identity-based encryption scheme of Gentry, Peikert and Vaikuntanathan (STOC 2008) are remarkably robust against memory attacks where the adversary can measure a large fraction of the bits of the secret-key, or more generally, can compute an arbitrary function of the secret-key of bounded output length. This is done without increasing the size of the secret-key, and without introducing any complication of the natural encryption and decryption :[177],"Hardcore Bits. We say that a block of bits of x are simultaneously hard-core for a one-way function f (x ), if given f (x ) they cannot be distinguished from a random string of the same length. Although any candidate one-way function can be shown to hide one hardcore bit and even a logarithmic number of simultaneously hardcore bits, there are few examples of one-way or trapdoor functions for which a linear number of the input bits have been proved simultaneously hardcore; the ones that are known relate the simultaneous security to the difficulty of factoring :[98],"show that for a :[275],"lattice-based (injective) trapdoor function which is a variant of function proposed earlier by Gentry, Peikert and Vaikuntanathan, an N *** o (N ) number of input bits are simultaneously hardcore, where N is the total length of the two :[318],"results rely on similar proof techniques.</abstract></paper>