<paper id="1561441787"><title>Universally Composable Notions of Key Exchange and Secure Channels</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="IBM T.J. Watson research center" id="687553606">Ran Canetti</author><author org="TECHNION" id="2025616804">Hugo Krawczyk</author></authors><n_citation>289</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>140743382</reference><reference>1490590996</reference><reference>1499934958</reference><reference>1527077352</reference><reference>1540322376</reference><reference>1542059364</reference><reference>1601458649</reference><reference>1660562555</reference><reference>1970606468</reference><reference>1974664062</reference><reference>1994386233</reference><reference>1997859100</reference><reference>2033766329</reference><reference>2047241038</reference><reference>2107515440</reference><reference>2142968417</reference><reference>2151413173</reference><reference>2153281696</reference><reference>2156186849</reference><reference>2161670619</reference><reference>2397756951</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-46035-7_22</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.48934">Authentication</keyword><keyword weight="0.52063">Cryptographic protocol</keyword><keyword weight="0.52277">Key exchange</keyword><keyword weight="0.44077">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.43387">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.51046">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.40141">Communication channel</keyword><keyword weight="0.44379">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.4769">Mathematical proof</keyword><keyword weight="0.52291">Composability</keyword><keyword weight="0.46912">Communications protocol</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Recently, Canetti and Krawczyk (Eurocryptu00272001) formulated a notion of security for key-exchange (ke) protocols, called SK-security, and showed that this notion suffices for constructing secure channels. However, their model and proofs do not suffice for proving more general composability properties of SK-secure ke protocols.We show that while the notion of SK-security is strictly weaker than a fully-idealized notion of key exchange security, it is sufficiently robust for providing secure composition with arbitrary protocols. In particular, SK-security guarantees the security of the key for any application that desires to set-up secret keys between pairs of parties. We also provide new definitions of secure-channels protocols with similarly strong composability properties, and show that SK-security suffices for obtaining these definitions.To obtain these results we use the recently proposed framework of "universally composable (UC) security." We also use a new tool, called "noninformation oracles," which will probably find applications beyond the present case. These tools allow us to bridge between seemingly limited indistinguishability-based definitions such as SK-security and more powerful, simulation-based definitions, such as UC security, where general composition theorems can be proven. Furthermore, based on such composition theorems we reduce the analysis of a full-fledged multi-session keyexchange protocol to the (simpler) analysis of individual, stand-alone, key-exchange sessions.</abstract></paper>