<paper id="1493155866"><title>An application of expectancy theory for assessing user motivation to utilize an expert system</title><year>1992</year><authors><author org="" id="2656352512">F. Greg Burton</author><author org="" id="2339890677">Yi-Ning Chen</author><author org="" id="2139753257">Varun Grover</author><author org="" id="2659948826">Kathy A. Stewart</author></authors><n_citation>64</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1977147643</reference><reference>2006877955</reference><reference>2094860006</reference><reference>2147470311</reference><reference>2773274691</reference></references><venue id="9954729" type="J">Journal of Management Information Systems</venue><doi>10.1080/07421222.1992.11517973</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.55133">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">System usage</keyword><keyword weight="0.65211">Expectancy theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.61754">Goal theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.43451">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.54218">Expert system</keyword><keyword weight="0.46495">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.50329">Implementation</keyword><keyword weight="0.45565">Management science</keyword></keywords><publisher>M. E. Sharpe, Inc.</publisher><abstract>Abstract:Evaluation of information system success has been the focus of much research. However, most variables such as user satisfaction and system usage can only be measured after system implementation. To predict system success before actual implementation, behavioral theories indicate that it is necessary to evaluate behavioral intention or users’ motivation to use the system. Expectancy theory is considered one of the most promising models of individual motivation. This study examines the use of expectancy theory in explaining the motivation to use an expert system. Data gathered from 95 M.B.A. students in a jUdgmental modeling exercise suggest that the model is a significant predictor of motivation. It also provides insight into the development of such systems. The successful use of this model further suggests that itis appropriate for evaluating and understanding individual motivation to use a system and, subsequently, system success.</abstract></paper>