<paper id="1984890936"><title>Structure and complexity of relational queries</title><year>1982</year><authors><author org="Computer Sciences Department, IBM Thomas J. Watson Research Center, Yorktown Heights, New York 10598, USA" id="2609124786">Ashok K. Chandra</author><author org="Computer Sciences Department, IBM Thomas J. Watson Research Center, Yorktown Heights, New York 10598, USA" id="427806604">David Harel</author></authors><n_citation>472</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>10948978</reference><reference>1975714036</reference><reference>1979514837</reference><reference>2000449151</reference><reference>2003895694</reference><reference>2017839108</reference><reference>2065251436</reference><reference>2072843304</reference><reference>2127425663</reference><reference>2161609549</reference><reference>2165467455</reference></references><venue id="141020589" type="J">Journal of Computer and System Sciences</venue><doi>10.1016/0022-0000(82)90012-5</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.54687">Complexity class</keyword><keyword weight="0.44993">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.59929">Structural complexity theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.44661">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.66818">Conjunctive query</keyword><keyword weight="0.51953">Relational database</keyword><keyword weight="0.60726">Spatial query</keyword><keyword weight="0.53567">Hierarchy</keyword><keyword weight="0.51931">Time complexity</keyword><keyword weight="0.41945">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.50902">Computational complexity theory</keyword></keywords><publisher>Academic Press</publisher><abstract>Abstract This paper is an attempt at laying the foundations for the classification of queries on relational data bases according to their structure and their computational complexity. Using the operations of composition and fixpoints, a Σ-π hierarchy of height ω 2 , called the fixpoint query hierarchy, is defined, and its properties investigated. The hierarchy includes most of the queries considered in the literature including those of Codd and Aho and Ullman. The hierarchy to level ω characterizes the first-order queries, and the levels up to ω are shown to be strict. Sets of queries larger than the fixpoint query hierarchy are obtained by considered the queries computable in polynomial time, queries computable in polynomial space, etc. It is shown that classes of queries defined from such complexity classes behave (with respect to containment) in a manner very similar to the corresponding complexity classes. Also, the set of second-order queries turns out to be the same as the set of queries defined from the polynomial-time hierarchy. Finally, these classes of queries are used to analyse a set of queries defined from language considerations: those expressible in a programming language with only typed (or ranked) relation variables.</abstract></paper>