<paper id="1601865486"><title>A model of summary data and its applications in statistical databases</title><year>1988</year><authors><author org="UCLA" id="2295467234">Meng Chang Chen</author><author org="UCLA" id="2268234549">Lawrence McNamee</author><author org="UCLA" id="182814146">Michel A. Melkanoff</author></authors><n_citation>26</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>50364406</reference><reference>131984587</reference><reference>150810515</reference><reference>166877302</reference><reference>172974961</reference><reference>1605220130</reference><reference>1608021062</reference><reference>1954820475</reference><reference>1980228393</reference><reference>1985203234</reference><reference>1986832527</reference><reference>1994299112</reference><reference>2034820806</reference><reference>2039601877</reference><reference>2083028719</reference><reference>2093467213</reference><reference>2113827629</reference><reference>2146139590</reference><reference>2154884904</reference><reference>2165467455</reference><reference>2168247528</reference></references><venue id="1156109491" type="C">Statistical and Scientific Database Management</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0027524</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46133">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.59561">Data modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.5982">Database model</keyword><keyword weight="0.4527">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.58035">Semi-structured model</keyword><keyword weight="0.56777">Logical data model</keyword><keyword weight="0.60739">Database design</keyword><keyword weight="0.57366">Relational model</keyword><keyword weight="0.58749">Statistical database</keyword><keyword weight="0.59459">Data model</keyword><keyword weight="0.43514">Database</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><abstract>The summary (statistics) data model described herein is an extension of the relational model. The concept of category (type or class) and the additivity property of some statistical functions form the basis of this model. In this approach category shields details of a database instance from users, and plays an important role in deriving new statistics data. Statistics data is a trinary tuple consisting of 〈statistical function, category, summary〉. The additivity property allows new statistics data to be generated without having to access the original database. Statistics data is meta-knowledge summarized by statistical functions of the detailed information typically stored in a conventional database. Unfortunately, deciding whether a category is derivable from a set of categories, in general, is NP-hard. The proposed generating category set can resolve the intractability problem of the category derivation. The derivation of new statistics data within a relation or on multi-relations is investigated, and the efficiency and correctness of the stored statistics data are guaranteed when the original database is updated or when new statistics data is obtained. Finally potential applications and security concerns applying to this model are also discussed.</abstract></paper>