<paper id="1482315504"><title>Key Role Players in the Initiation and Implementation of Intranet Technology</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org=", Aalborg University" id="2146723926">Rens Scheepers</author></authors><n_citation>24</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>61831010</reference><reference>1571815411</reference><reference>1616268389</reference><reference>1866066149</reference><reference>1918444149</reference><reference>2044779067</reference><reference>2064045042</reference><reference>2075759489</reference><reference>2077973880</reference><reference>2078678499</reference><reference>2087151730</reference><reference>2093277583</reference><reference>2135492276</reference><reference>2148277253</reference><reference>2152458990</reference></references><venue id="" type="">Proceedings of the IFIP TC8 WG8.2 International Working Conference on New Information Technologies in Organizational Processes: Field Studies and Theoretical Reflections on the Future of Work</venue><doi>10.1007/978-0-387-35566-5_12</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Content generation</keyword><keyword weight="0.40474">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.69128">Intranet</keyword><keyword weight="0.46951">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.45922">Champion</keyword><keyword weight="0.48786">Process theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.50247">The Internet</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Organizational innovation</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer US</publisher><abstract>Internet technologies have opened up vast possibilities for many organizations, including their application purely within the organizational boundary in the form of intranets. However, little is known about the organizational role players in the context of this technology. This paper describes afield study that examines the role players in the initiation and implementation of intranet technology in three large organizations in two countries. Using organizational innovation process theory and available intranet literature, the role players, their roles, their challenges and interrelationships are identified. Five key interrelated roles are isolated: the technology champion, organizational sponsor, intranet coordinator, intranet developer and content provider. Technology champions play the important role of initiating the technology in the organization. The organizational sponsor nurtures and protects the budding technology and its change agents throughout the process. The key role of intranet coordinator features prominently in organization-wide coordination, control and feedback across functional boundaries, while stimulating organizational use and content generation simultaneously. The intranet developer role is crucial for more advanced organizational application of the technology. Finally, the role of content providers is significant in creating a critical mass of content early during implementation to ensure progress.</abstract></paper>