<paper id="1519454115"><title>Building change-readiness capabilities in the IS organization: insights from the Bell Atlantic experience</title><year>1997</year><authors><author org="" id="2396153041">Charles E. Clark</author><author org="" id="1988667398">Nancy C. Cavanaugh</author><author org="" id="2799019117">Carol V. Brown</author><author org="" id="2009383894">V. Sambamurthy</author></authors><n_citation>160</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1487377635</reference><reference>1590859763</reference><reference>1594251055</reference><reference>2171272451</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/249722</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Design elements and principles</keyword><keyword weight="0.51206">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.4706">Workforce</keyword><keyword weight="0.42771">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.52845">People skills</keyword><keyword weight="0.56553">Organizational architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.4722">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.51783">Conceptualization</keyword><keyword weight="0.49259">Excellence</keyword><keyword weight="0.45203">Reward system</keyword><keyword weight="0.46075">Management science</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>Change-readiness is the ability of an information systems (IS) organization to deliver strategic IT applications within short development cycle times by utilizing a highly skilled internal IS workforce. This paper examines two important questions: What are the design elements of a change-ready IS organization? How can transformations to such designs be effectively managed? Insights to these questions are generated through a case study of the conceptualization and implementation of an innovative organization design within a large IS unit at Bell Atlantic, a Regional Bell Operating Company. First, a rich description is provided of the components (strategy, structure, processes, people skills, reward systems) of a centers of excellence (CoE) design that has yielded measurable gains in IS performance. Then, an analysis of the two-year implementation of this CoE design is provided in terms of anticipated and unanticipated change actions, as well as a summary of "lessons learned." The conclusion describes the design as a model worthy of consideration by other IS managers for developing change-readiness IT capabilities. Comparisons with other models for the IS organization are then drawn.</abstract></paper>