<paper id="1793265733"><title>Public key broadcast encryption for stateless receivers</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="New-York University &gt;  &gt;  &gt;  &gt;" id="1259442811">Yevgeniy Dodis</author><author org="New-York University &gt;  &gt;  &gt;  &gt;" id="2019133828">Nelly Fazio</author></authors><n_citation>242</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1493284097</reference><reference>1495266644</reference><reference>1516444320</reference><reference>1522268755</reference><reference>1569083856</reference><reference>1571147132</reference><reference>1576892942</reference><reference>1596144702</reference><reference>1599446772</reference><reference>1600192790</reference><reference>1604454960</reference><reference>1785500772</reference><reference>2030668447</reference><reference>2037515303</reference><reference>2064967060</reference><reference>2073210531</reference><reference>2086042811</reference><reference>2143545186</reference><reference>2164052311</reference><reference>2165482045</reference><reference>2168571148</reference><reference>2405015683</reference><reference>2610275508</reference><reference>2911777915</reference><reference>2914756988</reference></references><venue id="2626811229" type="C">Digital Rights Management</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-44993-5_5</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.64234">Key distribution</keyword><keyword weight="0.64931">Broadcast encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.58084">Symmetric-key algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.4092">Internet privacy</keyword><keyword weight="0.45572">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.53709">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.45007">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.58804">Encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.52139">Traitor tracing</keyword><keyword weight="0.54402">Ciphertext</keyword><keyword weight="0.58893">Public-key cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.44584">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>A broadcast encryption scheme allows the sender to securely distribute data to a dynamically changing set of users over an insecure channel. One of the most challenging settings for this problem is that of stateless receivers, where each user is given a fixed set of keys which cannot be updated through the lifetime of the system. This setting was considered by Naor, Naor and Lotspiech [17], who also present a very efficient “Subset Difference” (SD) method for solving this problem. The efficiency of this method (which also enjoys efficient traitor tracing mechanism and several other useful features) was recently improved by Halevi and Shamir [12], who called their refinement the “Layered SD” (LSD) method. Both of the above methods were originally designed to work in the centralized symmetric key setting, where only the trusted designer of the system can encrypt messages to users. On the other hand, in many applications it is desirable not to store the secret keys “on-line”, or to allow untrusted users to broadcast information. This leads to the question of building a public key broadcast encryption scheme for stateless receivers; in particular, of extending the elegant SD/LSD methods to the public key setting. Naor et al. [17] notice that the natural technique for doing so will result in an enormous public key and very large storage for every user. In fact, [17] pose this question of reducing the public key size and user’s storage as the first open problem of their paper. We resolve this question in the affirmative, by demonstrating that an O(1) size public key can be achieved for both of SD/LSD methods, in addition to the same (small) user’s storage and ciphertext size as in the symmetric key setting.</abstract></paper>