<paper id="1976606382"><title>Older people and internet engagement: acknowledging social moderators of internet adoption, access and use</title><year>2008</year><authors><author org="School of Business and Economics, Swansea University, Swansea, UK" id="2107163474">Rebecca A. Hill</author><author org="(Cardiff Business School, Cardiff University, Cardiff, UK)" id="4324181">Paul Beynon-Davies</author><author org="School of Business and Economics, Swansea University, Swansea, UK" id="2163788641">Michael D. Williams</author></authors><n_citation>78</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>2006755985</reference><reference>2033003001</reference><reference>2036411051</reference><reference>2043056116</reference><reference>2051660196</reference><reference>2078696338</reference><reference>2157767588</reference></references><venue id="185256354" type="J">Information Technology &amp; People</venue><doi>10.1108/09593840810896019</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.4512">Social psychology</keyword><keyword weight="0.49841">Literacy</keyword><keyword weight="0.46">Public relations</keyword><keyword weight="0.43706">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.51847">Disengagement theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.3499">Engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">User studies</keyword><keyword weight="0.45639">Welsh</keyword><keyword weight="0.58634">The Internet</keyword></keywords><publisher>Emerald</publisher><abstract>Purpose – This paper seeks to describe a deep investigation of the phenomenon of internet engagement amongst older people. The likelihood of internet engagement has been shown in previous work to rapidly decrease with age, and patterns of disengagement are most pronounced amongst older people.Design/methodology/approach – The study comprises a qualitative investigation consisting of observation and interviews conducted within a programme of internet literacy workshops funded by the Welsh Assembly Government.Findings – The reflection of previous research with data collected has led to the development of a model of older peopleu0027s internet engagement. This model helps us better understand the context for patterns of engagement and disengagement with the internet.Practical implications – The model of internet engagement is used to highlight a number of strategies that should be considered in future policy intervention in the area of digital inclusion.Originality/value – The model described offers a more sophi...</abstract></paper>