<paper id="1558378922"><title>A Second-Order DPA Attack Breaks a Window-Method Based Countermeasure against Side Channel Attacks</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="Hitachi. Ltd" id="1780672632">Katsuyuki Okeya</author><author org="#N##TAB##TAB##TAB##TAB# Kyushu University#N##TAB##TAB##TAB#" id="2138196911">Kouichi Sakurai</author></authors><n_citation>35</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1501115028</reference><reference>1503689022</reference><reference>1516510761</reference><reference>1531102506</reference><reference>1539482743</reference><reference>1548023999</reference><reference>1565369953</reference><reference>1591209990</reference><reference>1603321026</reference><reference>1613874182</reference><reference>1838435525</reference><reference>1996360405</reference><reference>2003736153</reference><reference>2105374413</reference><reference>2106876320</reference><reference>2117877038</reference><reference>2121017442</reference><reference>2137567577</reference><reference>2155244510</reference><reference>2407881616</reference></references><venue id="2754249383" type="C">International Conference on Information Security</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-45811-5_30</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44844">Countermeasure</keyword><keyword weight="0.56536">Power analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.55341">Scalar multiplication</keyword><keyword weight="0.48177">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.3954">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45893">Scalar (physics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.47648">Cryptanalysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.41817">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.59518">Pre-play attack</keyword><keyword weight="0.59557">Side channel attack</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>M?ller proposed a countermeasure using window method against side channel attacks. However, its immunity to side channel attacks is still controversial. In this paper, we show M?lleru0027s countermeasure is vulnerable to a second-order differential power analysis attack. A side channel attackis an attackthat takes advantage of information leaked during execution of a cryptographic procedure. An nth-order differential power analysis attackis the side channel attack which uses n different leaked data that correspond to n different intermediate values during the execution. Our proposed attackagainst M?lleru0027s countermeasure finds out the use of same elliptic points, and restricts candidates of the secret scalar value. In these circumstances, the attack completely detects the scalar value using Baby-Step-Giant-Step method as a direct-computational attack. For a 160-bit scalar value, the proposed attack restricts the number of candidates of the scalar to a 45-bit integer, and the direct-computational attackcan actually detect the scalar value. Besides, we improve M?lleru0027s countermeasure to prevent the proposed attack. We compare the original method and improved countermeasure in terms of the computational intractability and the computational cost of the scalar multiplication.</abstract></paper>