<paper id="1516444320"><title>Coding Constructions for Blacklisting Problems without Computational Assumptions</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="IBM Almaden Research Center" id="2577876495">Ravi Kumar</author><author org="IBM Almaden Research Center" id="2059781006">Sridhar Rajagopalan</author><author org="M. I. T" id="2159933393">Amit Sahai</author></authors><n_citation>151</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1512186075</reference><reference>1518164822</reference><reference>1539419769</reference><reference>1600192790</reference><reference>1741292496</reference><reference>2002568678</reference><reference>2013675512</reference><reference>2037515303</reference><reference>2064967060</reference><reference>2071679850</reference><reference>2073136473</reference><reference>2091915899</reference><reference>2159945176</reference><reference>2167541784</reference><reference>2168932491</reference><reference>2295616646</reference><reference>2911546054</reference><reference>2914756988</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-48405-1_38</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.57413">Broadcast encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.47805">Broadcasting</keyword><keyword weight="0.41393">Exponential function</keyword><keyword weight="0.45286">Polynomial</keyword><keyword weight="0.47356">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.44313">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45065">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45304">Coding (social sciences)</keyword><keyword weight="0.51049">Error detection and correction</keyword><keyword weight="0.49394">Combinatorial design</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We consider the broadcast exclusion problem: how to transmit a message over a broadcast channel shared by N = 2n users so that all but some specified coalition of k excluded users can understand the contents of the message. Using error-correcting codes, and avoiding any computational assumptions in our constructions, we construct natural schemes that completely avoid any dependence on n in the transmission we :[64],"construct: (i) (for illustrative purposes,) a randomized scheme where the serveru0027s storage is exponential (in n), but the transmission overhead is O(k), and each useru0027s storage is O(kn); (ii) a scheme based on polynomials where the transmission overhead is O(kn) and each useru0027s storage is O(kn); and (iii) a scheme using algebraic-geometric codes where the transmission overhead is O(k2) and each user is required to store O(kn) keys. In the process of proving these results, we show how to construct very good cover-free set systems and combinatorial designs based on algebraic-geometric codes, which may be of independent interest and :[165],"approach also naturally extends to solve the problem in the case where the broadcast channel may introduce errors or lose information.</abstract></paper>