<paper id="1559269151"><title>Influence of experience on personal computer utilization: testing a conceptual model</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="" id="2114259029">Ronald L. Thompson</author><author org="" id="2126999211">Christopher A. Higgins</author><author org="" id="2116529374">Jane M. Howell</author></authors><n_citation>545</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1484391273</reference><reference>1497226654</reference><reference>1520729343</reference><reference>1582170352</reference><reference>1595575146</reference><reference>2002913067</reference><reference>2052654950</reference><reference>2055201538</reference><reference>2116505349</reference><reference>2138672502</reference></references><venue id="9954729" type="J">Journal of Management Information Systems</venue><doi>10.1080/07421222.1994.11518035</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.52644">Conceptual model</keyword><keyword weight="0.42036">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.5131">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.61994">Personal computer</keyword><keyword weight="0.49348">Professional development</keyword><keyword weight="0.46917">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.49484">End-user computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.44804">Management science</keyword></keywords><publisher>M. E. Sharpe, Inc.</publisher><abstract>The influence of prior experience on personal computer utilization was examined through an extension of a conceptual model developed and tested previously. Respondents were classified on the basis of their self-reported skill level and length of time having used personal computers. Three competing ways of modeling the influence of experience were tested: (1) a direct influence, (2) an indirect influence through six distinct attitude and belief components, and (3) a moderating influence on the relations between the attitude/belief components and utilization. The results suggested that experience influenced utilization directly, that indirect influences were present but less pronounced, and that the moderating influence of experience on the relations between five of six antecedent constructs and utilization was generally quite strong. For researchers, the implications are that prior experience with an information technology (IT) is an important factor to include when developing, testing, or applying models of IT adoption and use. For practitioners, the results highlight the importance of emphasizing applicability of the information technology to the current job and professional development early in the adoption process, with more emphasis on future benefits as experience is gained.</abstract></paper>