<paper id="1897761346"><title>Towards Sound Approaches to Counteract Power-Analysis Attacks</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="I.B.M. Thomas J. Watson Research Center" id="2319998151">Suresh Chari</author><author org="I.B.M. Thomas J. Watson Research Center" id="2084288858">Charanjit S. Jutla</author><author org="I.B.M. Thomas J. Watson Research Center" id="2114007677">Josyula R. Rao</author><author org="I.B.M. Thomas J. Watson Research Center" id="2121267894">Pankaj Rohatgi</author></authors><n_citation>446</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1519080809</reference><reference>1601001795</reference><reference>1613874182</reference><reference>1985263989</reference><reference>2023906228</reference><reference>2568739026</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-48405-1_26</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.51015">Power analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.46067">Upper and lower bounds</keyword><keyword weight="0.48784">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.44924">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45526">A priori and a posteriori</keyword><keyword weight="0.44246">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.44378">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.57895">Side channel attack</keyword><keyword weight="0.43714">Power (physics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.50019">Energy consumption</keyword><keyword weight="0.45752">Computer engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.45979">Randomness</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Side channel cryptanalysis techniques, such as the analysis of instantaneous power consumption, have been extremely effective in attacking implementations on simple hardware platforms. There are several proposed solutions to resist these attacks, most of which are ad-hoc and can easily be rendered ineffective. A scientific approach is to create a model for the physical characteristics of the device, and then design implementations provably secure in that model, i.e, they resist generic attacks with an a priori bound on the number of experiments. We propose an abstract model which approximates power consumption in most devices and in particular small single-chip devices. Using this, we propose a generic technique to create provably resistant implementations for devices where the power model has reasonable properties, and a source of randomness exists. We prove a lower bound on the number of experiments required to mount statistical attacks on devices whose physical characteristics satisfy reasonable properties.</abstract></paper>