<paper id="1764952320"><title>Scenario-based reliability analysis of component-based software</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="Dept. of Comput. science &amp; Electr. Eng., West Virginia Univ., Morgantown, WV, USA" id="1262027015">S.M. Yacoub</author><author org="" id="2193052964">B. Cukic</author><author org="" id="2118420981">H.H. Ammar</author></authors><n_citation>176</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>22392828</reference><reference>1811527611</reference><reference>2027515180</reference><reference>2078513650</reference><reference>2102794137</reference><reference>2124734957</reference><reference>2142779122</reference><reference>2143314548</reference><reference>2163768520</reference><reference>2164482879</reference></references><venue id="1157832733" type="C">International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering</venue><doi>10.1109/ISSRE.1999.809307</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.48577">Rapid application development</keyword><keyword weight="0.45576">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47373">System testing</keyword><keyword weight="0.46766">Directed graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.44827">Real-time computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.49802">Software</keyword><keyword weight="0.55657">Component-based software engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.50603">Software maintenance</keyword><keyword weight="0.52304">Software quality</keyword><keyword weight="0.51101">Application software</keyword><keyword weight="0.47156">Reliability engineering</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>Software designers are motivated to utilize off-the-shelf software components for rapid application development. Such applications are expected to have high reliability as a result of deploying trusted components. The claims of high reliability need further investigation based on reliability analysis techniques that are applicable to component-based applications. This paper introduces a probabilistic model and a reliability analysis technique that is applicable to high-level designs. The technique is named scenario-based reliability analysis (SBRA). SBRA is specific to component-based software whose analysis is strictly based on execution scenarios. Using scenarios, we construct a probabilistic model named a "component-dependency graph" (CDG). CDGs are directed graphs that represent components, component reliabilities, link and interface reliabilities, transitions and transition probabilities. In CDGs, component interfaces and link reliabilities are treated as first-class elements of the model. Based on CDGs, an algorithm is presented to analyze the reliability of the application as the function of reliabilities of its components and interfaces. A case study illustrates the applicability of the algorithm. The SBRA is used to identify critical components and critical component interfaces, and to investigate the sensitivity of the application reliability to changes in the reliabilities of components and their interfaces.</abstract></paper>