<paper id="1500222399"><title>Key issues in information systems management: an international perspective</title><year>1991</year><authors><author org="Department of Management, College of Business Administration, University of Georgia, Athens, GA 30602, USA" id="2128964823">Richard T. Watson</author><author org="University of Colorado, Graduate School of Business, Boulder, CO 80309, USA" id="83789424">James C. Brancheau</author></authors><n_citation>102</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>108058141</reference><reference>1554953436</reference><reference>1592160544</reference><reference>1601788611</reference><reference>1734084043</reference><reference>1991355547</reference><reference>2048108246</reference><reference>2076823740</reference><reference>2089634599</reference><reference>2117442647</reference><reference>2269494362</reference><reference>2571873230</reference></references><venue id="38883057" type="J">Information &amp; Management</venue><doi>10.1016/0378-7206(91)90056-8</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.56351">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.55813">Management information systems</keyword><keyword weight="0.51311">Multinational corporation</keyword><keyword weight="0.49285">Information processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.39186">Engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.47285">Marketing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Elsevier Science Publishers B. V.</publisher><abstract>Abstract The study discussed here compares and contrasts the findings of recent IS management studies in Australia, Europe, Singapore and the United States. It examines the key concerns of IS executives in these areas, focusing on identifying and explaining regional similarities and differences. IS executives in Australia, Europe, and the US show a reasonable level of agreement on the most critical issues they face. They take a mid- to long-range perspective on their function and are very concerned with planning and managing external relationships. Singaporean managers perceive that their problems are different and several explanations are put forward for understanding this difference. IS executives in multinational firms who are aware of regional differences should be able to manage the IS function more effectively. At a minimum, IS executives must be cognizant of the varying perspectives inherent in a global economy.</abstract></paper>