<paper id="1489939810"><title>A longitudinal study of the impact of group decision support systems on group development</title><year>1990</year><authors><author org="" id="1690196379">Laku Chidambaram</author><author org="" id="2302943154">Robert P. Bostrom</author><author org="" id="2915520367">Bayard E. Wynne</author></authors><n_citation>135</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1578743203</reference><reference>2025833698</reference></references><venue id="9954729" type="J">Journal of Management Information Systems</venue><doi>10.1080/07421222.1990.11517894</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Computer support</keyword><keyword weight="0.49208">Research design</keyword><keyword weight="0.47741">Longitudinal study</keyword><keyword weight="0.38296">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.5395">Decision support system</keyword><keyword weight="0.43048">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.51811">Conflict management</keyword><keyword weight="0.57024">Group cohesiveness</keyword><keyword weight="0.46228">Repeated measures design</keyword><keyword weight="0.63625">Group development</keyword></keywords><publisher>M. E. Sharpe, Inc.</publisher><abstract>Abstract:This paper reports on a study aimed at integrating an important but neglected behavioral issue-group development-into group decision support systems (gdss) research. Group development is based on the fact that most groups have a past and a future, and this affects group outcomes. However, most gdss studies have investigated only a single group session. This study examined the behavior of groups using a gdss over multiple sessions.The study reported in this paper specifically examined the following two questions: (1) does computer support affect the development of decision-making groups? and (2) do the patterns of development differ over time between computer-supported and manual groups? These two questions were studied using a two-factorial repeated measures research design. Results showed significant differences in development patterns between computer-supported groups and manual groups in terms of conflict management and degree of cohesiveness. Mter adapting to gdss, computer-supported groups d...</abstract></paper>