<paper id="1481638950"><title>Comparing two notions of simulatability</title><year>2005</year><authors><author org="IAKS, Arbeitsgruppe Systemsicherheit, Prof. Dr. Th. Beth Fakultät für Informatik, Universität Karlsruhe, Karlsruhe, Germany" id="2311125173">Dennis Hofheinz</author><author org="IAKS, Arbeitsgruppe Systemsicherheit, Prof. Dr. Th. Beth Fakultät für Informatik, Universität Karlsruhe, Karlsruhe, Germany" id="2418737637">Dominique Unruh</author></authors><n_citation>21</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1499934958</reference><reference>1531644305</reference><reference>1997859100</reference><reference>2058014492</reference><reference>2113085788</reference><reference>2119708968</reference><reference>2157779300</reference><reference>2949264753</reference></references><venue id="1137528458" type="C">Theory of Cryptography Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-30576-7_6</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46912">Converse</keyword><keyword weight="0.55805">Cryptographic protocol</keyword><keyword weight="0.4356">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.44482">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Computational security</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Formal description</keyword><keyword weight="0.44958">Idealization</keyword><keyword weight="0.44876">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.58164">Cryptographic primitive</keyword><keyword weight="0.44639">If and only if</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In this work, relations between the security notions standard simulatability and universal simulatability for cryptographic protocols are :[17],"simulatability-based notion of security considers a protocol π as secure as an idealization τ of the protocol task, if and only if every attack on π can be simulated by an attack on :[51],"formalizations, which both provide secure composition of protocols, are common: standard simulatability means that for every π-attack and protocol user H, there is a τ-attack, such that H cannot distinguish π from τ. Universal simulatability means that for every π-attack, there is a τ-attack, such that no protocol user H can distinguish π from universal simulatability :[106],"implies standard simulatability. We show: the converse is true with respect to perfect security, but not with respect to computational or statistical :[131],"we give a formal definition of a time-lock puzzle, which may be of independent interest. Although the described results do not depend on any computational assumption, :[131],"we show that the existence of a time-lock puzzle gives an even stronger separation of standard and universal simulatability with respect to computational security.</abstract></paper>