<paper id="1763482972"><title>Multi-authority attribute based encryption</title><year>2007</year><authors><author org="Computer Science Department Brown University, Providence, RI#TAB#" id="2138923407">Melissa Chase</author></authors><n_citation>604</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1495266644</reference><reference>1498316612</reference><reference>1569083856</reference><reference>1797206029</reference><reference>1983238288</reference><reference>2046871034</reference><reference>2086042811</reference><reference>2117685508</reference><reference>2138001464</reference><reference>2168970529</reference><reference>2610525718</reference></references><venue id="1137528458" type="C">Theory of Cryptography Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-70936-7_28</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.59358">Multiple encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.44754">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.71589">Attribute-based encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.629">Encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.44544">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.57316">40-bit encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.58975">Probabilistic encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.59039">On-the-fly encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.56412">Filesystem-level encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.55959">56-bit encryption</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In an identity based encryption scheme, each user is identified by a unique identity string. An attribute based encryption scheme (ABE), in contrast, is a scheme in which each user is identified by a set of attributes, and some function of those attributes is used to determine decryption ability for each ciphertext. Sahai and Waters introduced a single authority attribute encryption scheme and left open the question of whether a scheme could be constructed in which multiple authorities were allowed to distribute attributes [SW05]. We answer this question in the scheme :[90],"allows any polynomial number of independent authorities to monitor attributes and distribute secret keys. An encryptor can choose, for each authority, a number dk and a set of attributes; he can then encrypt a message such that a user can only decrypt if he has at least dk of the given attributes from each authority k. Our scheme can tolerate an arbitrary number of corrupt :[157],"also show how to apply our techniques to achieve a multiauthority version of the large universe fine grained access control ABE presented by Gopal et al. [GPSW06].</abstract></paper>