<paper id="1487268209"><title>High Performance Single-Chip FPGA Rijndael Algorithm Implementations</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="The Queen's University Of Belfast" id="2053354340">Máire McLoone</author><author org="The Queen's University Of Belfast" id="2242512104">John V. McCanny</author></authors><n_citation>145</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>170872169</reference><reference>1660562555</reference><reference>2117013296</reference><reference>2885816077</reference></references><venue id="1127098075" type="C">Cryptographic Hardware and Embedded Systems</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-44709-1_7</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46057">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.58628">Advanced Encryption Standard</keyword><keyword weight="0.4174">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.44489">Parallel computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.50028">Field-programmable gate array</keyword><keyword weight="0.44744">Chip</keyword><keyword weight="0.49406">Encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.48534">Application-specific integrated circuit</keyword><keyword weight="0.51917">Virtex</keyword><keyword weight="0.65123">AES implementations</keyword><keyword weight="0.45082">Embedded system</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>This paper describes high performance single-chip FPGA implementations of the new Advanced Encryption Standard (AES) algorithm, Rijndael. The designs are implemented on the Virtex-E FPGA family of devices. FPGAs have proven to be very effective in implementing encryption algorithms. They provide more flexibility than ASIC implementations and produce higher data-rates than equivalent software implementations. A novel, generic, parameterisable Rijndael encryptor core capable of supporting varying key sizes is presented. The 192-bit key and 256-bit key designs run at data rates of 5.8 Gbits/sec and 5.1 Gbits/sec respectively. The 128-bit key encryptor core has a throughput of 7 Gbits/sec which is 3.5 times faster than similar existing hardware designs and 21 times faster than known software implementations, making it the fastest single-chip FPGA Rijndael encryptor core reported to date. A fully pipelined single-chip 128-bit key Rijndael encryptor/decryptor core is also presented. This design runs at a data rate of 3.2 Gbits/sec on a Xilinx Virtex-E XCV3200E-8-CG1156 FPGA device. There are no known single-chip FPGA implementations of an encryptor/decryptor Rijndael design.</abstract></paper>