<paper id="1983792103"><title>Synthesizing plans that contain actions with context-dependent effects</title><year>1988</year><authors><author org="Knowledge Systems Research Department, AT&amp;T Bell Laboratories, Crawfords Corner Road, Holmdel, NJ 07733, U.S.A." id="1970863571">Edwin P. D. Pednault</author></authors><n_citation>98</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1405936</reference><reference>50425026</reference><reference>101198466</reference><reference>125130877</reference><reference>133833791</reference><reference>179078360</reference><reference>1555519929</reference><reference>1708183013</reference><reference>1981627423</reference><reference>2009328995</reference><reference>2021337406</reference><reference>2039358567</reference><reference>2081885809</reference><reference>2125789851</reference><reference>2147072697</reference><reference>2171798962</reference></references><venue id="1120693805" type="C">Computational Intelligence</venue><doi>10.1111/j.1467-8640.1988.tb00285.x</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.42168">Automated reasoning</keyword><keyword weight="0.51391">Partial-order planning</keyword><keyword weight="0.38155">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.38415">Artificial intelligence</keyword></keywords><publisher>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher><abstract>This paper presents a method of solving planning problems that involve actions whose effects change according to the situations in which they are performed. The approach is an extension of the conventional planning methodology in which plans are constructed through an iterative process of scanning for goals that are not yet satisfied, inserting actions to achieve them, and introducing subgoals to these actions. This methodology was originally developed under the assumption that one would be dealing exclusively with actions that produce the same effects in every situation. The extension involves introducing additional subgoals to actions above and beyond the preconditions of execution normally introduced. These additional subgoals, called secondary preconditions, ensure that the actions are performed in contexts conducive to producing the effects we desire. This paper defines and analyzes secondary preconditions from a mathematically rigorous standpoint and demonstrates how they can be derived from regression :[146],"article presente une methode pour resoudre les problemes de planification qui mettent en cause des actions dont les effets varient selon les situations dans lesquelles elles sont executees. Cette methode est le prolongement du processus de planification traditionnel dans Iequel les plans sont elabores par le biais du0027un procede iteratif du0027analyse des objectifs qui ne sont pas encore rencontres, introduisant des actions qui produisent les memes effets dans chaque situation. Le prolongement necessite lu0027introduction de sous-buts additionnels a des actions au-dela des preconditions du0027execution normalement introduites. Ces sous-buts additionnels, appeles preconditions secondaires, garantissent lu0027execution des actions dans des contextes propices a lu0027obtention des effets desires. Cet :[146],"article definit et analyse les preconditions secondaires du0027un point de vue mathematique rigoureux et demontre comment elles peuvent ětre derivees du0027operateurs de regression.</abstract></paper>