<paper id="1493190649"><title>Pseudorandom function tribe ensembles based on one-way permutations: improvements and applications</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="Fachbereich Mathematik, Johann Wolfgang Goethe-Universität Frankfurt am Main, Frankfurt/Main, Germany#TAB#" id="132146421">Marc Fischlin</author></authors><n_citation>37</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1516512945</reference><reference>1589176872</reference><reference>1831174262</reference><reference>1909955916</reference><reference>1972464518</reference><reference>2012045293</reference><reference>2015880590</reference><reference>2027528470</reference><reference>2039594335</reference><reference>2052207834</reference><reference>2052267638</reference><reference>2055993618</reference><reference>2073210531</reference><reference>2077300005</reference><reference>2096430557</reference><reference>2117362057</reference><reference>2139033758</reference><reference>2139172211</reference><reference>2144560442</reference><reference>2912863417</reference></references><venue id="1140213147" type="C">Theory and Application of Cryptographic Techniques</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-48910-X_30</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.68948">Pseudorandom function family</keyword><keyword weight="0.4542">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.4507">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.66276">Pseudorandom generators for polynomials</keyword><keyword weight="0.41892">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.6703">Pseudorandomness</keyword><keyword weight="0.52372">Permutation</keyword><keyword weight="0.44306">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.65893">Pseudorandom permutation</keyword><keyword weight="0.6483">Pseudorandom generator</keyword><keyword weight="0.70511">Pseudorandom generator theorem</keyword><keyword weight="0.51868">Random function</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Pseudorandom function tribe ensembles are pseudorandom function ensembles that have an additional collision resistance property: almost all functions have disjoint ranges.We present an alternative to the construction of pseudorandom function tribe ensembles based on oneway permutations given by Canetti, Micciancio and Reingold [7]. Our approach yields two different but related solutions: One construction is somewhat theoretic, but conceptually simple and therefore gives an easier proof that one-way permutations suffice to construct pseudorandom function tribe ensembles. The other, slightly more complicated solution provides a practical construction; it starts with an arbitrary pseudorandom function ensemble and assimilates the one-way permutation to this ensemble. Therefore, the second solution inherits important characteristics of the underlying pseudorandom function ensemble: it is almost as efficient and if the starting pseudorandom function ensemble is invertible then so is the derived tribe ensemble. We also show that the latter solution yields so-called committing private-key encryption schemes. i.e., where each ciphertext corresponds to exactly one plaintext -- independently of the choice of the secret key or the random bits used in the encryption process.</abstract></paper>