<paper id="1964475161"><title>A spherical representation for recognition of free-form surfaces</title><year>1995</year><authors><author org="Robotics Institute, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, Pa, USA" id="2101365550">M. Hebert</author><author org="Robotics Institute, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, Pa, USA" id="1804221844">K. Ikeuchi</author><author org="Medical imaging and robotics" id="2923580267">H. Delingette</author></authors><n_citation>130</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>50465256</reference><reference>1634431074</reference><reference>1847105887</reference><reference>1985020152</reference><reference>1989784484</reference><reference>2033834476</reference><reference>2039005177</reference><reference>2049981393</reference><reference>2068204893</reference><reference>2077570953</reference><reference>2088535827</reference><reference>2099088762</reference><reference>2102902467</reference><reference>2104095591</reference><reference>2107198582</reference><reference>2114511347</reference><reference>2115315913</reference><reference>2131806657</reference><reference>2159709546</reference><reference>2175540240</reference><reference>2913090860</reference></references><venue id="199944782" type="J">IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence</venue><doi>10.1109/34.391410</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.48762">Facial recognition system</keyword><keyword weight="0.45857">Computer vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.51106">Ellipsoid</keyword><keyword weight="0.48883">Curvature</keyword><keyword weight="0.49739">Reference model</keyword><keyword weight="0.4231">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.50159">Computational geometry</keyword><keyword weight="0.49462">Geometric modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.50587">3D modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.5232">Cognitive neuroscience of visual object recognition</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><abstract>Introduces a new surface representation for recognizing curved objects. The authors approach begins by representing an object by a discrete mesh of points built from range data or from a geometric model of the object. The mesh is computed from the data by deforming a standard shaped mesh, for example, an ellipsoid, until it fits the surface of the object. The authors define local regularity constraints that the mesh must satisfy. The authors then define a canonical mapping between the mesh describing the object and a standard spherical mesh. A surface curvature index that is pose-invariant is stored at every node of the mesh. The authors use this object representation for recognition by comparing the spherical model of a reference object with the model extracted from a new observed scene. The authors show how the similarity between reference model and observed data can be evaluated and they show how the pose of the reference object in the observed scene can be easily computed using this representation. The authors present results on real range images which show that this approach to modelling and recognizing 3D objects has three main advantages: (1) it is applicable to complex curved surfaces that cannot be handled by conventional techniques; (2) it reduces the recognition problem to the computation of similarity between spherical distributions; in particular, the recognition algorithm does not require any combinatorial search; and (3) even though it is based on a spherical mapping, the approach can handle occlusions and partial views. u003e</abstract></paper>