<paper id="1969673882"><title>On Envelopes of Arrangements of Lines</title><year>1996</year><authors><author org="Softimage Inc. Montreal, Quebec, H2X 2V2, Canada#TAB#" id="2974773078">D. Eu</author><author org="School of Computer Science, Simon Fraser University, Burnaby, British Columbia, V5A 1S6, Canada#TAB#" id="690851432">E. Guévremont</author><author org="School of Computer Science, McGill University, Montreal, Quebec, H3A 2A7, Canada#TAB#" id="2134099986">G.T. Toussaint</author></authors><n_citation>12</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>84423448</reference><reference>1973293833</reference><reference>1977534285</reference><reference>1990613315</reference><reference>1993949040</reference><reference>1996641400</reference><reference>1997316506</reference><reference>2009461326</reference><reference>2022266599</reference><reference>2033226644</reference><reference>2035449000</reference><reference>2042039784</reference><reference>2080276023</reference></references><venue id="110520077" type="J">Journal of Algorithms</venue><doi>10.1006/jagm.1996.0040</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46432">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.59587">Polygon</keyword><keyword weight="0.46814">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.58602">Vertex (geometry)</keyword><keyword weight="0.50056">Hamiltonian path</keyword><keyword weight="0.49531">Upper and lower bounds</keyword><keyword weight="0.54616">Arrangement of lines</keyword><keyword weight="0.54785">Convex hull</keyword><keyword weight="0.57817">Regular polygon</keyword><keyword weight="0.50304">Time complexity</keyword><keyword weight="0.4029">Mathematics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Academic Press, Inc.</publisher><abstract>The envelope of an arrangement of lines is the polygon consisting of the finite length segments that bound the infinite faces of the arrangement. We study the geometry of envelope polygons (simple polygons that are the envelope of some arrangement). We show that envelope polygons areL-convex and derive several geometric properties of envelopes. Given an envelope polygonPofnvertices, we show how to sort its edges by slope inO(n) time (for unrestricted simple polygons this problem has complexity ?(nlogn)). Using this result, we give a linear time procedure to verify if a given polygon is an envelope polygon. We introduce a hierarchy of classes of arrangements of lines based on the number of convex vertices of their envelopes. In particular, we look at a class calledsail arrangements, which we prove has properties that enable us to solve a number of problems optimally. Given a sail arrangement consisting ofnlines (and ?(n2) vertices), we show how the prune-and-search technique can be used to determine all the convex vertices of its envelope inO(n) time. This implies that the intersection point with minimum or maximumx-coordinate, the diameter, and the convex hull of sail arrangements (problems that also have ?(nlogn) complexity for arbitrary arrangements) can be found inO(n) time. We show, in spite of this, that the problem of constructing thefullenvelope of a sail arrangement still has a lower bound of ?(nlogn). We also examine the existence of hamiltonian circuits through the intersection points of a nontrivial subclass of sail arrangements. Finally, we establish an ?(nlogn) time lower bound for the problem of constructing a hamiltonian circuit through the vertices of an arrangement ofnlines, where only the vertices where a turn is made need be output.</abstract></paper>