<paper id="1549804633"><title>Change as Crisis or Growth? Toward a Trans-disciplinary View of Information Systems as a Field of Study: A Response to Benbasat and Zmud's Call for Returning to the IT Artifact</title><year>2003</year><authors><author org="Bentley University#TAB#" id="162332485">Robert D. Galliers</author></authors><n_citation>135</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>595458010</reference><reference>1520729343</reference><reference>1537983568</reference><reference>1554440887</reference><reference>1560661387</reference><reference>1976410576</reference><reference>2007706163</reference><reference>2046080825</reference><reference>2062537330</reference><reference>2066621499</reference><reference>2066854129</reference><reference>2116721563</reference></references><venue id="30879505" type="J">Journal of the Association for Information Systems</venue><doi>10.17705/1jais.00040</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.54655">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.44416">Public relations</keyword><keyword weight="0.40422">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.43891">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.5465">Discipline</keyword><keyword weight="0.46847">Epistemology</keyword><keyword weight="0.49955">Ambiguity</keyword></keywords><publisher>Association for Information Systems</publisher><abstract>Benbasat and Zmud (2003) express concern that the research community in Information Systems is responsible for the ambiguity of the discipline’s central identity by “underinvestigating phenomena intimately associated with IT-based systems and overestimating phenomena distantly associated with IT-based systems” (p. 183). Their related argument is that IS needs to focus on the core of the discipline to survive. I seriously contend this point of view. Questioning that we are at a crossroads in the Information Systems (IS) field, I argue that the field should become less disciplinary, and more trans-disciplinary in nature. I build my case by focusing on –and then questioning – underpinnings in their argument. These include: (1) their definitions of IS as a field; (2) the locus of our field in organizations; (3) the assumption that IS is a discipline; and (4) the lack of consideration given to the interand trans-national nature of IS as a field of study. Thus, the paper attempts to reposition Information Systems (IS) as quintessentially trans-disciplinary in nature. This case develops by considering how fields of study evolve over time. This evolution can be seen as either natural or as producing crisis. Next, I offer an alternative “core” to Benbasat’s and Zmud’s “IT artifact.” Following this, I present an appropriate locus of study for IS, one that offers a less constricting boundary than that of the organization, including societal and cross-cultural considerations. Finally, I question the very notion of “discipline” as applied to IS, and identify implications</abstract></paper>