<paper id="1984976620"><title>Private coins versus public coins in interactive proof systems</title><year>1986</year><authors><author org="Computer Science Department, MIT" id="1728759264">S Goldwasser</author><author org="Computer Science Department, University of California at Berkeley and Mathematics Department, MIT#TAB#" id="2710631614">M Sipser</author></authors><n_citation>381</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2036265926</reference><reference>2052207834</reference><reference>2096390054</reference><reference>2131798840</reference></references><venue id="1190910084" type="C">Symposium on the Theory of Computing</venue><doi>10.1145/12130.12137</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.41943">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.50249">Permission</keyword><keyword weight="0.50124">Nondeterministic algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.70974">Interactive proof system</keyword><keyword weight="0.43827">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48252">Copying</keyword><keyword weight="0.43418">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48922">Turing machine</keyword><keyword weight="0.5517">Mathematical proof</keyword><keyword weight="0.4707">Probabilistic logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.52484">Gas meter prover</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>An interactive proof system is a method by which one party of unlimited resources, called the prover, can convince a party of limited resources, call the verifier, of the truth of a proposition. The verifier may toss coins, ask repeated questions of the prover, and run efficient tests upon the proveru0027s responses before deciding whether to be convinced. This extends the familiar proof system implicit in the notion of NP in that there the verifier may not toss coins or speak, but only listen and verify. Interactive proof systems may not yield proof in the strict mathematical sense: the "proofs" are probabilistic with an exponentially small, though non-zero chance of error. We consider two notions of interactive proof system. One, defined by Goldwasser, Micali, and Rackoff [GMR] permits the verifier a coin that can be tossed in private, i.e., a secret source of randomness. The Permission to copy without ice all or part of this material is granted provided that the copies are not made or distributed for direct commercial advantage, the ACM copyright notice and the title of the publication and its date appear, and notice is given that copying is by permission of the Association for Computing Machinery. To copy otherwise, or to republish, requires a fee and/or specific permission. © 1986 ACM 0-89791-193-8/86/0500/0059 $00.75 second, due to Babai, [B] requires that the outcome of the verifieru0027s coin tosses be public and thus accessible to the prover. Our main result is that these two systems are equivalent in power with respect to language recognition. The notion of interactive proof system may be seen to yield a probabilistic analog to NP much as BPP is the probabilistic analog to P. We define the probabilistic, nondeterministic, polynomial time Turing machine and show that it is also equivalent in power to these systems.</abstract></paper>