<paper id="1508903366"><title>Deductive Search for Errors in Free Data Type Specifications Using Model Generation</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="Chalmers University of Technology" id="2055881405">Wolfgang Ahrendt</author></authors><n_citation>15</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1503941568</reference><reference>1576898581</reference><reference>1584539716</reference><reference>1589905862</reference><reference>1826979233</reference><reference>1924552249</reference><reference>1964186134</reference><reference>2071100103</reference><reference>2108239812</reference><reference>2166841305</reference><reference>2408687970</reference><reference>2912913603</reference></references><venue id="1134440762" type="C">Conference on Automated Deduction</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-45620-1_18</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.57803">Abstract data type</keyword><keyword weight="0.55424">Data modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.52534">Search algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.45923">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.50633">Axiom</keyword><keyword weight="0.55427">Correctness</keyword><keyword weight="0.46498">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.54236">Data type</keyword><keyword weight="0.47225">Specification</keyword><keyword weight="0.51727">Completeness (statistics)</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The presented approach aims at identifying false conjectures about free data types. Given a specification and a conjecture, the method performs a search for a model of an according counter specification. The model search is tailor-made for the semantical setting of free data types, where the fixed domain allows to describe models just in terms of interpretations. For sake of interpretation construction, a theory specific calculus is provided. The concrete rules are ‘executed’ by a procedure known as model generation. As most free data types have infinite domains, the ability of automatically solving the non-consequence problem is necessarily limited. That problem is addressed by limiting the instantiation of the axioms. This approximation leads to a restricted notion of model correctness, which is discussed. At the same time, it enables model completeness for free data types, unlike approaches based on limiting the domain size.</abstract></paper>