<paper id="1963624584"><title>Information technology innovations: a classification by IT locus of impact and research approach</title><year>1995</year><authors><author org="University of South Florida-Tampa" id="2122988771">Mary B. Prescott</author><author org="Southern#N#          Methodist University" id="2241894076">Sue A. Conger</author></authors><n_citation>296</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>58927800</reference><reference>186529931</reference><reference>793986531</reference><reference>844371533</reference><reference>1487549583</reference><reference>1494791071</reference><reference>1498245362</reference><reference>1505201787</reference><reference>1553804892</reference><reference>1563663716</reference><reference>1564097354</reference><reference>1571209953</reference><reference>1597511063</reference><reference>1598226182</reference><reference>1781006076</reference><reference>1967594130</reference><reference>1977633095</reference><reference>1980486683</reference><reference>1986360221</reference><reference>1994740826</reference><reference>1999461998</reference><reference>2007441836</reference><reference>2020392011</reference><reference>2020710285</reference><reference>2028720697</reference><reference>2029022677</reference><reference>2043837795</reference><reference>2058028914</reference><reference>2078103815</reference><reference>2084213127</reference><reference>2094647106</reference><reference>2100408980</reference><reference>2147641373</reference><reference>2171378329</reference></references><venue id="199280970" type="J">ACM Sigmis Database</venue><doi>10.1145/217278.217284</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.54631">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.41848">Critical mass (software engineering)</keyword><keyword weight="0.52203">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.43215">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Classification scheme</keyword><keyword weight="0.46881">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.38242">Locus (genetics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">It innovation</keyword><keyword weight="0.45311">Management science</keyword><keyword weight="0.44116">Tracing</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>Research based on diffusion of innovation (DOI) theory investigates the evaluation, adoption, and implementation of innovations. Gaining understanding is difficult when tracing results on a study-by-study basis. To remove some of the barriers to comparison of results, we distinguish between innovations according to their locus of impact (IS unit, intra- or inter-organizational) and between studies according to research approach (factor or stage).A representative sample of 70 information technology (IT) related DOI research studies published by IT researchers over the last decade is evaluated using this classification scheme. From the analysis, it appears that the classification scheme may be used to provide a clearer understanding of IT innovation diffusion.Traditional DOI theory appears to be most applicable to ITs which have an intra-organizational locus of impact. ITs with an information system (IS) unit locus of impact appear to require less organizational support, and their extent of implementation appears to be related to nontraditional innovation characteristics such as functionality and efficiency. Inter-organizational locus of impact IT innovations, however, appear to be more affected by contextual and environmental variables, and their differences may be better explained by economic influence or critical mass theories.</abstract></paper>