<paper id="1587080007"><title>Factors affecting information satisfaction in the context of the small business environment</title><year>1988</year><authors><author org="" id="2019449795">Ali Reza Montazemi</author></authors><n_citation>253</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1494791071</reference><reference>1509283903</reference><reference>1520103841</reference><reference>1520685303</reference><reference>1547879404</reference><reference>1582170352</reference><reference>1897476265</reference><reference>1974984365</reference><reference>1981818985</reference><reference>1988920466</reference><reference>1995685988</reference><reference>2019474319</reference><reference>2035544757</reference><reference>2037027277</reference><reference>2055521902</reference><reference>2066764753</reference><reference>2076722567</reference><reference>2116457565</reference><reference>2127455238</reference><reference>2164832405</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/248849</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.57504">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.47095">Decentralization</keyword><keyword weight="0.41101">Data processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.52671">Small business</keyword><keyword weight="0.5423">End user</keyword><keyword weight="0.41294">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46934">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.53857">Computer literacy</keyword><keyword weight="0.46358">Marketing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>This study reports an empirical investigation of some of the relationship that exist between organizational characteristics and end-user satisfaction associated with computer-based information systems (CBIS) in small businesses. Eight hypotheses were tested using data collected in a two-phase study of 83 small firms. The major findings show that end-use satisfaction is correlated with the number of systems analysts present within a firm, with the degree of analysis of information requirements, with the level of participation, and with end usersu0027 level of computer literacy. In addition, it was found that decentralization of the decision-making process tends to create a need for more effective CBIS. As a result, end-user satisfaction as found to be higher in firms that were less centralized. Furthermore, there was a strong correlation between the end users and data processing personnelu0027s satisfaction with the CBIS environment.</abstract></paper>