<paper id="1976232673"><title>The connectivity server: fast access to linkage information on the Web</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="DIGITAL Systems Research Center, 130 Lytton Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94301, USA" id="2572317946">Krishna Bharat</author><author org="DIGITAL Systems Research Center, 130 Lytton Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94301, USA" id="1970098533">Andrei Broder</author><author org="DIGITAL Systems Research Center, 130 Lytton Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94301, USA" id="2695385476">Monika Henzinger</author><author org="DIGITAL Systems Research Center, 130 Lytton Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94301, USA" id="2687451912">Puneet Kumar</author><author org="Computer Science Department, Stanford University, Palo Alto, CA 94301, USA" id="2090109395">Suresh Venkatasubramanian</author></authors><n_citation>198</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1981202432</reference><reference>2028406909</reference><reference>2037498077</reference><reference>2048538797</reference><reference>2054119298</reference><reference>2059275719</reference></references><venue id="1135342153" type="C">The Web Conference</venue><doi>10.1016/S0169-7552(98)80047-0</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46783">Graph theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.45444">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.46383">Information retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.52991">Webgraph</keyword><keyword weight="0.46839">Ranking</keyword><keyword weight="0.47643">Visualization</keyword><keyword weight="0.45271">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.61042">Doorway page</keyword><keyword weight="0.48479">Information access</keyword><keyword weight="0.45979">Neighbourhood (mathematics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.45659">Database</keyword><keyword weight="0.48238">The Internet</keyword></keywords><publisher>Elsevier Science Publishers B. V.</publisher><abstract>Abstract We have built a server that provides linkage information for all pages indexed by the AltaVista search engine. In its basic operation, the server accepts a query consisting of a set L of one or more URLs and returns a list of all pages that point to pages in L (predecessors) and a list of all pages that are pointed to from pages in L (successors). More generally the server can produce the entire neighbourhood (in the graph theory sense) of L up to a given distance and can include information about all links that exist among pages in the neighbourhood. Although some of this information can be retrieved directly from Alta Vista or other search engines, these engines are not optimized for this purpose and the process of constructing the neighbourhood of a given set of pages is show and laborious. In contrast our prototype server needs less than 0.1 ms per result URL. So far we have built two applications that use the Connectivity Server: a direct interface that permits fast navigation of the Web via the predecessor/successor relation, and a visualization tool for the neighbourhood of a given set of pages. We envisage numerous other applications such as ranking, visualization, and classification.</abstract></paper>