<paper id="1977093964"><title>Randomness-optimal unique element isolation, with applications to perfect matching and related problems</title><year>1993</year><authors><author org="" id="2319998151">Suresh Chari</author><author org="" id="2121267894">Pankaj Rohatgi</author><author org="" id="2128242943">Aravind Srinivasan</author></authors><n_citation>9</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>189596568</reference><reference>1494759436</reference><reference>1553674362</reference><reference>1977741646</reference><reference>1982406523</reference><reference>1988698339</reference><reference>1995634807</reference><reference>2006019685</reference><reference>2011594074</reference><reference>2019038806</reference><reference>2022124805</reference><reference>2052207834</reference><reference>2057512592</reference><reference>2064306958</reference><reference>2069919161</reference><reference>2079828065</reference><reference>2113097540</reference><reference>2113291984</reference><reference>2125536734</reference><reference>2131399793</reference><reference>2137407595</reference><reference>2610479830</reference><reference>2610729871</reference></references><venue id="1190910084" type="C">Symposium on the Theory of Computing</venue><doi>10.1145/167088.167213</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.51313">Matroid</keyword><keyword weight="0.47171">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.47389">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.53956">Matroid intersection</keyword><keyword weight="0.51534">Upper and lower bounds</keyword><keyword weight="0.48532">Matching (graph theory)</keyword><keyword weight="0.48326">Treewidth</keyword><keyword weight="0.48529">Pathwidth</keyword><keyword weight="0.416">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.48454">Bounded function</keyword><keyword weight="0.49768">Randomness</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>In this paper, we precisely characterize the randomness complexity of the unique element isolation problem, a crucial step in the RNC algorithm for perfect matching due to Mulmuley, Vazirani \u0026 Vazirani[21] and in several other applications. Given a set $S$ and an unknown family $\cal F \subseteq$ $2^{S}$ with $|\cal F| \leq$ $Z$, we present a scheme to assign polynomially bounded weights to the elements of $S$, using only $O(\log Z + \log |S|)$ ransom bits, such that the minimum weight set in $\cal F$ is unique with high probability. This generalizes and improves the results of Mulmuley, Vazirani \u0026 Vazirani who give a scheme which uses $O(S \log S)$ random bits independent of $Z$. We also prove a matching lower bound for the randomness complexity of this problem. This new weight assignment scheme yields a randomness-efficient $RNC^{2}$ algorithm for perfect matching which uses $O(\log Z + \log n)$ random bits where $Z$ is any given upper bound on the number of perfect matchings in the input graph. This generalizes the result of Grigoriev \u0026 Karpinski[11] who present an $NC^{3}$ algorithm when $Z$ is polynomially bounded and also gives an improvement on the running time in this case. The worst-case randomness complexity of our algorithm is $O(n \log (m/n))$ random bits, as opposed to the previous bound of $O(m \log n)$ bits. Our technique also gives randomness-efficient solutions for several problems in which the unique element isolation tool is used, such as $RNC$ algorithms for variants of matching and basic problems on linear matroids such as matroid intersection and matroid matching. We also obtain a randomness-efficient alternative to the random reduction from $SAT$ to $USAT$, the language of uniquely satisfiable formulas, due to Valiant and Vazirani[32]. This reduction can be derandomized in the case of languages in $F ew P$ to yield new proofs of the results $F ew P \subseteq \oplus P$ and $F ew P \subseteq C_{=} P$.</abstract></paper>