<paper id="1534635956"><title>Evaluation of a system for personalized summarization of web contents</title><year>2005</year><authors><author org="CES Felipe II (Universidad Complutense de Madrid)" id="2150745483">Alberto Díaz</author><author org="SIP, Universidad Complutense de Madrid#TAB#" id="184266003">Pablo Gervás</author><author org="Departamento de Comunicación, Universidad Rey Juan Carlos," id="2142703762">Antonio García</author></authors><n_citation>5</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1488460679</reference><reference>1548791071</reference><reference>1582340466</reference><reference>1594485982</reference><reference>1833785989</reference><reference>1978329176</reference><reference>2028009320</reference><reference>2101390659</reference><reference>2102597631</reference><reference>2166347079</reference></references><venue id="2754031194" type="C">International Conference on User Modeling, Adaptation, and Personalization</venue><doi>10.1007/11527886_63</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.5177">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.6318">Multi-document summarization</keyword><keyword weight="0.64174">Automatic summarization</keyword><keyword weight="0.45684">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.64102">User profile</keyword><keyword weight="0.55225">Information needs</keyword><keyword weight="0.47221">Information retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.44317">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.61172">Computer user satisfaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.46331">The Internet</keyword><keyword weight="0.50359">Personalization</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Existing Web personalized information systems typically send to the users the title and the first lines of the chosen items, and links to the full text. This is, in most cases, insufficient for a user to detect if the item is relevant or not. An interesting approach is to replace the first sentences by a personalized summary extracted according to a user profile that represents the information needs of the user. On the other side, it is crucial to measure how much information is lost during the summarization process, and how this information loss may affect the ability of the user to judge the relevance of a given document. The system-oriented evaluation developed in this paper indicates that personalized summaries perform better than generic summaries in terms of identifying documents that satisfy user preferences. We also considered a user-centred qualitative evaluation indicating a high level of user satisfaction with the summarization method described, in consonance with the quantitative results.</abstract></paper>