<paper id="1716417115"><title>Formal modeling of space shuttle software change requests using SCR</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="Onera-Cert Toulouse, France" id="342554022">V. Wiels</author><author org="WEST VIRGINIA UNIVERSITY" id="329574911">S. Easterbrook</author></authors><n_citation>5</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1985566198</reference><reference>2081553013</reference><reference>2125708466</reference><reference>2125853559</reference><reference>2146191617</reference><reference>2163380638</reference></references><venue id="207090427" type="J">Requirements Engineering</venue><doi>10.1109/ISRE.1999.777991</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46402">Systems engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.5363">Verification and validation</keyword><keyword weight="0.47411">Software engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.46201">Space technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.46712">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.56168">Change request</keyword><keyword weight="0.50351">Systems analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.46254">Space Shuttle</keyword><keyword weight="0.59381">Formal specification</keyword><keyword weight="0.4927">Software</keyword><keyword weight="0.58096">Formal verification</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>This paper describes a feasibility study into the use of a formal requirements modeling method (SCR) to assist with independent verification and validation of change requests for space shuttle flight software. The goal of the study was to determine whether a formal modeling technique could automate some of the manual analysis tasks performed on change requests, including consistency checking. To analyze the change request, the key part of the original functionality was modeled in SCR. The model was then updated to reflect the proposed changes. Tool support was used to perform consistency checking and to validate the model against domain properties. The study showed that as an analysis tool, formal modeling offers some advantages over inspection-based approaches. However, the problem of analyzing change requests is sufficiently different from other requirements modeling tasks that some specialist tools will be needed. The paper ends with a discussion of the demands of these needs.</abstract></paper>