<paper id="1674"><title>A methodology for the physically accurate visualisation of roman polychrome statuary</title><year>2011</year><authors><author org="Archaeological Computing Research Group, University of Southampton, UK#TAB#" id="2103626414">G. Beale</author><author org="Archaeological Computing Research Group, University of Southampton, UK#TAB#" id="2117665592">G. Earl</author></authors><n_citation>1</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1535888970</reference><reference>1992876689</reference><reference>1993710814</reference><reference>2035653341</reference><reference>2043970887</reference><reference>2087778487</reference><reference>2094478046</reference><reference>2100468662</reference><reference>2110331535</reference><reference>2120448006</reference><reference>2138624212</reference><reference>2149970020</reference><reference>2150266006</reference><reference>2296384428</reference><reference>2403283736</reference></references><venue id="2754954274" type="C">International Conference on Virtual Reality</venue><doi>10.2312/VAST/VAST11/137-144</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.40216">Statue</keyword><keyword weight="0.43427">Engineering drawing</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Virtual reconstruction</keyword><keyword weight="0.42062">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.4595">Visualization</keyword><keyword weight="0.4474">Polychrome</keyword><keyword weight="0.40496">Artificial intelligence</keyword></keywords><publisher>Eurographics Association</publisher><abstract>This paper describes the design and implementation of a methodology for the visualisation and hypothetical virtual reconstruction of Roman polychrome statuary for research purposes. The methodology is intended as an attempt to move beyond visualisations which are simply believable towards a more physically accurate approach. Accurate representations of polychrome statuary have great potential utility both as a means of illustrating existing interpretations and as a means of testing and revising developing hypotheses. The goal of this methodology is to propose a pipeline which incorporates a high degree of physical accuracy whilst also being practically applicable in a conventional archaeological research setting. The methodology is designed to allow the accurate visualisation of surviving objects and colourants as well as providing reliable methods for the hypothetical reconstruction of elements which no longer survive. The process proposed here is intended to limit the need for specialist recording equipment, utilising existing data and those data which can be collected using widely available technology. It is at present being implemented as part of the u0027Statues in Contextu0027 project at Herculaneum and will be demonstrated here using the case study of a small area of the head of a painted female statue discovered at Herculaneum in 2006.</abstract></paper>