<paper id="1964653871"><title>An Experimental Comparison of the Effectiveness of Computers and Humans as Search Intermediaries.</title><year>1983</year><authors><author org="Laboratory for Information and Decision Systems, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA" id="2110650639">Richard S. Marcus</author></authors><n_citation>72</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1966415209</reference><reference>1966522973</reference><reference>1966637557</reference><reference>1978287827</reference><reference>1980056150</reference><reference>1985861836</reference><reference>2019251198</reference><reference>2023328205</reference><reference>2024072664</reference><reference>2053507957</reference><reference>2057323446</reference><reference>2066868202</reference><reference>2089196909</reference><reference>2163478907</reference><reference>2215745487</reference></references><venue id="80113298" type="J">Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology</venue><doi>10.1002/asi.4630340605</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46395">Intermediary</keyword><keyword weight="0.44696">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.65488">Cognitive models of information retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.46763">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.68426">Human–computer information retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.51895">End user</keyword><keyword weight="0.47682">Information retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.4504">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Database selection</keyword><keyword weight="0.61952">Relevance (information retrieval)</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Research methodology</keyword><keyword weight="0.45681">Recall</keyword></keywords><publisher>Wiley Subscription Services, Inc., A Wiley Company</publisher><abstract>An experimental computer intermediary system, CONIT, that assists users in accessing and searching heterogeneous retrieval systems has been enhanced with various search aids. Controlled experiments have been conducted to compare the effectiveness of the enhanced CONIT intermediary with that of human expert interme diary search specialists. Some 16 end users, none of whom had previously operated either CONIT or any of the four connected retrieval systems, performed searches on 20 different topics using CONIT with no assistance other than that provided by CONIT itself (except to recover from computerlsoftware bugs). These same users also performed searches on the same topics with the help of human expert intermediaries who searched using the retrieval systems directly. Sometimes CONIT and sometimes the human expert were clearly superior in terms of such parameters as recall and search time. In general, however, users searching alone with CONIT achieved somewhat higher online recall at the expense of longer session times. We conclude that advanced experimental intermediary techniques are now capable of providing search assistance whose effectiveness at least approximates that of human intermediaries in some contexts. Also analyzed is the cost effectlveness of current intermediary systems. Finally, consideration is given to the prospects for much more advanced systems which would perform such functions as automatic database selection and the simulation of human experts, and thereby make information retrieval more effective for all classes of users.</abstract></paper>