<paper id="1576835806"><title>Advanced Interaction in Context</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="External Organizations" id="2688824889">Albrecht Schmidt</author><author org="External Organizations" id="1977405903">Kofi Asante Aidoo</author><author org="External Organizations" id="2059290381">Antti Takaluoma</author><author org="External Organizations" id="2629851184">Urpo Tuomela</author><author org="External Organizations" id="1984888092">Kristof Van Laerhoven</author><author org="External Organizations" id="2099818162">Walter Van de Velde</author></authors><n_citation>531</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1985951810</reference><reference>2052861176</reference><reference>2064408462</reference><reference>2084069552</reference><reference>2131415946</reference><reference>2137304183</reference><reference>2160170050</reference><reference>2536445687</reference></references><venue id="1171345118" type="C">Ubiquitous Computing</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-48157-5_10</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45659">Point (typography)</keyword><keyword weight="0.50413">Smart environment</keyword><keyword weight="0.53899">User profile</keyword><keyword weight="0.44733">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48757">Situation awareness</keyword><keyword weight="0.45455">Self-organizing map</keyword><keyword weight="0.466">Software</keyword><keyword weight="0.475">Human–computer interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.43581">Information and Communications Technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.52769">Mobile phone</keyword><keyword weight="0.45512">Multimedia</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer</publisher><abstract>Mobile information appliances are increasingly used in numerous different situations and locations, setting new requirements to their interaction methods. When the useru0027s situation, place or activity changes, the functionality of the device should adapt to these changes. In this work we propose a layered real-time architecture for this kind of context-aware adaptation based on redundant collections of low-level sensors. Two kinds of sensors are distinguished: physical and logical sensors, which give cues from environment parameters and host information. A prototype board that consists of eight sensors was built for experimentation. The contexts are derived from cues using real-time recognition software, which was constructed after experiments with Kohonenu0027s Self-Organizing Maps and its variants. A personal digital assistant (PDA) and a mobile phone were used with the prototype to demonstrate situational awareness. On the PDA font size and backlight were changed depending on the demonstrated contexts while in mobile phone the active user profile was changed. The experiments have shown that it is feasible to recognize contexts using sensors and that context information can be used to create new interaction metaphors.</abstract></paper>