<paper id="1870432047"><title>Mining exception instances to facilitate workflow exception handling</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="Dept. of Inf. Manage., Nat. Sun Yat-Sen Univ., Kaohsiung, Taiwan#TAB#" id="2181734664">San-Yih Hwang</author><author org="" id="2391865268">Sun-Fa Ho</author><author org="" id="2973365119">J. Tang</author></authors><n_citation>47</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1570265525</reference><reference>1787564306</reference><reference>1809466700</reference><reference>1846888456</reference><reference>1855065956</reference><reference>2005314985</reference><reference>2015234709</reference><reference>2123437827</reference><reference>2149706766</reference></references><venue id="1184699546" type="C">Database Systems for Advanced Applications</venue><doi>10.1109/DASFAA.1999.765735</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44848">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.50554">Information management</keyword><keyword weight="0.45801">Algorithm design</keyword><keyword weight="0.45576">Job design</keyword><keyword weight="0.46215">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.57055">Exception handling</keyword><keyword weight="0.51558">Correctness</keyword><keyword weight="0.44011">Synthetic data</keyword><keyword weight="0.5101">Rollback</keyword><keyword weight="0.59991">Workflow</keyword><keyword weight="0.45739">Database</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><abstract>The importance of exception handling within the context of workflow management has been widely recognized. While some exceptions are expected at design time and thus can be incorporated into the workflow design via some flexible mechanism, others are totally unexpected. Previous work in handling unexpected workflow exceptions focuses on the run-time support to, for example, allow the rollback of some already completed activities, validate the correctness of dynamic workflow change, and deploy a solution to handle exceptions. Authorized persons are responsible for deriving solutions to handle exceptions. We propose a novel approach to facilitating users in proposing solutions for resolving a given exception. Specifically, our approach scans through the previous records in handling exceptions, looking for those that are close to the current exception. The ways in which those exceptions were handled serve as useful information in determining how to handle the current one. Several algorithms are proposed and evaluated through both theoretical analysis and a synthetic data set.</abstract></paper>