<paper id="1506013575"><title>What Is the Set of Images of an Object Under All Possible Illumination Conditions</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="Center for Comp. Vision and Control, Dept. of Electrical Engineering, Yale University, New Haven CT 06520#TAB#" id="2776195728">Peter N. Belhumeur</author><author org="Center for Comp. Vision and Control, Dept. of Electrical Engineering, Yale University, New Haven CT 06520#TAB#" id="2573551016">David J. Kriegman</author></authors><n_citation>475</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1524975883</reference><reference>1943001502</reference><reference>2020014224</reference><reference>2053197265</reference><reference>2056182445</reference><reference>2066303290</reference><reference>2098947662</reference><reference>2106687120</reference><reference>2111337582</reference><reference>2121647436</reference><reference>2122883383</reference><reference>2123977795</reference><reference>2157500953</reference><reference>2159686933</reference><reference>2168068730</reference><reference>2179426874</reference><reference>2295394636</reference></references><venue id="25538012" type="J">International Journal of Computer Vision</venue><doi>10.1023/A:1008005721484</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44673">Graphics</keyword><keyword weight="0.43375">Computer vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.49229">Shadow</keyword><keyword weight="0.36782">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.49486">Image processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.45107">Regular polygon</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.46032">Geometrical optics</keyword><keyword weight="0.51719">Lambertian reflectance</keyword><keyword weight="0.51057">Convex cone</keyword><keyword weight="0.48504">Cognitive neuroscience of visual object recognition</keyword></keywords><publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher><abstract>The appearance of an object depends on both the viewpoint from which it is observed and the light sources by which it is illuminated. If the appearance of two objects is never identical for any pose or lighting conditions, then–in theory–the objects can always be distinguished or recognized. The question arises: What is the set of images of an object under all lighting conditions and pose? In this paper, we consider only the set of images of an object under variable illumination, including multiple, extended light sources and shadows. We prove that the set of n-pixel images of a convex object with a Lambertian reflectance function, illuminated by an arbitrary number of point light sources at infinity, forms a convex polyhedral cone in R^n and that the dimension of this illumination cone equals the number of distinct surface normals. Furthermore, the illumination cone can be constructed from as few as three images. In addition, the set of n-pixel images of an object of any shape and with a more general reflectance function, seen under all possible illumination conditions, still forms a convex cone in R^n. Extensions of these results to color images are presented. These results immediately suggest certain approaches to object recognition. Throughout, we present results demonstrating the illumination cone representation.</abstract></paper>