<paper id="1936730819"><title>Preserving integrity in remote file location and retrieval</title><year>1996</year><authors><author org="Dept. of Electr. Eng. &amp; Comput. Sci.,, Michigan Univ., Ann Arbor, MI, USA#TAB#" id="2181741781">T. Jaeger</author><author org="Telcordia Technologies &lt;caruso@research.telcordia.com&gt;" id="2112283555">A.D. Rubin</author></authors><n_citation>15</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1645506484</reference><reference>2005725110</reference><reference>2043671329</reference><reference>2044902313</reference><reference>2121134342</reference><reference>2123837909</reference><reference>2130493426</reference><reference>2134342348</reference><reference>2145074871</reference><reference>2916302273</reference></references><venue id="1180274659" type="C">Network and Distributed System Security Symposium</venue><doi>10.1109/NDSS.1996.492413</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.54371">File Transfer Protocol</keyword><keyword weight="0.4104">Internet privacy</keyword><keyword weight="0.44419">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.44661">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.61562">Torrent file</keyword><keyword weight="0.61387">Unix file types</keyword><keyword weight="0.54286">Data integrity</keyword><keyword weight="0.63217">File synchronization</keyword><keyword weight="0.5987">Data file</keyword><keyword weight="0.62383">File system fragmentation</keyword><keyword weight="0.46008">Database</keyword><keyword weight="0.6445">Computer file</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>We present a service for locating and retrieving files from an untrusted network such that the integrity of the retrieved files can be verified. This service enables groups of people in geographically remote locations to share files using an untrusted network. For example, distribution, of an organizationu0027s software to all the organizationu0027s sites can be accomplished using this service. Distribution of files in an untrusted network is complicated by two issues: (1) location of files and (2) verification of file integrity. ftp and World-wide Web (WWW) services require some user intervention to locate a file, so they cannot be embedded in automated systems. Distributed systems have mechanisms for automated file location and retrieval, but they require trust in all system principals and do not provide an appropriate balance between availability of files and retrieval cost for our applications. Verification of the integrity of a file retrieved from an untrusted network is necessary because the file is subject to malicious modification attacks. Our service provides the capability to automatically locate, retrieve, and verify files specified by a client using a single trusted principal. We demonstrate our service by building a system shell that automatically downloads remote software when needed.</abstract></paper>