<paper id="177758670"><title>Specifying the Reuse Context of Scenario Method Chunks</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="Universite Paris-Sorbonne" id="2169618221">Colette Rolland</author><author org="Universite Paris-Sorbonne" id="7483917">Véronique Plihon</author><author org="Universite Paris-Sorbonne" id="1476870986">Jolita Ralyté</author></authors><n_citation>59</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>23914588</reference><reference>126455733</reference><reference>1484289724</reference><reference>1548825518</reference><reference>1787397658</reference><reference>1796836150</reference><reference>2041929143</reference><reference>2064419470</reference><reference>2069234241</reference><reference>2123939574</reference><reference>2131824369</reference><reference>2139907081</reference><reference>2158704465</reference><reference>2165023916</reference></references><venue id="1134069326" type="C">Conference on Advanced Information Systems Engineering</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0054226</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.48848">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.50648">Hypertext</keyword><keyword weight="0.562">Objectory</keyword><keyword weight="0.46684">Systems engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.46853">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.49296">Reuse</keyword><keyword weight="0.522">Software development process</keyword><keyword weight="0.4902">Modular design</keyword><keyword weight="0.5072">Reusability</keyword><keyword weight="0.52959">Software development</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>There has been considerable recent interest in scenarios for accompanying many of the various activities occurring in the development life cycle of computer based systems. Besides the integration of scenarios in methods such as Objectory and software tools such as Rationale Rose has proven useful and successful. Consequently, there is a demand for adapting existing methods to support specific design activities using scenario based approaches. The view developed in this paper is that scenario based approaches should be looked upon as reusable components. Our concern is therefore twofold: first, to represent scenario based approaches in a modular way which eases their reusability and second, to specify the design context in which these approaches can be reused in order to facilitate their integration in existing methods. The paper concentrates on these two aspects, presents an implementation of our proposal using SGML to store available scenario based approaches in a multimedia hypertext document and illustrates the retrieval of components meeting the requirements of the user by the means of SgmlQL queries.</abstract></paper>