<paper id="1984680759"><title>FairplayMP: a system for secure multi-party computation</title><year>2008</year><authors><author org="The Hebrew University Jerusalem Israel" id="2135161809">Assaf Ben-David</author><author org="The Hebrew University Jerusalem Israel" id="19031441">Noam Nisan</author><author org="University of Haifa, Haifa, Israel," id="259477981">Benny Pinkas</author></authors><n_citation>374</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>44936433</reference><reference>1480225633</reference><reference>1494138594</reference><reference>1526979127</reference><reference>1573476887</reference><reference>1775507803</reference><reference>1987667503</reference><reference>2036133214</reference><reference>2040168265</reference><reference>2101551271</reference><reference>2118179522</reference><reference>2121640981</reference><reference>2145818182</reference></references><venue id="1198471430" type="C">Computer and Communications Security</venue><doi>10.1145/1455770.1455804</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.50377">Boolean circuit</keyword><keyword weight="0.63803">Secure multi-party computation</keyword><keyword weight="0.55363">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.47105">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46118">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.46157">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.6583">Secure two-party computation</keyword><keyword weight="0.51181">Scalability</keyword><keyword weight="0.49881">Computation</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>We present FairplayMP (for "Fairplay Multi-Party"), a system for secure multi-party computation. Secure computation is one of the great achievements of modern cryptography, enabling a set of untrusting parties to compute any function of their private inputs while revealing nothing but the result of the function. In a sense, FairplayMP lets the parties run a joint computation that emulates a trusted party which receives the inputs from the parties, computes the function, and privately informs the parties of their outputs. FairplayMP operates by receiving a high-level language description of a function and a configuration file describing the participating parties. The system compiles the function into a description as a Boolean circuit, and perform a distributed evaluation of the circuit while revealing nothing else. FairplayMP supplements the Fairplay system [16], which supported secure computation between two parties. The underlying protocol of FairplayMP is the Beaver-Micali-Rogaway (BMR) protocol which runs in a constant number of communication rounds (eight rounds in our implementation). We modified the BMR protocol in a novel way and considerably improved its performance by using the Ben-Or-Goldwasser-Wigderson (BGW) protocol for the purpose of constructing gate tables. We chose to use this protocol since we believe that the number of communication rounds is a major factor on the overall performance of the protocol. We conducted different experiments which measure the effect of different parameters on the performance of the system and demonstrate its scalability. (We can now tell, for example, that running a second-price auction between four bidders, using five computation players, takes about 8 seconds.)</abstract></paper>