<paper id="1981626968"><title>LTSA-WS: a tool for model-based verification of web service compositions and choreography</title><year>2006</year><authors><author org="Imperial College, London #N#United Kingdom" id="2152446125">Howard Foster</author><author org="Imperial College, London #N#United Kingdom" id="307221030">Sebastian Uchitel</author><author org="Imperial College, London #N#United Kingdom" id="2097290386">Jeff Magee</author><author org="Imperial College, London #N#United Kingdom" id="2095806276">Jeff Kramer</author></authors><n_citation>152</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1239375374</reference><reference>1564561023</reference><reference>1801803219</reference><reference>2028722689</reference><reference>2123071544</reference><reference>2123986639</reference></references><venue id="1174403976" type="C">International Conference on Software Engineering</venue><doi>10.1145/1134285.1134408</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.59525">Verification and validation of computer simulation models</keyword><keyword weight="0.6243">Functional verification</keyword><keyword weight="0.51265">Model checking</keyword><keyword weight="0.5944">Verification and validation</keyword><keyword weight="0.45041">Systems engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.45563">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.63382">Runtime verification</keyword><keyword weight="0.4989">Implementation</keyword><keyword weight="0.62497">Verification</keyword><keyword weight="0.55777">Web service</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>In this paper we describe a tool for a model-based approach to verifying compositions of web service implementations. The tool supports verification of properties created from design specifications and implementation models to confirm expected results from the viewpoints of both the designer and implementer. Scenarios are modeled in UML, in the form of Message Sequence Charts (MSCs), and then compiled into the Finite State Process (FSP) process algebra to concisely model the required behavior. BPEL4WS implementations are mechanically translated to FSP to allow an equivalence trace verification process to be performed. By providing early design verification and validation, the implementation, testing and deployment of web service compositions can be eased through the understanding of the behavior exhibited by the composition. The approach is implemented as a plug-in for the Eclipse development environment providing cooperating tools for specification, formal modeling, verification and validation of the composition process.</abstract></paper>