<paper id="1517724544"><title>Elements of a plan-based theory of speech acts</title><year>1986</year><authors><author org="BOLT BERANEK AND NEWMAN,INC." id="2145462135">Philip R. Cohen</author><author org="Univ. of Toronto, Toronto, Ont., Canada#TAB#" id="1974896123">C. Raymond Perrault</author></authors><n_citation>70</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1498806819</reference><reference>1503622209</reference><reference>1545815294</reference><reference>1572073643</reference><reference>2083263181</reference><reference>2336060883</reference></references><venue id="106296714" type="J">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-44972-0_1</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.49252">Interpersonal communication</keyword><keyword weight="0.46278">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.4913">Truism</keyword><keyword weight="0.4642">Human–computer interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.45309">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.48151">Operator (computer programming)</keyword><keyword weight="0.45915">Comprehension</keyword><keyword weight="0.42968">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Morgan Kaufmann Publishers Inc.</publisher><abstract>This paper explores the truism that people think about what they say. It proposes hat, to satisfy their own goals, people often plan their speech acts to affect their listenersu0027 beliefs, goals, and emotional states. Such language use can be modelled by viewing speech acts as operators in a planning system, thus allowing both physical and speech acts to be integrated into :[62],"issues of how speech acts should be defined in a plan-based theory are illustrated by defining operators for requesting and informing. Plans containing those operators are presented and comparisons are drawn with Searleu0027s formulation. The operators are shown to be inadequate since they cannot be composed to form questions (requests to inform) and multiparty requests (requests to request). By refining the operator definitions and by identifying some of the side effects of requesting, compositional adequacy is achieved. The solution leads to a metatheoretical principle for modelling speech acts as planning operators.</abstract></paper>