<paper id="107001810"><title>Element finding: the impact of a group support system on a crucial phase of sense making</title><year>1995</year><authors><author org="" id="2141106565">Anne P. Massey</author><author org="" id="2175603599">Danial L. Clapper</author></authors><n_citation>33</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1480197836</reference><reference>1523264430</reference><reference>1578743203</reference><reference>1725321198</reference><reference>1980281387</reference><reference>2059308148</reference><reference>2080601274</reference><reference>2118612095</reference></references><venue id="9954729" type="J">Journal of Management Information Systems</venue><doi>10.1080/07421222.1995.11518063</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.55702">Brainstorming</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Support system</keyword><keyword weight="0.44016">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46436">Management science</keyword></keywords><publisher>M. E. Sharpe, Inc.</publisher><abstract>Many of the problem situations facing organizations today are complex and ill-structured, lacking a definitive structure and formulation. The attempt to clearly understand and make sense of these situations is a difficult, but crucial, early requirement for effective problem solving. Problem-solving theory suggests that element finding--identifying the elements or variables that are relevant to a problem situation--is one of the earliest essential divergent activities of sense making. This paper details a theoretical framework synthesizing the work of a number of problem-solving research streams to highlight how brainstorming, although with distinct objectives, can be used as a divergent tool during very different phases of the problem-solving process. Using this framework, we empirically explored the impact of electronic brainstorming--a feature of group support systems--on element finding as groups attempted to identify the elements of an ill-structured situation facing them.</abstract></paper>