<paper id="1590730688"><title>Building business process driven web applications</title><year>2006</year><authors><author org="Department of Information System and Computation, Technical University of Valencia, Valencia, Spain#TAB#" id="2139301491">Victoria Torres</author><author org="Department of Information System and Computation, Technical University of Valencia, Valencia, Spain#TAB#" id="126441702">Vicente Pelechano</author></authors><n_citation>29</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1239375374</reference><reference>1510755437</reference><reference>1872567804</reference><reference>2149007495</reference><reference>2152106013</reference><reference>2153163751</reference><reference>2170418117</reference><reference>2583236460</reference><reference>2584750259</reference></references><venue id="1152238068" type="C">Business Process Management</venue><doi>10.1007/11841760_22</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.669">Web development</keyword><keyword weight="0.47253">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.65842">Web page</keyword><keyword weight="0.46698">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.65713">Web standards</keyword><keyword weight="0.66391">Data Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.69238">Web engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.7196">Web modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.64923">Web application security</keyword><keyword weight="0.65761">Web service</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The Internet has turned to be one the most common platform for the development of applications. In addition, sometimes the specification of these applications is given to web developers in the form of Business Processes (BP), and from this specification they are asked to develop the corresponding Web Application. In this situation, Web Engineering Methods should provide a way in which these specifications could be taken and be transformed into a Web Application that gives support to the process execution. Furthermore, when we are talking about B2B applications, we have to take into account that these BP usually involve the use of distributed functionality where different partners collaborate to accomplish an agreed goal. Therefore, in this work we provide a method for the automatic generation of Web Applications that give support to BP specifications. For this purpose, we generate from a BP definition the Navigation (web pages) and the WS-BPEL executable description that implements the entire process.</abstract></paper>