<paper id="1977182536"><title>A method for disambiguating word senses in a large corpus</title><year>1992</year><authors><author org="Murray Hill," id="2114596471">William A. Gale</author><author org="Murray Hill," id="2172397963">Kenneth Ward Church</author><author org="Murray Hill," id="2042800127">David Yarowsky</author></authors><n_citation>489</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>30254004</reference><reference>1550769831</reference><reference>1969030495</reference><reference>1973394465</reference><reference>2019911971</reference><reference>2035408139</reference><reference>2066075273</reference><reference>2090543924</reference><reference>2099247782</reference><reference>2117652747</reference><reference>2122865782</reference><reference>2129139611</reference><reference>2137638032</reference><reference>2798434063</reference></references><venue id="93469583" type="J">Computers and The Humanities</venue><doi>10.1007/BF00136984</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.43337">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.58378">Noun</keyword><keyword weight="0.49309">Computational linguistics</keyword><keyword weight="0.49757">Natural language</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.47016">Natural language processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.50237">Document retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.49615">Lexical analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.49056">Ambiguity</keyword><keyword weight="0.44095">Linguistics</keyword><keyword weight="0.42066">Bayesian probability</keyword><keyword weight="0.52342">Polysemy</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer Nature</publisher><abstract>Word sense disambiguation has been recognized as a major problem in natural language processing research for over forty years. Both quantitive and qualitative methods have been tried, but much of this work has been stymied by difficulties in acquiring appropriate lexical resources. The availability of this testing and training material has enabled us to develop quantitative disambiguation methods that achieve 92% accuracy in discriminating between two very distinct senses of a noun. In the training phase, we collect a number of instances of each sense of the polysemous noun. Then in the testing phase, we are given a new instance of the noun, and are asked to assign the instance to one of the senses. We attempt to answer this question by comparing the context of the unknown instance with contexts of known instances using a Bayesian argument that has been applied successfully in related tasks such as author identification and information retrieval. The proposed method is probably most appropriate for those aspects of sense disambiguation that are closest to the information retrieval task. In particular, the proposed method was designed to disambiguate senses that are usually associated with different topics.</abstract></paper>