<paper id="1862293612"><title>Syntax and semantics in a distributed speech understanding system</title><year>1976</year><authors><author org="Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh Pa" id="2974751651">F. Hayes-Roth</author><author org="" id="2973583508">D. Mostow</author></authors><n_citation>9</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1687345816</reference><reference>1762923681</reference><reference>1904895072</reference><reference>2126977453</reference></references><venue id="1121227772" type="C">International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing</venue><doi>10.1109/ICASSP.1976.1170046</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44439">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.61256">Phrase</keyword><keyword weight="0.52878">Utterance</keyword><keyword weight="0.53867">Grammar</keyword><keyword weight="0.64319">Phrase structure rules</keyword><keyword weight="0.51972">Natural language</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.47725">Natural language processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.58997">Syntax</keyword><keyword weight="0.51907">Vocabulary</keyword><keyword weight="0.53704">Semantics</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>The Hearsay II speech understanding system being developed at Carnegie-Mellon University has an independent knowledge source module for each type of speech knowledge. Modules communicate by reading, writing, and modifying hypotheses about various constituents of the spoken utterance in a global data structure. The syntax and semantics module uses rules (productions) of four types: (1) recognition rules for generating a phrase hypothesis when its needed constituents have already been hypothesized; (2) prediction rules for inferring the likely presence of a word or phrase from previously recognized portions of the utterance; (3) respelling rules for hypothesizing the constituents of a predicted phrase; and (4) postdiction rules for supporting an existing hypothesis on the basis of additional confirming evidence. The rules are automatically generated from a declarative (Le., non-procedural) description of the grammar and semantics, and are embedded in a parallel recognition network for efficient retrieval of applicable rules. The current grammar uses a 450-word vocabulary and accepts simple English queries for an information retrieval system.</abstract></paper>