<paper id="1963662159"><title>An investigation of satisfaction when using a voice synchronous GDSS in dispersed meetings</title><year>1992</year><authors><author org="Marquette University, Milwaukee, WI, USA," id="2690347345">Kimberly Cass</author><author org="Marquette University, Milwaukee, WI, USA," id="2584996591">Timothy J. Heintz</author><author org="Marquette University, Milwaukee, WI, USA," id="2104150519">Kate M. Kaiser</author></authors><n_citation>32</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1480197836</reference><reference>1513402407</reference><reference>1523264430</reference><reference>1527944521</reference><reference>1578743203</reference><reference>1778357938</reference><reference>1972098965</reference><reference>1982876848</reference><reference>1984068726</reference><reference>2009365258</reference><reference>2014335760</reference><reference>2018146966</reference><reference>2033282075</reference><reference>2052876062</reference><reference>2159771480</reference></references><venue id="38883057" type="J">Information &amp; Management</venue><doi>10.1016/0378-7206(92)90042-E</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44892">Research design</keyword><keyword weight="0.43395">Collaborative software</keyword><keyword weight="0.47834">Decision support system</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Laboratory experiment</keyword><keyword weight="0.43001">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.34686">Engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Group process</keyword></keywords><publisher>Elsevier Science Publishers B. V.</publisher><abstract>Abstract This paper reports on a laboratory experiment which assesses the effect of a group decision support system (GDSS) on synchronous face-to-face and dispersed meetings with subjects linked via a voice connection. Location and GDSS-use form the basis for a 2×2 research design of 134 groups. Members solved a preference allocation task and reported their satisfaction with the meeting process and its outcome. Both GDSS and location effects were significant for discussion quality, with face-to-face non-GDSS group members reporting the highest level of satisfaction. The GDSS effect alone was significant for discussion effectiveness and outcome, with non-GDSS groups reporting the highest satisfaction. The solution satisfaction measure had a significant interaction between effects. Members of the dispersed GDSS groups appreciated the concept of this setting but not its implementation. Dispersed subjects without GDSS technology were more satisfied with both the process and the outcome of their meeting. When a GDSS was available, face-to-face subjects reported higher satisfaction with the meeting outcome than dispersed subjects.</abstract></paper>