<paper id="1550842947"><title>Masking and Dual-Rail Logic Don't Add Up</title><year>2007</year><authors><author org="ECE Department, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg VA 24061, USA#TAB#" id="2102130231">Patrick Schaumont</author><author org="Digital Enterprise Group, Intel Corporation, Hillsboro OR 97124, USA#TAB#" id="2583218792">Kris Tiri</author></authors><n_citation>68</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1506423869</reference><reference>1540392439</reference><reference>1569380263</reference><reference>1575446397</reference><reference>1594464909</reference><reference>1790072549</reference><reference>1806070087</reference><reference>2144630005</reference><reference>2165637947</reference></references><venue id="1127098075" type="C">Cryptographic Hardware and Embedded Systems</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-74735-2_7</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.6659">Sequential logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.4849">Masking (art)</keyword><keyword weight="0.66764">Pass transistor logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.44265">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45088">Parallel computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.46916">Filter (signal processing)</keyword><keyword weight="0.4582">Arithmetic</keyword><keyword weight="0.44912">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.4139">Implementation</keyword><keyword weight="0.47744">Chip</keyword><keyword weight="0.49668">Cycles per instruction</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Power consumption</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Masked logic styles use a random mask bit to de-correlate the power consumption of the circuit from the state of the algorithm. The effect of the random mask bit is that the circuit switches between two complementary states with a different power profile. Earlier work has shown that the mask-bit value can be estimated from the power consumption profile, and that masked logic remains susceptible to classic power attacks after only a simple filtering operation. In this contribution we will show that this conclusion also holds for masked pre-charged logic styles and for all practical implementations of masked dual-rail logic styles. Up to now, it was believed that masking and dual-rail can be combined to provide a routing-insensitive logic style. We will show that this assumption is not correct. We demonstrate that the routing imbalances can be used to detect the value of the mask bit. Simulations as well as analysis of design data from an AES chip support this conclusion.</abstract></paper>