<paper id="1575434894"><title>Focused concept formation</title><year>1989</year><authors><author org="Department of Information and Computer Science, University of California, Irvine CA 92717, USA" id="2980657200">John H. Gennari</author></authors><n_citation>17</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>201569951</reference><reference>2050206309</reference><reference>2073308541</reference></references><venue id="1180662882" type="C">International Conference on Machine Learning</venue><doi>10.1016/B978-1-55860-036-2.50096-5</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.40821">Small number</keyword><keyword weight="0.46059">Pattern recognition</keyword><keyword weight="0.46164">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.52565">Concept learning</keyword><keyword weight="0.4746">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.55762">Cluster analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.47634">Machine learning</keyword><keyword weight="0.46654">Salient</keyword></keywords><publisher>Morgan Kaufmann Publishers Inc.</publisher><abstract>Publisher Summary This chapter reviews the incremental concept formation systems COBWEB (Fisher, 1987) and CLASSIT (Gennari, Langley L. Fisher), and also CLASSIT-2. For COBWEB and CLASSIT, recognition of an instance occurred when all available attributes were used to classify the instance into some category. A better approach would be to recognize an instance based on only a small number of attributes. Additionally, a clustering system should be able to focus attention on some subset of attributes that are most salient for a given classification problem. These attributes should be inspected in sequence. The incremental algorithm used by both COBWEB and CLASSIT is only a partial specification of the clustering method. CLASSIT-2 extends the framework of incremental concept formation to include a mechanism for attention. This extension is well-integrated with the existing framework. The ability to focus attention on selected attributes of an instance is both an important step toward a model of human concept formation, and a useful method for improving efficiency without losing predictive ability.</abstract></paper>