<paper id="1589571834"><title>A broker-based framework for QoS-aware Web service composition</title><year>2005</year><authors><author org="Dept. of Electr. Eng. &amp; Comput. Sci.,, California Univ., Irvine, CA, USA" id="2202110290">Tao Yu</author><author org="Dept. of Electr. Eng. &amp; Comput. Sci.,, California Univ., Irvine, CA, USA" id="2101757531">K.-J. Lin</author></authors><n_citation>134</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>25663762</reference><reference>205989946</reference><reference>2103087994</reference><reference>2126027218</reference><reference>2141381353</reference><reference>2141880113</reference><reference>2145558183</reference><reference>2179016548</reference></references><venue id="2754955730" type="C">IEEE International Conference on e-Technology, e-Commerce and e-Service</venue><doi>10.1109/EEE.2005.1</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.70649">Services computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.63939">Mobile QoS</keyword><keyword weight="0.46255">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.65464">WS-Addressing</keyword><keyword weight="0.44806">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.67086">Web modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.67458">Business Process Execution Language</keyword><keyword weight="0.68471">Web service</keyword><keyword weight="0.69162">WS-Policy</keyword><keyword weight="0.66655">Service-oriented architecture</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>Web services are modular web applications that can be independently deployed and invoked by other software or services on the web. This offers enterprises the capability to integrate in-house business services with external Web services to conduct complex business transactions. The integration efficiency and flexibility are critical for services composition. For Web services providing a similar functionality, Quality of Service (QoS) is the main factor to differentiate them. The overall QoS of a business process must meet a useru0027s requirement. In this paper, we propose a broker-based framework to facilitate dynamic integration and adaptation of QoS-aware Web services with end-to-end QoS constraints. The key functions of a dynamic broker include service collection, selection, composition and adaptation. Our study considers both functional and QoS characteristics of Web services to identify the optimal business process solutions.</abstract></paper>