<paper id="1847491301"><title>Public key encryption with searchable keywords based on Jacobi symbols</title><year>2007</year><authors><author org="Telcordia Technologies, Piscataway, NJ" id="2923602960">Giovanni Di Crescenzo</author><author org="Univ of MInnesota, Minneapolis, MN" id="2065148359">Vishal Saraswat</author></authors><n_citation>78</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>8287904</reference><reference>1496801598</reference><reference>1512194687</reference><reference>1569083856</reference><reference>1580750219</reference><reference>1797206029</reference><reference>2027309293</reference><reference>2086042811</reference><reference>2110740499</reference><reference>2120976781</reference><reference>2141462088</reference><reference>2151471396</reference><reference>2161214567</reference><reference>2613557339</reference></references><venue id="2759168861" type="C">International Conference on Progress in Cryptology</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-77026-8_21</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.65181">Multiple encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.64324">Attribute-based encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.63229">Deterministic encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.44557">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.66368">Encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.68477">Probabilistic encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.64081">40-bit encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.64577">Filesystem-level encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.63308">56-bit encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.38623">Mathematics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Public-key encryption schemes with searchable keywords are useful to delegate searching capabilities on encrypted data to a third party, who does not hold the entire secret key, but only an appropriate token which allows searching operations but preserves data privacy. Such notion was previously proved to imply identity-based public-key encryption [5] and to be equivalent to anonymous (or key-private) identity-based encryption which are useful for fully-private :[66],"far all presented public-key encryption with keyword search (PEKS) schemes were based on bilinear forms and finding a PEKS that is not based on bilinear forms has been an open problem since the notion of PEKS was first introduced in [5]. We construct a public-key encryption scheme with keyword search based on a variant of the quadratic residuosity problem. We obtain our scheme using a non-trivial transformation of Cocksu0027 identity-based encryption scheme [9]. Thus we show that the primitive of PEKS can be based on additional intractability assumptions which is a conventional desiderata about all cryptographic primitives.</abstract></paper>