<paper id="1966880694"><title>AN EVALUATION OF FEEDBACK IN DOCUMENT RETRIEVAL USING CO‐OCCURRENCE DATA</title><year>1978</year><authors><author org="Computer Laboratory, University Of Cambridge" id="2917937235">David J. Harper</author><author org="" id="1999182239">C. J. van Rijsbergen</author></authors><n_citation>131</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1966365186</reference><reference>2043909051</reference></references><venue id="10082577" type="J">Journal of Documentation</venue><doi>10.1108/eb026659</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.55164">Divergence-from-randomness model</keyword><keyword weight="0.44504">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.49585">Weighting</keyword><keyword weight="0.6957">Relevance feedback</keyword><keyword weight="0.44504">Information retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.42561">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.653">Relevance (information retrieval)</keyword><keyword weight="0.43629">Boolean algebra</keyword><keyword weight="0.52887">Document retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.56613">Term Discrimination</keyword><keyword weight="0.6032">Vector space model</keyword></keywords><publisher>MCB UP Ltd</publisher><abstract>This paper reports experiments with a term weighting model incorporating relevance information in which it is assumed that index terms are distributed dependently. Initially this model was tested with complete relevance information against a similar model which assumes index terms are distributed independently. The experiments demonstrated conclusively that index terms are not independent for a number of diverse document collections. It was concluded that the use of relevance information together with dependence information could potentially improve retrieval effectiveness. As a result of further experiments the initial strict dependence model was modified and in particular a new relevance‐based term weight was developed. This modified dependence model was then used as the basis for relevance feedback, i.e. with partial relevance information only, and significant increases in retrieval effectiveness were achieved. The evaluation method used in the feedback experiments emphasized the effect of the feedback on documents which the potential user would not previously have seen. Finally the incorporation of relevance feedback in an operational system is considered and in particular it is argued that if high recall searches are required, relevance feedback based on the modified dependence model may be superior to the widely used Boolean search.</abstract></paper>