<paper id="1985925577"><title>Unreliable Channels Are Easier to Verify Than Perfect Channels</title><year>1996</year><authors><author org="ENS de Cachan, LIFAC, 61 avenue du Président Wilson, Cachan Cedex, France, 94235f1{cece, finkel}@lifac.ens-cachan.frf1#TAB#" id="1950628705">Gérard Cécé</author><author org="ENS de Cachan, LIFAC, 61 avenue du Président Wilson, Cachan Cedex, France, 94235f1{cece, finkel}@lifac.ens-cachan.frf1#TAB#" id="2118058895">Alain Finkel</author><author org="Department of Computer Science, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, North Carolina, 27695-8206, f2purush@csc.ncsu.eduf2#TAB#" id="2156495138">S. Purushothaman Iyer</author></authors><n_citation>118</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1505482284</reference><reference>1978358700</reference><reference>1980330971</reference><reference>1994564174</reference><reference>2004306067</reference><reference>2025970201</reference><reference>2029117638</reference><reference>2110697379</reference><reference>2123160677</reference><reference>2130994701</reference><reference>2688386367</reference></references><venue id="59933527" type="J">Information &amp; Computation</venue><doi>10.1006/inco.1996.0003</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.50285">FIFO (computing and electronics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.44611">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.49592">Correctness</keyword><keyword weight="0.49144">Deadlock</keyword><keyword weight="0.47924">Decidability</keyword><keyword weight="0.51265">Finite-state machine</keyword><keyword weight="0.44849">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48024">Model of computation</keyword><keyword weight="0.46958">Protocol stack</keyword><keyword weight="0.44534">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.48157">Theory of computation</keyword></keywords><publisher>Academic Press, Inc.</publisher><abstract>We consider the problem of verifying correctness of finite state machines that communicate with each other over unbounded FIFO channels that are unreliable. Various problems of interest in verification of FIFO channels that can lose messages have been considered by Finkel and by Abdulla and Jonsson. We consider, in this paper, other possible unreliable behaviors of communication channels, viz., (a) duplication and (b) insertion errors. Furthermore, we also consider various combinations of duplication, insertion, and lossiness errors. Finite state machines that communicate over unbounded FIFO buffers are a model of computation that forms the backbone of the ISO standard protocol specification languages Estelle and SDL. While the assumption of a perfect communication medium is reasonable at the higher levels of the OSI protocol stack, the lower levels have to deal with an unreliable communication medium; hence our motivation for the present work. The verification problems that are of interest arereachability,unboundedness,deadlock, andmodel-checking against CTL*. All of these problems are undecidable for machines communicating over reliable unbounded FIFO channels. So it is perhaps surprising that some of these problems become decidable when unreliable channels are modeled. The contributions of this paper are (a) an investigation of solutions to these problems for machines with insertion errors, duplication errors, or a combination of duplication, insertion, and lossiness errors, and (b) a comparison of the relative expressive power of the various errors.</abstract></paper>