<paper id="1553052391"><title>A spatio-temporal role-based access control model</title><year>2007</year><authors><author org="Department of Computer Science, Colorado State University#TAB#" id="1966110232">Indrakshi Ray</author><author org="Department of Computer Science, Colorado State University#TAB#" id="29756079">Manachai Toahchoodee</author></authors><n_citation>117</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1542283487</reference><reference>1583803066</reference><reference>1628797000</reference><reference>1998208223</reference><reference>2037716001</reference><reference>2042959266</reference><reference>2076004681</reference><reference>2134167896</reference><reference>2135550767</reference><reference>2141189433</reference><reference>2141696417</reference><reference>2154765153</reference><reference>2156245716</reference><reference>2166602595</reference></references><venue id="" type="">Proceedings of the 21st annual IFIP WG 11.3 working conference on Data and applications security</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-73538-0_16</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.71174">Computer access control</keyword><keyword weight="0.4565">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47278">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.44215">Harm</keyword><keyword weight="0.717">Role-based access control</keyword><keyword weight="0.6284">Access control</keyword><keyword weight="0.5393">Ubiquitous computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.63931">Physical access</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>With the growing advancement of pervasive computing technologies, we are moving towards an era where spatio-temporal information will be necessary for access control. The use of such information can be used for enhancing the security of an application, and it can also be exploited to launch attacks. For critical applications, a formal model for spatio-temporal-based access control is needed that increases the security of the application and ensures that the location information cannot be exploited to cause harm. In this paper, we propose a spatio-temporal access control model, based on the Role-Based Access Control (RBAC) model, that is suitable for pervasive computing applications. We show the association of each component of RBAC with spatio-temporal information. We formalize the model by enumerating the constraints. This model can be used for applications where spatial and temporal information of a subject and an object must be taken into account before granting or denying access.</abstract></paper>