<paper id="1489742585"><title>Working by Walking Around - Requirements of Flexible Interaction Management in Video-supported Collaborative Work</title><year>1996</year><authors><author org="Lancaster University ()" id="2195784926">Steinar Kristoffersen</author><author org="Lancaster University ()" id="1980670276">Tom Rodden</author></authors><n_citation>21</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1482095592</reference><reference>1520754775</reference><reference>1558430934</reference><reference>1977665993</reference><reference>2066432818</reference><reference>2092437514</reference><reference>2102969982</reference><reference>2144421702</reference></references><venue id="" type="">HCI '96 Proceedings of HCI on People and Computers XI</venue><doi>10.1007/978-1-4471-3588-3_20</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Interaction management</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Physical mobility</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Customer service</keyword><keyword weight="0.54294">Computer-supported cooperative work</keyword><keyword weight="0.46762">Communications system</keyword><keyword weight="0.46884">Human–computer interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.45563">High Street</keyword><keyword weight="0.39162">Engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.40298">Ethnography</keyword><keyword weight="0.46356">Multimedia</keyword><keyword weight="0.45264">Modal</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><abstract>This paper considers the effects of video-based communication systems on individual, local mobility in the everyday, practical ‘space’ of work. The notion of video as a vehicle that transcends physical space in an unproblematic fashion is carefully considered. Previous academic research has emphasized how video can extend and enhance the working environment. We found, doing a focused ethnography in the Customer Service Centre of a large high street bank, that video, in a trade-off between ‘real’ and ‘virtual’ mobility, restricted the use of personal, workaday, physical space. Issues thus raised for the design of video-based communication systems are: physical mobility in workaday space during interactive sessions; modal and temporal switching between and within different media; articulating and supporting collaborative work with private activities; and, accommodating alternating tasks.</abstract></paper>