<paper id="1495593089"><title>Understanding GDSS in symbolic context: shifting the focus from technology to interaction</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="" id="2695828771">Abhijit Gopal</author><author org="University of Calgary" id="2695121327">Pushkala Prasad</author></authors><n_citation>137</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1499788016</reference><reference>1552845745</reference><reference>1568426942</reference><reference>1571750337</reference><reference>1578743203</reference><reference>1595507819</reference><reference>1992902116</reference><reference>1998444060</reference><reference>2025621867</reference><reference>2031551260</reference><reference>2118612095</reference><reference>2124992332</reference><reference>2160214673</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/3250972</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.52827">Symbolic interactionism</keyword><keyword weight="0.437">Psychology</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Human interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.4953">Qualitative research</keyword><keyword weight="0.45316">Management science</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>GDSS has enjoyed about a decade and a half of vigorous research activity. Throughout this time, a problem that has occupied the research community is the inconsistent research results that have been obtained. The purpose of this paper is to assess whether the reason for these inconsistencies is rooted in the epistemological mode that has prevailed and to offer an alternative epistemological lens that might help advance our understanding of GDSS use and research. Using qualitative research methods and a symbolic interactionist theoretical basis, this paper examines how a particular group used a GDSS over two meetings. The findings indicate that GDSS use may result in reactions from its users that are difficult to capture using conventional methodological assumptions, thereby helping explain why past results have not been consistent. Based on these findings, a shift in focus is advocated from an emphasis on the technology to an emphasis on human interaction, one that embraces the reasons underlying past inconsistencies rather than attempting to overcome them.</abstract></paper>