<paper id="1764789126"><title>Semantically Guided First-Order Theorem Proving using Hyper-Linking</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="University of North Carolina" id="2140664243">Heng Chu</author><author org="University of North Carolina" id="174197633">David A. Plaisted</author></authors><n_citation>27</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>10893761</reference><reference>151139880</reference><reference>1518885648</reference><reference>1540452401</reference><reference>1564537570</reference><reference>1660563560</reference><reference>1757218398</reference><reference>1924552249</reference><reference>1998330152</reference><reference>1999997889</reference><reference>2013434344</reference><reference>2022796917</reference><reference>2026328078</reference><reference>2038464985</reference><reference>2062897452</reference><reference>2067716734</reference><reference>2069224897</reference><reference>2126583599</reference><reference>2913781829</reference></references><venue id="1134440762" type="C">Conference on Automated Deduction</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-58156-1_14</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.60622">Computer-assisted proof</keyword><keyword weight="0.43991">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.46091">Programming language</keyword><keyword weight="0.64042">Gödel's completeness theorem</keyword><keyword weight="0.45212">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.62833">Automated theorem proving</keyword><keyword weight="0.44176">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.61223">Mathematical proof</keyword><keyword weight="0.63374">First-order logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.58553">Fundamental theorem</keyword><keyword weight="0.59785">Compactness theorem</keyword><keyword weight="0.63984">Formal proof</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>An automated theorem prover accepts a set of axioms and a theorem, expressed in a formal logic, and then proves that the theorem logically follows from the axioms. Two basic aspects of a logic are syntax and semantics. Syntax refers to the form of the statements and semantics refers to their meanings. Most current theorem provers conduct proof searching based on syntax only and semantics is rarely :[67],"this dissertation we propose a new and complete theorem proving method, called semantic hyper-linking, which makes a substantial use of semantics in an instance-based theorem prover for first-order logic. Semantics is used to generate instances by a combination of unification and enumeration of the Herbrand base. In :[67],"this method, the proof searching is essentially a process of exhaustively searching for a model of the input :[133],"hyper-linking performs especially well on non-Horn problems whose proofs contain small instances of the input clauses. We also describe several refinements including (1) various model finding strategies to improve model searching without using expensive semantic checks or expanding the search space, (2) the rough resolution method to cooperate with semantic :[133],"hyper-linking and solve the part of the proof which contains large instances, and (3) the well-known UR resolution to solve the Horn part of the :[209],"have implemented semantic :[133],"hyper-linking with its refinements, and applied it to over a hundred problems in various domains. Our results show that semantic :[133],"hyper-linking is indeed a promising technique. Several hard theorems, which many other theorem provers find difficult, :[209],"have been proved by semantic :[133],"hyper-linking using no other guidance than the given semantics.</abstract></paper>