<paper id="1512948333"><title>Parametric queries, linear constraints and variable elimination</title><year>1990</year><authors><author org="IBM T.J. Watson research center" id="1997770148">Jean-Louis Lassez</author></authors><n_citation>13</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>34388807</reference><reference>75790213</reference><reference>1554378316</reference><reference>2030334004</reference><reference>2037690395</reference></references><venue id="2754737771" type="C">International Symposium on Design and Implementation of Symbolic Computation Systems</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-52531-9_136</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.50265">Extreme point</keyword><keyword weight="0.4678">Mathematical optimization</keyword><keyword weight="0.58423">Variable elimination</keyword><keyword weight="0.47027">Algebra</keyword><keyword weight="0.5256">Convex hull</keyword><keyword weight="0.52736">Symbolic computation</keyword><keyword weight="0.52792">Canonical form</keyword><keyword weight="0.52006">Parametric statistics</keyword><keyword weight="0.57061">Linear programming</keyword><keyword weight="0.57875">Linear programming relaxation</keyword><keyword weight="0.42648">Mathematics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Various forms of declarative linear arithmetic are introduced in a number of languages from CLP(ℛ) to Mathematica. In order to find canonical representations of constraints, to handle delays of non-linear constraints, to resolve guards in committed choice languages and other related problems, we need to answer a new and more powerful type of queries: parametric linear queries. We propose here a simple mathematical formalism to address that problem. In a first part we show that Fourieru0027s variable elimination procedure and associated elementary theorems allow us to derive directly from their specification a number of interesting sets. For instance we obtain the subsumption cone, which characterizes the set of all linear constraints implied by a set of linear constraints, the convex hull of a collection of polyhedral sets, the separability set which characterizes the hyperplanes separating two given polyhedral sets, and of course the set of answers to a given parametric query. If Fourieru0027s variable elimination is a very powerful conceptual tool telling us what problems we can solve trivially in principle via variable elimination, it is in general hopelessly impractical as it generates for each variable eliminated an exponentially growing set of mostly redundant constraints. In a second part we use a method for variable elimination which rests on a generalization of the notion of objective function in linear programming. It is more efficient than Fourieru0027s procedure as it bypasses all the costly intermediate steps and generates far less redundancy. In a third part we apply that method to solve more efficiently the problem of implicit equalities which is a key component in the computation of canonical representations of linear constraints. In the concluding remarks we mention that such techniques could be used as a basis for a symbolic computation system in the linear case. The main problem faced here is that the size of the output may be exponential. To (partially) overcome this problem we propose a technique to generate very efficiently approximations of the output. These approximations have a small size, they represent spheres rather than polyhedral sets.</abstract></paper>