<paper id="1532447905"><title>Characterizing Kripke structures in temporal logic</title><year>1987</year><authors><author org="Carnegie - Mellon University#TAB#" id="2410944151">Michael C. Browne</author><author org="Carnegie - Mellon University#TAB#" id="2129477832">Edmund M. Clarke</author><author org="Carnegie - Mellon University#TAB#" id="1993734283">Orna Grumberg</author></authors><n_citation>35</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>80787065</reference><reference>1487199072</reference><reference>1501731334</reference><reference>1535981988</reference><reference>1589421353</reference><reference>2000138546</reference><reference>2003227046</reference><reference>2004306067</reference><reference>2030926579</reference><reference>2040127143</reference><reference>2041403185</reference><reference>2054554282</reference><reference>2072887965</reference><reference>2080641824</reference><reference>2090398333</reference><reference>2401007240</reference></references><venue id="2756386172" type="C">Colloquium on trees in Algebra and Programming</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-17660-8_60</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.72515">Computation tree logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.44474">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.7021">Temporal logic of actions</keyword><keyword weight="0.70696">Interval temporal logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.45138">Algebra</keyword><keyword weight="0.70024">Multimodal logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.77719">Linear temporal logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.70871">Modal logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.70699">Temporal logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.40869">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.70273">Intermediate logic</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Abstract : The question of whether branching-time temporal logic or linear-time temporal logic is best for reasoning about concurrent programs is one of the most controversial issues in logics of programs. Concurrent programs are usually modelled by labelled state-transition graphs in which some state is designated as the initial state. For historical reasons such graphs are called Kripke structures. In linear temporal logic operators are provided for describing events along a single time path (i.e., along a single path in a Kripke structure). In a branching-time logic the temporal operators quantify over the futures that are possible from a given state (i.e., over the possible paths that lead from a state). It is well known that the two types of temporal logic have different expressive powers. Linear temporal logic, for example, can express certain fairness properties that cannot be expressed in branching-time temporal logic. On the other hand, certain practical decision problems like model checking are easier for branching-time temporal logic than for linear temporal logic. This paper provides further insight on which type of logic is best. It is shown that if two finite Kripke structures can be distinguished by some formula that contains both branching-time and linear-time operators, then the structures can be distinguished by a formula that contains only branching time operators. Specifically, we show that if two finite Kripke structures can be distinguished by some formula of the logic CTL (i.e., if there is some CTL formula that is true in one but not in the other), then they can be distinguished by some formula of the logic CTL.</abstract></paper>