<paper id="1936416101"><title>The AS/400 cluster engine: A case study</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="IBM Res. Labs, Haifa Univ., Israel" id="2763794349">G. Goft</author><author org="" id="2667998967">E.Y. Lotem</author></authors><n_citation>11</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2115173549</reference><reference>2117233780</reference><reference>2168380557</reference><reference>2171688871</reference></references><venue id="2756313409" type="C">ICPP Workshops on Collaboration and Mobile Computing</venue><doi>10.1109/ICPPW.1999.800039</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.50523">Middleware</keyword><keyword weight="0.44225">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.51533">Communication in small groups</keyword><keyword weight="0.46144">Computer network</keyword><keyword weight="0.47307">Internet protocol suite</keyword><keyword weight="0.46941">Callback</keyword><keyword weight="0.45826">Computer-aided software engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.5475">Virtual synchrony</keyword><keyword weight="0.50151">High availability</keyword><keyword weight="0.4563">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.46672">Disaster recovery</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>In this paper we share our experience in harnessing group communications for the AS/400 cluster infrastructure. The main fonts of the AS/400 cluster is providing high availability and disaster recovery of defined cluster resources. The cluster supports up to 128 nodes, connected via any IP network. Cluster nodes and resources can be dynamically added or removed. Administrative actions or failures trigger automatic cluster reconfigurations: CLUE (Cluster Engine) is the group communication middleware implemented in the OS/400 kernel. It exploits the strong virtual synchrony model. CLUE is unique in the following aspects: It is the first virtually synchronous group communication system incorporated into a cluster solution, and customized to meet cluster needs. It is the only group communication system (GCS) integrated into a commercial operating system kernel. CLUEu0027s special features (e.g., Flexible Group Member) can be relevant to other group communication systems.</abstract></paper>