<paper id="1665657766"><title>Virtual democratic dialogue? Bringing together citizens and politicians</title><year>2003</year><authors><author org="Department of Political Science, University of Aarhus, Universitetsparken, DK-8000 Aarhus C, Denmark. Tel.: +45 89421260" id="2478311549">Jakob Linaa Jensen</author></authors><n_citation>42</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>2082812744</reference></references><venue id="2764630084" type="J">Information Polity archive</venue><doi>10.3233/ip-2003-0025</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46401">Public administration</keyword><keyword weight="0.51664">Deliberation</keyword><keyword weight="0.44332">Sociology</keyword><keyword weight="0.48202">Local government</keyword><keyword weight="0.48832">Argumentation theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.49115">Democracy</keyword><keyword weight="0.49064">Politics</keyword><keyword weight="0.51323">E-democracy</keyword><keyword weight="0.44369">The Internet</keyword><keyword weight="0.48232">Government</keyword></keywords><publisher>IOS Press</publisher><abstract>How to realize the potential of the Internet for creating virtual public spheres for democratic dialogue has been widely discussed. It has been argued that government should play a more active role in that process. This paper examines a Danish case sponsored by a local government where citizens and politicians were invited to debate via the Internet. It is concluded that the project was quite a success. The overall tone of the debate was respectful and the levels of argumentation, information and deliberation were generally high. Further, the presence of politicians created a debate space consisting of two dimensions and five relations. Two main processes took place within that space: general debates and consultation processes between citizens and politicians. As such, the project achieved a double purpose. Problematically, the project did not succeed in mobilising new groups for political debate. Further, it was a tendency that the politicians tended to dominate the debate leaving less space for debates among citizens.</abstract></paper>