<paper id="1597103392"><title>Polarization and persuasive argumentation: a study of decision making in group settings</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="Texas A and M University#TAB#" id="1979134691">Maha El-Shinnawy</author><author org="WPC: Information Systems" id="2207498061">Ajay S. Vinze</author></authors><n_citation>83</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>606446868</reference><reference>831661962</reference><reference>1480197836</reference><reference>1523264430</reference><reference>1549595874</reference><reference>1552593222</reference><reference>1578743203</reference><reference>1589637088</reference><reference>1972098965</reference><reference>1995864118</reference><reference>2009365258</reference><reference>2088568710</reference><reference>2090115807</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/249394</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.43451">Social psychology</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Research method</keyword><keyword weight="0.4162">Covariate</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Support system</keyword><keyword weight="0.4688">Argumentation theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.42216">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.42014">Psychology</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Group composition</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Group process</keyword><keyword weight="0.65013">Group decision-making</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>ization in a contemporary communication context. The proposed model focuses on commu~ nication medium, task characteristics, group composition, and their interaction as explanations for the outcome of group polarization and the process that precedes it..An experimental research method is used to test the relationships suggested by the model. In this study, group polarization is recorded by comparing decisions at the individual level, face-to-face group settings, and GSS mediated settings. The initial agreement index indicates the diversity of individual stances within the group. This index is used as a covariate to enhance understanding of the extent of group polarization. The group process is documented by protocol analyzing transcriptions of the FTF and GSS group sessions for persuasive content. A 2x2x2 factorial design was used to analyze the results. The analysis indicates that, for both process and outcomes, the medium of communication and task characteristics interact with one another to provide the dominant explanation. Surprisingly, group composition had no impact on either polarization or persuasive arguments. The findings reported in this study are of importance to organizations that increasingly rely on groups as units of decision making. The results also provide insight to researchers of group decision making and to future developers and users of group support systems.</abstract></paper>