<paper id="1790973071"><title>Scholarly communication as a socioecological system</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="Helmke Library, Indiana University-Purdue University Fort Wayne, Fort Wayne, (USA)" id="2124680474">Pamela Effrein Sandstrom</author></authors><n_citation>48</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1484884568</reference><reference>1491354822</reference><reference>1966538856</reference><reference>1987606192</reference><reference>1992658095</reference><reference>1996426871</reference><reference>2005207065</reference><reference>2009833850</reference><reference>2010461395</reference><reference>2020713996</reference><reference>2055862326</reference><reference>2069081894</reference><reference>2072897447</reference><reference>2073608660</reference><reference>2129936978</reference></references><venue id="148561398" type="J">Scientometrics</venue><doi>10.1023/A:1019655305286</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44555">Data science</keyword><keyword weight="0.43035">Social psychology</keyword><keyword weight="0.59728">Information foraging</keyword><keyword weight="0.4858">Survey data collection</keyword><keyword weight="0.39793">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.50605">Multidimensional scaling</keyword><keyword weight="0.53745">Mediated communication</keyword><keyword weight="0.42043">Sociology</keyword><keyword weight="0.49241">Scientific communication</keyword><keyword weight="0.51878">Human behavioral ecology</keyword><keyword weight="0.50268">Scholarly communication</keyword><keyword weight="0.4981">Foraging</keyword></keywords><publisher>Akadémiai Kiadó, co-published with Springer Science+Business Media B.V., Formerly Kluwer Academic Publishers B.V.</publisher><abstract>Among Belver C. Griffithu0027s many contributions to disciplinary communication is the idea that science and scholarship at large constitute a social system to be investigated empirically. This paper reports findings of an author co-citation analysis of the field of human behavioral ecology that expands Griffithu0027s concept of the social system of scientific communication to fit a socioecological framework. Cluster analysis and multidimensional scaling techniques are used to characterize the research specialty at large and portray five respondentsu0027 individual resource maps. The techniques reveal co-citation relationships among authors whose work they had referenced in recent articles. Survey data on searching and handling behaviors for an aggregated sample of 180 cited references are correlated with core-periphery zones of the individual maps. Findings that types of socially mediated communication and distinctive information foraging behaviors correlate with different zones of a bibliographic microhabitat support an interpretation that active specialty members conform to foraging efficiency principles as predicted by prey-choice models from optimal foraging theory.</abstract></paper>