<paper id="1555310264"><title>On the Definition of a Framework for an Architecting Process Supporting Product Family Development</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="ROBERT BOSCH CORP." id="2295788397">Steffen Thiel</author></authors><n_citation>19</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1516156619</reference><reference>1553120816</reference><reference>1554977156</reference><reference>1571440521</reference><reference>1600979142</reference><reference>2023546887</reference><reference>2077318760</reference><reference>2105539612</reference><reference>2116844130</reference><reference>2122824813</reference><reference>2157130167</reference><reference>2524834217</reference></references><venue id="" type="">PFE '01 Revised Papers from the 4th International Workshop on Software Product-Family Engineering</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-47833-7_13</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.6103">Product engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.46144">Systems engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.60106">Design review</keyword><keyword weight="0.58595">Product management</keyword><keyword weight="0.60043">Product design specification</keyword><keyword weight="0.54892">Software product line</keyword><keyword weight="0.40704">Engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.55811">View model</keyword><keyword weight="0.55992">Cost reduction</keyword><keyword weight="0.46583">Process management</keyword><keyword weight="0.60509">New product development</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Product families are an important system development paradigm that can yield significant improvements in time-to-market, cost reduction, and quality. In order to gain such improvements, a product family must be built based on a common architecture. The architecture is a key artifact of the development process because all product family members make use of it. However, not all requirements on designing such architectures have been addressed in depth within current research. This paper presents QUASAR, a process framework that supports the design of high-quality product family architectures. QUASAR deals with early architectural considerations, guides the modelling of architectural views and variability, and documents how to evaluate the achievement of architectural qualities. The paper describes fundamental concepts, activities, and benefits of the QUASAR framework.</abstract></paper>