<paper id="1563242841"><title>Coverage Preserving Reduction Strategies for Reachability Analysis</title><year>1992</year><authors><author org="AT&amp;T Bell Laboratories, Murray Hill, New Jersey 07974, USA" id="2028047182">Gerard J. Holzmann</author><author org="Université de Liège, Institut Montefiore B28, 4000 Liège Sart-Tilman, Belgium" id="2634395717">Patrice Godefroid</author><author org="Université de Liège, Institut Montefiore B28, 4000 Liège Sart-Tilman, Belgium" id="2151914609">Didier Pirottin</author></authors><n_citation>88</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1552945284</reference><reference>1573453798</reference><reference>1968552123</reference><reference>2016300863</reference><reference>2131101129</reference><reference>2147539576</reference><reference>2554105671</reference></references><venue id="" type="">Proceedings of the IFIP TC6/WG6.1 Twelth International Symposium on Protocol Specification, Testing and Verification XII</venue><doi>10.1016/B978-0-444-89874-6.50028-3</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46983">Mathematical optimization</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">State space exploration</keyword><keyword weight="0.47195">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.4759">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.54559">Reachability</keyword><keyword weight="0.45456">Implementation</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">State space reduction</keyword><keyword weight="0.65312">State space</keyword><keyword weight="0.45166">Semantics</keyword></keywords><publisher>North-Holland Publishing Co.</publisher><abstract>Abstract We study the effect of three new reduction strategies for conventional reachability analysis, as used in automated protocol validation algorithms. The first two strategies are implementations of partial order semantics rules that attempt to minimize the number of execution sequences that need to be explored for a full state space exploration. The third strategy is the implementation of a state compression scheme that attempts to minimize the amount of memory that is used to built a state space. The three strategies are shown to have a potential for substantially improving the performance of a conventional search. The paper discusses the optimal choices for reducing either run time or memory requirements by four to six times. The strategies can readily be combined with each other and with alternative state space reduction techniques such as supertrace or state space caching methods.</abstract></paper>