<paper id="176704956"><title>A case-based framework for workflow model management</title><year>2003</year><authors><author org="MIS Department, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona" id="2177969657">Therani Madhusudan</author><author org="MIS Department, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona" id="2112241722">J. Leon Zhao</author></authors><n_citation>7</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1509999309</reference><reference>1841745562</reference><reference>2008896880</reference><reference>2027236907</reference><reference>2050137450</reference><reference>2055487721</reference><reference>2084011773</reference><reference>2105718463</reference><reference>2126385963</reference><reference>2142386413</reference><reference>2151542743</reference><reference>2154581711</reference><reference>2156543375</reference><reference>2163733570</reference><reference>2170275915</reference></references><venue id="1152238068" type="C">Business Process Management</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-44895-0_24</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.63844">Business process management</keyword><keyword weight="0.67187">Workflow Management Coalition</keyword><keyword weight="0.76877">Workflow technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.46058">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.71036">Windows Workflow Foundation</keyword><keyword weight="0.69737">XPDL</keyword><keyword weight="0.79486">Workflow engine</keyword><keyword weight="0.76526">Workflow management system</keyword><keyword weight="0.68022">Workflow</keyword><keyword weight="0.46353">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Case-oriented workflow modeling provides flexibility in specifying and executing workflows because it is possible to consider unique, organization-specific business process conditions and thereby minimize exceptions. However, it is a laborious task for a workflow designer to derive a case-oriented workflow model from a business specification, resulting in high modeling overhead. Recent commercial systems are providing generic templates of common business processes which may be adapted to an organizations requirements. These templates, called cases, can be modified individually or multiple cases may be composed into a more complex workflow and then the assembled workflow may be modified as needed to meet the business specification. In this paper, we propose a novel framework for case-oriented retrieval, instantiation and reuse of workflow models utilizing Case-Based Reasoning (CBR) techniques. We describe key modules of a prototypical implementation to facilitate model management activities such as model retrieval, reuse and composition of component case models from a workflow repository.</abstract></paper>