<paper id="89505884"><title>Representation and utilization of non-functional requirements for information system design</title><year>1991</year><authors><author org="University of Toronto,#TAB#" id="2702792241">Lawerence Chung</author></authors><n_citation>47</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>36459598</reference><reference>1510321966</reference><reference>1524141096</reference><reference>1542413779</reference><reference>1979635618</reference><reference>2028606263</reference><reference>2072443175</reference><reference>2079814255</reference><reference>2089763961</reference><reference>2146054836</reference><reference>2160645305</reference><reference>2162598207</reference><reference>2173365148</reference><reference>2293634425</reference></references><venue id="1134069326" type="C">Conference on Advanced Information Systems Engineering</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-54059-8_78</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.52496">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.54678">Functional requirement</keyword><keyword weight="0.59078">Axiomatic design</keyword><keyword weight="0.46005">Systems engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.46212">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46399">Premise</keyword><keyword weight="0.5321">Engineering design process</keyword><keyword weight="0.50732">Application domain</keyword><keyword weight="0.49184">Executive information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.62871">Non-functional requirement</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The complexity and usefulness of large information systems are determined partly by their functionality, i.e., what they do, and partly by global constraints on their accuracy, security, cost, user-friendliness, performance, and the like. Even with the growing interest in developing higher-level models and design paradigms, current technology is inadequate both representationally for expressing such global constraints as formal non-functional requirements and methodologically for utilizing them in generating designs. We propose both a representational and methodological framework for non-functional requirements, focusing on accuracy requirements. With the premise that accuracy is an inherent semantic attribute of information, we take a first step towards establishing a representational basis for accuracy. To guide the design process and justify design decisions, we propose a goal-oriented methodology. In the methodology, accuracy requirements are treated as (potentially conflicting) goals, for which two types of methods are presented: one for decomposing the goals in terms of affected design components, and the other for contributing, either positively or negatively, to goal satisfaction. Non-functional requirements are further investigated for their cooperation and conflicts, which enables the assessment of the quality of overall design. A detailed illustration demonstrates how the framework aids a designeru0027s decision-making process by recommending the types of consultation needed with users in the intended application domain.</abstract></paper>