<paper id="1965537706"><title>Dynamic and adaptive composition of e-services</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="Software Technology Lab, Hewlett-Packard Laboratories, IU-4A, 1501 Page Mill Road, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA" id="2145207705">Fabio Casati</author><author org="Software Technology Lab, Hewlett-Packard Laboratories, IU-4A, 1501 Page Mill Road, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA" id="2951858106">Ming-Chien Shan</author></authors><n_citation>326</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1570265525</reference><reference>1784424132</reference><reference>1885634701</reference><reference>1987024198</reference><reference>2062756186</reference><reference>2104910798</reference></references><venue id="193006928" type="J">Information Systems</venue><doi>10.1016/S0306-4379(01)00014-X</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.40597">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.45548">Pace</keyword><keyword weight="0.43595">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.51799">E-services</keyword><keyword weight="0.53121">Business opportunity</keyword><keyword weight="0.45742">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.59274">Service provider</keyword><keyword weight="0.53625">Integrated services</keyword><keyword weight="0.49731">Business intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.52605">Workflow</keyword><keyword weight="0.48678">Payment</keyword><keyword weight="0.44046">Database</keyword></keywords><publisher>Pergamon</publisher><abstract>Abstract The Web is rapidly becoming the platform through which many companies deliver services to businesses and individual customers. The number and type of on-line services increase day by day, and this trend is likely to continue at an even faster pace in the immediate future. Examples of e-services currently available include bill payment, delivery of customized news, or archiving and sharing of digital documents. E-Services are typically delivered individually. However, the e-service market creates the opportunity for providing value-added , integrated services , which are delivered by composing existing e-services. To support organizations in pursuing this business opportunity we have developed eFlow , a system that supports the specification, enactment, and management of composite e-services, modeled as processes that are enacted by a service process engine. Composite e-services have to cope with a highly dynamic business environment in terms of services and of service providers. In addition, the increased competition forces companies to provide customized services to better satisfy the needs of every individual customer. Ideally, service process should be able to transparently adapt to changes in the environment and to the need of different customers with minimal or no user intervention. In addition, it should be possible to dynamically modify service process definitions in a simple and effective way to manage cases where user intervention is indeed required. In this paper we show how eFlow achieves these goals.</abstract></paper>