<paper id="1568745847"><title>Designated verifier signature schemes: attacks, new security notions and a new construction</title><year>2005</year><authors><author org="Cybernetica AS and University of Tartu, Estonia#TAB#" id="15605393">Helger Lipmaa</author><author org="Institute for Infocomm Research (I2R), Singapore#TAB#" id="2780829145">Guilin Wang</author><author org="Institute for Infocomm Research (I2R), Singapore#TAB#" id="2924724599">Feng Bao</author></authors><n_citation>117</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1500682127</reference><reference>1546600652</reference><reference>1566256504</reference><reference>1569033204</reference><reference>2107561818</reference><reference>2126609334</reference><reference>2132022887</reference><reference>2405024498</reference><reference>2610184982</reference></references><venue id="1141821850" type="C">International Colloquium on Automata, Languages and Programming</venue><doi>10.1007/11523468_38</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.43939">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45318">Automaton</keyword><keyword weight="0.61999">Random oracle</keyword><keyword weight="0.54583">Oracle</keyword><keyword weight="0.43082">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.59062">Digital signature</keyword><keyword weight="0.44412">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48147">String (computer science)</keyword><keyword weight="0.64461">Designated verifier signature</keyword><keyword weight="0.52293">Diffie–Hellman problem</keyword><keyword weight="0.68731">Schnorr signature</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We show that the signer can abuse the disavowal protocol in the Jakobsson-Sako-Impagliazzo designated-verifier signature scheme. In addition, we identify a new security property—non-delegatability—that is essential for designated-verifier signatures, and show that several previously proposed designated-verifier schemes are delegatable. We give a rigorous formalisation of the security for designated-verifier signature schemes, and propose a new and efficient designated-verifier signature scheme that is provably unforgeable under a tight reduction to the Decisional Diffie-Hellman problem in the non-programmable random oracle model, and non-delegatable under a loose reduction in the programmable random oracle model. As a direct corollary, we also get a new efficient conventional signature scheme that is provably unforgeable under a tight reduction to the Decisional Diffie-Hellman problem in the non-programmable random oracle plus common reference string model.</abstract></paper>