<paper id="1872862526"><title>Syntax, Semantics, and Pragmatics of Contexts</title><year>1995</year><authors><author org="State University of New York at Binghamton" id="2101903223">John F. Sowa</author></authors><n_citation>20</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1493596129</reference><reference>1555476679</reference><reference>1582487692</reference><reference>2063205466</reference><reference>2081781117</reference></references><venue id="1137878512" type="C">International Conference on Conceptual Structures</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-60161-9_25</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.5487">Pragmatics</keyword><keyword weight="0.40535">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.59228">Situation semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.57466">Conceptual graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.53874">Semantic network</keyword><keyword weight="0.57138">Discourse representation theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.52853">Predicate (grammar)</keyword><keyword weight="0.47015">Linguistics</keyword><keyword weight="0.5003">Syntax</keyword><keyword weight="0.53304">Semantics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The notion of context is indispensable in discussions of meaning, but the word context has often been used in conflicting senses. In logic, the first representation of context as a formal object was by the philosopher C. S. Peirce; but for nearly eighty years, his treatment was unknown outside a small group of Peirce afficionados. In the early 1980s, three new theories included related notions of context: Kampu0027s discourse representation theory; Barwise and Perryu0027s situation semantics; and Sowau0027s conceptual graphs, which explicitly introduced Peirceu0027s approach to the AI community. More recently, John McCarthy and his students have begun to use a closely related notion of context as a basis for organizing and partitioning knowledge bases. Each of the theories has distinctive, but complementary ideas that can enrich the others, but the relationships between them are far from clear. This paper analyzes the semantic foundations of these theories and shows how McCarthyu0027s ist(c,p) predicate can be interpreted in terms of the semantic notions underlying the others.</abstract></paper>