<paper id="1961867604"><title>Is anybody out there?: antecedents of trust in global virtual teams</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="" id="229437117">Sirkka L. Jarvenpaa</author><author org="University of Colorado - Denver" id="2158581469">Kathleen Knoll</author><author org="University of Texas at Austin" id="729327767">Dorothy E. Leidner</author></authors><n_citation>1436</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>47070747</reference><reference>2132277798</reference></references><venue id="9954729" type="J">Journal of Management Information Systems</venue><doi>10.1080/07421222.1998.11518185</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.65569">Team effectiveness</keyword><keyword weight="0.56">Teamwork</keyword><keyword weight="0.3857">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.65864">Psychological safety</keyword><keyword weight="0.4576">Public relations</keyword><keyword weight="0.45102">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.66246">Virtual team</keyword><keyword weight="0.42816">Perception</keyword></keywords><publisher>M. E. Sharpe, Inc.</publisher><abstract>A global virtual team is an example of a boundaryless network organization form where a temporary team is assembled on an as-needed basis for the duration of a task and staffed by members from different countries. In such teams, coordination is accomplished via trust and shared communication systems. The focus of the reported study was to explore the antecedents of trust in a global virtual-team setting. Seventyfive teams, consisting of four to six members residing in different countries, interacted and worked together for eight weeks. The two-week trust-building exercises did have a significant effect on the team membersu0027 perceptions of the other membersu0027 ability, integrity, and benevolence. In the early phases of teamwork, team trust was predicted strongest by perceptions of other team membersu0027 integrity, and weakest by perceptions of their benevolence. The effect of other membersu0027 perceived ability on trust decreased over time. The membersu0027 own propensity to trust had a significant, though unchanging, effect on trust. A qualitative analysis of six teamsu0027 electronic mail messages explored strategies that were used by the three highest trust teams, but were used infrequently or not at all by the three lowest trust teams. The strategies suggest the presence of "swift" trust. The paper advances a research model for explaining trust in global virtual teams.</abstract></paper>