<paper id="1551401137"><title>Formal Verification of BPEL4WS Business Collaborations</title><year>2004</year><authors><author org="Carlos III University of Madrid," id="2006328392">Jesús Arias Fisteus</author><author org="Carlos III University of Madrid," id="2231045907">Luis Sánchez Fernández</author><author org="Carlos III University of Madrid," id="1995220988">Carlos Delgado Kloos</author></authors><n_citation>71</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2105718463</reference><reference>2145860989</reference><reference>2164015376</reference><reference>2166309559</reference><reference>2340735175</reference></references><venue id="2627069240" type="C">International Conference on Electronic Commerce</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-30077-9_8</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.49239">Model checking</keyword><keyword weight="0.56689">Business process</keyword><keyword weight="0.47888">Software engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.43361">Simulation</keyword><keyword weight="0.46677">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48965">Linear temporal logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.67021">Promela</keyword><keyword weight="0.4939">Modular design</keyword><keyword weight="0.5689">Formal methods</keyword><keyword weight="0.50217">Web service</keyword><keyword weight="0.55944">Formal verification</keyword><keyword weight="0.45643">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Web services are a very appropriate communication mechanism to perform distributed business processes among several organisations. These processes should be reliable, because a failure in them can cause high economic losses. To increase their reliability at design time, we have developed VERBUS, a framework for the formal verification of business processes. VERBUS can automatically translate business process definitions to specifications verifiable in several available tools. It is based on a modular and extensible architecture: new process definition languages and verification tools can be added easily to the framework. The prototype of VERBUS presented in this work can verify BPEL4WS process specifications, by translating them to Promela. The Promela specifications are verified with the well known model checker Spin. In this paper we describe the general architecture of VERBUS and how BPEL4WS specifications are translated and verified. The explanation is completed by describing what types of properties can be verified and providing an overview of the implementation.</abstract></paper>