<paper id="1481712943"><title>The Sum-and-Lattice-Points Method Based on an Evidential-Reasoning System Applied to the Real-Time Vehicle Guidance Problem</title><year>1988</year><authors><author org="640 Taylor Court, #504, Mountain View, California 94043" id="2552819165">Shoshana Abel</author></authors><n_citation>8</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2015071685</reference></references><venue id="1204606053" type="C">Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence</venue><doi>10.1016/B978-0-444-70396-5.50035-2</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.5089">Conceptual design</keyword><keyword weight="0.54343">Knowledge representation and reasoning</keyword><keyword weight="0.46613">Systems engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.45965">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.58538">Expert system</keyword><keyword weight="0.62518">Navigation system</keyword><keyword weight="0.45461">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.589">Guidance system</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Vehicle guidance</keyword><keyword weight="0.52221">Evidential reasoning approach</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Basic research</keyword><keyword weight="0.45653">Machine learning</keyword></keywords><publisher>North-Holland</publisher><abstract>Publisher Summary This chapter discusses the sum-and-lattice-points method based on an evidential-reasoning system applied to the real-time vehicle guidance problem. It presents a methodology for research and development of the inferencing and knowledge representation aspects of an expert system approach for performing reasoning under uncertainty in support of a real time vehicle guidance and navigation system. Such a system can be of major benefit for nonterrain following low altitude flight systems operating in foreign hostile environments. The chapter describes the basic research, development, and conceptual design of a prototype based on numerical algorithms and an evidential-reasoning expert system for effective real-time flight guidance and navigation. The primary function of the expert system is, at a minimum, to provide the pilot with guidance or to perform autonomous navigation and response. This response is based on the perceived situation in conjunction with the mission and basic operational guidelines. The information combination and usage of artificial intelligence techniques for real-time flight guidance system yield the real-time displays, recommendations to the pilot, and the automated computer commands to the flight vehicle.</abstract></paper>