<paper id="1703497850"><title>A Workflow System through Cooperating Agents for Control and Document Flow over the Internet</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="Middle East Technical University, METU" id="582313750">Asuman Dogac</author><author org="Middle East Technical University, METU" id="2017570010">Yusuf Tambag</author><author org="Middle East Technical University, METU" id="2112976725">A. Tumer</author><author org="Middle East Technical University, METU" id="368100679">M. Ezbiderli</author><author org="Middle East Technical University, METU" id="679539391">Nesime Tatbul</author><author org="Middle East Technical University, METU" id="360810803">N. Hamali</author><author org="Middle East Technical University, METU" id="2864319206">C. Icdem</author><author org="Hebrew University" id="345432764">Catriel Beeri</author></authors><n_citation>11</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2159718730</reference></references><venue id="1147734270" type="C">Cooperative Information Systems</venue><doi>10.1007/10722620_14</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.52732">Information flow (information theory)</keyword><keyword weight="0.46147">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.47155">Software engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.50555">Firewall (construction)</keyword><keyword weight="0.45975">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.55099">Document management system</keyword><keyword weight="0.5196">Graphical user interface</keyword><keyword weight="0.5824">User interface</keyword><keyword weight="0.54705">Workflow</keyword><keyword weight="0.54557">Data flow diagram</keyword><keyword weight="0.5258">The Internet</keyword><keyword weight="0.46176">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In this paper we describe an architecture that provides for automating and monitoring the flow of control and document over the Internet among different organizations, thereby creating a platform necessary to describe higher order processes involving several organizations and companies. The higher order process is designed through a graphical user interface and is executed through cooperating agents that are automatically initialized at each site that the process executes. Agents handle the activities at their site, provide for coordination with other agents in the system by routing the documents in electronic form according to the process description. The system is capable of activating external applications (which may be inside the company firewall) when necessary, keeping track of process information, and providing for the security and authentication of documents as well as comprehensive monitoring facilities. The architecture is general enough to be applied to any business practice where data flow and invocation of activities among different industries and cooperations follow a pattern that can be described through a process definition, however since the project is on maritime industry, some of the graphical user interfaces are customized accordingly. The system is fully operational for industrial use.</abstract></paper>