<paper id="1502954553"><title>FastFDs: A Heuristic-Driven, Depth-First Algorithm for Mining Functional Dependencies from Relation Instances - Extended Abstract</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="(Indiana University)" id="2140469335">Catharine Wyss</author><author org="(Indiana University)" id="2423939272">Chris Giannella</author><author org="(Indiana University)" id="2151243420">Edward L. Robertson</author></authors><n_citation>115</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1506623181</reference><reference>1553696291</reference><reference>1571341547</reference><reference>1881756506</reference><reference>1972004026</reference><reference>2077053297</reference><reference>2150817871</reference><reference>2166549982</reference></references><venue id="1128002137" type="C">Data Warehousing and Knowledge Discovery</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-44801-2_11</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.43749">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.5204">Heuristic</keyword><keyword weight="0.47351">Relational database</keyword><keyword weight="0.44469">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46729">Hypergraph</keyword><keyword weight="0.49872">Constraint graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.54733">Depth-first search</keyword><keyword weight="0.45535">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.49556">Functional dependency</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Exponential complexity</keyword><keyword weight="0.51595">Search tree</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The problem of discovering functional dependencies (FDs) from an existing relation instance has received considerable attention in the database research community. To date, even the most efficient solutions have exponential complexity in the number of attributes of the instance. We develop an algorithm, FastFDs, for solving this problem based on a depth-first, heuristic-driven (DFHD) search for finding minimal covers of hypergraphs. The technique of reducing the FD discovery problem to the problem of finding minimal covers of hypergraphs was applied previously by Lopes et al. in the algorithm Dep-Miner. Dep-Miner employs a levelwise search for minimal covers, whereas FastFDs uses DFHD search. We report several tests on distinct benchmark relation instances involving Dep-Miner, FastFDs, and TANE. Our experimental results indicate that DFHD search is more efficient than Dep-Mineru0027s levelwise search or TANEu0027s partitioning approach for many of these benchmark instances.</abstract></paper>