<paper id="1534636739"><title>Reducing Disjunctive to Non-Disjunctive Semantics by Shift-Operations</title><year>1996</year><authors><author org="Department of Computer Science, University of Koblenz-Landau, Rheinau 1, 56075 Koblenz, Germany. dix@mailhost.informatik.uni-koblenz.de#TAB#" id="2095738856">Jürgen Dix</author><author org="Institut für Informationssysteme, Technical University of Vienna, Paniglgasse 14, 1040 Wien, Austria. gottlob@vexpert.dbai.tuwien.ac.at#TAB#" id="1873538321">Georg Gottlob</author><author org="Department of Computer Science, University of Kentucky, Lexington, KY 40506, USA. marek@cs.engr.uky.edu#TAB#" id="2305100404">Wiktor Marek</author></authors><n_citation>34</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>100060371</reference><reference>111873265</reference><reference>118616176</reference><reference>203630350</reference><reference>1486205590</reference><reference>1494051470</reference><reference>1505455772</reference><reference>1524811847</reference><reference>1706499668</reference><reference>1766332311</reference><reference>1968513265</reference><reference>1980706206</reference><reference>2000740920</reference><reference>2022740624</reference><reference>2023141722</reference><reference>2061967591</reference><reference>2083568285</reference><reference>2111353076</reference><reference>2146128827</reference><reference>2945259913</reference></references><venue id="39012697" type="J">Fundamenta Informaticae</venue><doi>10.3233/FI-1996-281205</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.50266">Polynomial hierarchy</keyword><keyword weight="0.43821">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.60324">Operational semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.43602">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.46025">Logical consequence</keyword><keyword weight="0.46656">Minimal models</keyword><keyword weight="0.43739">Polynomial</keyword><keyword weight="0.59381">Stable model semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.40978">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.46824">Semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Semantics of logic</keyword></keywords><publisher>IOS Press</publisher><abstract>It is wellknown that Minkeru0027s semantics GCWA for positive disjunctive programs P, i.e. to decide if a literal is true in all minimal models of P is Π P 2-complete. This is in contrast to the same entailment problem for semantics of non-disjunctive programs such as STABLE and SUPPORTED (both are co-NP-complete) as well as M supp P and WFS (that are even polynomial). Recently, the idea of reducing disjunctive to non-disjunctive programs by using so called shift-operations was introduced independently by Bonatti, Dix/Gottlob/Marek, and Schaerf. In fact, Schaerf associated to each semantics SEM for normal programs a corresponding semantics Weak-SEM for disjunctive programs and asked for the properties of these weak semantics, in particular for the complexity of their entailment relations. While Schaerf concentrated on Weak-STABLE and Weak-SUPPORTED, we investigate the weak versions of Apt/Blair/Walkeru0027s stratified semantics M supp P and of Van Gelder/Ross/Schlipfu0027s well-founded semantics WFS. We show that credulous entailment for both semantics is NP-complete (consequently, sceptical entailment is co-NP-complete). Thus, unlike GCWA, the complexity of these semantics belongs to the first level of the polynomial hierarchy. Note that, unlike Weak-WFS, the semantics Weak-M supp P is not always defined: testing consistency of Weak-M supp P is also NP-complete. We also show that Weak-WFS and Weak-M supp P are cumulative and rational and that., in addition, Weak-WFS satisfies some of the well-behaved principles introduced by Dix.</abstract></paper>