<paper id="1954091702"><title>GridStix: supporting flood prediction using embedded hardware and next generation grid middleware</title><year>2006</year><authors><author org="Comput. Dept., Lancaster Univ." id="2190143158">D. Hughes</author><author org="Comput. Dept., Lancaster Univ." id="2110052347">P. Greenwood</author><author org="Comput. Dept., Lancaster Univ." id="1966456890">Coulson G</author><author org="Comput. Dept., Lancaster Univ." id="2131332028">G. Blair</author></authors><n_citation>50</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1885006328</reference><reference>2118428193</reference><reference>2134570896</reference><reference>2147188593</reference><reference>2153576586</reference></references><venue id="1152111034" type="C">World of Wireless, Mobile and Multimedia Networks</venue><doi>10.1109/WOWMOM.2006.49</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.55695">Middleware</keyword><keyword weight="0.51264">Wireless network</keyword><keyword weight="0.61509">Grid computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.45394">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.49184">Intelligent sensor</keyword><keyword weight="0.46887">Computer network</keyword><keyword weight="0.47225">Real-time computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.5216">Heterogeneous network</keyword><keyword weight="0.53891">Grid</keyword><keyword weight="0.49488">Flood myth</keyword><keyword weight="0.51456">Control reconfiguration</keyword><keyword weight="0.47778">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>The cost of damage caused by flooding is directly related to the warning-time given before a flood occurs. Therefore, improving the coverage, accuracy and reliability of flood prediction systems is of great importance. This paper proposes a novel Grid-based approach to supporting flood prediction through the use of embedded sensor nodes equipped with wireless networking technology. These nodes implement a light-weight Grid capable of collecting and transmitting data gathered by flood sensors for off-site analysis. Additionally, the nodes are capable of performing basic on-site analysis that is used to inform system behavior. The proposed system utilizes Lancasteru0027s next-generation component-based Grid middleware platform u0027GridKitu0027, which offers inherent support for reconfiguration, embedded devices and heterogeneous network technologies, making it ideally suited to this application.</abstract></paper>