<paper id="1983818780"><title>A visual calendar for scheduling group meetings</title><year>1990</year><authors><author org="Department of Computer Science, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill NC#TAB#" id="2140629791">David Beard</author><author org="Department of Computer Science, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill NC#TAB#" id="2681043443">Murugappan Palaniappan</author><author org="Department of Computer Science, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill NC#TAB#" id="2722510809">Alan Humm</author><author org="Department of Computer Science, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill NC#TAB#" id="2575097706">David Banks</author><author org="Department of Computer Science, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill NC#TAB#" id="2694742465">Anil Nair</author><author org="Department of Computer Science, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill NC#TAB#" id="2973536803">Yen-Ping Shan</author></authors><n_citation>90</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>117491099</reference><reference>1587166076</reference><reference>1964994389</reference><reference>1972753943</reference><reference>1984543852</reference><reference>2025172185</reference><reference>2041280856</reference><reference>2156492599</reference></references><venue id="1195049314" type="C">Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work</venue><doi>10.1145/99332.99361</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45863">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.60829">Scheduling (computing)</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Scheduling system</keyword><keyword weight="0.46055">Human–computer interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Controlled experiment</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>Scheduling group meetings requires access to participantsu0027 calendars, typically located in scattered pockets or desks. Placing participantsu0027 calendars on-line and using a rule-based scheduler to find a time slot would alleviate the problem to some extent, but it often is difficult to trust the results, because correct scheduling rules are elusive, varying with the participants and the agenda of a particular meeting. Whatu0027s needed is a comprehensive scheduling system that summarizes the available information for quick, flexible, and reliable scheduling. We have developed a prototype of a priority-based, graphical scheduling system called Visual Scheduler (VS). A controlled experiment comparing automatic scheduling with VS to manual scheduling demonstrated the former to be faster and less error prone. A field study conducted over six weeks at the UNC-CH Computer Science Department showed VS to be a generally useful system and provided valuable feedback on ways to enhance the functionality of the system to increase its value as a groupwork tool. In particular, users found priority-based time-slots and access to scheduling decision reasoning advantageous. VS has been in use by more than 75 faculty, staff, and graduate students since Fall 1987.</abstract></paper>