<paper id="1847217253"><title>Easy come — Easy go divisible cash</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="Northeastern, University" id="2159499223">Agnes Hui Chan</author><author org="CertCo" id="2295350866">Yair Frankel</author><author org="GTE Laboratories" id="27022033">Yiannis Tsiounis</author></authors><n_citation>185</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1482004896</reference><reference>1484069097</reference><reference>1493969756</reference><reference>1494232233</reference><reference>1507197912</reference><reference>1511288679</reference><reference>1535861450</reference><reference>1555822216</reference><reference>1555860423</reference><reference>1594128832</reference><reference>1601001795</reference><reference>1610603564</reference><reference>1791720435</reference><reference>2031618446</reference><reference>2052267638</reference><reference>2095708839</reference><reference>2101805403</reference><reference>2114611273</reference><reference>2145376736</reference><reference>2166462813</reference></references><venue id="1140213147" type="C">Theory and Application of Cryptographic Techniques</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0054154</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45801">Byte</keyword><keyword weight="0.45019">Authentication</keyword><keyword weight="0.47917">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.43109">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.49355">Electronic cash</keyword><keyword weight="0.43118">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.49901">Strong RSA assumption</keyword><keyword weight="0.48868">Public-key cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.45438">Payment</keyword><keyword weight="0.47648">Exponentiation</keyword><keyword weight="0.41951">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer Berlin Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Recently, there has been an interest in making electronic cash protocols more practical for electronic commerce by developing e-cash which is divisible (e.g., a coin which can be spent incrementally but total purchases are limited to the monetary value of the coin). In Crypto`95, T. Okamoto presented the first practical divisible, untraceable, off-line e-cash scheme, which requires only O(log N) computations for each of the withdrawal, payment and deposit procedures, where N = (total coin value)/(smallest divisible unit). However, Okamoto`s set-up procedure is quite inefficient (on the order of 4,000 multi-exponentiations and depending on the size of the RSA modulus). The authors formalize the notion of range-bounded commitment, originally used in Okamoto`s account establishment protocol, and present a very efficient instantiation which allows one to construct the first truly efficient divisible e-cash system. The scheme only requires the equivalent of one (1) exponentiation for set-up, less than 2 exponentiations for withdrawal and around 20 for payment, while the size of the coin remains about 300 Bytes. Hence, the withdrawal protocol is 3 orders of magnitude faster than Okamoto`s, while the rest of the system remains equally efficient, allowing for implementation in smart-cards. Similar to Okamoto`s, the scheme is based on proofs whose cryptographic security assumptions are theoretically clarified.</abstract></paper>