<paper id="1553738619"><title>Business value of information technology: a study of electronic data interchange</title><year>1995</year><authors><author org="Carnegie - Mellon University#TAB#" id="2105501499">Tridas Mukhopadhyay</author><author org="Carnegie - Mellon University#TAB#" id="2170553344">Sunder Kekre</author><author org="Carnegie - Mellon University#TAB#" id="2706317545">Suresh Kalathur</author></authors><n_citation>825</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>21609909</reference><reference>1504845112</reference><reference>1583335172</reference><reference>1955623976</reference><reference>1978484347</reference><reference>2010406767</reference><reference>2045449564</reference><reference>2082238712</reference><reference>2104735397</reference><reference>2134830607</reference><reference>2135871035</reference><reference>2160786722</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/249685</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.43799">Corporation</keyword><keyword weight="0.50166">Business value</keyword><keyword weight="0.62207">Electronic data interchange</keyword><keyword weight="0.52428">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.41185">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.4379">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.44141">Operations research</keyword><keyword weight="0.5051">Electronic document</keyword><keyword weight="0.45141">Industrial organization</keyword><keyword weight="0.4563">Liberian dollar</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>A great deal of controversy exists about the impact of information technology on firm performance. While some authors have reported positive impacts, others have found negative or no impacts. This study focuses on Electronic Data Interchange (EDI) technology. Many of the problems in this line of research are over-come in this study by conducting a careful analysis of the performance data of the past decade gathered from the assembly centers of Chrysler Corporation. This study estimates the dollar benefits of improved information exchanges between Chrysler and its suppliers that result from using EDI. After controlling for variations in operational complexity arising from mix, volume, parts complexity, model, and engineering changes, the savings per vehicle that result from improved information exchanges are estimated to be about $60. Including the additional savings from electronic document preparation and transmission, the total benefits of EDI per vehicle amount to over $100. System wide, this translates to annual savings of $220 million for the company.</abstract></paper>