<paper id="1553595359"><title>On Differential and Linear Crytoanalysis of the RC5 Encryption Algorithm</title><year>1995</year><authors><author org="RSA Laboratories" id="2803421804">Burton S. Kaliski</author><author org="RSA Laboratories" id="2098722298">Yiqun Lisa Yin</author></authors><n_citation>56</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1500356409</reference><reference>1537206908</reference><reference>1542500920</reference><reference>1556727271</reference><reference>1964723977</reference><reference>1978695162</reference><reference>1979802565</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-44750-4_14</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.63776">Symmetric-key algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.43111">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.65998">Higher-order differential cryptanalysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.68962">Block cipher</keyword><keyword weight="0.42096">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.43792">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.43215">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.65969">XSL attack</keyword><keyword weight="0.66701">Linear cryptanalysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.66235">Ciphertext-only attack</keyword><keyword weight="0.64147">Plaintext</keyword><keyword weight="0.69382">Differential cryptanalysis</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>This paper analyzes the security of the RC5 encryption algorithm against differential and linear cryptanalysis. RC5 is a new block cipher recently designed by Ron Rivest. It has a variable word size, a variable number of rounds, and a variable-length secret key. In RC5, the secret key is used to fill an expanded key table which is then used in encryption. Both our differential and linear attacks on RC5 recover every bit of the expanded key table without any exhaustive search. However, the plaintext requirement is strongly dependent on the number of rounds. For 64-bit block size, our differential attack on nine-round RC5 uses 245 chosen plaintext pairs (about the same as DES), while 262 pairs are needed for 12-round RC5. Similarly, our linear attack on live-round RC5 uses 247 known plaintexts (about the same as DES), and the plaintext requirement is impractical for more than six rounds. We conjecture that the linear approximations used in our linear cryptanalysis are optimal. Thus, we conclude that Rivestu0027s suggested use of 12 rounds is sufficient to make differential and linear cryptanalysis of RC5 impractical.</abstract></paper>