<paper id="1976815826"><title>Extractors with weak random seeds</title><year>2005</year><authors><author org="Israel Science Foundation (ISF), Weizmann Institute of Science" id="2096418959">Ran Raz</author></authors><n_citation>155</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>202464134</reference><reference>1576688884</reference><reference>1797136128</reference><reference>1999736539</reference><reference>2019807548</reference><reference>2037514418</reference><reference>2060474153</reference><reference>2102906040</reference><reference>2108347494</reference><reference>2110218640</reference><reference>2114137349</reference><reference>2120164218</reference><reference>2130140688</reference><reference>2137178175</reference><reference>2157843680</reference><reference>2163137752</reference></references><venue id="1190910084" type="C">Symposium on the Theory of Computing</venue><doi>10.1145/1060590.1060593</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44184">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.49038">Complete bipartite graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.41701">Monochromatic color</keyword><keyword weight="0.44439">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.49203">Pseudorandomness</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Extractor</keyword><keyword weight="0.47278">Logarithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Probability of error</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Merge (version control)</keyword><keyword weight="0.40403">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.51429">Randomness</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>We show how to extract random bits from two or more independent weak random sources in cases where only one source is of linear min-entropy and all other sources are of logarithmic min-entropy. Our main results are as follows: A long line of research, starting by Nisan and Zuckerman[14], gives explicit constructions of seeded-extractors, that is, extractors that use a short seed of truly random bits to extract randomness from a weak random source. For every such extractor E, with seed of length d, we construct an extractor E′, with seed of length d′=O(d), that achieves the same parameters as E but only requires the seed to be of min-entropy larger than (1⁄2+δ) •d′ (rather than fully random), where δ is an arbitrary small constant. Fundamental results of Chor and Goldreich and Vazirani [6,21] show how to extract Ω(n) random bits from two (independent) sources of length n and min-entropy larger than (1⁄2δ) • n, where δ is an arbitrary small constant. We show how to extract Ω(n) random bits (with optimal probability of error) when only one source is of min-entropy (1⁄2+δ) •n and the other source is of logarithmic min entropy.3 A recent breakthrough of Barak, Impagliazzo and Wigderson[4] shows how to extract Ω(n) random bits from a constant number of (independent) sources of length n and min-entropy larger than δ n, where δ is an arbitrary small constant. We show how to extract Ω (n) random bits (with optimal probability of error) when only one source is of min-entropy δ n and all other (constant number of) sources are of logarithmic min-entropy. A very recent result of Barak, Kindler, Shaltiel, Sudakov and Wigderson[5] shows how to extract a constant number of random bits from three (independent) sources of length n and min-entropy larger than δn, where δ is an arbitrary small constant. We show how to extract Ω(n)/ random bits, with sub-constant probability of error, from one source of min-entropy δ n and two sources of logarithmic min-entropy. In the same paper, Barak, Kindler, Shaltiel, Sudakov and Wigderson[5] give an explicit coloring of the complete bipartite graph of size 2n x 2n with two colors, such that there is no monochromatic subgraph of size larger than 2δn x 2 2δn, where δ is an arbitrary small constant. We give an explicit coloring of the complete bipartite graph of size 2n x 2n with a constant number of colors, such that there is no monochromatic subgraph of size larger than 2δn x n5. We also give improved constructions of mergers and condensers. In particular, We show that using a constant number of truly random bits, one can condense a source of length n and min-entropy rate δ into a source of length Ω (n) and min-entropy rate 1-δ, where δ is an arbitrary small constant. We show that using a constant number of truly random bits, one can merge a constant number of sources of length n, such that at least one of them is of min-entropy rate 1-δ, into one source of length Ω(n) and min-entropy rate slightly less than 1-δ, where δ is any small constant.</abstract></paper>