<paper id="1592800357"><title>Emotional intelligence: constructing user stereotypes for affective bi-modal interaction</title><year>2006</year><authors><author org="Department of Informatics; University of Piraeus; Piraeus Greece" id="218416969">Efthymios Alepis</author><author org="Department of Informatics; University of Piraeus; Piraeus Greece" id="81737176">Maria Virvou</author></authors><n_citation>17</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2006590470</reference><reference>2018543616</reference><reference>2070648328</reference><reference>2077898435</reference><reference>2117688236</reference></references><venue id="2754242139" type="C">International Conference on Knowledge-Based and Intelligent Information and Engineering Systems</venue><doi>10.1007/11892960_53</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.42352">Expressed emotion</keyword><keyword weight="0.41758">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45691">Human–computer interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.44055">Stereotype</keyword><keyword weight="0.43521">Knowledge engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.58482">User modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.41537">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.49642">Emotional intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.42583">Affect (psychology)</keyword><keyword weight="0.56321">User interface</keyword><keyword weight="0.4574">Empirical research</keyword><keyword weight="0.39315">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The need of incorporating stereotypes concerning usersu0027 emotional characteristics in affective multi-modal user interfaces is important. To this end we present user stereotypes that we have constructed concerning the emotional behavior of users while they interact with computers. The construction of these user stereotypes have been based on an empirical study. The empirical study has been conducted among different kinds of computer users in terms of how they express emotions while they interact with a through a keyboard and a microphone in a bi-modal kind of interaction. The stereotypes have been incorporated in a user modeling component underlying an affective bi-modal user interface that uses a microphone and a keyboard. Actions of the users in terms of what they said and/or what they typed computer in the context of typical interaction situations are interpreted in terms of their feelings so that appropriate affective messages may be generated.</abstract></paper>