<paper id="1976183756"><title>Dense Subsets of Pseudorandom Sets</title><year>2008</year><authors><author org="Weizmann institute of Science" id="109346679">O. Reingold</author><author org="&quot;University of California, Berkeley&quot;" id="2115996045">L. Trevisan</author><author org="&quot;University of California, Berkeley&quot;" id="205901955">M. Tulsiani</author><author org="Harvard University" id="173843361">S. Vadhan</author></authors><n_citation>93</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1496806208</reference><reference>1558669467</reference><reference>2015880590</reference><reference>2016201895</reference><reference>2160403361</reference></references><venue id="1150208541" type="C">Foundations of Computer Science</venue><doi>10.1109/FOCS.2008.38</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.67219">Analytic proof</keyword><keyword weight="0.4718">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.4709">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.61461">Proof by contradiction</keyword><keyword weight="0.60971">Furstenberg's proof of the infinitude of primes</keyword><keyword weight="0.53453">Pseudorandomness</keyword><keyword weight="0.61215">Mathematical proof</keyword><keyword weight="0.63558">Combinatorial proof</keyword><keyword weight="0.66042">Proof complexity</keyword><keyword weight="0.42074">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.6401">Direct proof</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>A theorem of Green, Tao, and Ziegler can be stated (roughly) as follows: ifR is a pseudorandom set, and D is a dense subset of R, then D may be modeled by a set M that is dense in the entire domain such that D and M are indistinguishable. (The precise statement refers to"measures" or distributions rather than sets.) The proof of this theorem is very general, and it applies to notions of pseudo-randomness and indistinguishability defined in terms of any family of distinguishers with some mild closure properties. The proof proceeds via iterative partitioning and an energy increment argument, in the spirit of the proof of the weak Szemeredi regularity lemma. The "reduction" involved in the proof has exponential complexity in the distinguishing probability. We present a new proof inspired by Nisanu0027s proof of Impagliazzou0027s hardcore set theorem. The reduction in our proof has polynomial complexity in the distinguishing probability and provides a new characterization of the notion of "pseudoentropy" of a distribution. A proof similar to ours has also been independently discovered by Gowers [2]. We also follow the connection between the two theorems and obtain a new proof of Impagliazzou0027s hardcore set theorem via iterative partitioning and energy increment. While our reduction has exponential complexity in some parameters, it has the advantage that the hardcore set is efficiently recognizable.</abstract></paper>