<paper id="1593374757"><title>Speech Output for Older Visually Impaired Adults</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="*Oxford Brookes University." id="670832443">Mary Zajicek</author><author org="*Oxford Brookes University." id="2161949549">Wesley Morrissey</author></authors><n_citation>28</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>327450034</reference><reference>2108048984</reference></references><venue id="" type="">BCS HCI/IHM</venue><doi>10.1007/978-1-4471-0353-0_31</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45652">Visual impairment</keyword><keyword weight="0.44612">Conceptual model</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Speech output</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Web browser</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Web access</keyword><keyword weight="0.42258">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.52265">Graphical user interface</keyword><keyword weight="0.45773">Human–computer interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Interface design</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, London</publisher><abstract>The ageing process affects an individual’s ability to use the standard Graphical User Interface (GUI). In fact the facilities, which are required for successful use of a GUI, are the very ones that deteriorate most markedly with age. Visual impairment, together with memory loss in particular, reduce the user’s ability to build conceptual models of the working of the interface. The ability to navigate successfully and build strategies also deteriorates with age, an aspect which is especially important when moving from page to page on the World Wide Web. Interface design for older adults should acknowledge these factors. This paper reports the results of experiments, which show that there is a significant difference in spoken information retention between older and younger adults and that older visually impaired users retain more information from shorter messages in a speech output Web browser with voice help. The paper also discusses optimum levels of functionality for older adults, an important consideration when designing interfaces for Web access for this user group.</abstract></paper>