<paper id="1535992660"><title>Querying Semi-Structured Data</title><year>1997</year><authors><author org="INRIA Rocquencourt#TAB#" id="172400696">Serge Abiteboul</author></authors><n_citation>682</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>21010746</reference><reference>1528249715</reference><reference>1529427704</reference><reference>1529524927</reference><reference>1534002024</reference><reference>1549804464</reference><reference>1558832481</reference><reference>1565065452</reference><reference>1590548044</reference><reference>1603435928</reference><reference>1605802622</reference><reference>1705152440</reference><reference>1879587332</reference><reference>1908950999</reference><reference>1968945891</reference><reference>1971708293</reference><reference>1971845537</reference><reference>1973415432</reference><reference>1977583107</reference><reference>1996126974</reference><reference>2014257213</reference><reference>2021253160</reference><reference>2027750453</reference><reference>2029326070</reference><reference>2031703228</reference><reference>2042317756</reference><reference>2087060113</reference><reference>2094677764</reference><reference>2103219113</reference><reference>2109660182</reference><reference>2113397233</reference><reference>2117849706</reference><reference>2124812961</reference><reference>2135282325</reference><reference>2149532506</reference><reference>2154294048</reference><reference>2168605051</reference><reference>2336159763</reference><reference>2492106958</reference></references><venue id="1165285842" type="C">International Conference on Database Theory</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-62222-5_33</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.65941">Semi-structured data</keyword><keyword weight="0.65366">Data warehouse</keyword><keyword weight="0.65456">Data transformation</keyword><keyword weight="0.64647">Data modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.46188">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.45489">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.64939">Data element</keyword><keyword weight="0.64658">Data mapping</keyword><keyword weight="0.64467">Database design</keyword><keyword weight="0.64174">Data virtualization</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer Berlin Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Querying Semi-Structured Data Serge Abiteboul ? INRIA-Rocquencourt Serge.Abiteboul@inria.fr 1 Introduction The amount of data of all kinds available electronically has increased dramatically in recent years. The data resides in different forms, ranging from unstructured data in file systems to highly structured in relational database systems. Data is accessible through a variety of interfaces including Web browsers, database query languages, application-specific interfaces, or data exchange formats. Some of this data is raw data, e.g., images or sound. Some of it has structure even if the structure is often implicit, and not as rigid or regular as that found in standard database systems. Sometimes the structure exists but has to be extracted from the data. Sometimes also it exists but we prefer to ignore it for certain purposes such as browsing. We call here semi-structured data this data that is (from a particular viewpoint) neither raw data nor strictly typed, i.e., not table-oriented as in a relational model or sorted-graph as in object databases. As will seen later when the notion of semi-structured data is more precisely defined, the need for semi-structured data arises naturally in the context of data integration, even when the data sources are themselves well-structured. Although data integration is an old topic, the need to integrate a wider variety of dataformats (e.g., SGML or ASN.1 data) and data found on the Web has brought the topic of semi-structured data to the forefront of research. The main purpose of the paper is to isolate the essential aspects of semistructured data. We also survey some proposals of models and query languages for semi-structured data. In particular, we consider recent works at Stanford U. and U. Penn on semi-structured data. In both cases, the motivation is found in the integration of heterogeneous data. The "lightweight" data models they use (based on labelled graphs) are very similar. As we shall see, the topic of semi-structur</abstract></paper>