<paper id="100321389"><title>Mapping chargeback systems to organizational environments</title><year>1987</year><authors><author org="Administration &amp; Planning, I.S.S., Public Service of New Hampshire, Manchester, New Hampshire#TAB#" id="2438671028">William P. McKinnon</author><author org="Bentley College Waltham Massachusetts" id="890238499">Ernest A. Kallman</author></authors><n_citation>20</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>2041781852</reference><reference>2137515990</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/248820</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.62304">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.60074">Management information systems</keyword><keyword weight="0.53711">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.43902">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47906">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.46602">Accountability</keyword><keyword weight="0.63712">Chargeback</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>A critical problem facing information systems management is what kind of chargeback system to install and will it be appropriate in the future? The solution is to map the chargeback system to the organizational environment. This organizational environment can be described by: 1) the use to which the information technology is put, 2) the maturity of the information systems function, and 3) the level of development of the information systems managerial function. The authors have developed a model that defines the organizational environments according to these three dimensions, giving management an organizational definition by which to choose the chargeback system that best accommodates the organizationu0027s accountability needs. This paper describes characteristics of chargeback systems, major chargeback methods and the authorsu0027 model. Then the impact of the model and the extent of its implementation are displayed through two case analyses.</abstract></paper>