<paper id="1954882695"><title>Randomizing polynomials: A new representation with applications to round-efficient secure computation</title><year>2000</year><authors><author org="" id="114908009">Y. Ishai</author><author org="" id="307687659">E. Kushilevitz</author></authors><n_citation>170</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>59079490</reference><reference>98016092</reference><reference>137928579</reference><reference>1494759436</reference><reference>1510713793</reference><reference>1528330226</reference><reference>1541083511</reference><reference>1556155774</reference><reference>1570143742</reference><reference>1596412683</reference><reference>1607280525</reference><reference>1969865855</reference><reference>1983236952</reference><reference>1997859100</reference><reference>2016443801</reference><reference>2021276494</reference><reference>2041261351</reference><reference>2054996571</reference><reference>2070678975</reference><reference>2077315235</reference><reference>2106476824</reference><reference>2121423622</reference><reference>2147154704</reference><reference>2160473547</reference><reference>2171197316</reference></references><venue id="1150208541" type="C">Foundations of Computer Science</venue><doi>10.1109/SFCS.2000.892118</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.57405">Boolean function</keyword><keyword weight="0.47197">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.46529">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.53768">Secure multi-party computation</keyword><keyword weight="0.51387">Finite field</keyword><keyword weight="0.53067">Polynomial</keyword><keyword weight="0.43089">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48136">Quadratic equation</keyword><keyword weight="0.52574">Binary decision diagram</keyword><keyword weight="0.52388">Communication complexity</keyword><keyword weight="0.6367">Difference polynomials</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><abstract>Motivated by questions about secure multi-party computation, we introduce and study a new natural representation of functions by polynomials, which we term randomizing polynomials. "Standard" low-degree polynomials over a finite field are easy to compute with a small number of communication rounds in virtually any setting for secure computation. However, most Boolean functions cannot be evaluated by a polynomial whose degree is smaller than their input size. We get around this barrier by relaxing the requirement of evaluating f into a weaker requirement of randomizing f: mapping the inputs of f along with independent random inputs into a vector of outputs, whose distribution depends only on the value of f. We show that degree-3 polynomials are sufficient to randomize any function f, relating the efficiency of such a randomization to the branching program size of f. On the other hand, by characterizing the exact class of Boolean functions which can be randomized by degree-2 polynomials, we show that 3 is the minimal randomization degree of most functions. As an application, randomizing polynomials provide a powerful, general, and conceptually simple tool for the design of round-efficient secure protocols. Specifically, the secure evaluation of any function can be reduced to a secure evaluation of degree-3 polynomials. One corollary of this reduction is that two (respectively, three) communication rounds are sufficient for k parties to compute any Boolean function f of their inputs, with perfect information-theoretic [k-1/3]-privacy (resp., [k-1/2]-privacy), and communication complexity which is at most quadratic in the branching program size of f (with a small probability of one-sided error).</abstract></paper>