<paper id="1979416796"><title>Blogging by the rest of us</title><year>2004</year><authors><author org="Stanford Univ., Stanford, CA" id="2989327156">Diane J. Schiano</author><author org="University of California at Irvine, Irvine, CA." id="2015738512">Bonnie A. Nardi</author><author org="Stanford Univ., Stanford, CA" id="255929025">Michelle Gumbrecht</author><author org="Stanford Univ., Stanford, CA" id="2136585103">Luke Swartz</author></authors><n_citation>93</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2156589869</reference></references><venue id="1163450153" type="C">Human Factors in Computing Systems</venue><doi>10.1145/985921.986009</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45251">Internet privacy</keyword><keyword weight="0.44286">Web page</keyword><keyword weight="0.38621">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47817">Popularity</keyword><keyword weight="0.49385">Journaling file system</keyword><keyword weight="0.41449">Ethnography</keyword><keyword weight="0.41842">Politics</keyword><keyword weight="0.43006">Multimedia</keyword><keyword weight="0.47156">Mainstream</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>Weblogs (or blogs) are frequently updated webpages with posts typically in reverse-chronological order. Blogging is the latest form of online communication to gain widespread popularity and it is rapidly becoming mainstream. Media attention tends to focus on "heavy-hitting" blogs devoted to politics, punditry and technology, but it has recently become apparent that vast majority of blogs are written by ordinary people for much smaller audiences, and on largely personal themes. Surprisingly little is known about this "blogging by the rest of us", especially from the bloggeru0027s point of view. This paper presents the preliminary results of an ethnographic study of blogging as a form of personal expression and communication. We characterize a number of blogging practices, and then consider blogging as personal journaling. We find blogging to be a surprisingly versatile medium, with uses similar to an online diary, personal chronicle or newsletter, and much more. The next few years should provide a fascinating opportunity for research and design as blogging tools improve and blog usage evolves and flourishes.</abstract></paper>