<paper id="1974984365"><title>A descriptive model of success for computer-based information systems</title><year>1984</year><authors><author org="Department of Computer Science and Post Graduate Management School, Potchefstroom University for CHE, Potchefstroom 2520, South Africa" id="2495011482">P.J.S. Bruwer</author></authors><n_citation>43</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>2138672502</reference></references><venue id="38883057" type="J">Information &amp; Management</venue><doi>10.1016/0378-7206(84)90010-7</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.6539">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.64822">Management information systems</keyword><keyword weight="0.50079">Structured systems analysis and design method</keyword><keyword weight="0.4443">Warrant</keyword><keyword weight="0.47972">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Computerized system</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Management support</keyword><keyword weight="0.40254">Engineering</keyword></keywords><publisher>North-Holland</publisher><abstract>Abstract This article presents a model of the success of computer-based information systems. We hypothesize that the following variables influence the success of the system: involvement of managers in computerization projects: higher-level managerial support; the technical quality of the system; personal factors; the attitude of managers towards EDP personnel and the attitude of managers towards the computerized system. The research finds that the manageru0027s attitudes to computerization are related to all but the last two. Certain classes of variables are difficult to relate to the success of the system (for example, personal factors). If the evidence for the model is considered strong enough to warrant action, the organization should concentrate on several key variables: high quality of the system; good management support, and good training and management involvement. The results of our research should provide better understanding of the variables associated with the success of a computer-based system.</abstract></paper>