<paper id="1552210990"><title>The importance of learning style in end-user training</title><year>1990</year><authors><author org="" id="2302943154">Robert P. Bostrom</author><author org="" id="356142320">Lorne Olfman</author><author org="" id="2281147955">Maung K. Sein</author></authors><n_citation>386</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1791587663</reference><reference>1979064760</reference><reference>2014295780</reference><reference>2016900109</reference><reference>2023495440</reference><reference>2038564082</reference><reference>2049276535</reference><reference>2049650335</reference><reference>2052654950</reference><reference>2058580210</reference><reference>2059311901</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/249313</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.52465">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.51313">End user</keyword><keyword weight="0.46791">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.43892">Psychology</keyword><keyword weight="0.42734">Software</keyword><keyword weight="0.57089">Educational psychology</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>The importance of effective training in ensuring the success of end-user computing (EUC) has been emphasized by several researchers in information systems. A vast amount of evidence from research in related areas such as educational psychology suggests that individual differences, such as learning style, may affect users learning about a new EUC software package. This article reports the findings of a series of studies that examine the influence of a noviceu0027s learning style in learning typical EUC tools such as spreadsheets and electronic mail. A consistent pattern of findings emerges that indicates that learning modes is an important predictor of learning performance, both by itself and in interaction with training methods. The findings suggest that in the design of training, it is essential to match training methods to individual difference variables. Based on these findings, guidelines are recommended for IS professionals involved in EUC training and further research directions are discussed.</abstract></paper>