<paper id="1494811192"><title>An Object-oriented Rule-based Approach to the Dynamic Modelling of Information Systems</title><year>1990</year><authors><author org="National and Kapodistrian University of Athens" id="2193845714">Aphrodite Tsalgatidou</author><author org="MSM Decision Sciences" id="2973323668">Pericles Loucopoulos</author></authors><n_citation>17</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>19453802</reference><reference>285770658</reference><reference>1493596129</reference><reference>1530174170</reference><reference>1970658603</reference><reference>1982571652</reference><reference>1994227812</reference><reference>1997089705</reference><reference>2060431549</reference><reference>2060872161</reference><reference>2076722567</reference><reference>2096875993</reference><reference>2097680763</reference><reference>2133534940</reference></references><venue id="" type="">International Conference on Dynamic Modelling of Information Systems;Noordwijkerhout, The Netherlands.1990.</venue><doi>10.1016/B978-0-444-88923-2.50009-4</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.57518">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.61272">Object-oriented design</keyword><keyword weight="0.49126">Notation</keyword><keyword weight="0.55626">Rule-based system</keyword><keyword weight="0.55529">Object-oriented programming</keyword><keyword weight="0.46903">Software engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.47565">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.5077">Source code</keyword><keyword weight="0.48461">Software</keyword><keyword weight="0.46185">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.47012">Factoring</keyword></keywords><publisher>North-Holland</publisher><abstract>Abstract The problems inherent in the task of developing and maintaining large scale information systems have received wide coverage. The essential problem with these systems is their inflexibility to change, compounded by the fact that most contemporary software processes fail to adequately address the specific problem of system evolution. This paper argues that the development of information systems requires the adoption of a new paradigm which recognises the explicit separation of organisational policy from programming code. To this end the paper discusses a rule-based model which is used for the specification of all control aspects of an information system. The definition of this model is achieved within a framework which is based on an object-oriented approach. This framework requires the definition of objects on the basis of a binary relationship model and the identification of operations on these objects. The invocation of these operations is handled by the rule-model. Rules pertaining to the behaviour aspects of an object class may be viewed in terms of a network graphical notation. Such a network can be used for the dual purpose of factoring a rule-base as well as animating the behaviour of each object class.</abstract></paper>