<paper id="1589135661"><title>Scheduling for Parallel Supercomputing: A Historical Perspective of Achievable Utilization</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="NASA/Ames Research Center#TAB#" id="2106728085">James Patton Jones</author><author org="NASA/Ames Research Center#TAB#" id="2310488852">Bill Nitzberg</author></authors><n_citation>88</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1487076132</reference><reference>1589576271</reference><reference>1605746882</reference><reference>2160982301</reference></references><venue id="1122827389" type="C">Job Scheduling Strategies for Parallel Processing</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-47954-6_1</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45358">IBM</keyword><keyword weight="0.48936">Scheduling (computing)</keyword><keyword weight="0.42408">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.42696">Real-time computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.42638">Software</keyword><keyword weight="0.43873">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.58036">Intel Paragon</keyword><keyword weight="0.53074">Supercomputer</keyword><keyword weight="0.45112">Workload</keyword><keyword weight="0.43982">Parallel computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.47041">Resource allocation</keyword><keyword weight="0.4398">Operating system</keyword><keyword weight="0.56084">Intel iPSC</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The NAS facility has operated parallel supercomputers for the past 11 years, including the Intel iPSC/860, Intel Paragon, Thinking Machines CM-5, IBM SP-2, and Cray Origin 2000. Across this wide variety of machine architectures, across a span of 10 years, across a large number of different users, and through thousands of minor configuration and policy changes, the utilization of these machines shows three general trends: (1) scheduling using a naive FCFS first-fit policy results in 40-60% utilization, (2) switching to the more sophisticated dynamic backfilling scheduling algorithm improves utilization by about 15 percentage points (yielding about 70% utilization), and (3) reducing the maximum allowable job size further increases utilization. Most surprising is the consistency of these trends. Over the lifetime of the NAS parallel systems, we made hundreds, perhaps thousands, of small changes to hardware, software, and policy, yet utilization was affected little. In particular, these results show that the goal of achieving near 100% utilization while supporting a real parallel supercomputing workload is unrealistic.</abstract></paper>