<paper id="1971377258"><title>Electronic transformation of government in the U.K.: a research agenda</title><year>2007</year><authors><author org="Brunel Business School, Brunel University West London U.K." id="1987606741">Zahir Irani</author><author org="School of Information Systems and Computing, Brunel University, West London, U.K." id="2245522007">Tony Elliman</author><author org="CIPFA Performance Improvement Network (PIN), Chartered Institute of Public Finance and Accountancy, U.K." id="2161019430">Paul Jackson</author></authors><n_citation>173</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1966340945</reference></references><venue id="116712389" type="J">European Journal of Information Systems</venue><doi>10.1057/palgrave.ejis.3000698</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.50502">Brainstorming</keyword><keyword weight="0.47437">Information management</keyword><keyword weight="0.52409">Soft systems methodology</keyword><keyword weight="0.38982">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47331">Public relations</keyword><keyword weight="0.53754">Transformational Government</keyword><keyword weight="0.49093">Road map</keyword><keyword weight="0.46194">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.53975">Exploratory research</keyword><keyword weight="0.47505">Strategic information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.4501">Management science</keyword><keyword weight="0.51712">Government</keyword></keywords><publisher>Palgrave Macmillan UK</publisher><abstract>This paper presents the findings of an exploratory research project into future e-Government (electronic Government) initiatives. The Virtual Institute for Electronic Government Research (VIEGO) project aimed at identifying and further developing the research agenda of e-Government based on a solid practical ground. As such, the paper offers a novel methodology in identifying the road map for future e-Government initiatives based on a series of workshops organised around the U.K. hosting a mixture of stakeholders involving both academics and practitioners. The analysis of the VIEGO workshops depicted that an e-Government research agenda involves a combination of social, technological and organisational issues at both governmental and individual citizen level, ultimately driven by empirical case-based experience and active participation in e-Government processes. Unlike other propositions for the future of e-Government offered in the e-Government literature, it raised research questions not only originated from an analysis of e-Government literature but also on the outcome of brainstorming, reflections and contemplations throughout the duration of the project.</abstract></paper>