<paper id="1966568196"><title>Simplified Voronoi diagrams</title><year>1987</year><authors><author org="Artificial Intelligence Laboratory, Massachusetts Institute of Technology#TAB#" id="2101610026">J. Canny</author><author org="Artificial Intelligence Laboratory, Massachusetts Institute of Technology#TAB#" id="2183038711">B. Donald</author></authors><n_citation>73</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1965440866</reference><reference>2015751084</reference><reference>2065283065</reference><reference>2147159598</reference><reference>2150500908</reference><reference>2163178194</reference></references><venue id="1143959562" type="C">Symposium on Computational Geometry</venue><doi>10.1145/41958.41974</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45611">Topology</keyword><keyword weight="0.73062">Power diagram</keyword><keyword weight="0.4581">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.45474">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.63129">Centroidal Voronoi tessellation</keyword><keyword weight="0.60443">Mathematical diagram</keyword><keyword weight="0.54404">Diagram</keyword><keyword weight="0.73041">Weighted Voronoi diagram</keyword><keyword weight="0.73204">Voronoi diagram</keyword><keyword weight="0.59244">Elementary diagram</keyword><keyword weight="0.40761">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.54573">Configuration space</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>We are interested in Voronoi diagrams as a tool in robot path planning, where the search for a path in an τ dimensional space may be simplified to a search on an τ - 1 dimensional Voronoi diagram. We define a Voronoi diagram V based on a measure of distance which is not a true metric. This formulation has lower algebraic complexity than the usual definition, which is a considerable advantage in motion planning problems with many degrees of freedom. In its simplest form, the measure of distance between a point and a polytope is the maximum of the distances of the point from the half-spaces which pass through faces of the polytope. More generally, the measure is defined in configuration spaces which represent rotation. The Voronoi diagram defined using this distance measure is no longer a strong deformation retract of free space, but it has the following useful property: any path through free space which starts and ends on the diagram can be continuously deformed so that it lies entirely on the diagram. Thus it is still complete for motion planning, but it has lower algebraic complexity than a diagram based on the Euclidean metric.</abstract></paper>