<paper id="1965416263"><title>Mining from open answers in questionnaire data</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="NEC Corporation, 4-1-1 Miyazaki, Miyamae-ku, Kawasaki, Kanagawa, Japan" id="2128739099">Hang Li</author><author org="NEC Corporation, 4-1-1 Miyazaki, Miyamae-ku, Kawasaki, Kanagawa, Japan" id="1444602532">Kenji Yamanishi</author></authors><n_citation>38</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1969530623</reference><reference>1975685775</reference><reference>2004180556</reference><reference>2044854172</reference><reference>2056957301</reference><reference>2067981498</reference><reference>2068782468</reference><reference>2081908866</reference><reference>2105154442</reference><reference>2112378479</reference><reference>2121940249</reference><reference>2144212226</reference></references><venue id="1130985203" type="C">Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</venue><doi>10.1145/502512.502579</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.4666">Data science</keyword><keyword weight="0.51666">Customer relationship management</keyword><keyword weight="0.44103">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.50937">Survey data collection</keyword><keyword weight="0.48425">Text mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Questionnaire data</keyword><keyword weight="0.46674">Information retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.44212">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.53495">Association rule learning</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Statistical learning</keyword><keyword weight="0.47728">Correspondence analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.49529">Desk</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>Surveys are an important part of marketing and customer relationship management, and open answers (i.e., answers to open questions) in particular may contain valuable information and provide an important basis for making business decisions. We have developed a text mining system that provides a new way for analyzing open answers in questionnaire data. The product is able to perform the following two functions: (A) accurate extraction of characteristics for individual analysis targets, (B) accurate extraction of the relationships among characteristics of analysis targets. In this paper, we describe the working of our text mining system. It employs two statistical learning techniques: rule analysis and Correspondence Analysis for performing the two functions. Our text mining system has already been put into use by a number of large corporations in Japan in the performance of text mining on various types of survey data, including open answers about brand images, open answers about company images, complaints about products, comments written on home pages, business reports, and help desk records. In this it has been found to be useful in forming a basis for effective business decisions.</abstract></paper>