<paper id="1512068198"><title>Feasible Direction Decomposition Algorithms for Training Support Vector Machines</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="Department of Computer and Information Sciences, 102 Smith Hall, University of Delaware, Newark, DE 19718, USA. laskov@cis.udel.edu#TAB#" id="2209303800">Pavel Laskov</author></authors><n_citation>45</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>854322902</reference><reference>1543810117</reference><reference>1964357740</reference><reference>2100038678</reference><reference>2110899801</reference><reference>2151040995</reference><reference>2156909104</reference><reference>2167280730</reference></references><venue id="62148650" type="J">Machine Learning</venue><doi>10.1023/A:1012479116909</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.51135">Kernel (linear algebra)</keyword><keyword weight="0.43233">Information processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.45286">Pattern recognition</keyword><keyword weight="0.42184">Regression</keyword><keyword weight="0.43108">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.56429">Support vector machine</keyword><keyword weight="0.46224">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.45351">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.4779">Rate of convergence</keyword><keyword weight="0.57377">Kernel method</keyword><keyword weight="0.45063">Machine learning</keyword></keywords><publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher><abstract>The article presents a general view of a class of decomposition algorithms for training Support Vector Machines (SVM) which are motivated by the method of feasible directions. The first such algorithm for the pattern recognition SVM has been proposed in Joachims, T. (1999, Scholkopf et al. (Eds.) Advances in kernel methods-Support vector learning (pp. 185–208). MIT Press). Its extension to the regression SVM—the maximal inconsistency algorithm—has been recently presented by the author (Laskov, 2000, Solla, Leen, u0026 Muller (Eds.) Advances in neural information processing systems 12 (pp. 484–490). MIT Press). A detailed account of both algorithms is carried out, complemented by theoretical investigation of the relationship between the two algorithms. It is proved that the two algorithms are equivalent for the pattern recognition SVM, and the feasible direction interpretation of the maximal inconsistency algorithm is given for the regression SVM. The experimental results demonstrate an order of magnitude decrease of training time in comparison with training without decomposition, and, most importantly, provide experimental evidence of the linear convergence rate of the feasible direction decomposition algorithms.</abstract></paper>