<paper id="1501342036"><title>More About Control Conditions for Transformation Units</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="Universitat Bremen." id="304074003">Sabine Kuske</author></authors><n_citation>22</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>8360613</reference><reference>127565347</reference><reference>129545406</reference><reference>1482012210</reference><reference>1512007370</reference><reference>1522538549</reference><reference>1523742478</reference><reference>1525397299</reference><reference>1603358947</reference><reference>1665726835</reference><reference>1740797132</reference><reference>1983037164</reference><reference>2044439000</reference><reference>2082530393</reference><reference>2087327214</reference></references><venue id="" type="">TAGT'98 Selected papers from the 6th International Workshop on Theory and Application of Graph Transformations</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-46464-8_23</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46123">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.48865">Regular expression</keyword><keyword weight="0.47057">Algebra</keyword><keyword weight="0.54555">Binary relation</keyword><keyword weight="0.57634">Graph rewriting</keyword><keyword weight="0.5003">Formalism (philosophy)</keyword><keyword weight="0.45378">Structuring</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Expressive power</keyword><keyword weight="0.42445">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.46983">Semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.44665">restrict</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer Berlin Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>A transformation unit is a structuring principle for composing graph transformation systems from small units. One of the basic components of a transformation unit is its control condition which allows to restrict the non-determinism of graph transformation. The concept of transformation units is generic in the sense that each formalism which specifies a binary relation on graphs can be used as a control condition. This paper discusses a selection of concrete classes of control conditions which seem to provide reasonable expressive power for specifying and programming with transformation units. These include regular expressions, once, as-long-as-possible, priorities, and conditionals; some of them were already used in an ad hoc manner in earlier papers. It is shown which classes of control conditions can be replaced by others without changing the semantics of the corresponding transformation unit. Moreover, three properties of control conditions are studied: minimality, invertibility and continuity.</abstract></paper>