<paper id="1694796700"><title>Evaluating the progress of e-government development: A critical analysis</title><year>2004</year><authors><author org="(Corresponding author) University of Ljubljana, Faculty of Administration, Gosarjeva 5, 1000 Ljubljana, Slovenia. Tel.: +386 1 5805 554; Fax: +386 1 5805 541, E-mail: mateja.kunstelj@fu.uni-lj.si#TAB#" id="1279246518">Mateja Kunstelj</author><author org="University of Ljubljana, Faculty of Administration, Gosarjeva 5, 1000 Ljubljana, Slovenia. Tel.: +386 1 5805 554; Fax: +386 1 5805 541, E-mail: mateja.kunstelj@fu.uni-lj.si#TAB#" id="1994841207">Mirko Vintar</author></authors><n_citation>149</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1489027171</reference><reference>1526552016</reference><reference>1526626758</reference><reference>1562605467</reference><reference>1799731611</reference><reference>1831845202</reference><reference>1975385385</reference><reference>1976431997</reference><reference>1979929841</reference><reference>2000151453</reference><reference>2021423964</reference><reference>2037779348</reference><reference>2132742686</reference><reference>2160196038</reference></references><venue id="2764630084" type="J">Information Polity archive</venue><doi>10.3233/ip-2004-0055</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">E-Government</keyword><keyword weight="0.47187">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.51469">Integrated services</keyword><keyword weight="0.4309">Developed country</keyword><keyword weight="0.54876">Business process reengineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.55355">Benchmarking</keyword><keyword weight="0.53424">Government</keyword><keyword weight="0.45043">Business</keyword><keyword weight="0.49698">The Internet</keyword></keywords><publisher>IOS Press</publisher><abstract>The development of e-government in most countries is still primarily aimed at developing electronic services that customers can access via the internet. This has been matched by the methods for monitoring e-government development, which fall far short of providing a true overall assessment. Such a narrow focus on e-government has led to a significant slowdown of development in most countries. Countries have used "quick fix, quick win" solutions, while continued development require above all the development of an integrated government portal and reengineering of back-office processes. The more developed countries are therefore increasingly tailoring their e-government strategies in the direction of customer-orientation and instead of persisting with rigid organisational structures are working on integrating services and processes across individual administrative bodies and institutions and even include private businesses. The development of e-government therefore demands a holistic strategic approach that encompasses the entire public administration and is not limited to individual bodies and institutions, or individual sectors and levels of administration. The methods of monitoring, evaluating and benchmarking e-government development will have to follow the same principles. Based on critical analyses of existing approaches, this paper attempts to define the areas and aspects that must be included within the integrated approach in order to facilitate the progress of e-government towards its strategic objectives, that is the development of services based on useru0027s needs and problems, i.e. integrated services or life-events.</abstract></paper>