<paper id="1738398458"><title>Hypothesis-Driven Constructive Induction in AQ17-HCI: A Method and Experiments</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="Center for Artificial Intelligence, George Mason University, Fairfax, VA 22030. WNEK@AIC.GMU.EDU#TAB#" id="1992635785">Janusz Wnek</author><author org="Center for Artificial Intelligence, George Mason University, Fairfax, VA 22030. MICHALSKI@AIC.GMU.EDU#TAB#" id="2617907882">Ryszard S. Michalski</author></authors><n_citation>175</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>6996585</reference><reference>41262972</reference><reference>129125113</reference><reference>177590838</reference><reference>184117529</reference><reference>206415041</reference><reference>1485130760</reference><reference>1489112261</reference><reference>1521724262</reference><reference>1526261699</reference><reference>1527189973</reference><reference>1562138751</reference><reference>1570286060</reference><reference>1592888257</reference><reference>1988757393</reference><reference>2018642704</reference><reference>2044998449</reference><reference>2053937765</reference><reference>2089967664</reference><reference>2110473729</reference><reference>2136000097</reference><reference>2149706766</reference><reference>2165347852</reference><reference>2402405544</reference><reference>2484153108</reference><reference>2914032229</reference><reference>2974365732</reference></references><venue id="62148650" type="J">Machine Learning</venue><doi>10.1023/A:1022622132310</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.51278">Decision rule</keyword><keyword weight="0.49737">Decision tree</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Constructive induction</keyword><keyword weight="0.63855">Multi-task learning</keyword><keyword weight="0.51188">Iterative and incremental development</keyword><keyword weight="0.4631">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.54018">Concept learning</keyword><keyword weight="0.51417">Decision list</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Discrete functions</keyword><keyword weight="0.47521">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.46987">Machine learning</keyword></keywords><publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher><abstract>The proposed method for constructive induction searches for concept descriptions in a representation space that is being iteratively improved. In each iteration, the system learns concept description from training examples projected into a newly constructed representation space, using an Aq algorithm-based inductive learning system (AQ15). The learned description is analyzed to determine desirable problem-oriented modifications of the representation space. These modifications include generating new attributes, removing redundant or insignificant ones, and/or agglomerating attribute values into larger units. New attributes are constructed by assigning names to groups of the best-performing characteristic rules for each decision class, and then are used to define the representation space for the next iteration. This iterative process repeats until the created hypotheses satisfy a stopping criterion. In several experiments on learning discrete functions, the developed AQ17-HCI system consistently outperformed, in terms of the prediction accuracy on new examples, all systems that it was compared to, including the AQ15 rule learning system, GREEDY3 and GROVE decision-list learning systems, and REDWOOD and FRINGE decision-tree learning systems. Although the proposed method was developed for the Aq-based rule learning system, it can potentially be adapted to any other inductive learning system. In this sense, it represents a universal new approach to constructive induction.</abstract></paper>