<paper id="1963969815"><title>Balancing strategic interests and technological requirements for mobile services</title><year>2004</year><authors><author org="Telematica Instituut, The Netherlands" id="2025293551">Timber Haaker</author><author org="Telematica Instituut, The Netherlands" id="2036347682">Edward Faber</author><author org="Delft Univ of Tech, The Netherlands" id="2086109825">Harry Bouwman</author></authors><n_citation>16</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2026835877</reference><reference>2035547073</reference><reference>2073205498</reference><reference>2165574216</reference><reference>2167752114</reference></references><venue id="2627069240" type="C">International Conference on Electronic Commerce</venue><doi>10.1145/1052220.1052298</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.64843">New business development</keyword><keyword weight="0.61285">Industrialization of services business model</keyword><keyword weight="0.44197">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.67096">Mobile business development</keyword><keyword weight="0.47889">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.68869">Business domain</keyword><keyword weight="0.63544">Business model</keyword><keyword weight="0.63045">Business requirements</keyword><keyword weight="0.61735">Business process modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.63657">Business rule</keyword><keyword weight="0.45264">Marketing</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>Designing business models for mobile services is a complex undertaking because it requires multiple actors to balance different design requirements. A business model can be seen as a blueprint of four interrelated components or domains: service, technology, organization and finance domain. Little attention has been paid to how these different domains are related to one another. This knowledge is needed to enhance our understanding of what constitutes a viable business model. In this paper the interdependencies between two of these domains, namely organization and technology domain, are explored by analyzing critical design issues in business models for mobile services, i.e. partner selection, network openness, network governance, and network complexity in the organization domain, and security, quality of service, management of service profiles, system integration and accessibility in the technology domain. A causal framework is developed, which links these critical design issues to expected network value and business model viability.</abstract></paper>