<paper id="1971378428"><title>Satisfiability threshold for random XOR-CNF formulas</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="Département de Mathématiques, Université de Caen, Campus II, 14032 Caen, France" id="2641453884">Nadia Creignou</author><author org="Département de Mathématiques, Université d’ Aix-Marseille I, 13013 Marseille, France" id="2169571456">Hervé Daude</author></authors><n_citation>38</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>4983232</reference><reference>1561608403</reference><reference>1636182933</reference><reference>2031823362</reference><reference>2036265926</reference><reference>2051580875</reference><reference>2091345559</reference><reference>2166566648</reference></references><venue id="171741597" type="J">Discrete Applied Mathematics</venue><doi>10.1016/S0166-218X(99)00032-3</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46355">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.46235">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.47418">Decision problem</keyword><keyword weight="0.53465">Random graph</keyword><keyword weight="0.45896">Exclusive or</keyword><keyword weight="0.50787">Satisfiability</keyword><keyword weight="0.51623">Counting problem</keyword><keyword weight="0.48319">Time complexity</keyword><keyword weight="0.49837">Probability density function</keyword><keyword weight="0.41906">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.44645">Special case</keyword></keywords><publisher>Elsevier Science Publishers B. V.</publisher><abstract>Abstract Various experimental investigations have shown a sharp transition between satisfiability and unsatisfiability of CNF formulas with L clauses over n variables as c = L / n is varied. For 2-SAT it has been shown theoretically that a threshold phenomenon occurs at the critical value c =1. For 3-SAT experimental results show a sharp transition near c =4 but no such threshold phenomenon has already been proved. Noticing that the XOR-SAT problem (in which one uses the ‘exclusive or’ instead of the usual ‘or’) is a special case of satisfiability which is solvable in polynomial time as decision problem as well as counting problem leads to the natural question: is there a satisfiability threshold for XOR-SAT? In this paper, we answer this question in establishing a threshold phenomenon for XOR-SAT, with associated critical value c =1. So, consider randomly generated XOR-CNF formulas F. We prove that F is satisfiable with probability 1−o(1) whenever c c u003e1 as n tends to infinity. Indeed, in following the nice terminology classification given by Erdos and Renyi for random graphs, we obtain much better: we exhibit a probability distribution function that gives a complete understanding of the transition from satisfiability to unsatisfiability for random XOR-SAT formulas.</abstract></paper>