<paper id="1975006305"><title>Image clustering with tensor representation</title><year>2005</year><authors><author org="Univ, of Chicago, Chicago, IL" id="2157503142">Xiaofei He</author><author org="UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS AT URBANA–CHAMPAIGN, URBANA, IL" id="2141500565">Deng Cai</author><author org="University of Toronto Toronto Canada" id="2157173648">Haifeng Liu</author><author org="UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS AT URBANA–CHAMPAIGN, URBANA, IL" id="2121939561">Jiawei Han</author></authors><n_citation>35</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1570386387</reference><reference>1834069999</reference><reference>2010434073</reference><reference>2013029404</reference><reference>2031095833</reference><reference>2045971250</reference><reference>2121947440</reference><reference>2133455944</reference><reference>2134958224</reference><reference>2154872931</reference><reference>2156718197</reference><reference>2165874743</reference></references><venue id="1135237122" type="C">ACM Multimedia</venue><doi>10.1145/1101149.1101169</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.63029">Tensor product</keyword><keyword weight="0.64484">Tensor</keyword><keyword weight="0.65183">Tensor (intrinsic definition)</keyword><keyword weight="0.41794">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.69858">Tensor contraction</keyword><keyword weight="0.63921">Cluster analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.68564">Two-vector</keyword><keyword weight="0.44524">Computer vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.65915">Cartesian tensor</keyword><keyword weight="0.45864">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.66601">Structure tensor</keyword><keyword weight="0.43165">Machine learning</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>We consider the problem of image representation and clustering. Traditionally, an n 1 x n 2 image is represented by a vector in the Euclidean space R n1 x n2. Some learning algorithms are then applied to these vectors in such a high dimensional space for dimensionality reduction, classification, and clustering. However, an image is intrinsically a matrix, or the second order tensor. The vector representation of the images ignores the spatial relationships between the pixels in an image. In this paper, we introduce a tensor framework for image analysis. We represent the images as points in the tensor space Rn1 mathcal Rn2 which is a tensor product of two vector spaces. Based on the tensor representation, we propose a novel image representation and clustering algorithm which explicitly considers the manifold structure of the tensor space. By preserving the local structure of the data manifold, we can obtain a tensor subspace which is optimal for data representation in the sense of local isometry. We call it TensorImage approach. Traditional clustering algorithm such as k-means is then applied in the tensor subspace. Our algorithm shares many of the data representation and clustering properties of other techniques such as Locality Preserving Projections, Laplacian Eigenmaps, and spectral clustering, yet our algorithm is much more computationally efficient. Experimental results show the efficiency and effectiveness of our algorithm.</abstract></paper>