<paper id="1486788401"><title>TKQML: A Scripting Tool for Building Agents</title><year>1997</year><authors><author org="Univ. of Maryland, Baltimore County#TAB#" id="2125572757">R. Scott Cost</author><author org="Univ. of Maryland, Baltimore County#TAB#" id="2031005049">Ian Soboroff</author><author org="Univ. of Maryland, Baltimore County#TAB#" id="2274405597">Jeegar Lakhani</author><author org="Univ. of Maryland, Baltimore County#TAB#" id="2066282134">Timothy W. Finin</author><author org="Univ. of Maryland, Baltimore County#TAB#" id="2168190067">Ethan L. Miller</author><author org="Univ. of Maryland, Baltimore County#TAB#" id="2127501897">Charles Nicholas</author></authors><n_citation>8</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>151073703</reference><reference>1483827732</reference><reference>1532766933</reference><reference>1696393724</reference><reference>2064023648</reference><reference>2134342348</reference><reference>2160484851</reference><reference>2165558305</reference></references><venue id="1195874795" type="C">Intelligent Agents</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0026770</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.63175">Intelligent agent</keyword><keyword weight="0.45382">Standard language</keyword><keyword weight="0.45682">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.64435">Agent architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.51903">Interpreter</keyword><keyword weight="0.47247">Human–computer interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.58711">User interface</keyword><keyword weight="0.53919">Natural user interface</keyword><keyword weight="0.58283">Scripting language</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Tcl/Tk is an attractive language for the design of intelligent agents because it allows the quick construction of prototypes and user interfaces; new scripts can easily be bound at runtime to respond to events; and execution state is encapsulated by the interpreter, which helps in agent migration. However, a system of intelligent agents must share a common language for communicating requests and knowledge. We have integrated KQML (Knowledge Query Manipulation Language), one such standard language, into Tcl/Tk. The resulting system, called TKQML, provides several benefits to those building intelligent agent systems. First, TKQML allows easy integration of existing tools which have Tcl/Tk interfaces with an agent system by using TO to move information between KQML and the application. Second, TKQML is an excellent language with which to build agents, allowing on-the-fly specification of message handlers and construction of graphical interfaces. This paper describes the implementation of TKQML, and discusses its use in our intelligent agent system for information retrieval.</abstract></paper>