<paper id="1520067393"><title>Methodology-driven use of automated support in business process re-engineering</title><year>1993</year><authors><author org="University of Georgia." id="2166812292">Alan R. Dennis</author><author org="University of South Alabama ," id="2560974151">Robert M. Daniels</author><author org="University of South Alabama ," id="2102717018">Glenda Hayes</author><author org="" id="2148746491">Jay F. Nunamaker</author></authors><n_citation>48</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1991168909</reference><reference>1992439356</reference><reference>2012996218</reference><reference>2015865347</reference><reference>2158342889</reference></references><venue id="9954729" type="J">Journal of Management Information Systems</venue><doi>10.1080/07421222.1993.11518013</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.64802">Artifact-centric business process model</keyword><keyword weight="0.63846">Business case</keyword><keyword weight="0.44591">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47852">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.63805">Business requirements</keyword><keyword weight="0.68145">Business process modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.62687">Business process discovery</keyword><keyword weight="0.64746">Business Process Model and Notation</keyword><keyword weight="0.66923">Business rule</keyword><keyword weight="0.47029">Management science</keyword><keyword weight="0.63843">Business architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.48399">Process management</keyword></keywords><publisher>M. E. Sharpe, Inc.</publisher><abstract>This article describes a three-month pilot project to model and re-engineer an internal business unit of a major multinational firm using Enterprise Analyzer, a methodology and supporting group software tool for modeling and analyzing business processes. The methodology combines collaborative model building with creative problem reframing to enable multilevel, cross-functional business teams to quickly examine and redesign business processes. The tools developed for this project extend the capabilities of existing electronic meeting system technology to help groups build complex representations of their organization. The results of this pilot project suggest that the methodology and supporting tools can be effectively applied to re-engineer business processes, but also suggest the need for better ways to help groups accept innovative ideas. Many innovative ideas were generated, but few made it past the participantsu0027 evaluation and into the projectu0027s final recommendations.</abstract></paper>