<paper id="1584824347"><title>An empirical assessment of a modified technology acceptance model</title><year>1996</year><authors><author org="" id="662435172">Patrick Y. K. Chau</author></authors><n_citation>773</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1493155866</reference><reference>1497226654</reference><reference>1497252209</reference><reference>1515402129</reference><reference>1558680053</reference><reference>1559269151</reference><reference>1561539683</reference><reference>1564097354</reference><reference>1791587663</reference><reference>2008441192</reference><reference>2043837795</reference><reference>2048550469</reference><reference>2081293998</reference><reference>2100408980</reference><reference>2108354866</reference><reference>2111899499</reference><reference>2138882002</reference><reference>2163507788</reference></references><venue id="9954729" type="J">Journal of Management Information Systems</venue><doi>10.1080/07421222.1996.11518128</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.50622">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Empirical assessment</keyword><keyword weight="0.49465">Structural equation modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.40197">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.49506">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.64993">Technology acceptance model</keyword><keyword weight="0.46662">Usability</keyword><keyword weight="0.44425">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.43111">Management science</keyword></keywords><publisher>Routledge</publisher><abstract>The technology acceptance model (TAM) is one of the most influential research models in studies of the determinants of information systems/information technology (IS/IT) acceptance. In TAM, perceived usefulness and perceived ease of use are hypothesized and empirically supported as fundamental determinants of user acceptance of a given IS/IT. A review of the IS and psychology literature, however, suggests that perceived usefulness can be of two distinct types: near-term usefulness and long-term usefulness. This paper reviews the concept of perceived usefulness and modifies TAM to include the two types of perceived usefulness. Data collected from nearly 285 administrative/clerical staff in a large organization were tested against the modified model using the structural equation modeling approach. The results of the study showed that, even though perceived near-term usefulness had the most significant influence on the behavioral intention to use a technology, perceived long-term usefulness also exerted a positive, though lesser, impact. No significant, direct relationship was found between ease of use and behavioral intention to use a technology. Implications of the findings and future research areas are discussed.</abstract></paper>