<paper id="1518083319"><title>Pseudorandom generators from one-way functions: a simple construction for any hardness</title><year>2006</year><authors><author org="Department of Computer Science, ETH Zurich, Zurich" id="80731854">Thomas Holenstein</author></authors><n_citation>57</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>65739208</reference><reference>2012045293</reference><reference>2015880590</reference><reference>2016201895</reference><reference>2027528470</reference><reference>2032821770</reference><reference>2077300005</reference><reference>2107324709</reference><reference>2113999696</reference><reference>2117362057</reference><reference>2119871351</reference><reference>2159460804</reference><reference>2160403361</reference></references><venue id="1137528458" type="C">Theory of Cryptography Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/11681878_23</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.63874">Pseudorandom function family</keyword><keyword weight="0.47263">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.6638">Pseudorandom generators for polynomials</keyword><keyword weight="0.65626">Pseudorandomness</keyword><keyword weight="0.53707">One-way function</keyword><keyword weight="0.57115">Random number generation</keyword><keyword weight="0.66824">Pseudorandom generator</keyword><keyword weight="0.6897">Pseudorandom generator theorem</keyword><keyword weight="0.42497">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.59831">Pseudorandom number generator</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>In a seminal paper, Hastad, Impagliazzo, Levin, and Luby showed that pseudorandom generators exist if and only if one-way functions exist. The construction they propose to obtain a pseudorandom generator from an n-bit one-way function uses $\mathcal{O}(n^8)$ random bits in the input (which is the most important complexity measure of such a construction). In this work we study how much this can be reduced if the one-way function satisfies a stronger security requirement. For example, we show how to obtain a pseudorandom generator which satisfies a standard notion of security using only $\mathcal{O}(n^4log^2(n))$ bits of randomness if a one-way function with exponential security is given, i.e., a one-way function for which no polynomial time algorithm has probability higher than 2−cn in inverting for some constant the :[125],"uniform variant of Impagliazzou0027s hard-core lemma given in [7] our constructions and proofs are self-contained within this paper, and as a special case of our main theorem, we give the first explicit description of the most efficient construction from [6].</abstract></paper>