<paper id="1502487491"><title>Information links and electronic marketplaces: the role of interorganizational information systems in vertical markets</title><year>1991</year><authors><author org="" id="2294113044">J. Yannis Bakos</author></authors><n_citation>293</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1517176575</reference><reference>1568507576</reference><reference>1579194127</reference><reference>1600707278</reference><reference>1663328209</reference><reference>1916225327</reference><reference>1965602688</reference><reference>1983600827</reference><reference>2104735397</reference><reference>2118936359</reference><reference>2125757739</reference><reference>2134830607</reference><reference>2135871035</reference><reference>2141553985</reference><reference>2156284882</reference></references><venue id="9954729" type="J">Journal of Management Information Systems</venue><doi>10.1080/07421222.1991.11517920</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.64443">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.52599">Economic efficiency</keyword><keyword weight="0.49973">Economic model</keyword><keyword weight="0.40812">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46738">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Electronic markets</keyword><keyword weight="0.57174">Market system</keyword><keyword weight="0.61601">Strategic information system</keyword></keywords><publisher>M. E. Sharpe, Inc.</publisher><abstract>Interorganizational information systems--i.e., systems spanning more than a single organization--are proliferating as companies become aware of the potential of these systems to affect interorganizational interactions in terms of economic efficiency and strategic conduct. This new technology can have a far-reaching impact on the structure of entire industries. This article identifies two types of interorganizational information systems: information links and electronic markets. It then explores how economic models can be employed to study the implications of information links for the coordination of individual organizations with their customers and their suppliers, and the implications of electronic market systems for efficiency and competition in vertical markets. Finally, the strategic significance of inter-organizational systems is addressed, and certain potential long-term impacts on the structure of markets, industries, and organizations are discussed.</abstract></paper>