<paper id="1528991045"><title>Heuristic development: a redesign of systems design</title><year>1979</year><authors><author org="" id="2276362250">Thomas Berrisford</author><author org="" id="116766436">James Wetherbe</author></authors><n_citation>91</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1504986418</reference><reference>1564930140</reference><reference>1584215834</reference><reference>2017563110</reference><reference>2035557221</reference><reference>2039248724</reference><reference>2085412841</reference><reference>2128487013</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/249144</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.65581">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.61743">Management information systems</keyword><keyword weight="0.60321">Intelligent decision support system</keyword><keyword weight="0.47233">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.60053">Method engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.6518">System of systems</keyword><keyword weight="0.60351">Automated information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.46352">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.64037">Systems design</keyword><keyword weight="0.65847">Systems development life cycle</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>This article proposes a major modification to the traditional systems development process. Traditional systems development approaches delay the delivery of tangible information system capabilities to users (i.e., query capabilities and decision support models, etc.) until the last stages of systems development. Consequently, it is not until after systems are developed that shortcomings in systems design surface. The authors advocate providing or at least simulating user capabilities early in the systems development process. Such an approach is made possible by the use of an online relational-type Database Management System. Introduction of such user capabilities allows users to interact with the system and heuristically determine information authors :[104],"present behavioral, technical, and operational arguments for a heuristic approach. Also, several case studies of heuristic development are heuristic approach to information systems development is a :[124],"useful concept for MIS managers, systems analysts, and users of computer-based information systems.</abstract></paper>