<paper id="1516849933"><title>Probabilistic Model Checking of the IEEE 802.11 Wireless Local Area Network Protocol</title><year>2002</year><authors><author org="University of Birmingham" id="2156109015">Marta Z. Kwiatkowska</author><author org="University of Birmingham" id="2123615300">Gethin Norman</author><author org="Universita' di Torino#TAB#" id="2069577751">Jeremy Sproston</author></authors><n_citation>109</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>138290785</reference><reference>160297318</reference><reference>1559321056</reference><reference>1601373402</reference><reference>1621538476</reference><reference>1850900101</reference><reference>1903000972</reference><reference>1968057948</reference><reference>2000947342</reference><reference>2005998857</reference><reference>2009280542</reference><reference>2057873236</reference><reference>2068486694</reference><reference>2101508170</reference><reference>2136545402</reference><reference>2145444024</reference><reference>2162598825</reference><reference>2162943184</reference><reference>2165161585</reference><reference>2567822803</reference></references><venue id="106296714" type="J">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-45605-8_11</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.61257">Exponential backoff</keyword><keyword weight="0.55555">IEEE 802.11</keyword><keyword weight="0.54501">Nondeterministic algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.4443">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45574">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.62506">Probabilistic CTL</keyword><keyword weight="0.57535">Timed automaton</keyword><keyword weight="0.6121">Probabilistic logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.57078">Carrier sense multiple access with collision avoidance</keyword><keyword weight="0.56412">Probabilistic automaton</keyword><keyword weight="0.45137">Distributed computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>The international standard IEEE 802.11 was developed recently in recognition of the increased demand for wireless local area networks. Its medium access control mechanism is described according to a variant of the Carrier Sense Multiple Access with Collision Avoidance (CSMA/CA) scheme. Although collisions cannot always be prevented, randomised exponential backoff rules are used in the retransmission scheme to minimise the likelihood of repeated collisions. More precisely, the backoff procedure involves a uniform probabilistic choice of an integer-valued delay from an interval, where the size of the interval grows exponentially with regard to the number of retransmissions of the current data packet. We model the two-way handshake mechanism of the IEEE 802.11 standard with a fixed network topology using probabilistic timed automata, a formal description mechanism in which both nondeterministic choice and probabilistic choice can be represented. From our probabilistic timed automaton model, we obtain a finite-state Markov decision process via a property-preserving discrete-time semantics. The Markov decision process is then verified using Prism, a probabilistic model checking tool, against probabilistic, timed properties such as "at most 5,000 microseconds pass before a station sends its packet correctly."</abstract></paper>