<paper id="1561421835"><title>A Flexible and Adaptable Tool Kit Approach for Concurrency Control in Non Standard Database Systems</title><year>1990</year><authors><author org="University of Hagen" id="664262605">Rainer Unland</author></authors><n_citation>5</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>50944095</reference><reference>196018858</reference><reference>1517915834</reference><reference>1570983218</reference><reference>1572967552</reference><reference>1573966373</reference><reference>1816319839</reference><reference>2016590848</reference><reference>2024167194</reference><reference>2036862988</reference><reference>2041414515</reference><reference>2067686439</reference><reference>2072346647</reference><reference>2087733696</reference><reference>2092639071</reference><reference>2113906833</reference><reference>2125565960</reference><reference>2130281490</reference><reference>2707532992</reference></references><venue id="1165285842" type="C">International Conference on Database Theory</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-53507-1_83</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.60028">Database tuning</keyword><keyword weight="0.625">Serializability</keyword><keyword weight="0.68555">Isolation (database systems)</keyword><keyword weight="0.4644">Programming language</keyword><keyword weight="0.60248">Concurrency control</keyword><keyword weight="0.4636">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.69656">Multiversion concurrency control</keyword><keyword weight="0.6832">Distributed concurrency control</keyword><keyword weight="0.68892">Non-lock concurrency control</keyword><keyword weight="0.45655">Database</keyword><keyword weight="0.67719">Optimistic concurrency control</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Concurrency control has been thoroughly investigated in the context of traditional database applications. There are relatively few studies, however, that address the concurrency control issues of u0027advanced database applicationsu0027 like, e. g., CAD/CAM, CASE, large AI applications or image and voice processing. The demands on concurrency control in such application areas differ substantially from those in traditional database applications; in particular, there is a need to support u0027enrichedu0027 data models (which include, e. g., complex objects or version and configuration management), u0027synergisticu0027 cooperative work, and application or user supported consistency. But, unfortunately, the demands are not only sophisticated but also diversified, which means that different application areas might even place contradictory demands on transaction management. This paper deals with the problem of concurrency control and offers a solution by introducing a flexible, adaptable, and extensible tool kit approach. This tool kit is meant to be the basis for a database implementor (DBI) to assemble application specific concurrency control mechanisms.</abstract></paper>