<paper id="1589187426"><title>The Use of Background Knowledge in Decision Tree Induction</title><year>1991</year><authors><author org="TELEFONICA I+D, C/Emilio Vargas, 6, 28043 Madrid, Spain. mnunez@ts.tid.es#TAB#" id="2163251176">Marlon Núñez</author></authors><n_citation>193</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1514032333</reference><reference>1527418157</reference><reference>1574272650</reference><reference>1978515644</reference><reference>2053937765</reference><reference>2085412104</reference><reference>2116298505</reference><reference>2128420091</reference><reference>2974365732</reference></references><venue id="62148650" type="J">Machine Learning</venue><doi>10.1023/A:1022609710832</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.58911">Decision tree</keyword><keyword weight="0.54711">Logical conjunction</keyword><keyword weight="0.47368">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47725">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.47322">ID3</keyword><keyword weight="0.51236">Hierarchy</keyword><keyword weight="0.56027">Knowledge acquisition</keyword><keyword weight="0.47698">Machine learning</keyword><keyword weight="0.62456">Incremental decision tree</keyword></keywords><publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher><abstract>At present, algorithms of the ID3 family are not based on background knowledge. For that reason, most of the time they are neither logical nor understandable to experts. These algorithms cannot perform different types of generalization as others can do (Michalski, 1983s Kodratoff, 1983), nor can they can reduce the cost of classifications. The algorithm presented in this paper tries to generate more logical and understandable decision trees than those generated by ID3-like algorithmss it executes various types of generalization and at the same time reduces the classification cost by means of background knowledge. The background knowledge contains the ISA hierarchy and the measurement cost associated with each attribute. The user can define the degrees of economy and generalization. These data will influence directly the quantity of search that the algorithm must undertake. This algorithm, which is an attribute version of the EG2 method (Nunez, 1988a, 1988b), has been implemented and the results appear in this paper comparing them with other methods.</abstract></paper>