<paper id="1488817203"><title>Data and Model-Driven Selection Using Color Regions</title><year>1997</year><authors><author org="Xerox Webster Research Center, 800 Phillips Road, Webster NY 14580#TAB#" id="2021909339">Tanveer Fathima Syeda-Mahmood</author></authors><n_citation>58</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>48233118</reference><reference>1506525286</reference><reference>1571260490</reference><reference>1842135878</reference><reference>1978578701</reference><reference>1995376165</reference><reference>2000048778</reference><reference>2053197265</reference><reference>2069266228</reference><reference>2105994593</reference><reference>2109172751</reference><reference>2125320063</reference><reference>2129104643</reference><reference>2141151193</reference><reference>2145526806</reference><reference>2148220292</reference><reference>2151173386</reference><reference>2171681042</reference><reference>2914885528</reference></references><venue id="25538012" type="J">International Journal of Computer Vision</venue><doi>10.1023/A:1007919421801</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.64384">Color constancy</keyword><keyword weight="0.46056">Computer vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.689">Color space</keyword><keyword weight="0.42478">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.50872">Salience (neuroscience)</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.58164">Color vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.67572">Color normalization</keyword><keyword weight="0.64654">Color quantization</keyword><keyword weight="0.50605">Cognitive neuroscience of visual object recognition</keyword><keyword weight="0.70142">Color image</keyword></keywords><publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher><abstract>A key problem in model-based object recognition is selection, namely, the problem of determining which regions in the image are likely to come from a single object. In this paper we present an approach that uses color as a cue to perform selection either based solely on image-data (data-driven), or based on the knowledge of the color description of the model (model-driven). Specifically, the paper presents a method of color specification in terms of perceptual color categories and shows its relevance for the task of selection. The color categories are used to develop a fast region segmentation algorithm that extracts perceptual color regions in images. The color regions extracted form the basis for performing data and model-driven selection. Data-driven selection is achieved by selecting salient color regions as judged by a color-saliency measure that emphasizes attributes that are also important in human color perception. The approach to model-driven selection, on the other hand, exploits the color and other region information in the 3d model object to locate instances of the object in a given image. The approach presented tolerates some of the problems of occlusion, pose and illumination changes that make a model instance in an image appear different from its original description. Finally, the utility of color-based selection is demonstrated by showing the extent of search reduction possible when color-based selection is integrated with a recognition system.</abstract></paper>