<paper id="1507223999"><title>Question Answering from Frequently Asked Question Files: Experiences with the FAQ Finder System</title><year>1997</year><authors><author org="Electrical Engineering and Computer Science" id="2122091461">Robin D. Burke</author><author org="Electrical Engineering and Computer Science" id="2616952818">Kristian J. Hammond</author><author org="" id="378826902">Vladimir A. Kulyukin</author><author org="" id="312172926">Steven L. Lytinen</author><author org="" id="10987593">N. Tomuro</author><author org="" id="2120679740">S. Schoenberg</author></authors><n_citation>419</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1956559956</reference><reference>2046224275</reference><reference>2081580037</reference></references><venue id="163019073" type="J">Ai Magazine</venue><doi>10.1609/aimag.v18i2.1294</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45199">Semantic memory</keyword><keyword weight="0.68197">Question answering</keyword><keyword weight="0.4731">Information retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.44782">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Natural language question answering</keyword><keyword weight="0.53989">Knowledge base</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Textual case-based reasoning</keyword><keyword weight="0.54352">WordNet</keyword><keyword weight="0.43624">Technical report</keyword></keywords><publisher>University of Chicago</publisher><abstract>This technical report describes FAQ Finder, a natural language question answering system that uses files of frequently asked questions as its knowledge base. Unlike AI question-answering systems that focus on the generation of new answers, FAQ Finder retrieves existing ones found in frequently-asked question files. Unlike information retrieval approaches that rely on a purely lexical metric of similarity between query and document, FAQ Finder uses a semantic knowledge base (WordNet) to improve its ability to match question and answer. We describe the design and the current implementation of the system and its support components, including results from an evaluation of the systemu0027u0027s performance against a corpus of user questions. An important finding was that a combination of semantic and statistical techniques works better than any single approach. We analyze failures of the system and discuss future research aimed at addressing them.</abstract></paper>