<paper id="1531731596"><title>On the intertranslatability of non-monotonic logics</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="Laboratory for Theoretical Computer Science, Helsinki University of Technology, P.O. Box 5400, FIN&amp;dash" id="2018242697">Tomi Janhunen</author></authors><n_citation>33</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>36580660</reference><reference>68551149</reference><reference>72953418</reference><reference>84120850</reference><reference>117351571</reference><reference>168384132</reference><reference>211984302</reference><reference>292459908</reference><reference>1584225025</reference><reference>1589418907</reference><reference>1610119672</reference><reference>1776669836</reference><reference>1831160428</reference><reference>1966761138</reference><reference>1982644464</reference><reference>1987903153</reference><reference>1997714358</reference><reference>2002476082</reference><reference>2007660757</reference><reference>2017956822</reference><reference>2029246084</reference><reference>2065251436</reference><reference>2067326626</reference><reference>2069174070</reference><reference>2083568285</reference><reference>2101017866</reference><reference>2123810163</reference><reference>2127005081</reference><reference>2129670289</reference><reference>2146658047</reference><reference>2155322595</reference><reference>2913309218</reference><reference>2945259913</reference></references><venue id="90199469" type="J">Annals of Mathematics and Artificial Intelligence</venue><doi>10.1023/A:1018915113814</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.42679">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.63946">T-norm fuzzy logics</keyword><keyword weight="0.63421">Autoepistemic logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.62592">Substructural logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.62782">Classical logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.61923">Monoidal t-norm logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.6486">Non-monotonic logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.61917">Many-valued logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.40654">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.62325">Intermediate logic</keyword></keywords><publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher><abstract>This paper concentrates on comparing the expressive powers of five nondmonotonic logics that have appeared in the literature. For this purpose, the concept of a polynomial, faithful and modular (PFM) translation function is adopted from earlier work by Gottlob, but a weaker notion of faithfulness is proposed. The existence of a PFM translation function from one nondmonotonic logic to another is interpreted to indicate that the latter logic is capable of expressing everything that the former logic does. Several translation functions are presented in the paper and shown to be PFM. Moreover, it is shown that PFM translation functions are impossible in certain cases, which indicates that the expressive powers of the logics involved differ strictly. The comparisons made in terms of PFM translation functions give rise to an exact classification of nondmonotonic logics, which is then named as the expressive power hierarchy (EPH) of nondmonotonic logics. Three syntactically restricted variants of default logic are also analyzed, and EPH is refined accordingly. Most importantly, the classes of EPH indicate some astonishing relationships in light of earlier results on the expressive power of nondmonotonic logics presented by Gottlob as well as Bonatti and Eiter: Moore’s autoepistemic logic and prerequisitedfree default logic are of equal expressive power and less expressive than Reiter’s default logic and Marek and Truszczynski’s strong autoepistemic logic.</abstract></paper>