<paper id="1526421749"><title>Executive involvement and participation in the management of information technology</title><year>1991</year><authors><author org="" id="229437117">Sirkka L. Jarvenpaa</author><author org="Southern#N#          Methodist University" id="2160064358">Blake Ives</author></authors><n_citation>610</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>58544695</reference><reference>1498240737</reference><reference>1534734121</reference><reference>1551457744</reference><reference>1698680534</reference><reference>2019410574</reference><reference>2107258608</reference><reference>2113954314</reference><reference>2124330866</reference><reference>2125752931</reference><reference>2129641617</reference><reference>2135871035</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/249382</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.49742">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.52716">Management information systems</keyword><keyword weight="0.44487">Public relations</keyword><keyword weight="0.46356">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.34059">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Survey research</keyword><keyword weight="0.42235">Perception</keyword><keyword weight="0.45133">Shareholder</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>Executive support is often prescribed as critical for fully tapping the benefits of information technology (IT). However, few investigations have attempted to determine what type of executive support is likely or organizationally appropriate. This article puts forward alternative models of executive support. The models are tested by examining chief executive officersu0027 behaviors in and perceptions of IT activities. CEOs and information systems executives are surveyed and further data collected from industry handbooks and from chairmenu0027s annual letters to shareholders. The results suggest that executive involvement (a psychological state) is more strongly associated with the firmu0027s progressive use of IT than executive participation (actual behaviors) in IT activities. Executive involvement is influenced by a CEOu0027s participation, prevailing organizational conditions, and the executiveu0027s functional background. CEOu0027s perceptions about the importance of IT in their firms were generally positive, although they participated in IT activities rather infrequently.</abstract></paper>