<paper id="136050693"><title>Self-calibration from multiple views with a rotating camera</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="G.E. CRD" id="2138371963">Richard I. Hartley</author></authors><n_citation>302</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1630235098</reference><reference>1943823759</reference><reference>2065592949</reference><reference>2121417205</reference><reference>2157405987</reference><reference>2164232884</reference><reference>2912369374</reference></references><venue id="1124077590" type="C">European Conference on Computer Vision</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-57956-7_52</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Calibration algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.46945">Computer vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.51663">Plane at infinity</keyword><keyword weight="0.48704">Rotation matrix</keyword><keyword weight="0.64344">Epipolar geometry</keyword><keyword weight="0.40194">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47489">Synthetic data</keyword><keyword weight="0.52442">Homography</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.5804">Real image</keyword><keyword weight="0.47399">Calibration</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>A new practical method is given for the self-calibration of a camera. In this method, at least three images are taken from the same point in space with different orientations of the camera and calibration is computed from an analysis of point matches between the images. The method requires no knowledge of the orientations of the camera. Calibration is based on the image correspondences only. This method differs fundamentally from previous results by Maybank and Faugeras on selfcalibration using the epipolar structure of image pairs. In the method of this paper, there is no epipolar structure since all images are taken from the same point in space. Since the images are all taken from the same point in space, determination of point matches is considerably easier than for images taken with a moving camera, since problems of occlusion or change of aspect or illumination do not occur. The calibration method is evaluated on several sets of synthetic and real image data.</abstract></paper>