<paper id="1844320176"><title>A Multi-criteria Taxonomy of Business Models in Electronic Commerce</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="University of Hamburg, VSYS" id="1979433016">Andreas Bartelt</author><author org="University of Hamburg, VSYS" id="2157994539">Winfried Lamersdorf</author></authors><n_citation>32</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>94619067</reference><reference>1607184504</reference><reference>1970801473</reference><reference>2026080185</reference><reference>2114169952</reference><reference>2124344619</reference><reference>2142532474</reference><reference>2146439955</reference><reference>2161670755</reference><reference>2166792323</reference><reference>2169541324</reference></references><venue id="106296714" type="J">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-45598-1_18</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.66932">Artifact-centric business process model</keyword><keyword weight="0.66374">New business development</keyword><keyword weight="0.71251">Electronic business</keyword><keyword weight="0.44577">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47322">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.6699">Business domain</keyword><keyword weight="0.66602">Business process modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.66">Business Process Model and Notation</keyword><keyword weight="0.69526">Business rule</keyword><keyword weight="0.42812">Distributed computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.64873">Business analysis</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Looking at the ongoing evolution in electronic commerce there are more and more business models becoming significant. E-shops, e-auctions or e-tendering are not the only possibilities for a company to be active in electronic commerce. This article presents many relevant business models and systematically classifies them. Mainly the classification is based on the type of business subjects like suppliers, customers and mediators and their active or passive role as initiators and carrier of a business model. Another basis for the classification is the breakdown of the concept of electronic commerce and an explicit modeling. This allows to build up a taxonomy using multiple criteria and the presentation and subsumption of individual business models. The taxonomy can be used to analyze and enhance existing systems and business models as well as to develop new internet strategies for companies. An example of the implementation of the business model e-portal concludes the article.</abstract></paper>