<paper id="1813469589"><title>Learning from AI: New Trends in Database Technology</title><year>1986</year><authors><author org="University of California" id="2228702940">Bic</author><author org="" id="2433288755">Gilbert</author></authors><n_citation>69</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>2001074770</reference><reference>2009921028</reference><reference>2027750453</reference><reference>2039601877</reference><reference>2056911890</reference><reference>2074891686</reference><reference>2115166955</reference><reference>2122789628</reference><reference>2130474477</reference><reference>2168787502</reference></references><venue id="178916657" type="J">IEEE Computer</venue><doi>10.1109/MC.1986.1663178</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47416">Data science</keyword><keyword weight="0.62022">Data modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.66202">Data administration</keyword><keyword weight="0.64627">Database model</keyword><keyword weight="0.45378">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45462">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.47024">Context model</keyword><keyword weight="0.47249">Knowledge representation and reasoning</keyword><keyword weight="0.46123">Software engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.63607">Database testing</keyword><keyword weight="0.70836">Database design</keyword><keyword weight="0.64497">Intelligent database</keyword><keyword weight="0.45816">Database</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>Database management systems evolved in response to the need for efficient maintenance of increasingly large amounts of data. The relatively slow speed of secondary storage devices holding the data is one of the main limitations of database design. Hence, the internal organization of databases has been the primary focus of research in the past. Another major influence on database research was the need to share information among a variety of users. In such an environment, strict rules governing the manipulation of data had to be imposed to preserve the integrity of the database and to guarantee privacy for each user. These needs led to the development of several basic data models. With the steadily increasing demand for user-oriented systems, however, new trends in database technology have evolved outside of the scope of the traditional data models. In this article the authors are concerned with two closely related efforts: (1) The incorporation of more semantic modeling capabilities into database models. (2) The development of better user environments, which include user-friendly interfaces and support different user views of the content and organization of the data.</abstract></paper>