<paper id="130544901"><title>From contexts to constructs: the use of grounded theory in operationalising contingent process models</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="School of Informatics and Multimedia Technology, University of North London" id="2232702103">G. H. Galal</author></authors><n_citation>42</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1590667944</reference><reference>2066900729</reference><reference>2073849932</reference><reference>2106952701</reference></references><venue id="116712389" type="J">European Journal of Information Systems</venue><doi>10.1057/palgrave.ejis.3000381</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47984">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.5865">Grounded theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.476">Management information systems</keyword><keyword weight="0.46584">Information management</keyword><keyword weight="0.51461">Soft systems methodology</keyword><keyword weight="0.43271">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45434">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.50109">Process modeling</keyword><keyword weight="0.45095">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.48393">Strategic information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.45986">Management science</keyword></keywords><publisher>Palgrave Macmillan UK</publisher><abstract>In software and systems engineering, process models have been suggested that partly develop artifacts and then deploy them to evaluate the degree of their success in satisfying requirements, using the results of the evaluation to inform further engineering efforts. This paper discusses the important role of evaluation in non-sequential process models, and suggests an interpretive framework for effecting such evaluation, as well as the determination of risks and constraints to operationalise such models. We outline a particular mode of the Grounded Systems Engineering Methodology (GSEM) which aims at supporting the application of non-sequential process models, thus enabling them to be more responsive to the development context. GSEM utilises the philosophy and procedures of the Grounded Theory method, an interpretive research strategy which is being widely used for the inductive analysis of qualitative data in theory building. An illustrative case study is used to show how the framework can be applied in practice.</abstract></paper>