<paper id="1498316612"><title>Fuzzy identity-based encryption</title><year>2005</year><authors><author org="University of california, Los Angeles" id="2159933393">Amit Sahai</author><author org="Stanford, University" id="2131229705">Brent Waters</author></authors><n_citation>2388</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1515786888</reference><reference>1569083856</reference><reference>1607264302</reference><reference>2017439879</reference><reference>2032551902</reference><reference>2046871034</reference><reference>2085733527</reference><reference>2086042811</reference><reference>2110740499</reference><reference>2117685508</reference><reference>2127697997</reference><reference>2131183039</reference><reference>2138474025</reference><reference>2159339434</reference><reference>2610525718</reference></references><venue id="1140213147" type="C">Theory and Application of Cryptographic Techniques</venue><doi>10.1007/11426639_27</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.56417">Ciphertext indistinguishability</keyword><keyword weight="0.44392">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.52237">Cryptography</keyword><keyword weight="0.62421">Attribute-based encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.54097">Fuzzy logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.45152">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.62653">Encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.63222">Functional encryption</keyword><keyword weight="0.54734">Ciphertext</keyword><keyword weight="0.53088">Proxy re-encryption</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We introduce a new type of Identity-Based Encryption (IBE) scheme that we call Fuzzy Identity-Based Encryption. In Fuzzy IBE we view an identity as set of descriptive attributes. A Fuzzy IBE scheme allows for a private key for an identity, ω, to decrypt a ciphertext encrypted with an identity, ω ′, if and only if the identities ω and ω ′ are close to each other as measured by the “set overlap” distance metric. A Fuzzy IBE scheme can be applied to enable encryption using biometric inputs as identities; the error-tolerance property of a Fuzzy IBE scheme is precisely what allows for the use of biometric identities, which inherently will have some noise each time they are sampled. Additionally, we show that Fuzzy-IBE can be used for a type of application that we term “attribute-based :[135],"this paper we present two constructions of Fuzzy IBE schemes. Our constructions can be viewed as an Identity-Based Encryption of a message under several attributes that compose a (fuzzy) identity. Our IBE schemes are both error-tolerant and secure against collusion attacks. Additionally, our basic construction does not use random oracles. We prove the security of our schemes under the Selective-ID security model.</abstract></paper>