<paper id="1545190392"><title>Information privacy: measuring individuals' concerns about organizational practices</title><year>1996</year><authors><author org="Georgetown Univ.,#TAB#" id="2292866723">H. Jeff Smith</author><author org="" id="2946004576">Sandra J. Milberg</author></authors><n_citation>1271</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1538573233</reference><reference>1558927404</reference><reference>1595575146</reference><reference>2073957514</reference><reference>2077477140</reference><reference>2086944813</reference><reference>2122418187</reference><reference>2128992662</reference><reference>2138709157</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/249477</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47257">Generalizability theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Ethical issues</keyword><keyword weight="0.64104">Privacy by Design</keyword><keyword weight="0.39422">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.46157">Public relations</keyword><keyword weight="0.45114">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Public opinion polls</keyword><keyword weight="0.67479">Information privacy</keyword><keyword weight="0.4373">Perception</keyword><keyword weight="0.48065">Focus group</keyword><keyword weight="0.43597">LISREL</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>Information privacy has been called one of the most important ethical issues of the informa1 Alien Lee was the accepting senior for this paper. tion age. Public opinion polls show rising levels of concer about privacy among Americans. Against this backdrop, research into issues associated with information privacy is increasing. Based on a number of preliminary studies, it has become apparent that organizational practices, individualsu0027 perceptions of these practices, and societal responses are inextricably linked in many ways. Theories regarding these relationships are slowly emerging. Unfortunately, researchers attempting to examine such relationships through confirmatory empirical approaches may be impeded by the lack of validated instruments for measuring individualsu0027 concerns about organizational information privacy practices. To enable future studies in the information privacy research stream, we developed and validated an instrument that identifies and measures the primary dimensions of individualsu0027 concers about organizational information privacy practices. The development process included examinations of privacy literature; experience surveys and focus groups; and the use of expert judges. The result was a parsimonious 15-item instrument with four subscales tapping into dimensions of individualsu0027 concerns about organizational information privacy practices. The instrument was rigorously tested and validated across several heterogenous populations, providing a high degree of confidence in the scalesu0027 validity, reliability, and generalizability.</abstract></paper>