<paper id="1520051037"><title>Combining Z-buffer Engines for Higher-Speed Rendering</title><year>1991</year><authors><author org="" id="2754722827">Steven Molnar</author></authors><n_citation>37</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2012896450</reference><reference>2017120873</reference><reference>2057910062</reference><reference>2088138267</reference><reference>2103151360</reference><reference>2103607478</reference><reference>2112812291</reference><reference>2143425433</reference><reference>2166557212</reference><reference>2176659664</reference><reference>2295329974</reference></references><venue id="2754362256" type="C">Eurographics</venue><doi>10.2312/EGGH/EGGH88/171-182</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.45973">Polygon</keyword><keyword weight="0.42109">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48689">Binary tree</keyword><keyword weight="0.47911">Display device</keyword><keyword weight="0.49179">Multiplexer</keyword><keyword weight="0.4517">Computer hardware</keyword><keyword weight="0.48429">Multiplexing</keyword><keyword weight="0.5841">Rendering (computer graphics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.48716">Computer graphics</keyword><keyword weight="0.54758">Hardware architecture</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer-Verlag New York, Inc.</publisher><abstract>Described is a hardware architecture for combining the outputs of a number of z-buffer rendering engines to achieve higher performance than is possible with a single renderer. It allows a combination of renderers to achieve the same price/ performance ratio as the individual renderers that compose it, and can be extended to create systems with arbitrarily high :[57],"described architecture is based on a fusion of scan-line rendering and the conventional z-buffer algorithm. The frame buffers of several z-buffer engines are modified to scan out z-values as well as color values. Multiplexing devices combine the z/color streams from each pair of frame-buffers. These z/color streams are then combined by further multiplexers, creating a binary tree that funnels the z/color information from the many conventional frame buffers into a single z/color stream. The color stream is then used to dnve a standard display :[142],"proposed architecture allows rendering rates of millions and even tens of millions of polygons per second. The basic architecture can be extended with additional hardware to perform antialiasing and texture-mapping.</abstract></paper>