<paper id="1982747710"><title>Agents with power</title><year>1999</year><authors><author org="Univ. of Karlskrona/Ronneby, Ronneby, Sweden" id="1173604282">Rune Gustavsson</author></authors><n_citation>93</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1484566787</reference><reference>1518533288</reference><reference>1548384707</reference><reference>2148305586</reference><reference>2152737448</reference></references><venue id="103482838" type="J">Communications of The ACM</venue><doi>10.1145/295685.295698</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.37698">Programming language</keyword><keyword weight="0.44606">Telecommunications</keyword><keyword weight="0.47964">Business process</keyword><keyword weight="0.40787">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.44433">Commodity</keyword><keyword weight="0.43628">Download</keyword><keyword weight="0.4616">Home automation</keyword><keyword weight="0.44129">Upgrade</keyword><keyword weight="0.49606">Monopoly</keyword><keyword weight="0.41106">Operating system</keyword><keyword weight="0.47164">Grid</keyword><keyword weight="0.45981">The Internet</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>It should be noted there are also some potentialthreats for the utilities to lose customers or lose mar-ket opportunities due to inability to upgrade orchange their products or to change their market viewfrom a monopoly to a highly competitive market.Here, we describe project ISES (Information,Society, Energy, and Systems) in Swedenwhere these types of issues are addressed.The main business process of the energy sec-tor has typically been around productionand distribution of kiloWatt hours (kWh).However, the power grid can also be used as adata communication channel with increasinglyhigher bandwidth—over 1 Mb/s on parts of the grid—which creates new business opportunities. Another keytechnological driving force is the rapid development oftechnologies supporting design and implementation ofsmart distributed equipment communicating on theelectric grid. Since the grid can be Internet acces-sible, we can foresee how we will one dayphone our smart home from any place inthe world and ask the refrigerator if it needsto download an agent to meet a new envi-ronmental regulation.In a deregulated market, customers caneasily change their kWh commodity provider,</abstract></paper>