<paper id="1562411557"><title>An analysis of empirical PMF based tests for least significant bit image steganography</title><year>2005</year><authors><author org="&quot;University of California, Berkeley&quot;" id="1909012232">Stark Draper</author><author org="&quot;University of California, Berkeley&quot;" id="2103211980">Prakash Ishwar</author><author org="&quot;University of California, Berkeley&quot;" id="2001305480">David Molnar</author><author org="&quot;University of California, Berkeley&quot;" id="1498798796">Vinod Prabhakaran</author><author org="&quot;University of California, Berkeley&quot;" id="2205924584">Kannan Ramchandran</author><author org="&quot;University of California, Berkeley&quot;" id="2051316417">Daniel Schonberg</author><author org="&quot;University of California, Berkeley&quot;" id="2109123731">David Wagner</author></authors><n_citation>2</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1565541031</reference><reference>1998058925</reference><reference>2037956730</reference><reference>2103228545</reference><reference>2153039987</reference><reference>2153615901</reference><reference>2484649938</reference><reference>2576355915</reference></references><venue id="1175805213" type="C">Information Hiding</venue><doi>10.1007/11558859_24</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.49122">Probability mass function</keyword><keyword weight="0.50707">Steganography</keyword><keyword weight="0.46919">Statistic</keyword><keyword weight="0.40851">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45007">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.45438">Digital image</keyword><keyword weight="0.47533">Pixel</keyword><keyword weight="0.50357">Independent and identically distributed random variables</keyword><keyword weight="0.48231">Statistical hypothesis testing</keyword><keyword weight="0.52603">Least significant bit</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We consider here the class of probability mass-function (PMF) based detectors of least significant bit (LSB) embedded steganography. That is, in this paper we investigate the use of frequency counts of pixel intensities as a statistic for tests detecting the presence of hidden messages. We focus on LSB replacement (though we briefly consider LSB matching) embedding as it is a simple technique where the effect on the true PMF of the resulting image can be understood mathematically. We begin our study by considering the existing tests of Westfeld and Pfitzmann [11] and Dabeer et al.[1]. These tests assume that pixel intensities are random values that are independent and identically distributed (i.i.d.). We generalize these tests by considering PMFs of neighboring pixel intensities. We argue that consideration of higher order of correlations provide only diminishing marginal returns, and thus we can make general statements on the value of PMF based detectors. We measure the performance of our tests by calculation of receiver operating curves (ROC) over a corpus of 350 digital images. We then proceed to compare to a non-PMF based test, in particular the RS tests of Fridrich et al [3]. Although our generalized tests outperform existing PMF based predecessors, they are outperformed by the RS tests. This indicates that using PMFs as a statistic for detecting hidden messages is inherently insufficient.</abstract></paper>