<paper id="1552902269"><title>A Theory of Bisimulation for the pi-Calculus</title><year>1993</year><authors><author org="University of Edinburgh," id="279913708">Davide Sangiorgi</author></authors><n_citation>51</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>304220975</reference><reference>1503973138</reference><reference>1515953445</reference><reference>1547562281</reference><reference>1605829531</reference><reference>1771902143</reference><reference>1790031272</reference><reference>1988856107</reference><reference>2013672985</reference><reference>2128932399</reference><reference>2153411278</reference><reference>2170626879</reference></references><venue id="1145706541" type="C">International Conference on Concurrency Theory</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-57208-2_10</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.48283">Transition system</keyword><keyword weight="0.42997">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Pi calculus</keyword><keyword weight="0.46421">Modulo</keyword><keyword weight="0.44169">Prefix</keyword><keyword weight="0.57569">Bisimulation</keyword><keyword weight="0.4671">Equivalence class</keyword><keyword weight="0.47047">Completeness (statistics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.39564">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.43574">Sublanguage</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We study a new formulation of bisimulation for the π-calculus [9], which we have called open bisimulation (∼). In contrast with the previously known bisimilarity equivalences, ∼ is preserved by name substitution and (hence) by input prefix. The differences among all these equivalences already appear in the sublanguage without restriction: Here the definition of ∼ can be factorised into a “standard” part which, modulo the different syntax of actions, is the CCS bisimulation, and a part specific to the π-calculus, which requires name instantiation. Attractive features of ∼ are: a simple axiomatisation (of the finite terms), with a completeness proof which leads to the construction of minimal canonical representatives for the equivalence classes of ∼; an “efficient” characterisation, based on a modified transition system. This characterisation seems promising for the development of automated-verification tools and also shows the call-by-need flavour of ∼. Although in the paper we stick to π-calculus, the issues developed may be relevant to value-passing calculi in general.</abstract></paper>