<paper id="1932587904"><title>A motivational model of microcomputer usage</title><year>1996</year><authors><author org="" id="2239390665">Magid Igbaria</author><author org="" id="1963338072">Saroj Parasuraman</author><author org="" id="1972538261">Jack J. Baroudi</author></authors><n_citation>697</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1497226654</reference><reference>1500319018</reference><reference>1515402129</reference><reference>1568106064</reference><reference>1582170352</reference><reference>1603160327</reference><reference>1606169904</reference><reference>1791587663</reference><reference>1972888601</reference><reference>2008441192</reference><reference>2042496886</reference><reference>2116505349</reference><reference>2124330866</reference><reference>2138672502</reference><reference>2151090070</reference></references><venue id="9954729" type="J">Journal of Management Information Systems</venue><doi>10.1080/07421222.1996.11518115</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47421">Survey data collection</keyword><keyword weight="0.49405">Management information systems</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Intervening variable</keyword><keyword weight="0.40331">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.45758">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.42564">Microcomputer</keyword></keywords><publisher>M. E. Sharpe, Inc.</publisher><abstract>Survey data gathered from 471 professionals and managers in 62 companies in North America were used to test a motivational model of microcomputer usage. The model synthesized prior research findings and proposed that perceived usefulness, perceived fun/enjoyment, and social pressure would motivate increased use of microcomputers by professionals and managers. Results provided substantial support for the proposition that perceived usefulness (rather than perceived fun or social pressure) is the principal motivator. The findings also demonstrated that perceived complexity is a key intervening variable linking the antecedent variables (skills, organizational support, and organizational usage) with the three motivational variables. The results also suggested that skills play a critical role in affecting microcomputer usage. Skills directly promote microcomputer usage and influence usage through their effects on perceived usefulness, perceived enjoyment, and social pressure. The findings of the study contribute to an expanded understanding of the factors that promote microcomputer usage and also have important implications for the management of information systems.</abstract></paper>