<paper id="1580996832"><title>Key issues in information systems management: 1994–95 SIM Delphi results</title><year>1996</year><authors><author org="University of Colorado—Boulder" id="83789424">James C. Brancheau</author><author org=", University of Memphis" id="2085701858">Brian D. Janz</author><author org="University of Minnesota" id="116766436">James C. Wetherbe</author></authors><n_citation>631</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1554953436</reference><reference>1978484347</reference><reference>2101103738</reference><reference>2571873230</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/249479</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.60146">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.58162">Management information systems</keyword><keyword weight="0.62148">Information management</keyword><keyword weight="0.4124">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.47744">Delphi</keyword><keyword weight="0.47192">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.56775">Business relationship management</keyword><keyword weight="0.60259">Data management</keyword><keyword weight="0.50902">Excellence</keyword><keyword weight="0.45612">Management science</keyword><keyword weight="0.55347">Benchmarking</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>Over the past 15 years, the Society for Information Management (SIM) has periodically 1 Sirkka Jarvenpaa was the accepting senior editor for this paper. 2 Dr. Wetherbe is also FedEx Professor of Excellence at the University of Memphis. surveyed its members to determine the most critical issues in IS management. Again in 1994-95, SIM institutional and board members were asked to consider what they felt were the most critical issues facing IS executives over the next three to five years. Signaling an evolutionary shift in IS management, this study shows that business relationship issues have declined in importance compared to technology infrastructure issues. For IS executives and general managers, the key issue framework suggests some general directions for emphasis and provides a coarse measure for benchmarking their own concerns against those of their peers. The results of this study also impact educational missions in teaching and research to the extent that they need to be sensitive to the views of practicing fS executives.</abstract></paper>