<paper id="1553516176"><title>A Compositional Proof Theory for Real-Time Distributed Message Passing</title><year>1987</year><authors><author org="Eindhoven University of Technology" id="2061488235">Jozef Hooman</author></authors><n_citation>26</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1491245462</reference><reference>1573218854</reference><reference>1976029121</reference><reference>2017451766</reference><reference>2073981447</reference><reference>2086070079</reference><reference>2102728965</reference><reference>2110425399</reference><reference>2808688690</reference></references><venue id="2754330098" type="C">International Conference on Parallel Architectures and Languages Europe</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-17945-3_18</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46478">Programming language</keyword><keyword weight="0.58584">Concurrency</keyword><keyword weight="0.52036">Axiom</keyword><keyword weight="0.45954">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.58472">Denotational semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.60842">Proof theory</keyword><keyword weight="0.46163">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48231">Observer (quantum physics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.59092">Message passing</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>A compositional proof system is given for an OCCAM-like real-time programming language for distributed computing with communication via synchronous message passing. This proof system is based on specifications of processes which are independent of the program text of these processes. These specifications state (1) the assumptions of a process about the behaviour of its environment, and (2) the commitments of that process towards that environment provided these assumptions are met. The proof system is sound w.r.t a denotational semantics which incorporates assumptions regarding actions of the environment, thereby closely approximating the assumption/commitment style of reasoning on which the proof system is based. Concurrency is modelled as "maximal parallelism"; that is, if a process can proceed it will do so immediately. A process only waits when no local action is possible and no partner is available for communication. This maximality property is imposed on the domain of interpretation of assertions by postulating it as separate axiom. The timing behaviour of a system is expressed from the viewpoint of a global external observer, so there is a global notion of time. Time is not necessarily discrete.</abstract></paper>