<paper id="1849939664"><title>Metamodeling editor as a front end tool for a CASE shell</title><year>1992</year><authors><author org="University of Jyväskylä**" id="2161564812">Matti Rossi</author><author org="Swedish Institute for Systems Development" id="2694789586">Mats Gustafsson</author><author org="University of Jyväskylä**" id="2019241556">Kari Smolander</author><author org="Swedish Institute for Systems Development" id="2664734515">Lars-Åke Johansson</author><author org="University of Jyväskylä**" id="2051429859">Kalle Lyytinen</author></authors><n_citation>16</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>166854877</reference><reference>2399236057</reference></references><venue id="1134069326" type="C">Conference on Advanced Information Systems Engineering</venue><doi>10.1007/BFb0035153</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.55695">Front and back ends</keyword><keyword weight="0.49851">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.45909">Systems engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.46108">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.50407">Object type</keyword><keyword weight="0.51397">Graphical model</keyword><keyword weight="0.60632">Computer-aided software engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.62694">Metamodeling</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Customizable Computer Aided Software Engineering (CASE) tools, often called CASE shells, are penetrating in the market. CASE shells provide a flexible environment to support a variety of information systems development methods. CASE shells are often cumbersome to use and in practice few people can model and implement methods in them. To overcome these problems we have developed a graphical metamodeling environment called MetaEdit and a method modeling interface to the CASE shell RAMATIC. Using this interface the methodology engineer can develop graphical models in RAMATICu0027s model definition language and then easily generate the resource files that control the operations of RAMATIC. MetaEdit is used as a graphical front end tool to develop, fast and in user-friendly manner, method models that can then be supported using RAMATIC. In this paper we shortly present the MetaEdit tool and then describe how the interface operates by illustrating how a new method for RAMATIC is defined using MetaEditu0027s interface tool. The defined method is called TEMPORA-ER.</abstract></paper>