<paper id="1949892024"><title>The information systems identity crisis: focusing on high-visibility and high-impact research</title><year>2005</year><authors><author org="Robert H. Smith School of Business, University of Maryland,College Park, MD#TAB#" id="2281577623">Ritu Agarwall</author><author org="Robert H. Smith School of Business, University of Maryland,College Park, MD#TAB#" id="2145774684">Henry C. Lucas</author></authors><n_citation>259</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>48488267</reference><reference>81941933</reference><reference>146766432</reference><reference>160536159</reference><reference>167568186</reference><reference>174437412</reference><reference>175737083</reference><reference>178795483</reference><reference>1522120993</reference><reference>1524827457</reference><reference>1529765481</reference><reference>1544099675</reference><reference>1549804633</reference><reference>1585948735</reference><reference>1593903722</reference><reference>1971113481</reference><reference>2107934780</reference><reference>2116721563</reference><reference>2574713709</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/25148689</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.50564">Information system</keyword><keyword weight="0.48973">Identity crisis</keyword><keyword weight="0.45656">Public relations</keyword><keyword weight="0.41555">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.48654">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.45882">As is</keyword><keyword weight="0.44765">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.49052">Heuristics</keyword><keyword weight="0.50409">Transformational leadership</keyword><keyword weight="0.42446">Macro</keyword><keyword weight="0.43395">Inclusion–exclusion principle</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>This paper presents an alternative view of the Information Systems identity crisis described recently by Benbasat and Zmud (2003). We agree with many of their observations, but we are con cerned with their prescription for IS research. We critique their discussion of errors of inclusion and exclusion in IS research and highlight the potential misinterpretations that are possible from a literal 1Ron Weber was the accepting senior editor for this paper. Iris Vessey and Rudy Hirschheim served as reviewers. reading of their comments. Our conclusion is that following Benbasat and Zmudu0027s nomological net will result in a micro focus for IS research. The results of such a focus are potentially dangerous for the field. They could result in the elimination of IS from many academic programs. We present an alternative set of heuristics that can be used to assess what lies within the domain of IS scholar ship. We argue that the IS community has a powerful story to tell about the transformational impact of information technology. We believe that a significant portion of our research should be macro studies of the impact of IT. It is important for academic colleagues, deans, and managers to understand the transformational power of the technology. As IS researchers with deep knowl edge of the underlying artifact, we are best positioned to do such research.</abstract></paper>