<paper id="1533789579"><title>Training end users: an experimental investigation of the roles of the computer interface and training methods</title><year>1993</year><authors><author org="Department of Management College of Business Administration, University of Nebraska-Lincoln, Lincoln, Nebraska#TAB#" id="2114244411">Sid A. Davis</author><author org="Department of Management College of Business Administration, The University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia#TAB#" id="2302943154">Robert P. Bostrom</author></authors><n_citation>222</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1499604882</reference><reference>1552210990</reference><reference>1791587663</reference><reference>1979064760</reference><reference>1991355547</reference><reference>2003989280</reference><reference>2027280740</reference><reference>2039883913</reference><reference>2052654950</reference><reference>2053665053</reference><reference>2059311901</reference><reference>2066845089</reference><reference>2099305423</reference><reference>2115647291</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/249510</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">Assimilation (phonology)</keyword><keyword weight="0.51658">End user</keyword><keyword weight="0.45329">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Laboratory experiment</keyword><keyword weight="0.49259">Software</keyword><keyword weight="0.46901">Human–computer interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.48194">User Friendly</keyword><keyword weight="0.45869">Multimedia</keyword><keyword weight="0.55823">Interface (computing)</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>End-user computing has become an area of major importance to organizations over the past several years. As non-professional computer users come to rely on computer systems to perform more and more of their basic tasks, MIS managers need to ensure that those individuals learn to use software packages effectively. Two common, and often complementary, approaches for achieving this goal have been to develop in-house training programs and to utilize computer systems that are "user friendly." Using Assimilation Theory a basis for this study, we investigate the impacts of two types of training methods and two computer interfaces on usersu0027 learning performance and attitudes toward a computer system. A laboratory experiment was conducted to compare a commonly used direct manipulation interface-DMI (the Apple Macintosh)-with a commonly used command-based interface-Disk Operating System (DOS). Each interface was presented to subjects by using either an exploration training approach or an instruction-based training approach. Results of the study indicate that individuals using the DMI performed substantially better than those using the command-based interface. However, there was no difference between these two groups in terms of perceived ease of system use. Also, in contrast to previous studies, there were no differences in outcomes related to the two types of training methods. Assimilation Theory is used to explain these results, and recommendations are made for future research.</abstract></paper>