<paper id="1979601782"><title>Learning quickly when irrelevant attributes abound: A new linear-threshold algorithm</title><year>1987</year><authors><author org="Department of Computer and Information Sciences, University of California, Santa Cruz, U.S.A." id="1995744572">Nick Littlestone</author></authors><n_citation>106</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>43951409</reference><reference>1574848081</reference><reference>1609370892</reference><reference>1766442844</reference><reference>2009207944</reference><reference>2019363670</reference><reference>2061079066</reference><reference>2091401625</reference><reference>2139709458</reference></references><venue id="1150208541" type="C">Foundations of Computer Science</venue><doi>10.1109/SFCS.1987.37</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.52879">Boolean function</keyword><keyword weight="0.42622">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.53121">Algorithm design</keyword><keyword weight="0.45658">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.44942">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.47452">Data pre-processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.46581">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.4756">Feature extraction</keyword><keyword weight="0.46308">Context model</keyword><keyword weight="0.51908">Artificial neural network</keyword><keyword weight="0.51304">Statistical classification</keyword><keyword weight="0.48251">Bounded function</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>Valiant and others have studied the problem of learning various classes of Boolean functions from examples. Here we discuss on-line learning of these functions. In on-line learning, the learner responds to each example according to a current hypothesis. Then the learner updates the hypothesis, if necessary, based on the correct classification of the example. One natural measure of the quality of learning in the on-line setting is the number of mistakes the learner makes. For suitable classes of functions, on-line learning algorithms are available that make a bounded number of mistakes, with the bound independent of the number of examples seen by the learner. We present one such algorithm, which learns disjunctive Boolean functions, and variants of the algorithm for learning other classes of Boolean functions. The algorithm can be expressed as a linear-threshold algorithm. A primary advantage of this algorithm is that the number of mistakes that it makes is relatively little affected by the presence of large numbers of irrelevant attributes in the examples; we show that the number of mistakes grows only logarithmically with the number of irrelevant attributes. At the same time, the algorithm is computationaUy time and space efficient.</abstract></paper>