<paper id="1983105110"><title>Knowledge-based image retrieval with spatial and temporal constructs</title><year>1998</year><authors><author org="Dept. of Comput Sci., California Univ., Los Angeles, CA, USA" id="2168131383">W.W. Chu</author><author org="" id="2591958292">Chih-Cheng Hsu</author><author org="" id="2109512996">A.F. Cardenas</author><author org="" id="2159224453">R.K. Taira</author></authors><n_citation>146</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1533680255</reference><reference>2012331051</reference><reference>2023808162</reference><reference>2024828209</reference><reference>2029765716</reference><reference>2039142913</reference><reference>2044322962</reference><reference>2044365240</reference><reference>2053482498</reference><reference>2068666541</reference><reference>2070102156</reference><reference>2085827136</reference><reference>2093191240</reference><reference>2111554743</reference><reference>2118892191</reference><reference>2118948416</reference><reference>2121732645</reference><reference>2128356591</reference><reference>2131385151</reference><reference>2132381663</reference><reference>2141860785</reference><reference>2146993849</reference><reference>2157592119</reference><reference>2162748630</reference></references><venue id="30698027" type="J">IEEE Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering</venue><doi>10.1109/69.738355</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.46904">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.5717">Query language</keyword><keyword weight="0.45262">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.57122">Image retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.54311">Image processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.58697">Temporal database</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.47276">Information retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.56707">Feature (computer vision)</keyword><keyword weight="0.54758">Knowledge-based systems</keyword><keyword weight="0.52153">Temporal logic</keyword><keyword weight="0.5922">Object Query Language</keyword><keyword weight="0.46212">Machine learning</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE Educational Activities Department</publisher><abstract>A knowledge-based approach to retrieve medical images by feature and content with spatial and temporal constructs is developed. Selected objects of interest in an image are segmented and contours are generated. Features and content are extracted and stored in a database. Knowledge about image features can be expressed as a type abstraction hierarchy (TAH), the high-level nodes of which represent the most general concepts. Traversing TAH nodes allows approximate matching by feature and content if an exact match is not available. TAHs can be generated automatically by clustering algorithms based on feature values in the databases and hence are scalable to large collections of image features. Since TAHs are generated based on user classes and applications, they are context- and user-sensitive. A knowledge-based semantic image model is proposed to represent the various aspects of an image objectu0027s characteristics. The model provides a mechanism for accessing and processing spatial, evolutionary and temporal queries. A knowledge-based spatial temporal query language (KSTL) has been developed that extends ODMGu0027s OQL and supports approximate matching of features and content, conceptual terms and temporal logic predicates. Further, a visual query language has been developed that accepts point-click-and-drag visual iconic input on the screen that is then translated into KSTL. User models are introduced to provide default parameter values for specifying query conditions. We have implemented the KMeD (Knowledge-based Medical Database) system using these concepts.</abstract></paper>