<paper id="1494802451"><title>The influence of IT management practice on IT use in large organizations</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="Florida State University#TAB#" id="2306278708">Andrew C. Boynton</author><author org="" id="101071923">Robert W. Zmud</author><author org="" id="2117045478">Gerry C. Jacobs</author></authors><n_citation>566</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1490628909</reference><reference>1607696742</reference><reference>2068558843</reference><reference>2081737649</reference><reference>2126762059</reference></references><venue id="57293258" type="J">Management Information Systems Quarterly</venue><doi>10.2307/249620</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.39389">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.51273">Information technology</keyword><keyword weight="0.47226">Knowledge management</keyword><keyword weight="0.61615">Absorptive capacity</keyword><keyword weight="0.57987">Information technology management</keyword><keyword weight="0.45259">Management science</keyword><keyword weight="0.52907">LISREL</keyword></keywords><publisher>Society for Information Management and The Management Information Systems Research Center</publisher><abstract>This paper draws upon the absorptive capacity as the theoretical basis for a pragmatic explanation of key factors affecting information technology (IT) use in large, complex organizations. IT use is defined as the extent to which an organization deploys IT to support operational and strategic tasks. The study uses results from a survey of senior IT managers from 132 firms to examine hypothesized relationships among the following constructs: IT management climate, managerial IT knowledge, IT-management-process effectiveness, and IT use. A structural-equation model is developed using LISREL to assess the relative effects of and interrelationships among these constructs. The studyu0027s findings indicate that managerial IT knowledge is a dominant factor in explaining high levels of IT use and that both managerial IT knowledge and IT-management-process effectiveness are influenced by IT management climate.</abstract></paper>