<paper id="1485374110"><title>Key Distribution Systems Based on Identification Information</title><year>1987</year><authors><author org="NEC CORPORATION" id="2936276540">Eiji Okamoto</author></authors><n_citation>45</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1569083856</reference><reference>1976767440</reference><reference>1996360405</reference><reference>2156186849</reference></references><venue id="1153524033" type="C">International Cryptology Conference</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-48184-2_15</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.62318">Key distribution</keyword><keyword weight="0.60257">Key management</keyword><keyword weight="0.46364">Computer security</keyword><keyword weight="0.52273">Directory</keyword><keyword weight="0.46272">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Distribution system</keyword><keyword weight="0.51984">Identification (information)</keyword><keyword weight="0.50131">Cryptosystem</keyword><keyword weight="0.62948">Key distribution center</keyword><keyword weight="0.59125">Public-key cryptography</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Two types of key distribution systems based on identification information are proposed, one for decentralized networks and the other for centralized networks. The system suitable for decentralized networks is analogous to the Diffie-Hellman public key distribution system, in which the former uses each useru0027s identification information instead of a public file used in the latter. The proposed system is able to defend the networks from impostors. The system suitable for centralized networks, which is less analogous to the Diffie-Hellman system, can also defend the networks from impostors, though the network center does not have any directory of public or private key-encrypting keys of the users. Both of the systems proposed in this paper do not require any seivices of a center to distribute work keys, or users to keep directories of key-encrypting keys. Therefore, key management in cryptosystems can be practical and simplified by adopting the identity-based key distribution systems.</abstract></paper>