<paper id="1969698078"><title>Pattern recognition of strings with substitutions, insertions, deletions and generalized transpositions☆</title><year>1997</year><authors><author org="School of Computer Science, Carleton University, Ottawa, Canada KIS 5B6" id="2679239725">B.J. Oommen</author><author org="School of Computer Science, Carleton University, Ottawa, Canada KIS 5B6" id="2719019589">R.K.S. Loke</author></authors><n_citation>39</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1970026646</reference><reference>1982042557</reference><reference>1986124289</reference><reference>2011632873</reference><reference>2012010763</reference><reference>2018366250</reference><reference>2027506564</reference><reference>2038268267</reference><reference>2039262760</reference><reference>2071663716</reference><reference>2088381812</reference><reference>2088534759</reference><reference>2108701227</reference><reference>2111192396</reference><reference>2111643688</reference><reference>2162744351</reference><reference>2165654401</reference><reference>2169906351</reference></references><venue id="414566" type="J">Pattern Recognition</venue><doi>10.1016/S0031-3203(96)00101-X</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.63402">String-to-string correction problem</keyword><keyword weight="0.48389">Cursive</keyword><keyword weight="0.47294">Search algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.42752">Pattern recognition</keyword><keyword weight="0.47089">Noisy text</keyword><keyword weight="0.44412">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.54111">Syntactic pattern recognition</keyword><keyword weight="0.40827">Machine learning</keyword><keyword weight="0.38955">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Alphabet</keyword></keywords><publisher>Pergamon</publisher><abstract>Abstract We study the problem of recognizing a string Y which is the noisy version of some unknown string X chosen from a finite dictionary, H . The traditional case which has been extensively studied in the literature is the one in which Y contains substitution, insertion and deletion (SID) errors. Although some work has been done to extend the traditional set of edit operations to include the straightforward transposition of adjacent eharacters [see J. Assoc. Comput. Mach. 22 , 177–183 (1975)] the problem is unsolved when the transposed characters are themselves subsequently substituted, as is typical in cursive and typewritten script, in molecular biology and in noisy chain-coded boundaries. In this paper we present the first reported solution to the analytic problem of editing one string X to another, Y , using these four edit operations. A scheme for obtaining the optimal edit operations has also been given. Both these solutions are optimal for the infinite alphabet case. Using these algorithms we present a syntactic pattern recognition scheme which corrects noisy text containing all these types of errors. The paper includes experimental results involving sub-dictionaries of the most common English words which demonstrate the superiority of our system over existing methods.</abstract></paper>