<paper id="1545967542"><title>New Perspectives on Ubiquitous Computing from Ethnographic Study of Elders with Cognitive Decline</title><year>2003</year><authors><author org="Intel Research#TAB#" id="2098259900">Margaret E. Morris</author><author org="Intel Research#TAB#" id="2145636857">Jay Lundell</author><author org="Intel Research#TAB#" id="2113154552">Eric Dishman</author><author org="Intel Research#TAB#" id="2151949948">Brad Needham</author></authors><n_citation>93</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1515685044</reference><reference>2002076319</reference><reference>2150634379</reference><reference>2164691964</reference></references><venue id="1171345118" type="C">Ubiquitous Computing</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-39653-6_18</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.49881">Successful aging</keyword><keyword weight="0.43321">Mobile computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Design elements and principles</keyword><keyword weight="0.49953">Health care</keyword><keyword weight="0.51142">Population</keyword><keyword weight="0.44962">Public relations</keyword><keyword weight="0.3917">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.41589">Human–computer interaction</keyword><keyword weight="0.37506">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.53618">Ubiquitous computing</keyword><keyword weight="0.4023">Ethnography</keyword><keyword weight="0.65661">Cognitive decline</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>A rapidly growing elder population is placing unprecedented demands on health care systems around the world. Cognitive decline is one of the most taxing health problems in terms of both its relation to elders’ overall functioning and the cost of care. The needs of elders with cognitive decline – for invisible, intuitive support and assessment – invite a reconsideration of the assumptions behind and specifications for ubiquitous computing solutions. This paper describes findings and implications of ethnographic research conducted with cognitively impaired individuals and their informal care networks in 45 households in 5 U.S. regions. Key themes regarding needs and barriers to successful aging are addressed through a set of design principles which apply across the stages of cognitive decline. To convey stage-specific findings and associated challenges for ubiquitous computing, case studies of four representative households and example concept solutions are presented. The design principles and technology challenges outlined in this paper may generalize to other contexts for ubiquitous computing.</abstract></paper>