<paper id="1974672137"><title>Isomorphism of graphs of bounded valence can be tested in polynomial time</title><year>1982</year><authors><author org="Department of Mathematics, Bucknell University, Lewisburg, Pennsylvania 17837, USA" id="2470953425">Eugene M. Luks</author></authors><n_citation>544</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>2017265236</reference><reference>2124052428</reference><reference>2139569497</reference></references><venue id="141020589" type="J">Journal of Computer and System Sciences</venue><doi>10.1016/0022-0000(82)90009-5</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.55758">Graph canonization</keyword><keyword weight="0.4749">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.47902">Combinatorics</keyword><keyword weight="0.59439">Graph isomorphism</keyword><keyword weight="0.5764">Automorphism</keyword><keyword weight="0.54508">Permutation</keyword><keyword weight="0.61595">Permutation group</keyword><keyword weight="0.55169">System of imprimitivity</keyword><keyword weight="0.41735">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.58265">Graph isomorphism problem</keyword><keyword weight="0.56459">Bounded function</keyword></keywords><publisher>Academic Press</publisher><abstract>Abstract Suppose we are given a set of generators for a group G of permutations of a colored set A . The color automorphism problem for G involves finding generators for the subgroup of G which stabilizes the color classes. It is shown that testing isomorphism of graphs of bounded valance is polynomial-time reducible to the color automorphism problem for groups with composition factors of bounded order. The algorithm for the latter problem involves three divide-and-conquer maneuvers. The problem is solved sequentially on the G-orbits. An orbit is broken into a minimal system of imprimitivity blocks. At that point, the hypothesis on G guarantees the presence of a subgroup P of “small” index which acts a p -group on the blocks. Divide-and-conquer is then used on the group, trading the problem on G for a small number of similar problems on P . In the trivalent case p = 2, P = G and the analysis requires only elementary notions. For higher valence, the justification requires some new observations about primitive permutation groups.</abstract></paper>