<paper id="1539419769"><title>A Secure, Robust Watermark for Multimedia</title><year>1996</year><authors><author org="NEC Research Institute" id="2128956250">Ingemar J. Cox</author><author org="NEC Research Institute" id="2983408107">Joe Kilian</author><author org="mit" id="2178157365">Frank Thomson Leighton</author><author org="NEC Research Institute" id="326541501">Talal Shamoon</author></authors><n_citation>419</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>79957971</reference><reference>1482673219</reference><reference>1639643357</reference><reference>2117197027</reference><reference>2144556767</reference><reference>2158518777</reference><reference>2158587798</reference></references><venue id="1175805213" type="C">Information Hiding</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-61996-8_41</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.44019">Computer vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.61939">Digital watermarking</keyword><keyword weight="0.42684">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.4692">Discrete cosine transform</keyword><keyword weight="0.68813">Watermark</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.49503">Dither</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Narrow band</keyword><keyword weight="0.40545">Multimedia</keyword><keyword weight="0.40474">Resampling</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Wideband channels</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We describe a digital watermarking method for use in audio, image, video and multimedia data. We argue that a watermark must be placed in perceptually significant components of a signal if it is to be robust to common signal distortions and malicious attack. However, it is well known that modification of these components can lead to perceptual degradation of the signal. To avoid this, we propose to insert a watermark into the spectral components of the data using techniques analogous to spread sprectrum communications, hiding a narrow band signal in a wideband channel that is the data. The watermark is difficult for an attacker to remove, even when several individuals conspire together with independently watermarked copies of the data. It is also robust to common signal and geometric distortions such as digital-to-analog and analog-to-digital conversion, resampling, and requantization, including dithering and recompression and rotation, translation, cropping and scaling. The same digital watermarking algorithm can be applied to all three media under consideration with only minor modifications, making it especially appropriate for multimedia products. Retrieval of the watermark unambiguously identifies the owner, and the watermark can be constructed to make counterfeiting almost impossible. Experimental results are presented to support these claims.</abstract></paper>