<paper id="1621418330"><title>Content-Based Networking: A New Communication Infrastructure</title><year>2001</year><authors><author org="University of colorado." id="699336959">Antonio Carzaniga</author><author org="University of colorado." id="2115607830">Alexander L. Wolf</author></authors><n_citation>154</n_citation><doc_type /><references><reference>1513710402</reference><reference>1971405342</reference><reference>2067580069</reference><reference>2123732385</reference><reference>2131185826</reference><reference>2134686414</reference><reference>2137899328</reference><reference>2141375288</reference></references><venue id="" type="">IMWS '01 Revised Papers from the NSF Workshop on Developing an Infrastructure for Mobile and Wireless Systems</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-36257-6_6</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.47871">Open research</keyword><keyword weight="0.59936">Middleware</keyword><keyword weight="0.4658">World Wide Web</keyword><keyword weight="0.63888">Middleware (distributed applications)</keyword><keyword weight="0.44647">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.63198">Networking hardware</keyword><keyword weight="0.63237">Active networking</keyword><keyword weight="0.50321">Multicast</keyword><keyword weight="0.63628">Software-defined networking</keyword><keyword weight="0.47611">Routing table</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>We argue that the needs of many classes of modern applications, especially those targeted at mobile or wireless computing, demand the services of content-based publish/subscribe middleware, and that this middleware in turn demands a new kind of communication infrastructure for its proper implementation. We refer to this new communication infrastructure as content-based networking. The service model of this network must directly support the interface of an advanced content-based publish/subscribe middleware service. At the same time, the implementation must be architected as a true distributed network, providing appropriate guarantees of reliability, security, and performance. We do not propose content-based networking as a replacement for IP, nor do we advocate an implementation of a publish/subscribe middleware at the network level (i.e., within routers). Instead, we argue that content-based networking must be designed according to established networking principles and techniques. To this end, in this paper, we formulate the foundational concepts of content-based networking, and relate them to the corresponding concepts in traditional networking. We also briefly review our experience with content-based publish/subscribe middleware and suggest some open research problems in the area of content-based networking.</abstract></paper>