<paper id="1494762195"><title>Integrating Primary Ocular Processes</title><year>1992</year><authors><author org="Royal Institute of Tech." id="1969992295">Kourosh Pahlavan</author><author org="Royal Institute of Tech." id="2042553572">Tomas Uhlin</author><author org="Royal Institute of Tech." id="2042689995">Jan-Olof Eklundh</author></authors><n_citation>56</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>2061894728</reference><reference>2112128543</reference><reference>2710962803</reference></references><venue id="1124077590" type="C">European Conference on Computer Vision</venue><doi>10.1016/0262-8856(92)90010-Z</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.418">Computer vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.55421">Active vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.45492">Binocular vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.49404">Machine vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.43946">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.44721">Binocular rivalry</keyword><keyword weight="0.44167">Rivalry</keyword><keyword weight="0.42107">Eye movement</keyword><keyword weight="0.42495">Fault tolerance</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.43691">Robotics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Abstract The study of active vision using binocular head-eye systems requires answers to some fundamental questions in control of attention. This paper presents a cooperative solution to resolve the ambiguities generated by the processes engaged in fixation. We suggest an approach based on integration of these processes, resulting in cooperatively extracted unique solutions. The discussion begins by looking at biological vision. Based on this discussion, a model of integration for machine vision is suggested. The implementation of the model on the KTH-head — a head-eye system simulating the essential degrees of freedom in mammalians — is explained, and in this context the primary processes in the head-eye system are briefly described. The major stress is put on the idea that the rivalry processes in vision in general, and the headu0027s behavioural processes in particular, results in a reliable outcome. As an experiment, the ambiguities raised by fixation at repetitive patterns is tested; the cooperative approach proves to handle the problem correctly and find a unique solution for the fixation point dynamically and in real-time.</abstract></paper>