<paper id="6458718"><title>Automatic detection of rib contours in chest radiographs</title><year>1975</year><authors><author org="Department of Computer Science and School of Engineering, University of California, Irvine, California#TAB#" id="2182147601">H. Wechsler</author><author org="Department of Computer Science and School of Engineering, University of California, Irvine, California#TAB#" id="1984663976">J. Sklansky</author></authors><n_citation>24</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>50425026</reference><reference>1747804349</reference><reference>2010283933</reference><reference>2022286645</reference><reference>2057162280</reference><reference>2085864267</reference><reference>2095905764</reference><reference>2170633497</reference></references><venue id="1203999783" type="C">International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-0348-5767-3</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.40555">Computer vision</keyword><keyword weight="0.4867">Line (geometry)</keyword><keyword weight="0.53669">Rib cage</keyword><keyword weight="0.33542">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.41334">Filter (signal processing)</keyword><keyword weight="0.42371">STRIPS</keyword><keyword weight="0.41051">Radiography</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.46876">Thresholding</keyword><keyword weight="0.47355">Conic section</keyword><keyword weight="0.41673">Laplace operator</keyword></keywords><publisher>Morgan Kaufmann Publishers Inc.</publisher><abstract>We have constructed a computer algorithm that finds the contours of the dorsal and ventral portions of the images of ribs in chest :[23],"following are a few of the expected uses for the automatic detection of rib contours: 1. Rib images contribute false positives in tumor-detection algorithms. Hence detecting the rib contours should facilitate removal of these lalse posltives. 2. The ribs provide a frame of reference for the description and location of lesions within the thoracic cavity. 3. The envelope of the ribs provides a more accurate basis for computing the boundary of the chest cavity (referred to as the "lung boundary" In other papers) than other known algorithm :[110],"consists of a) high-pass filtering of the digitized picture, b) local "edge" detection by a combination of thresholding, Laplacian, and gradient operators, c) selection of edge elements in accordance with their angular orientation, d) matching straight line segments and conic sections to the selected edge elements, e) constructing strips centered on the straight line segments and conic sections, and f) heuristic search within these strips.</abstract></paper>