<paper id="1513238603"><title>Convertible Nominative Signatures</title><year>2004</year><authors><author org="Xidian University#TAB#" id="2687524803">Zhenjie Huang</author><author org="(Xidian University)" id="2722727638">Yumin Wang</author></authors><n_citation>30</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1524339785</reference><reference>1590696383</reference><reference>1763199136</reference><reference>1852820576</reference><reference>2095708839</reference><reference>2143832005</reference><reference>2911473785</reference></references><venue id="1131830996" type="C">Australasian Conference on Information Security and Privacy</venue><doi>10.1007/978-3-540-27800-9_30</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.40458">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.54258">Nominative case</keyword><keyword weight="0.418">Convertible</keyword><keyword weight="0.41942">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.42315">Algorithm</keyword><keyword weight="0.42244">Theoretical computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.43479">Formal specification</keyword><keyword weight="0.55956">Digital signature</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Formal description</keyword><keyword weight="0.47786">Verifiable secret sharing</keyword><keyword weight="0.46681">Diffie–Hellman problem</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>A feasible solution to prevent potential misuse of signatures is to put some restrictions on their verification. Therefore S.J.Kim, [4] S.J.Park and D.H.Won introduced the nominative signature, in which only the nominee can verify and prove the validity of given signatures, and proposed a nominative signature scheme (called KPW scheme). In this paper, we first show that KPW scheme is not nominative because the nominator can also verify and prove the validity of given signatures. Then we extend the concept of nominative signature to the convertible nominative signature which has an additional property that the nominee can convert given nominative signatures into universally verifiable signatures. We give a formal definition for it and propose a practical scheme that implements it. The proposed scheme is secure, in which its unforgeability is the same as that of the Schnorr’s signature scheme and its untransferability relies on the hardness of the Decision-Diffie-Hellman Problem.</abstract></paper>