<paper id="1606211267"><title>Modelling inside GIS : Part 1, Model structures, exploratory spatial data analysis and aggregation</title><year>1994</year><authors><author org="National Center for Geographic Information and Analysis, State University of New York at Buffalo , 301, Wilkeson Quad, Buffalo, NY, 14261-0023, U.S.A." id="2021322682">Michael Batty</author><author org="National Center for Geographic Information and Analysis, State University of New York at Buffalo , 301, Wilkeson Quad, Buffalo, NY, 14261-0023, U.S.A." id="2147387002">Yichun Xie</author></authors><n_citation>90</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1544752055</reference><reference>1970396124</reference><reference>1993292463</reference></references><venue id="60606061" type="J">International Journal of Geographic Information Systems</venue><doi>10.1080/02693799408902001</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.53778">Spatial analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.51635">Population</keyword><keyword weight="0.45933">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.4271">Embedding</keyword><keyword weight="0.44148">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.49153">Software</keyword><keyword weight="0.49011">Thematic map</keyword><keyword weight="0.65003">Enterprise GIS</keyword><keyword weight="0.43888">Specification</keyword><keyword weight="0.48655">User interface</keyword></keywords><publisher>Taylor &amp; Francis Group</publisher><abstract>Abstract This is the first of two papers elaborating a framework for embedding urban models within GIS. This framework is based upon using the display capabilities of GIS as the user interface to the conventional modelling process, beginning with data selection and analysis, moving to model specification and calibration, and thence to prediction. In this paper, we outline how various stages in this process based on purpose-built software outside the system, are accessed and operated through the GIS. We first deal with display based on thematic maps, surfaces, graphs and linked windows, standard to any data from whatever source, be it observations, model estimates or predictions. We then describe how various datasets are selected, how the spatial system can be partitioned or aggregated, and how rudimentary exploratory spatial data analysis enables scatterplots to be associated with thematic maps. We illustrate all these functions and operations using the proprietary GIS ARC-INFO applied to population data ...</abstract></paper>