<paper id="1969553191"><title>Continuous stochastic logic characterizes bisimulation of continuous-time Markov processes</title><year>2003</year><authors><author org="Département d’Informatique, Université Laval, Que., Canada G1K 7P4" id="2008651352">Josée Desharnais</author><author org="School of Computer Science, McGill University, Montreal, Canada H3A 2A7" id="2216498992">Prakash Panangaden</author></authors><n_citation>72</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1498125516</reference><reference>1531625469</reference><reference>1865728679</reference><reference>2021089599</reference><reference>2096899005</reference><reference>2100893927</reference><reference>2152692559</reference></references><venue id="70478294" type="J">The Journal of Logic and Algebraic Programming</venue><doi>10.1016/S1567-8326(02)00068-1</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.43031">Zeno's paradoxes</keyword><keyword weight="0.46773">Null set</keyword><keyword weight="0.45467">Discrete mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.4628">Converse</keyword><keyword weight="0.50321">Markov process</keyword><keyword weight="0.50422">Markov chain</keyword><keyword weight="0.53255">Bisimulation</keyword><keyword weight="0.48685">State space</keyword><keyword weight="0.4184">Mathematics</keyword><keyword weight="0.50406">Bounded function</keyword></keywords><publisher>North-Holland</publisher><abstract>In a recent paper Baier et al. [Lecture Notes in Computer Science, Springer-Verlag, 2000, p. 358] analyzed a new way of model-checking formulas of a logic for continuous-time processes—called continuous stochastic logic (henceforth CSL)—against continuous-time Markov chains—henceforth CTMCs. One of the important results of that paper was the proof that if two CTMCs were bisimilar then they would satisfy exactly the same formulas of CSL. This raises the converse question—does satisfaction of the same collection of CSL formulas imply bisimilarity? In other words, given two CTMCs which are known to satisfy exactly the same formulas of CSL does it have to be the case that they are bisimilar? We prove that the answer to the question just raised is “yes”. In fact we prove a significant extension, namely that a subset of CSL suffices even for systems where the state space may be a continuum. Along the way we prove a result to the effect that the set of Zeno paths has measure zero provided that the transition rates are bounded.</abstract></paper>