<paper id="1548983485"><title>A cross border collaboration environment, as a means for offering online public services and for evaluating the performance of public executives</title><year>2005</year><authors><author org="Dept. of Informatics, Aristotelian Univ. of Thessaloniki, Greece" id="2973889457">L. Anthopoulos</author><author org="Dept. of Informatics, Aristotelian Univ. of Thessaloniki, Greece" id="2973644075">I.A. Tsoukalas</author></authors><n_citation>3</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>1598117333</reference><reference>2049976527</reference><reference>2055564965</reference><reference>2120053216</reference><reference>2152328567</reference><reference>2153456088</reference></references><venue id="2754955730" type="C">IEEE International Conference on e-Technology, e-Commerce and e-Service</venue><doi>10.1109/EEE.2005.3</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.49628">Human resources</keyword><keyword weight="0.47997">Public relations</keyword><keyword weight="0.47615">Collaborative software</keyword><keyword weight="0.66347">Public sector</keyword><keyword weight="0.67046">New public management</keyword><keyword weight="0.47324">Marketing</keyword><keyword weight="0.51496">Government</keyword><keyword weight="0.46358">Business</keyword><keyword weight="0.51724">The Internet</keyword></keywords><publisher>IEEE</publisher><abstract>Current e-government systems offer only a few digital public services. Additionally, studies carried out around the world show that citizens who have used digital means to access the public administration prefer the traditional methods for their transactions with government agencies. Two surveys carried out in Greece show that citizens feel more confident when civil servants handle their affairs. These results could lead to the re-designation of e-government platforms, so that public executives could be involved in the execution of digital public services. In this paper a concept of a collaboration system is presented, as the proper environment that unifies distributed agencies, maps all available human resource in the public administration, shares processes equally to equivalent agencies and evaluates the performance of public executives.</abstract></paper>