<paper id="1509153766"><title>Active Database Rules with Transaction-Conscious Stable-Model Semantics</title><year>1995</year><authors><author org="University of California" id="2028117853">Carlo Zaniolo</author></authors><n_citation>54</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>270081759</reference><reference>1524852452</reference><reference>1541526834</reference><reference>1597227583</reference><reference>1672891595</reference><reference>1768000531</reference><reference>1839937676</reference><reference>2057552436</reference><reference>2062851028</reference><reference>2120052337</reference><reference>2122211300</reference><reference>2159808530</reference><reference>2170551989</reference></references><venue id="2756318837" type="C">International Conference on Deductive and Object-Oriented Databases</venue><doi>10.1007/3-540-60608-4_34</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.64044">Formal semantics (linguistics)</keyword><keyword weight="0.71116">Operational semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.46257">Programming language</keyword><keyword weight="0.60383">Axiomatic semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.64266">Computational semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.4595">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.66257">Denotational semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.67173">Action semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.5992">Stable model semantics</keyword><keyword weight="0.73217">Well-founded semantics</keyword></keywords><publisher>Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher><abstract>Semantics represents a major problem area for active databases in as much as (i) there is no formal framework for defining an implementation-independent semantics of active rules, and (ii) the various systems developed so far have ad-hoc operational semantics that are widely different from each other. This situation contributes to the difficulty of predicting the run-time behavior of sets of rules: thus, ensuring the termination of a given set of rules is currently viewed as a major research issue. In this paper, we introduce a durable change semantics for active database rules; this semantics improves Starburstu0027s deferred activation notion with concepts taken from Postgres and Heraclitus and the semantic foundations of deductive databases. We provide a formal logic-based model for this transaction-oriented semantics, show that it is amenable to efficient implementation, and prove that it solves the non-termination problem.</abstract></paper>