<paper id="1971889796"><title>Product feature categorization with multilevel latent semantic association</title><year>2009</year><authors><author org="IBM, China Research Lab, Beijing, China" id="2943282897">Honglei Guo</author><author org="IBM, China Research Lab, Beijing, China" id="2165111143">Huijia Zhu</author><author org="IBM, China Research Lab, Beijing, China" id="2157942709">Zhili Guo</author><author org="IBM, China Research Lab, Beijing, China" id="2126744454">XiaoXun Zhang</author><author org="IBM, China Research Lab, Beijing, China" id="2305826094">Zhong Su</author></authors><n_citation>99</n_citation><doc_type>Conference</doc_type><references><reference>3195375</reference><reference>153318553</reference><reference>1581485226</reference><reference>1593045043</reference><reference>1880262756</reference><reference>2010163591</reference><reference>2033403400</reference><reference>2042980227</reference><reference>2081375810</reference><reference>2096110600</reference><reference>2103464847</reference><reference>2107743791</reference><reference>2114581066</reference><reference>2119864770</reference><reference>2131090205</reference><reference>2134089414</reference><reference>2141631351</reference><reference>2143027446</reference><reference>2154970197</reference><reference>2160660844</reference><reference>2166817967</reference><reference>2172083107</reference></references><venue id="1194094125" type="C">Conference on Information and Knowledge Management</venue><doi>10.1145/1645953.1646091</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.4607">Data mining</keyword><keyword weight="0.57846">Categorization</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Latent semantic indexing</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Semantic association</keyword><keyword weight="0.47297">Information retrieval</keyword><keyword weight="0.44754">Computer science</keyword><keyword weight="0.55618">Sentiment analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.47501">Natural language processing</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword weight="0.68431">Probabilistic latent semantic analysis</keyword><keyword weight="0.6181">Semantic computing</keyword></keywords><publisher>ACM</publisher><abstract>In recent years, the number of freely available online reviews is increasing at a high speed. Aspect-based opinion mining technique has been employed to find out reviewersu0027 opinions toward different product aspects. Such finer-grained opinion mining is valuable for the potential customers to make their purchase decisions. Product-feature extraction and categorization is very important for better mining aspect-oriented opinions. Since people usually use different words to describe the same aspect in the reviews, product-feature extraction and categorization becomes more challenging. Manually product-feature extraction and categorization is tedious and time consuming, and practically infeasible for the massive amount of products. In this paper, we propose an unsupervised product-feature categorization method with multilevel latent semantic association. After extracting product-features from the semi-structured reviews, we construct the first latent semantic association (LaSA) model to group words into a set of concepts according to their virtual context documents. It generates the latent semantic structure for each product-feature. The second LaSA model is constructed to categorize the product-features according to their latent semantic structures and context snippets in the reviews. Experimental results demonstrate that our method achieves better performance compared with the existing approaches. Moreover, the proposed method is language- and domain-independent.</abstract></paper>