<paper id="1980314090"><title>The 5ESS switching system: Maintenance capabilities</title><year>1985</year><authors><author org="Authors are employees of AT&amp;T Bell Laboratories" id="2556607722">G. Haugk</author><author org="Authors are employees of AT&amp;T Bell Laboratories" id="2549596428">F. M. Lax</author><author org="Authors are employees of AT&amp;T Bell Laboratories" id="2556983706">R. D. Royer</author><author org="Authors are employees of AT&amp;T Bell Laboratories" id="2549058974">J. R. Williams</author></authors><n_citation>43</n_citation><doc_type>Journal</doc_type><references><reference>1976886284</reference><reference>1988203744</reference><reference>2084603716</reference><reference>2087529930</reference><reference>2149654680</reference></references><venue id="2764907053" type="J">AT&amp;T technical journal</venue><doi>10.1002/j.1538-7305.1985.tb00280.x</doi><keywords><keyword weight="0.0">System maintenance</keyword><keyword weight="0.0">5ESS switch</keyword><keyword weight="0.54206">Systems design</keyword><keyword weight="0.49656">Quality of service</keyword><keyword weight="0.51233">Software</keyword><keyword weight="0.38407">Engineering</keyword><keyword weight="0.5394">Software architecture</keyword><keyword weight="0.56884">Operations support system</keyword><keyword weight="0.47064">Embedded system</keyword><keyword weight="0.50352">Human interface device</keyword></keywords><publisher>Alcatel-Lucent</publisher><abstract>In developing the 5ESS™ switching system, a digital switch with distributed control, major emphasis has been placed on reliability, quality of service to the customer, and efficiency of the human interface for the telephone operating companies. To achieve a high-reliability design for this system, a robust hardware/software architecture has been developed with emphasis on a networking approach to functional maintenance organization. Building on this approach, a highly effective set of capabilities is provided for the detection and sectionalization of errors, and for recovery from software and hardware faults. Complete diagnostic aids are available, and flexible video display terminals provide an efficient and attractive means for telephone operating company personnel to interface to the system. Further, a wide range of automated, as well as manual, trunk and line test features are integrated into the system design; and interfaces to both local work stations and operational support systems provide a variety of options for efficient maintenance operation.</abstract></paper>